{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Data retention and storage in Application Insights",
      "pos": [
        28,
        78
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retention and privacy policy statement",
      "pos": [
        98,
        136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data collection, retention and storage in Application Insights",
      "pos": [
        453,
        515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application Insights is in preview.",
      "pos": [
        519,
        554
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        560,
        568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article answers questions about the data collected by  [Visual Studio Application Insights][start] and how it is processed and stored.",
      "pos": [
        570,
        709
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application Insights is an Azure Service in Preview.",
      "pos": [
        711,
        763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While in Preview we are working towards protecting your data per the policies described in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Security, Privacy, and Compliance white paper<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=392408)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        764,
        960
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Collection",
      "pos": [
        966,
        976
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How is data collected by Application Insights?",
      "pos": [
        983,
        1029
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application Insights SDKs and agents that you combine with your application send data to the Application Insights service.",
      "pos": [
        1031,
        1153
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The data is processed by the service to provide you with reports, alerts and other functionality.",
      "pos": [
        1155,
        1252
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This can include data that you choose to capture by using the API, for example in properties and custom events.",
      "pos": [
        1254,
        1365
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How much data can be captured?",
      "pos": [
        1372,
        1402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Per second<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Up to 500 data points per second per instrumentation key (that is, per application).",
      "pos": [
        1405,
        1505
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the free [pricing tier][pricing], the limit is 100 dp/s.",
      "pos": [
        1506,
        1566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are three buckets which are counted separately:",
      "pos": [
        1568,
        1621
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1625,
        1754
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>TrackTrace calls<ept id=\"p1\">](app-insights-api-custom-events-metrics.md#track-trace)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>captured logs<ept id=\"p2\">](app-insights-asp-net-trace-logs.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1757,
        1863
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Exceptions<ept id=\"p1\">](app-insights-api-custom-events-metrics.md#track-exception)</ept>, subject to a lower limit of 50/s."
    },
    {
      "content": "All other telemetry (page views, requests, dependencies, metrics, custom events and web test results).",
      "pos": [
        1866,
        1968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Monthly<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Between 5 and 15 million data points in each calendar month, depending on your <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>pricing plan<ept id=\"p2\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/details/application-insights/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1970,
        2143
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Except for the free [pricing tier][pricing], you can buy additional capacity if you hit the limit.",
      "pos": [
        2144,
        2242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>data point<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is an item of telemetry sent to the Azure portal about your app.",
      "pos": [
        2245,
        2324
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It can be sent by:",
      "pos": [
        2325,
        2343
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2347,
        2525
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SDK modules<ept id=\"p1\">](app-insights-configuration-with-applicationinsights-config.md)</ept> that automatically collect data, for example to report a request or crash, or to measure performance."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2528,
        2657
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>API<ept id=\"p1\">](app-insights-api-custom-events-metrics.md)</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">`Track...`</ph> calls that you have written, such as <ph id=\"ph2\">`TrackEvent`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph3\">`trackPageView`</ph>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2660,
        2752
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Availability web tests<ept id=\"p1\">](app-insights-monitor-web-app-availability.md)</ept> that you have set up."
    },
    {
      "content": "Telemetry data include:",
      "pos": [
        2754,
        2777
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2781,
        2847
      ],
      "content": "Each row in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>diagnostic search<ept id=\"p1\">](app-insights-diagnostic-search.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "The raw data from which charts in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>metric explorer<ept id=\"p1\">](app-insights-metrics-explorer.md)</ept> are aggregated.",
      "pos": [
        2850,
        2951
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Metric data such as performance counter data don't usually appear as individual points in metric explorer.",
      "pos": [
        2952,
        3058
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3061,
        3156
      ],
      "content": "Each web test result in an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>availability<ept id=\"p1\">](app-insights-monitor-web-app-availability.md)</ept> report."
    },
    {
      "content": "User and session counts aren't included in the quota for pricing purposes.",
      "pos": [
        3158,
        3232
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How do I know how many data points my app is sending?",
      "pos": [
        3235,
        3288
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open Settings/Quota and Pricing to see the Data Volume chart.",
      "pos": [
        3293,
        3354
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Or in Metrics Explorer, add a new chart and select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data point volume<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as its metric.",
      "pos": [
        3357,
        3444
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Switch on Grouping, and group by <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3445,
        3492
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How long is the data kept?",
      "pos": [
        3500,
        3526
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3529,
        3629
      ],
      "content": "It depends on your <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>pricing plan<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/details/application-insights/)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Raw data points (that is, items that you can inspect in Diagnostic Search): between 7 and 30 days.",
      "pos": [
        3631,
        3729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Aggregated data (that is, counts, averages and other statistical data that you see in Metric Explorer) are retained at a grain of 1 minute for 30 days, and 1 hour or 1 day (depending on type) for at least 13 months.",
      "pos": [
        3731,
        3946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What limits are there on different types of data?",
      "pos": [
        3953,
        4002
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Maximum of 200 unique metric names and 200 unique property names for your application.",
      "pos": [
        4008,
        4094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Metrics include data send via TrackMetric as well as measurements on other  data types such as Events.",
      "pos": [
        4095,
        4197
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics and property names][api] are global per instrumentation key not scoped to data type.",
      "pos": [
        4199,
        4292
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Properties][apiproperties] can be used for filtering and group by only while they have less than 100 unique values for each property.",
      "pos": [
        4297,
        4431
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the unique values exceed 100, the property can still be used for search and filtering but no longer for filters.",
      "pos": [
        4432,
        4550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard properties such as Request Name and Page URL are limited to 1000 unique values per week.",
      "pos": [
        4555,
        4652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After 1000 unique values, additional values are marked as “Other values”.",
      "pos": [
        4653,
        4726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The original value can still be used for full text search and filtering.",
      "pos": [
        4727,
        4799
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access",
      "pos": [
        4805,
        4811
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Who can see the data?",
      "pos": [
        4818,
        4839
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The data is visible to you and, if you have an organization account, your team members.",
      "pos": [
        4841,
        4928
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It can be exported by you and your team members and could be copied to other locations and passed on to other people.",
      "pos": [
        4931,
        5048
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What does Microsoft do with the information my app sends to Application Insights?",
      "pos": [
        5055,
        5136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft uses the data only in order to provide the service to you.",
      "pos": [
        5138,
        5206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Location",
      "pos": [
        5212,
        5220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Where is the data held?",
      "pos": [
        5227,
        5250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the USA.",
      "pos": [
        5255,
        5266
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can it be stored somewhere else, for example in Europe?",
      "pos": [
        5274,
        5329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not yet.",
      "pos": [
        5334,
        5342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Security",
      "pos": [
        5348,
        5356
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How secure is my data?",
      "pos": [
        5364,
        5386
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The data is stored in Microsoft Azure servers.",
      "pos": [
        5389,
        5435
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For accounts in the Azure Preview Portal, account restrictions are described in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Security, Privacy, and Compliance document<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=392408)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5436,
        5618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For accounts in the Visual Studio Online Portal, the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Visual Studio Online Data Protection<ept id=\"p1\">](http://download.microsoft.com/download/8/E/E/8EE6A61C-44C2-4F81-B870-A267F1DF978C/MicrosoftVisualStudioOnlineDataProtection.pdf)</ept> document applies.",
      "pos": [
        5619,
        5857
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access to your data by Microsoft personnel is restricted.",
      "pos": [
        5860,
        5917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We access your data only with your permission and if it is necessary to support your use of Application Insights.",
      "pos": [
        5918,
        6031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data in aggregate across all our customers' applications (such as data rates and average size of traces) is used to improve Application Insights.",
      "pos": [
        6034,
        6179
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Could someone else's telemetry interfere with my Application Insights data?",
      "pos": [
        6186,
        6261
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They could send additional telemetry to your account by using the instrumentation key, which can be found in the code of your web pages.",
      "pos": [
        6263,
        6399
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With enough additional data, your metrics would not correctly represent your app's performance and usage.",
      "pos": [
        6400,
        6505
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you share code with other projects, remember to remove your instrumentation key.",
      "pos": [
        6507,
        6590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Encryption",
      "pos": [
        6595,
        6605
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Is the data encrypted in Application Insights servers?",
      "pos": [
        6612,
        6666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not inside the servers at present.",
      "pos": [
        6669,
        6703
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All data is encrypted as it moves between data centers.",
      "pos": [
        6705,
        6760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Is the data encrypted in transit from my application to Application Insights servers?",
      "pos": [
        6767,
        6852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes, we use https to send data to the portal from nearly all SDKs, including web servers, devices and HTTPS web pages.",
      "pos": [
        6854,
        6972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The only exception is data sent from plain HTTP web pages.",
      "pos": [
        6973,
        7031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Personally Identifiable Information",
      "pos": [
        7036,
        7071
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Could Personally Identifiable Information (PII) be sent to Application Insights?",
      "pos": [
        7078,
        7158
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes.",
      "pos": [
        7161,
        7165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As general guidance:",
      "pos": [
        7168,
        7188
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Most standard telemetry (that is, telemetry sent without you writing any code) does not include explicit PII.",
      "pos": [
        7192,
        7301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, it might be possible to identify individuals by inference from a collection of events.",
      "pos": [
        7302,
        7397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exception and trace messages could contain PII",
      "pos": [
        7400,
        7446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Custom telemetry - that is, calls such as TrackEvent that you write in code using the API or log traces - can contain any data you choose.",
      "pos": [
        7449,
        7587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The table at the end of this document contains more detailed descriptions of the data collected.",
      "pos": [
        7590,
        7686
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Am I responsible for complying with laws and regulations in regard to PII?",
      "pos": [
        7695,
        7769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes.",
      "pos": [
        7771,
        7775
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is your responsibility to ensure that the collection and use of the data complies with laws and regulations, and with the Microsoft Online Services Terms.",
      "pos": [
        7776,
        7933
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should inform your customers appropriately about the data your application collects and how the data is used.",
      "pos": [
        7935,
        8048
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can my users turn off Application Insights?",
      "pos": [
        8055,
        8098
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not directly.",
      "pos": [
        8100,
        8113
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We don't provide a switch that your users can operate to turn off Application Insights.",
      "pos": [
        8114,
        8201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, you can implement such a feature in your application.",
      "pos": [
        8203,
        8265
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All the SDKs include an API setting that turns off telemetry collection.",
      "pos": [
        8266,
        8338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "My application is unintentionally collecting sensitive information.",
      "pos": [
        8346,
        8413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can Application Insights scrub this data so it isn't retained?",
      "pos": [
        8414,
        8476
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application Insights does not filter or delete your data.",
      "pos": [
        8478,
        8535
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should manage the data appropriately and avoid sending such data to Application Insights.",
      "pos": [
        8536,
        8629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data sent by Application Insights",
      "pos": [
        8636,
        8669
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The SDKs vary between platforms, and there are are several components that you can install.",
      "pos": [
        8671,
        8762
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(Refer to [Application Insights - get started][start].) Each component sends different data.",
      "pos": [
        8763,
        8855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Classes of data sent in different scenarios",
      "pos": [
        8862,
        8905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your action",
      "pos": [
        8907,
        8918
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data classes collected (see next table)",
      "pos": [
        8922,
        8961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Add Application Insights SDK to a .NET web project][greenbrown]",
      "pos": [
        8970,
        9034
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ServerContext",
      "pos": [
        9037,
        9050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inferred",
      "pos": [
        9055,
        9063
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Perf counters",
      "pos": [
        9068,
        9081
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Requests",
      "pos": [
        9086,
        9094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Exceptions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        9099,
        9113
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Session",
      "pos": [
        9118,
        9125
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "users",
      "pos": [
        9130,
        9135
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Install Status Monitor on IIS][redfield]",
      "pos": [
        9136,
        9177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Add AI Extension to Azure VM or Web App][azure]",
      "pos": [
        9182,
        9230
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Dependencies",
      "pos": [
        9231,
        9243
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ServerContext",
      "pos": [
        9248,
        9261
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inferred",
      "pos": [
        9266,
        9274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Perf counters",
      "pos": [
        9279,
        9292
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Add Application Insights SDK to a Java web app][java]",
      "pos": [
        9293,
        9347
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ServerContext",
      "pos": [
        9348,
        9361
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inferred",
      "pos": [
        9366,
        9374
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Request",
      "pos": [
        9379,
        9386
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Session",
      "pos": [
        9391,
        9398
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "users",
      "pos": [
        9403,
        9408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Add JavaScript SDK to web page][client]",
      "pos": [
        9409,
        9449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ClientContext",
      "pos": [
        9450,
        9463
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inferred",
      "pos": [
        9469,
        9477
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Page",
      "pos": [
        9482,
        9486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ClientPerf",
      "pos": [
        9491,
        9501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Add SDK to Windows Store app][windows]",
      "pos": [
        9502,
        9541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DeviceContext",
      "pos": [
        9542,
        9555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users",
      "pos": [
        9560,
        9565
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Crash data",
      "pos": [
        9570,
        9580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Define default properties][apiproperties]",
      "pos": [
        9581,
        9623
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9624,
        9672
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Properties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on all standard and custom events"
    },
    {
      "content": "[Call TrackMetric][api]",
      "pos": [
        9673,
        9696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Numeric values",
      "pos": [
        9697,
        9711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Properties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        9716,
        9730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Call Track*][api]",
      "pos": [
        9731,
        9749
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Event name",
      "pos": [
        9750,
        9760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Properties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        9765,
        9779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Call TrackException][api]",
      "pos": [
        9780,
        9806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Exceptions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        9807,
        9821
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stack dump",
      "pos": [
        9826,
        9836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Properties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        9841,
        9855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SDK can't collect data.",
      "pos": [
        9856,
        9879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example:",
      "pos": [
        9880,
        9892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "- can't access perf counters",
      "pos": [
        9899,
        9927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "-  exception in telemetry initializer",
      "pos": [
        9933,
        9970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SDK diagnostics",
      "pos": [
        9973,
        9988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For [SDKs for other platforms][platforms], see their documents.",
      "pos": [
        9992,
        10055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The classes of collected data",
      "pos": [
        10064,
        10093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Collected data class",
      "pos": [
        10095,
        10115
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Includes (not an exhaustive list)",
      "pos": [
        10118,
        10151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Properties",
      "pos": [
        10163,
        10173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any data - determined by your code",
      "pos": [
        10178,
        10212
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DeviceContext",
      "pos": [
        10215,
        10228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Id, IP, Locale, Device model, network, network type, OEM name, screen resolution, Role Instance, Role Name, Device Type",
      "pos": [
        10230,
        10349
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ClientContext",
      "pos": [
        10350,
        10363
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "OS, locale, language, network, window resolution",
      "pos": [
        10365,
        10413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Session",
      "pos": [
        10414,
        10421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "session id",
      "pos": [
        10424,
        10434
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ServerContext",
      "pos": [
        10435,
        10448
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Machine name, locale, OS, device, user session, user context, operation",
      "pos": [
        10450,
        10521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inferred",
      "pos": [
        10523,
        10531
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "geo location from IP address, timestamp, OS, browser",
      "pos": [
        10533,
        10585
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Metrics",
      "pos": [
        10586,
        10593
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Metric name and value",
      "pos": [
        10596,
        10617
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Events",
      "pos": [
        10618,
        10624
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Event name and value",
      "pos": [
        10627,
        10647
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PageViews",
      "pos": [
        10648,
        10657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "URL and page name or screen name",
      "pos": [
        10660,
        10692
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Client perf",
      "pos": [
        10693,
        10704
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "URL/page name, browser load time",
      "pos": [
        10707,
        10739
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Requests",
      "pos": [
        10740,
        10748
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "URL, duration, response code",
      "pos": [
        10750,
        10778
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Dependencies",
      "pos": [
        10779,
        10791
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Type(SQL, HTTP, ...), connection string or URI, sync/async, duration, success, SQL statement (with Status Monitor)",
      "pos": [
        10792,
        10906
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exceptions",
      "pos": [
        10909,
        10919
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10924,
        10994
      ],
      "content": "Type, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>message<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, call stacks, source file and line number, thread id"
    },
    {
      "content": "Crashes",
      "pos": [
        10995,
        11002
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Process id, parent process id, crash thread id; application patch, id, build;  exception type, address, reason; obfuscated symbols and registers, binary start and end addresses, binary name and path, cpu type",
      "pos": [
        11005,
        11213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Trace",
      "pos": [
        11214,
        11219
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11222,
        11252
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Message<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and severity level"
    },
    {
      "content": "Perf counters",
      "pos": [
        11253,
        11266
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Processor time, available memory, request rate, exception rate, process private bytes, IO rate, request duration, request queue length",
      "pos": [
        11269,
        11403
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Availability",
      "pos": [
        11404,
        11416
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Web test response code, duration of each test step, test name, timestamp, success, response time, test location",
      "pos": [
        11419,
        11530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SDK diagnostics",
      "pos": [
        11531,
        11546
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Trace message or Exception",
      "pos": [
        11549,
        11575
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can [switch off some of the data by editing ApplicationInsights.config][config]",
      "pos": [
        11578,
        11661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Credits",
      "pos": [
        11667,
        11674
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11676,
        11796
      ],
      "content": "This product includes GeoLite2 data created by MaxMind, available from <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>http://www.maxmind.com<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.maxmind.com)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11801,
        11827
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"video\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Videos"
    },
    {
      "content": "Introduction",
      "pos": [
        11834,
        11846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get started",
      "pos": [
        11904,
        11915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        12642,
        12646
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Data retention and storage in Application Insights\" \n    description=\"Retention and privacy policy statement\" \n    services=\"application-insights\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"alancameronwills\" \n    manager=\"douge\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"application-insights\" \n    ms.workload=\"tbd\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"ibiza\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"08/11/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"awills\"/>\n\n# Data collection, retention and storage in Application Insights \n\n*Application Insights is in preview.*\n\n## Overview\n\nThis article answers questions about the data collected by  [Visual Studio Application Insights][start] and how it is processed and stored.\n\nApplication Insights is an Azure Service in Preview. While in Preview we are working towards protecting your data per the policies described in the [Azure Security, Privacy, and Compliance white paper](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=392408).\n\n\n## Collection\n\n#### How is data collected by Application Insights?\n\nApplication Insights SDKs and agents that you combine with your application send data to the Application Insights service.  The data is processed by the service to provide you with reports, alerts and other functionality.  This can include data that you choose to capture by using the API, for example in properties and custom events.\n\n#### How much data can be captured? \n\n**Per second**: Up to 500 data points per second per instrumentation key (that is, per application). For the free [pricing tier][pricing], the limit is 100 dp/s.\n\nThere are three buckets which are counted separately:\n\n* [TrackTrace calls](app-insights-api-custom-events-metrics.md#track-trace) and [captured logs](app-insights-asp-net-trace-logs.md)\n* [Exceptions](app-insights-api-custom-events-metrics.md#track-exception), subject to a lower limit of 50/s.\n* All other telemetry (page views, requests, dependencies, metrics, custom events and web test results).\n\n**Monthly**: Between 5 and 15 million data points in each calendar month, depending on your [pricing plan](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/details/application-insights/). Except for the free [pricing tier][pricing], you can buy additional capacity if you hit the limit.\n\n\nA *data point* is an item of telemetry sent to the Azure portal about your app. It can be sent by:\n\n* [SDK modules](app-insights-configuration-with-applicationinsights-config.md) that automatically collect data, for example to report a request or crash, or to measure performance.\n* [API](app-insights-api-custom-events-metrics.md) `Track...` calls that you have written, such as `TrackEvent` or `trackPageView`.\n* [Availability web tests](app-insights-monitor-web-app-availability.md) that you have set up.\n\nTelemetry data include:\n\n* Each row in [diagnostic search](app-insights-diagnostic-search.md)\n* The raw data from which charts in [metric explorer](app-insights-metrics-explorer.md) are aggregated. Metric data such as performance counter data don't usually appear as individual points in metric explorer.\n* Each web test result in an [availability](app-insights-monitor-web-app-availability.md) report.\n\nUser and session counts aren't included in the quota for pricing purposes.\n\n*How do I know how many data points my app is sending?*\n\n* Open Settings/Quota and Pricing to see the Data Volume chart.\n* Or in Metrics Explorer, add a new chart and select **Data point volume** as its metric. Switch on Grouping, and group by **Data type**.\n\n\n#### How long is the data kept? \n\nIt depends on your [pricing plan](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/details/application-insights/).\n\nRaw data points (that is, items that you can inspect in Diagnostic Search): between 7 and 30 days.\n\nAggregated data (that is, counts, averages and other statistical data that you see in Metric Explorer) are retained at a grain of 1 minute for 30 days, and 1 hour or 1 day (depending on type) for at least 13 months.\n\n#### What limits are there on different types of data?\n\n1.  Maximum of 200 unique metric names and 200 unique property names for your application. Metrics include data send via TrackMetric as well as measurements on other  data types such as Events.  [Metrics and property names][api] are global per instrumentation key not scoped to data type.\n2.  [Properties][apiproperties] can be used for filtering and group by only while they have less than 100 unique values for each property. After the unique values exceed 100, the property can still be used for search and filtering but no longer for filters.\n3.  Standard properties such as Request Name and Page URL are limited to 1000 unique values per week. After 1000 unique values, additional values are marked as “Other values”. The original value can still be used for full text search and filtering.\n\n\n## Access\n\n#### Who can see the data?\n\nThe data is visible to you and, if you have an organization account, your team members. \n\nIt can be exported by you and your team members and could be copied to other locations and passed on to other people.\n\n#### What does Microsoft do with the information my app sends to Application Insights?\n\nMicrosoft uses the data only in order to provide the service to you.\n\n\n## Location\n\n#### Where is the data held? \n\n* In the USA. \n\n#### Can it be stored somewhere else, for example in Europe? \n\n* Not yet. \n\n## Security \n\n#### How secure is my data? \n\nThe data is stored in Microsoft Azure servers. For accounts in the Azure Preview Portal, account restrictions are described in the [Azure Security, Privacy, and Compliance document](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=392408). For accounts in the Visual Studio Online Portal, the [Visual Studio Online Data Protection](http://download.microsoft.com/download/8/E/E/8EE6A61C-44C2-4F81-B870-A267F1DF978C/MicrosoftVisualStudioOnlineDataProtection.pdf) document applies. \n\nAccess to your data by Microsoft personnel is restricted. We access your data only with your permission and if it is necessary to support your use of Application Insights. \n\nData in aggregate across all our customers' applications (such as data rates and average size of traces) is used to improve Application Insights.\n\n#### Could someone else's telemetry interfere with my Application Insights data?\n\nThey could send additional telemetry to your account by using the instrumentation key, which can be found in the code of your web pages. With enough additional data, your metrics would not correctly represent your app's performance and usage.\n\nIf you share code with other projects, remember to remove your instrumentation key.\n\n## Encryption\n\n#### Is the data encrypted in Application Insights servers? \n\nNot inside the servers at present.\n\nAll data is encrypted as it moves between data centers.\n\n#### Is the data encrypted in transit from my application to Application Insights servers?\n\nYes, we use https to send data to the portal from nearly all SDKs, including web servers, devices and HTTPS web pages. The only exception is data sent from plain HTTP web pages.\n\n## Personally Identifiable Information\n\n#### Could Personally Identifiable Information (PII) be sent to Application Insights? \n\nYes. \n\nAs general guidance:\n\n* Most standard telemetry (that is, telemetry sent without you writing any code) does not include explicit PII. However, it might be possible to identify individuals by inference from a collection of events.\n* Exception and trace messages could contain PII\n* Custom telemetry - that is, calls such as TrackEvent that you write in code using the API or log traces - can contain any data you choose.\n\n\nThe table at the end of this document contains more detailed descriptions of the data collected.\n\n\n\n#### Am I responsible for complying with laws and regulations in regard to PII?\n\nYes. It is your responsibility to ensure that the collection and use of the data complies with laws and regulations, and with the Microsoft Online Services Terms.\n\nYou should inform your customers appropriately about the data your application collects and how the data is used.\n\n#### Can my users turn off Application Insights?\n\nNot directly. We don't provide a switch that your users can operate to turn off Application Insights.\n\nHowever, you can implement such a feature in your application. All the SDKs include an API setting that turns off telemetry collection. \n\n#### My application is unintentionally collecting sensitive information. Can Application Insights scrub this data so it isn't retained?\n\nApplication Insights does not filter or delete your data. You should manage the data appropriately and avoid sending such data to Application Insights.\n\n\n\n## Data sent by Application Insights\n\nThe SDKs vary between platforms, and there are are several components that you can install. (Refer to [Application Insights - get started][start].) Each component sends different data.\n\n#### Classes of data sent in different scenarios\n\nYour action  | Data classes collected (see next table)\n---|---\n[Add Application Insights SDK to a .NET web project][greenbrown] | ServerContext<br/>Inferred<br/>Perf counters<br/>Requests<br/>**Exceptions**<br/>Session<br/>users\n[Install Status Monitor on IIS][redfield]<br/>[Add AI Extension to Azure VM or Web App][azure]|Dependencies<br/>ServerContext<br/>Inferred<br/>Perf counters\n[Add Application Insights SDK to a Java web app][java]|ServerContext<br/>Inferred<br/>Request<br/>Session<br/>users\n[Add JavaScript SDK to web page][client]|ClientContext <br/>Inferred<br/>Page<br/>ClientPerf\n[Add SDK to Windows Store app][windows]|DeviceContext<br/>Users<br/>Crash data\n[Define default properties][apiproperties]|**Properties** on all standard and custom events\n[Call TrackMetric][api]|Numeric values<br/>**Properties**\n[Call Track*][api]|Event name<br/>**Properties**\n[Call TrackException][api]|**Exceptions**<br/>Stack dump<br/>**Properties**\nSDK can't collect data. For example: <br/> - can't access perf counters<br/> -  exception in telemetry initializer | SDK diagnostics\n \n\nFor [SDKs for other platforms][platforms], see their documents.\n\n\n\n#### The classes of collected data\n\nCollected data class | Includes (not an exhaustive list) \n---|---\n**Properties**|**Any data - determined by your code**\nDeviceContext |Id, IP, Locale, Device model, network, network type, OEM name, screen resolution, Role Instance, Role Name, Device Type\nClientContext |OS, locale, language, network, window resolution\nSession | session id\nServerContext |Machine name, locale, OS, device, user session, user context, operation \nInferred |geo location from IP address, timestamp, OS, browser\nMetrics | Metric name and value\nEvents | Event name and value\nPageViews | URL and page name or screen name\nClient perf | URL/page name, browser load time\nRequests |URL, duration, response code\nDependencies|Type(SQL, HTTP, ...), connection string or URI, sync/async, duration, success, SQL statement (with Status Monitor)\n**Exceptions** | Type, **message**, call stacks, source file and line number, thread id\nCrashes | Process id, parent process id, crash thread id; application patch, id, build;  exception type, address, reason; obfuscated symbols and registers, binary start and end addresses, binary name and path, cpu type\nTrace | **Message** and severity level\nPerf counters | Processor time, available memory, request rate, exception rate, process private bytes, IO rate, request duration, request queue length\nAvailability | Web test response code, duration of each test step, test name, timestamp, success, response time, test location\nSDK diagnostics | Trace message or Exception \n\nYou can [switch off some of the data by editing ApplicationInsights.config][config]\n\n\n## Credits\n\nThis product includes GeoLite2 data created by MaxMind, available from [http://www.maxmind.com](http://www.maxmind.com).\n\n## <a name=\"video\"></a>Videos\n\n#### Introduction\n\n> [AZURE.VIDEO application-insights-introduction]\n\n#### Get started\n\n> [AZURE.VIDEO getting-started-with-application-insights]\n\n\n\n\n<!--Link references-->\n\n[api]: app-insights-api-custom-events-metrics.md\n[apiproperties]: app-insights-api-custom-events-metrics.md#properties\n[azure]: ../insights-perf-analytics.md\n[client]: app-insights-javascript.md\n[config]: app-insights-configuration-with-applicationinsights-config.md\n[greenbrown]: app-insights-start-monitoring-app-health-usage.md\n[java]: app-insights-java-get-started.md\n[platforms]: app-insights-platforms.md\n[pricing]: http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/details/application-insights/\n[redfield]: app-insights-monitor-performance-live-website-now.md\n[start]: app-insights-get-started.md\n[windows]: app-insights-windows-get-started.md\n\n \ntest\n"
}