{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Common DocumentDB use cases | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        28,
        73
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn about the top five use cases for DocumentDB: user generated content, event logging, catalog data, user preferences data, and  Internet of Things (IoT).",
      "pos": [
        93,
        250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Common DocumentDB use cases",
      "pos": [
        567,
        594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article provides an overview of several common use cases for DocumentDB.",
      "pos": [
        595,
        672
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The recommendations in this article serve as a starting point as you develop your application with DocumentDB.",
      "pos": [
        674,
        784
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After reading this article, you'll be able to answer the following questions:",
      "pos": [
        789,
        866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What are the common use cases for DocumentDB?",
      "pos": [
        872,
        917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a user generated content store?",
      "pos": [
        920,
        996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a catalog data store?",
      "pos": [
        999,
        1065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a event log store?",
      "pos": [
        1068,
        1131
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a user preferences data store?",
      "pos": [
        1134,
        1209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a data store for Internet of Things (IoT) systems?",
      "pos": [
        1212,
        1307
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User generated content",
      "pos": [
        1317,
        1339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A common use case for DocumentDB is to store and query user generated content (UGC) for web and mobile applications, particularly social media applications.",
      "pos": [
        1340,
        1496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some examples of UGC are chat sessions, tweets, blog posts, ratings, and comments.",
      "pos": [
        1498,
        1580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Often, the UGC in social media applications is a blend of free form text, properties, tags and relationships that are not bounded by rigid structure.",
      "pos": [
        1582,
        1731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Content such as chats, comments, and posts can be stored in DocumentDB without requiring transformations or complex object to relational mapping layers.",
      "pos": [
        1736,
        1888
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data properties can be added or modified easily to match requirements as developers iterate over the application code, thus promoting rapid development.",
      "pos": [
        1890,
        2042
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Applications that integrate with various social networks must respond to changing schemas from these networks.",
      "pos": [
        2046,
        2156
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As data is automatically indexed by default in DocumentDB, data is ready to be queried at any time.",
      "pos": [
        2158,
        2257
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hence, these applications have the flexibility to retrieve projections as per their respective needs.",
      "pos": [
        2259,
        2360
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Many of the social applications run at global scale and can exhibit unpredictable usage patterns.",
      "pos": [
        2369,
        2466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Flexibility in scaling the data store is essential as the application layer scales to match usage demand.",
      "pos": [
        2468,
        2573
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can scale out by adding additional data partitions under a DocumentDB account.",
      "pos": [
        2575,
        2657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition, you can also create additional DocumentDB accounts across multiple regions.",
      "pos": [
        2659,
        2747
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For DocumentDB service region availability, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Regions<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/regions/#services)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2748,
        2858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Catalog data",
      "pos": [
        2866,
        2878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Catalog data usage scenarios involve storing and querying a set of attributes for entities such as people, places and products.",
      "pos": [
        2879,
        3006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some examples of catalog data are user accounts, product catalogs, device registries for IoT, and bill of materials systems.",
      "pos": [
        3008,
        3132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Attributes for this data may vary and can change over time to fit application requirements.",
      "pos": [
        3134,
        3225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Consider an example of a product catalog for an automotive parts supplier.",
      "pos": [
        3229,
        3303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Every part may have its own attributes in addition to the common attributes that all parts share.",
      "pos": [
        3304,
        3401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Furthermore, attributes for a specific part can change the following year when a new model is released.",
      "pos": [
        3403,
        3506
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a JSON document store, DocumentDB supports flexible schemas and allows you to represent data with nested properties, and thus it is well suited for storing product catalog data.",
      "pos": [
        3508,
        3688
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log data",
      "pos": [
        3700,
        3708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application logging is often emitted in large volumes and may have varying attributes based on the deployed application version or the component logging events.",
      "pos": [
        3709,
        3869
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log data is not bounded by complex relationships or rigid structures.",
      "pos": [
        3871,
        3940
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Increasingly, log data is persisted in JSON format since JSON is lightweight and easy for humans to read.",
      "pos": [
        3941,
        4046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are typically two major use cases related to event log data.",
      "pos": [
        4051,
        4117
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The first use case is to perform ad-hoc queries over a subset of data for troubleshooting.",
      "pos": [
        4119,
        4209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During troubleshooting, a subset of data is first retrieved from the logs, typically by time series.",
      "pos": [
        4211,
        4311
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then, a drill-down is performed by filtering the dataset with error levels or error messages.",
      "pos": [
        4313,
        4406
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is where storing event logs in DocumentDB is an advantage.",
      "pos": [
        4407,
        4470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log data stored in DocumentDB is automatically indexed by default, and thus it is ready to be queried at any time.",
      "pos": [
        4471,
        4585
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition, log data can be persisted across data partitions as a time-series.",
      "pos": [
        4586,
        4665
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Older logs can be rolled out to cold storage per your retention policy.",
      "pos": [
        4666,
        4737
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The second use case involves long running data analytics jobs performed offline over a large volume of log data.",
      "pos": [
        4749,
        4861
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Examples of this use case include server availability analysis, application error analysis, and clickstream data analysis.",
      "pos": [
        4863,
        4985
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, Hadoop is used to perform these types of analyses.",
      "pos": [
        4987,
        5048
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With the Hadoop Connector for DocumentDB, DocumentDB databases function as data sources and sinks for Pig, Hive and Map/Reduce jobs.",
      "pos": [
        5050,
        5182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For details on the Hadoop Connector for DocumentDB, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Run a Hadoop job with DocumentDB and HDInsight<ept id=\"p1\">](documentdb-run-hadoop-with-hdinsight/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5183,
        5327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User preferences data",
      "pos": [
        5338,
        5359
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Nowadays, most modern web and mobile applications come with complex views and experiences.",
      "pos": [
        5360,
        5450
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These views and experiences are usually dynamic, catering to user preferences or moods and branding needs.",
      "pos": [
        5451,
        5557
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hence, applications need to be able to retrieve personalized settings effectively in order to render UI elements and experiences quickly.",
      "pos": [
        5559,
        5696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "JSON is an effective format to represent UI layout data as it is not only lightweight, but also can be easily interpreted by JavaScript.",
      "pos": [
        5699,
        5835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DocumentDB offers tunable consistency levels that allow fast reads with low latency writes.",
      "pos": [
        5837,
        5928
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hence, storing UI layout data including personalized settings as JSON documents in DocumentDB is an effective means to get this data across the wire.",
      "pos": [
        5929,
        6078
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Device sensor data",
      "pos": [
        6083,
        6101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "IoT use cases commonly share some patterns in how they ingest, process and store data.",
      "pos": [
        6102,
        6188
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "First, these systems allow for data intake that can ingest bursts of data from device sensors of various locales.",
      "pos": [
        6190,
        6303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, these systems process and analyze streaming data to derive real time insights.",
      "pos": [
        6305,
        6389
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "And last but not least, most if not all data will eventually land in a data store for adhoc querying and offline analytics.",
      "pos": [
        6390,
        6513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Azure offers rich services that can be leveraged for IoT use cases.",
      "pos": [
        6519,
        6596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure IoT services are a set of services including Azure Event Hubs, Azure DocumentDB, Azure Stream Analytics, Azure Notification Hub, Azure Machine Learning, Azure HDInsight, and PowerBI.",
      "pos": [
        6598,
        6786
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Bursts of data can be ingested by Azure Event Hubs as it offers high throughput data ingestion with low latency.",
      "pos": [
        6789,
        6901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data ingested that needs to be processed for real time insight can be funneled to Azure Stream Analytics for real time analytics.",
      "pos": [
        6902,
        7031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data can be loaded into DocumentDB for adhoc querying.",
      "pos": [
        7032,
        7086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the data is loaded into DocumentDB, the data is ready to be queried.",
      "pos": [
        7087,
        7160
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The data in DocumentDB can be used as reference data as part of real time analytics.",
      "pos": [
        7162,
        7246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addtion, data can further be refined and processed by connecting DocumentDB data to HDInsight for Pig, Hive or Map/Reduce jobs.",
      "pos": [
        7248,
        7378
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Refined data is then loaded back to DocumentDB for reporting.",
      "pos": [
        7380,
        7441
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7446,
        7623
      ],
      "content": "For a sample IoT solution using DocumentDB, EventHubs and Storm, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>hdinsight-storm-examples repository on GitHub<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/hdinsight/hdinsight-storm-examples/)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7625,
        7784
      ],
      "content": "For more information on Azure offerings for IoT, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create the Internet of Your Things<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/internet-of-things.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        7789,
        7799
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7802,
        8035
      ],
      "content": "To get started with DocumentDB, you can create an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>account<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/)</ept> and then follow our <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>learning guide<ept id=\"p2\">](documentdb-learning-map.md)</ept> to learn about DocumentDB and find the information you need."
    },
    {
      "content": "Or, if you'd like to read more about customers using DocumentDB, the following customer stories are available:",
      "pos": [
        8038,
        8148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Breeze<ept id=\"p1\">](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18602)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8152,
        8231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Leading Integrator Gives Multinational Firms Global Insight in Minutes with Flexible Cloud Technologies.",
      "pos": [
        8232,
        8336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>News Republic<ept id=\"p1\">](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18639)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8339,
        8425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adding intelligence to the news to provide information with purpose for engaged citizens.",
      "pos": [
        8426,
        8515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SGS International<ept id=\"p1\">](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18653)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8519,
        8609
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For consistent color across the globe, major brands turn to SGS.",
      "pos": [
        8610,
        8674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "And SGS turns to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        8675,
        8698
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Telenor<ept id=\"p1\">](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18608)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8701,
        8781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Global leader Telenor uses the cloud to move with the speed of a startup.",
      "pos": [
        8782,
        8855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>XOMNI<ept id=\"p1\">](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18667)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8859,
        8937
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The store of the future runs on speedy search and the easy flow of data.",
      "pos": [
        8938,
        9010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        9014,
        9018
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Common DocumentDB use cases | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"Learn about the top five use cases for DocumentDB: user generated content, event logging, catalog data, user preferences data, and  Internet of Things (IoT).\" \n    services=\"documentdb\" \n    authors=\"h0n\" \n    manager=\"jhubbard\" \n    editor=\"monicar\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"documentdb\" \n    ms.workload=\"data-services\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"07/10/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"hawong\"/>\n\n# Common DocumentDB use cases\nThis article provides an overview of several common use cases for DocumentDB.  The recommendations in this article serve as a starting point as you develop your application with DocumentDB.   \n\nAfter reading this article, you'll be able to answer the following questions: \n \n- What are the common use cases for DocumentDB?\n- What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a user generated content store?\n- What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a catalog data store?\n- What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a event log store?\n- What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a user preferences data store?\n- What are the benefits of using DocumentDB as a data store for Internet of Things (IoT) systems?\n\n    \n## User generated content\nA common use case for DocumentDB is to store and query user generated content (UGC) for web and mobile applications, particularly social media applications.  Some examples of UGC are chat sessions, tweets, blog posts, ratings, and comments.  Often, the UGC in social media applications is a blend of free form text, properties, tags and relationships that are not bounded by rigid structure.   \n\nContent such as chats, comments, and posts can be stored in DocumentDB without requiring transformations or complex object to relational mapping layers.  Data properties can be added or modified easily to match requirements as developers iterate over the application code, thus promoting rapid development.  \n\nApplications that integrate with various social networks must respond to changing schemas from these networks.  As data is automatically indexed by default in DocumentDB, data is ready to be queried at any time.  Hence, these applications have the flexibility to retrieve projections as per their respective needs.       \n\nMany of the social applications run at global scale and can exhibit unpredictable usage patterns.  Flexibility in scaling the data store is essential as the application layer scales to match usage demand.  You can scale out by adding additional data partitions under a DocumentDB account.  In addition, you can also create additional DocumentDB accounts across multiple regions. For DocumentDB service region availability, see [Azure Regions](http://azure.microsoft.com/regions/#services).   \n\n## Catalog data\nCatalog data usage scenarios involve storing and querying a set of attributes for entities such as people, places and products.  Some examples of catalog data are user accounts, product catalogs, device registries for IoT, and bill of materials systems.  Attributes for this data may vary and can change over time to fit application requirements.  \n\nConsider an example of a product catalog for an automotive parts supplier. Every part may have its own attributes in addition to the common attributes that all parts share.  Furthermore, attributes for a specific part can change the following year when a new model is released.  As a JSON document store, DocumentDB supports flexible schemas and allows you to represent data with nested properties, and thus it is well suited for storing product catalog data.       \n\n## Log data\nApplication logging is often emitted in large volumes and may have varying attributes based on the deployed application version or the component logging events.  Log data is not bounded by complex relationships or rigid structures. Increasingly, log data is persisted in JSON format since JSON is lightweight and easy for humans to read.\n   \nThere are typically two major use cases related to event log data.  The first use case is to perform ad-hoc queries over a subset of data for troubleshooting.  During troubleshooting, a subset of data is first retrieved from the logs, typically by time series.  Then, a drill-down is performed by filtering the dataset with error levels or error messages. This is where storing event logs in DocumentDB is an advantage. Log data stored in DocumentDB is automatically indexed by default, and thus it is ready to be queried at any time. In addition, log data can be persisted across data partitions as a time-series. Older logs can be rolled out to cold storage per your retention policy.          \n\nThe second use case involves long running data analytics jobs performed offline over a large volume of log data.  Examples of this use case include server availability analysis, application error analysis, and clickstream data analysis.  Typically, Hadoop is used to perform these types of analyses.  With the Hadoop Connector for DocumentDB, DocumentDB databases function as data sources and sinks for Pig, Hive and Map/Reduce jobs. For details on the Hadoop Connector for DocumentDB, see [Run a Hadoop job with DocumentDB and HDInsight](documentdb-run-hadoop-with-hdinsight/).      \n\n## User preferences data\nNowadays, most modern web and mobile applications come with complex views and experiences. These views and experiences are usually dynamic, catering to user preferences or moods and branding needs.  Hence, applications need to be able to retrieve personalized settings effectively in order to render UI elements and experiences quickly. \n\nJSON is an effective format to represent UI layout data as it is not only lightweight, but also can be easily interpreted by JavaScript.  DocumentDB offers tunable consistency levels that allow fast reads with low latency writes. Hence, storing UI layout data including personalized settings as JSON documents in DocumentDB is an effective means to get this data across the wire.\n\n## Device sensor data\nIoT use cases commonly share some patterns in how they ingest, process and store data.  First, these systems allow for data intake that can ingest bursts of data from device sensors of various locales.  Next, these systems process and analyze streaming data to derive real time insights. And last but not least, most if not all data will eventually land in a data store for adhoc querying and offline analytics.    \n\nMicrosoft Azure offers rich services that can be leveraged for IoT use cases.  Azure IoT services are a set of services including Azure Event Hubs, Azure DocumentDB, Azure Stream Analytics, Azure Notification Hub, Azure Machine Learning, Azure HDInsight, and PowerBI. \n\nBursts of data can be ingested by Azure Event Hubs as it offers high throughput data ingestion with low latency. Data ingested that needs to be processed for real time insight can be funneled to Azure Stream Analytics for real time analytics. Data can be loaded into DocumentDB for adhoc querying. Once the data is loaded into DocumentDB, the data is ready to be queried.  The data in DocumentDB can be used as reference data as part of real time analytics.  In addtion, data can further be refined and processed by connecting DocumentDB data to HDInsight for Pig, Hive or Map/Reduce jobs.  Refined data is then loaded back to DocumentDB for reporting.   \n\nFor a sample IoT solution using DocumentDB, EventHubs and Storm, see the [hdinsight-storm-examples repository on GitHub](https://github.com/hdinsight/hdinsight-storm-examples/).\n\nFor more information on Azure offerings for IoT, see [Create the Internet of Your Things](http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/internet-of-things.aspx).\n\n## Next steps\n \nTo get started with DocumentDB, you can create an [account](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/) and then follow our [learning guide](documentdb-learning-map.md) to learn about DocumentDB and find the information you need. \n\nOr, if you'd like to read more about customers using DocumentDB, the following customer stories are available:\n\n- [Breeze](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18602). Leading Integrator Gives Multinational Firms Global Insight in Minutes with Flexible Cloud Technologies.\n- [News Republic](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18639). Adding intelligence to the news to provide information with purpose for engaged citizens. \n- [SGS International](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18653). For consistent color across the globe, major brands turn to SGS. And SGS turns to Azure.\n- [Telenor](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18608). Global leader Telenor uses the cloud to move with the speed of a startup. \n- [XOMNI](https://customers.microsoft.com/Pages/CustomerStory.aspx?recid=18667). The store of the future runs on speedy search and the easy flow of data.\n \n\ntest\n"
}