{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Creating and deploying Azure Resource Group deployment projects",
      "pos": [
        27,
        90
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating and deploying Azure Resource Group deployment projects",
      "pos": [
        108,
        171
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating and deploying Azure Resource Group deployment projects",
      "pos": [
        480,
        543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Resource Group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> deployment project template is available in Visual Studio when Azure SDK 2.6 is installed.",
      "pos": [
        545,
        664
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Resource Group projects let you group together and publish multiple related Azure resources in a single deployment operation.",
      "pos": [
        665,
        796
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Resource Group projects use a technology called <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Resource Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to do their work.",
      "pos": [
        797,
        895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Resource Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is a REST API service that lets you define Azure resource groups, which contain multiple Azure resources that are typically used together and have a similar lifecycle.",
      "pos": [
        896,
        1090
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By using resource groups, you can operate on all the resources in a group with a single function call, instead of calling different functions for each individual resource.",
      "pos": [
        1091,
        1262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To learn more about Azure resource groups, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using resource groups to manage your Azure resources<ept id=\"p1\">](./azure-portal/azure-preview-portal-using-resource-groups/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1263,
        1425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Resource Group projects contain Azure Resource Manager JSON templates, which define the elements that are deployed to a resource group.",
      "pos": [
        1427,
        1568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Resource Manager Template Language<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn835138.aspx)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        1569,
        1693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Resource Manager has many different resource providers available that can be used to deploy resources such as Ubuntu Server and Windows Server 2012 R2.",
      "pos": [
        1695,
        1852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic uses a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Web Apps<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> resource, which deploys a basic, empty website to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        1853,
        1940
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating Azure Resource Group projects",
      "pos": [
        1945,
        1983
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1985,
        2088
      ],
      "content": "In this procedure, you learn how to create an Azure Resource Group project with a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Web App<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> template."
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a Azure Resource Group project",
      "pos": [
        2094,
        2134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Visual Studio, choose <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>File<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>New Project<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, choose <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>C#<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Visual Basic<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2139,
        2225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then choose <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then choose <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Azure Resource Group<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> project.",
      "pos": [
        2226,
        2298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cloud Deployment Project",
      "pos": [
        2306,
        2330
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose the template that you want to deploy to Azure Resource Manager.",
      "pos": [
        2423,
        2493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For this example, we'll choose the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Web app<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> template.",
      "pos": [
        2494,
        2550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose a template",
      "pos": [
        2559,
        2576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also add more resources to the Resource Group later.",
      "pos": [
        2670,
        2730
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2737,
        2817
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> The list of available templates is retrieved online and may change."
    },
    {
      "content": "Visual Studio creates an Azure Resource Group deployment project for a web app.",
      "pos": [
        2823,
        2902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Expand the nodes in the deployment project to see what was created.",
      "pos": [
        2907,
        2974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since we chose the Web app template for this example, you see the following files.",
      "pos": [
        2980,
        3062
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "File name",
      "pos": [
        3066,
        3075
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        3076,
        3087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy-AzureResourceGroup.ps1",
      "pos": [
        3100,
        3129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A PowerShell script that invokes PowerShell commands to deploy to Azure Resource Manager.",
      "pos": [
        3130,
        3219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> This PowerShell script is used by Visual Studio to deploy your template.",
      "pos": [
        3221,
        3302
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any changes you make to this script will also affect deployment in Visual Studio, so be careful.|",
      "pos": [
        3303,
        3400
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "!WebSite.json|A configuration file that specifies all the details that you want deployed to Azure Resource Manager.|",
      "pos": [
        3401,
        3517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "|WebSite.param.dev.json|A parameters file that contains specific values needed by the configuration file.|",
      "pos": [
        3518,
        3624
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "|AzCopy.exe|A tool used by the PowerShell script to copy files from the local storage drop path to the storage account container.",
      "pos": [
        3625,
        3754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tool is used only if you configure the deployment project to deploy your code along with the template.|",
      "pos": [
        3755,
        3863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All Azure Resource Group deployment projects contain these four basic files.",
      "pos": [
        3865,
        3941
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Other projects may contain additional files to support other functionality.",
      "pos": [
        3942,
        4017
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Customizing an Azure Resource Group project",
      "pos": [
        4022,
        4065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can customize a deployment project by modifying the JSON template files that describe the Azure resources you want to deploy.",
      "pos": [
        4067,
        4196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "JSON stands for JavaScript Object Notation, and is a serialized data format that is easy to work with.",
      "pos": [
        4197,
        4299
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4301,
        4487
      ],
      "content": "Azure Resource Group projects have two template files under the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Templates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> node in Solution Explorer that you can modify: an Azure Resource Manager template file and a parameter file."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Resource Manager template files<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (which have the extension .json) specify the file(s) containing the resources you want, as well as parameters needed by the deployment project, such as site name and location.",
      "pos": [
        4491,
        4708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They also specify the dependencies of the components in the Azure Resource Group and their properties, such as names, tags, and rules for triggers.",
      "pos": [
        4709,
        4856
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can modify this file to add your own functionality.",
      "pos": [
        4857,
        4912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, you could add a database to the template.",
      "pos": [
        4913,
        4967
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Refer to the documentation for each resource provider to find out the parameters you need to provide.",
      "pos": [
        4968,
        5069
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Resource Providers<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn790572.aspx)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        5070,
        5172
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Parameter files<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (which have the extension .param.*.json) contain values for the parameters specified in the configuration file that are needed for each resource provider.",
      "pos": [
        5176,
        5350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example, the configuration file for a web app (WebSite.json) defines parameters for siteName and siteLocation.",
      "pos": [
        5351,
        5469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During deployment, you are asked to provide values for the parameters in the template file, and these values are stored in the parameters file.",
      "pos": [
        5470,
        5613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also edit the parameter file directly.\"",
      "pos": [
        5614,
        5661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "JSON files can be edited in the Visual Studio editor.",
      "pos": [
        5663,
        5716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you install the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>PowerShell Tools for Visual Studio<ept id=\"p1\">](https://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/c9eb3ba8-0c59-4944-9a62-6eee37294597)</ept>, then you'll also get syntax highlighting, brace matching, and IntelliSense to make it easier to read and edit PowerShell scripts.",
      "pos": [
        5717,
        5988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A link to install the PowerShell Tools appears at the top of the editor if it's not already installed.",
      "pos": [
        5989,
        6091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install PowerShell Tools",
      "pos": [
        6095,
        6119
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The JSON files use a schema which is referenced at the top of each file.",
      "pos": [
        6209,
        6281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download the schema and analyze it if you want to understand it better.",
      "pos": [
        6282,
        6361
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The schema defines what elements are allowed, the types and formats of fields, the possible values of enumerated values, and so on.",
      "pos": [
        6362,
        6493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to deploy to different configurations or change settings often, you can create different copies of the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>param<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> file.",
      "pos": [
        6495,
        6623
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Try to use the same template for all environments.",
      "pos": [
        6624,
        6674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploying an Azure Resource Group project to an Azure resource group",
      "pos": [
        6679,
        6747
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you deploy an Azure Resource Group project, you deploy it to an Azure resource group, which is just a logical grouping of resources in Azure such as web apps, databases, and so on.",
      "pos": [
        6749,
        6934
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6939,
        7030
      ],
      "content": "On the shortcut menu of the deployment project node, choose <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deploy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>New Deployment<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy, New Deployment menu item",
      "pos": [
        7038,
        7070
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7164,
        7216
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deploy to Resource Group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box appears."
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy To Resource Group Dialog Box",
      "pos": [
        7224,
        7259
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7352,
        7546
      ],
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Resource group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dropdown box, choose an existing resource group or create a new one.To create a resource group, open the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Resource Group<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> dropdown box and choose <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;Create New...&gt;</ph><ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7553,
        7602
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create Resource Group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box appears."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create Resource Group Dialog Box",
      "pos": [
        7611,
        7643
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7738,
        7859
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Typically when you start a new deployment project you will want to create a new resource group to deploy to."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7864,
        7952
      ],
      "content": "Enter a name and location for the resource group, and then choose the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button."
    },
    {
      "content": "The location of the resource group doesn't need to be the same as the location of the resources, since resources in a group can span regions.",
      "pos": [
        7958,
        8099
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose the template configuration and parameters files you want to use for this deployment, or accept the defaults.",
      "pos": [
        8104,
        8219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can edit the properties for a resource by choosing the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit Parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button.",
      "pos": [
        8226,
        8312
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If required parameters are missing when you deploy, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit Parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box appears so that you can provide them.",
      "pos": [
        8313,
        8437
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Parameters that are missing values have <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;null&gt;</ph><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> appearing in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Value<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> box next to them.",
      "pos": [
        8438,
        8533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For this example (a web app resource), the required parameters include the site name, hosting plan, and site location.",
      "pos": [
        8534,
        8652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(If you recall, these parameter values are set to null by default in the parameters file.) The other parameters have default values.",
      "pos": [
        8653,
        8785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Edit Parameters Dialog Box",
      "pos": [
        8793,
        8819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit Parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box, enter the site name, site location, hosting plan name, and check the values of any other properties.",
      "pos": [
        8912,
        9051
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you're done, choose the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button.",
      "pos": [
        9052,
        9097
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>siteName<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> parameter is the first part of the URL of the web page.",
      "pos": [
        9105,
        9175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, for the URL mywebsitename.azurewebsites.net, the site name is mywebsitename.",
      "pos": [
        9176,
        9265
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>hostingPlanName<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> parameter specifies your hosting plan.",
      "pos": [
        9273,
        9333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For this example, you can use \"Free\".",
      "pos": [
        9334,
        9371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about hosting plans, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Web Site Hosting Plans in Depth Overview<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/azure-web-sites-web-hosting-plans-in-depth-overview/)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        9372,
        9570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>siteLocation<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> parameter refers to the Azure region where the site is to be hosted, such as \"West US\".",
      "pos": [
        9578,
        9684
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a list of available regions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Regions<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/regions/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9685,
        9775
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9780,
        9840
      ],
      "content": "Choose the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deploy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button to deploy the project to Azure."
    },
    {
      "content": "You can see the progress of the deployment in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Output<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> window.",
      "pos": [
        9846,
        9914
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deployment may take several minutes to complete, depending on your configuration.",
      "pos": [
        9915,
        9996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> You may be asked to install the Microsoft Azure PowerShell cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        10003,
        10083
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because these cmdlets are required to deploy Azure resource groups, you need to install them.",
      "pos": [
        10084,
        10177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In a browser, open the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://portal.azure.com/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        10182,
        10247
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since this is a new change, there should be a new notification message available in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Notifications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.",
      "pos": [
        10248,
        10358
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose it to view details about the new Azure Resource Group.",
      "pos": [
        10359,
        10420
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To see a list of all the available resource groups, you can choose the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Browse<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab and then choose <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Resource Groups<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        10421,
        10543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The provisioned Azure Resource Group",
      "pos": [
        10551,
        10587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you make changes and want to redeploy your project, you can choose the existing resource group directly from the Azure resource group project's shortcut menu.",
      "pos": [
        10680,
        10841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the shortcut menu, choose <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deploy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then choose the resource group you just deployed to.",
      "pos": [
        10842,
        10939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure resource group deployed",
      "pos": [
        10947,
        10976
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploying an Azure resource group deploys only that project.",
      "pos": [
        11070,
        11130
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If your solution has a code project or any other projects, you need to deploy them separately.",
      "pos": [
        11131,
        11225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment Projects with Azure SDK 2.6",
      "pos": [
        11230,
        11294
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using Cloud Deployment projects that were created with Azure SDK 2.5, you'll want to upgrade to Azure SDK 2.6 to be able to use the new features for editing and deploying Azure resource templates.",
      "pos": [
        11296,
        11503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The easiest way to reuse the templates you created with Azure SDK 2.5 is to create the Azure SDK 2.6 version of the project, move your templates to that project and do some modifications.",
      "pos": [
        11504,
        11691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment projects with Azure SDK 2.6",
      "pos": [
        11697,
        11762
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add a new Azure SDK 2.6 Azure Resource Group project to your solution.",
      "pos": [
        11767,
        11837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open the solution that contains your Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment project.",
      "pos": [
        11846,
        11922
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11931,
        11981
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>File<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu, choose <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Project<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11990,
        12127
      ],
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New Project<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box, find the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Azure Resource Group <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>project under <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Visual C#<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>/<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>Cloud<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Visual Basic<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>/<bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>Cloud<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12142,
        12230
      ],
      "content": "The project template name was changed from <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud Deployment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to Azure Resource Group."
    },
    {
      "content": "Give the project a name.",
      "pos": [
        12239,
        12263
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12272,
        12329
      ],
      "content": "Change the solution drop-down box to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add to solution<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, you will be asked to pick a template.",
      "pos": [
        12338,
        12381
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since you’ll be moving your existing templates from your Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment project, you can choose any template, so let’s choose the blank template at the bottom of the list.",
      "pos": [
        12382,
        12569
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12578,
        12603
      ],
      "content": "Choose the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button."
    },
    {
      "content": "The new project is added to your solution.",
      "pos": [
        12618,
        12660
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy your template and parameter files from the Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment project to your Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project.",
      "pos": [
        12665,
        12797
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Solution Explorer, find the template and parameter files you want to copy in the Azure SDK 2.5 deployment project, select them and copy them.",
      "pos": [
        12806,
        12950
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12963,
        13058
      ],
      "content": "Paste the files into the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Templates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> folder in your new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project."
    },
    {
      "content": "In Solution Explorer, find the template and parameter files you want to copy in the Azure SDK 2.5 deployment project, select them and copy them.",
      "pos": [
        13063,
        13207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Paste the files into the Templates folder in your new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project.",
      "pos": [
        13212,
        13303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're also deploying a web application with your template, you’ll need to create a reference from the new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project to your Web Application.",
      "pos": [
        13308,
        13479
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13488,
        13631
      ],
      "content": "On the context menu of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>References<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> node of your new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project in Solution Explorer, choose <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add Reference<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13640,
        13742
      ],
      "content": "Select the box next to your Web Application in the list of projects and then choose the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button."
    },
    {
      "content": "On the context menu of the References node of your new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project in Solution Explorer, choose Add Reference.",
      "pos": [
        13747,
        13882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the box next to your Web Application in the list of projects and then choose the OK button.",
      "pos": [
        13887,
        13985
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13990,
        14130
      ],
      "content": "Rename all occurrences of the parameters <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>dropLocation<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>dropLocationSasToken<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> to <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>_artifactsLocation<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept> and <bpt id=\"p4\">*</bpt>_artifactsLocationSasToken<ept id=\"p4\">*</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don’t plan to use them, you can delete the empty template and parameter files that were automatically added to the Azure SDK 2.6 project when you created it",
      "pos": [
        14135,
        14298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete the file DeployTemplate.json.",
      "pos": [
        14307,
        14343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete the file DeploymentTemplate.param.dev.json.",
      "pos": [
        14352,
        14402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have made changes to the Publish-AzureResourceGroup.ps1 script in the Azure SDK 2.5 project, you’ll need to move those changes to the Deploy-AzureResourceGroup.ps1 script in the Azure SDK 2.6 project.",
      "pos": [
        14407,
        14614
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Now you can deploy your template using the deployment command in the Azure SDK 2.6 Azure Resource Group project and take advantage of the new features for editing templates in Azure SDK 2.6.",
      "pos": [
        14620,
        14810
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have the 2.6 project working to your satisfaction, you can remove the Azure SDK 2.5 project from your solution.",
      "pos": [
        14811,
        14931
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Why the project required updating",
      "pos": [
        14936,
        14969
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A couple of changes were made in templates are deployed in Azure SDK 2.6 that makes Azure SDK 2.5 deployment script and templates incompatible.",
      "pos": [
        14971,
        15114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The first, and biggest change, is the deployment is launched.",
      "pos": [
        15115,
        15176
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Azure SDK 2.5, we had compiled code that used the Azure REST APIs to upload your template and start the deployment.",
      "pos": [
        15177,
        15295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We heard feedback from many developers that they would like Visual Studio to just launch the PowerShell script that is included in the project.",
      "pos": [
        15296,
        15439
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "So in Azure SDK 2.6, the deploy command launches the PowerShell script that is included in the project to deploy the template.",
      "pos": [
        15440,
        15566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "That allows you to customize the deployment and have those customizations always run, whether you are deploying from the command line using Azure PowerShell or deploying through VS using the deploy command.",
      "pos": [
        15567,
        15773
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To deploy from Visual Studio, you'll need to use the Azure SDK 2.6 deployment PowerShell script when you have the Azure SDK 2.6 installed.",
      "pos": [
        15774,
        15912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adjustements were also made to some variable names and build tasks to better align with naming conventions in TFS automated builds and other projects within Microsoft.",
      "pos": [
        15914,
        16081
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The code in Visual Studio that gathers the variables and values needed to launch the PowerShell script will look for these new names.",
      "pos": [
        16082,
        16215
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        16220,
        16230
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16232,
        16415
      ],
      "content": "To learn how to add resources to your Azure Resource Group in Visual Studio, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Adding resources to an Azure Resource Group<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/mt125415.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        16419,
        16423
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Creating and deploying Azure Resource Group deployment projects\"\n   description=\"Creating and deploying Azure Resource Group deployment projects\"\n   services=\"visual-studio-online\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   authors=\"kempb\"\n   manager=\"douge\"\n   editor=\"tlee\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"azure-resource-manager\"\n   ms.devlang=\"multiple\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"na\"\n   ms.date=\"08/24/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"kempb\" />\n\n# Creating and deploying Azure Resource Group deployment projects\n\nThe **Azure Resource Group** deployment project template is available in Visual Studio when Azure SDK 2.6 is installed. Azure Resource Group projects let you group together and publish multiple related Azure resources in a single deployment operation. Azure Resource Group projects use a technology called **Azure Resource Manager** to do their work. **Azure Resource Manager** is a REST API service that lets you define Azure resource groups, which contain multiple Azure resources that are typically used together and have a similar lifecycle. By using resource groups, you can operate on all the resources in a group with a single function call, instead of calling different functions for each individual resource. To learn more about Azure resource groups, see [Using resource groups to manage your Azure resources](./azure-portal/azure-preview-portal-using-resource-groups/).\n\nAzure Resource Group projects contain Azure Resource Manager JSON templates, which define the elements that are deployed to a resource group. See [Azure Resource Manager Template Language](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn835138.aspx) for more information.\n\nAzure Resource Manager has many different resource providers available that can be used to deploy resources such as Ubuntu Server and Windows Server 2012 R2. This topic uses a **Web Apps** resource, which deploys a basic, empty website to Azure.\n\n## Creating Azure Resource Group projects\n\nIn this procedure, you learn how to create an Azure Resource Group project with a **Web App** template.\n\n### To create a Azure Resource Group project\n\n1. In Visual Studio, choose **File**, **New Project**, choose **C#** or **Visual Basic**. Then choose **Cloud**, and then choose **Azure Resource Group** project.\n\n    ![Cloud Deployment Project](./media/vs-azure-tools-resource-groups-deployment-projects-create-deploy/IC796668.png)\n\n1. Choose the template that you want to deploy to Azure Resource Manager. For this example, we'll choose the **Web app** template. \n\n    ![Choose a template](./media/vs-azure-tools-resource-groups-deployment-projects-create-deploy/IC796669.png)\n\n    You can also add more resources to the Resource Group later.\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] The list of available templates is retrieved online and may change.\n\n    Visual Studio creates an Azure Resource Group deployment project for a web app.\n\n1. Expand the nodes in the deployment project to see what was created.\n\n    Since we chose the Web app template for this example, you see the following files. \n\n|File name|Description|\n|---|---|\n|Deploy-AzureResourceGroup.ps1|A PowerShell script that invokes PowerShell commands to deploy to Azure Resource Manager.\n\n**Note** This PowerShell script is used by Visual Studio to deploy your template. Any changes you make to this script will also affect deployment in Visual Studio, so be careful.|\n!WebSite.json|A configuration file that specifies all the details that you want deployed to Azure Resource Manager.|\n|WebSite.param.dev.json|A parameters file that contains specific values needed by the configuration file.|\n|AzCopy.exe|A tool used by the PowerShell script to copy files from the local storage drop path to the storage account container. This tool is used only if you configure the deployment project to deploy your code along with the template.|\n\nAll Azure Resource Group deployment projects contain these four basic files. Other projects may contain additional files to support other functionality.\n\n## Customizing an Azure Resource Group project\n\nYou can customize a deployment project by modifying the JSON template files that describe the Azure resources you want to deploy. JSON stands for JavaScript Object Notation, and is a serialized data format that is easy to work with.\n\nAzure Resource Group projects have two template files under the **Templates** node in Solution Explorer that you can modify: an Azure Resource Manager template file and a parameter file.\n\n- **Azure Resource Manager template files** (which have the extension .json) specify the file(s) containing the resources you want, as well as parameters needed by the deployment project, such as site name and location. They also specify the dependencies of the components in the Azure Resource Group and their properties, such as names, tags, and rules for triggers. You can modify this file to add your own functionality. For example, you could add a database to the template. Refer to the documentation for each resource provider to find out the parameters you need to provide. See [Resource Providers](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn790572.aspx) for more information.\n\n- **Parameter files** (which have the extension .param.*.json) contain values for the parameters specified in the configuration file that are needed for each resource provider. In this example, the configuration file for a web app (WebSite.json) defines parameters for siteName and siteLocation. During deployment, you are asked to provide values for the parameters in the template file, and these values are stored in the parameters file. You can also edit the parameter file directly.\"\n\nJSON files can be edited in the Visual Studio editor. If you install the [PowerShell Tools for Visual Studio](https://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/c9eb3ba8-0c59-4944-9a62-6eee37294597), then you'll also get syntax highlighting, brace matching, and IntelliSense to make it easier to read and edit PowerShell scripts. A link to install the PowerShell Tools appears at the top of the editor if it's not already installed.\n\n![Install PowerShell Tools](./media/vs-azure-tools-resource-groups-deployment-projects-create-deploy/IC796671.png)\n\nThe JSON files use a schema which is referenced at the top of each file. You can download the schema and analyze it if you want to understand it better. The schema defines what elements are allowed, the types and formats of fields, the possible values of enumerated values, and so on.\n\nIf you want to deploy to different configurations or change settings often, you can create different copies of the *param* file. Try to use the same template for all environments.\n\n## Deploying an Azure Resource Group project to an Azure resource group\n\nWhen you deploy an Azure Resource Group project, you deploy it to an Azure resource group, which is just a logical grouping of resources in Azure such as web apps, databases, and so on.\n\n1. On the shortcut menu of the deployment project node, choose **Deploy**, **New Deployment**.\n\n    ![Deploy, New Deployment menu item](./media/vs-azure-tools-resource-groups-deployment-projects-create-deploy/IC796672.png)\n\n    The **Deploy to Resource Group** dialog box appears.\n\n    ![Deploy To Resource Group Dialog Box](./media/vs-azure-tools-resource-groups-deployment-projects-create-deploy/IC796673.png)\n\n1. In the **Resource group** dropdown box, choose an existing resource group or create a new one.To create a resource group, open the **Resource Group** dropdown box and choose **<Create New...>**. \n\n    The **Create Resource Group** dialog box appears. \n\n    ![Create Resource Group Dialog Box](./media/vs-azure-tools-resource-groups-deployment-projects-create-deploy/IC796674.png)\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] Typically when you start a new deployment project you will want to create a new resource group to deploy to.\n\n1. Enter a name and location for the resource group, and then choose the **Create** button.\n\n    The location of the resource group doesn't need to be the same as the location of the resources, since resources in a group can span regions.\n\n1. Choose the template configuration and parameters files you want to use for this deployment, or accept the defaults. \n\n    You can edit the properties for a resource by choosing the **Edit Parameters** button. If required parameters are missing when you deploy, the **Edit Parameters** dialog box appears so that you can provide them. Parameters that are missing values have **<null>** appearing in the **Value** box next to them. For this example (a web app resource), the required parameters include the site name, hosting plan, and site location. (If you recall, these parameter values are set to null by default in the parameters file.) The other parameters have default values.\n\n    ![Edit Parameters Dialog Box](./media/vs-azure-tools-resource-groups-deployment-projects-create-deploy/IC796675.png)\n\n1. In the **Edit Parameters** dialog box, enter the site name, site location, hosting plan name, and check the values of any other properties. When you're done, choose the **Save** button.\n\n    - The *siteName* parameter is the first part of the URL of the web page. For example, for the URL mywebsitename.azurewebsites.net, the site name is mywebsitename.\n\n    - The *hostingPlanName* parameter specifies your hosting plan. For this example, you can use \"Free\". For more information about hosting plans, see [Azure Web Site Hosting Plans in Depth Overview](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/azure-web-sites-web-hosting-plans-in-depth-overview/)\n\n    - The *siteLocation* parameter refers to the Azure region where the site is to be hosted, such as \"West US\". For a list of available regions, see [Azure Regions](http://azure.microsoft.com/regions/).\n\n1. Choose the **Deploy** button to deploy the project to Azure.\n\n    You can see the progress of the deployment in the **Output** window. Deployment may take several minutes to complete, depending on your configuration.\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] You may be asked to install the Microsoft Azure PowerShell cmdlets. Because these cmdlets are required to deploy Azure resource groups, you need to install them.\n\n1. In a browser, open the [Azure portal](https://portal.azure.com/). Since this is a new change, there should be a new notification message available in the **Notifications** tab. Choose it to view details about the new Azure Resource Group. To see a list of all the available resource groups, you can choose the **Browse** tab and then choose **Resource Groups**.\n\n    ![The provisioned Azure Resource Group](./media/vs-azure-tools-resource-groups-deployment-projects-create-deploy/IC796676.png)\n\n1. If you make changes and want to redeploy your project, you can choose the existing resource group directly from the Azure resource group project's shortcut menu. On the shortcut menu, choose **Deploy**, and then choose the resource group you just deployed to.\n\n    ![Azure resource group deployed](./media/vs-azure-tools-resource-groups-deployment-projects-create-deploy/IC796677.png)\n\n    Deploying an Azure resource group deploys only that project. If your solution has a code project or any other projects, you need to deploy them separately.\n\n## Using Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment Projects with Azure SDK 2.6\n\nIf you are using Cloud Deployment projects that were created with Azure SDK 2.5, you'll want to upgrade to Azure SDK 2.6 to be able to use the new features for editing and deploying Azure resource templates. The easiest way to reuse the templates you created with Azure SDK 2.5 is to create the Azure SDK 2.6 version of the project, move your templates to that project and do some modifications.\n\n### To use Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment projects with Azure SDK 2.6\n\n1. Add a new Azure SDK 2.6 Azure Resource Group project to your solution.\n\n    1. Open the solution that contains your Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment project.\n\n    1. On the **File** menu, choose **New**, **Project**.\n\n    1. In the **New Project** dialog box, find the **Azure Resource Group **project under **Visual C#**/**Cloud** or **Visual Basic**/**Cloud**.\n    \n         The project template name was changed from **Cloud Deployment** to Azure Resource Group.\n\n    1. Give the project a name.\n\n    1. Change the solution drop-down box to **Add to solution**.\n\n    1. Next, you will be asked to pick a template. Since you’ll be moving your existing templates from your Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment project, you can choose any template, so let’s choose the blank template at the bottom of the list.\n\n    1. Choose the **OK** button. \n    \n        The new project is added to your solution.\n\n1. Copy your template and parameter files from the Azure SDK 2.5 Cloud Deployment project to your Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project.\n\n    1. In Solution Explorer, find the template and parameter files you want to copy in the Azure SDK 2.5 deployment project, select them and copy them.\n    \n    2. Paste the files into the **Templates** folder in your new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project.\n\n1. In Solution Explorer, find the template and parameter files you want to copy in the Azure SDK 2.5 deployment project, select them and copy them.\n\n1. Paste the files into the Templates folder in your new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project.\n\n1. If you're also deploying a web application with your template, you’ll need to create a reference from the new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project to your Web Application.\n\n    1. On the context menu of the **References** node of your new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project in Solution Explorer, choose **Add Reference**.\n\n    1. Select the box next to your Web Application in the list of projects and then choose the **OK** button.\n\n1. On the context menu of the References node of your new Azure SDK 2.6 Resource Group project in Solution Explorer, choose Add Reference.\n\n1. Select the box next to your Web Application in the list of projects and then choose the OK button.\n\n1. Rename all occurrences of the parameters *dropLocation* and *dropLocationSasToken* to *_artifactsLocation* and *_artifactsLocationSasToken*.\n\n1. If you don’t plan to use them, you can delete the empty template and parameter files that were automatically added to the Azure SDK 2.6 project when you created it\n\n    1. Delete the file DeployTemplate.json.\n\n    1. Delete the file DeploymentTemplate.param.dev.json.\n\n1. If you have made changes to the Publish-AzureResourceGroup.ps1 script in the Azure SDK 2.5 project, you’ll need to move those changes to the Deploy-AzureResourceGroup.ps1 script in the Azure SDK 2.6 project.\n\n    Now you can deploy your template using the deployment command in the Azure SDK 2.6 Azure Resource Group project and take advantage of the new features for editing templates in Azure SDK 2.6. Once you have the 2.6 project working to your satisfaction, you can remove the Azure SDK 2.5 project from your solution.\n\n## Why the project required updating\n\nA couple of changes were made in templates are deployed in Azure SDK 2.6 that makes Azure SDK 2.5 deployment script and templates incompatible. The first, and biggest change, is the deployment is launched. In Azure SDK 2.5, we had compiled code that used the Azure REST APIs to upload your template and start the deployment. We heard feedback from many developers that they would like Visual Studio to just launch the PowerShell script that is included in the project. So in Azure SDK 2.6, the deploy command launches the PowerShell script that is included in the project to deploy the template. That allows you to customize the deployment and have those customizations always run, whether you are deploying from the command line using Azure PowerShell or deploying through VS using the deploy command. To deploy from Visual Studio, you'll need to use the Azure SDK 2.6 deployment PowerShell script when you have the Azure SDK 2.6 installed.\n\nAdjustements were also made to some variable names and build tasks to better align with naming conventions in TFS automated builds and other projects within Microsoft. The code in Visual Studio that gathers the variables and values needed to launch the PowerShell script will look for these new names.\n\n## Next steps\n\nTo learn how to add resources to your Azure Resource Group in Visual Studio, see [Adding resources to an Azure Resource Group](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/mt125415.aspx).\n\n\n\ntest\n"
}