{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Manage Key Vault using CLI | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        71
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use this tutorial to automate common tasks in Key Vault by using the CLI",
      "pos": [
        90,
        162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Manage Key Vault using CLI",
      "pos": [
        477,
        503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Key Vault is available in most regions.",
      "pos": [
        506,
        551
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Key Vault pricing page<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../../pricing/details/key-vault/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        552,
        647
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Introduction",
      "pos": [
        652,
        664
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use this tutorial to help you get started with Azure Key Vault to create a hardened container (a vault) in Azure, to store and manage cryptographic keys and secrets in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        667,
        841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It walks you through the process of using Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface to create a vault that contains a key or password that you can then use with an Azure application.",
      "pos": [
        842,
        1026
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It then shows you how an application can then use that key or password.",
      "pos": [
        1027,
        1098
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1100,
        1142
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Estimated time to complete:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> 20 minutes"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1145,
        1357
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph>  This tutorial does not include instructions on how to write the Azure application that one of the steps includes, which shows how to authorize an application to use a key or secret in the key vault."
    },
    {
      "content": "Currently, you cannot configure Azure Key Vault in the Azure portal.",
      "pos": [
        1361,
        1429
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instead, use these Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface  instructions.",
      "pos": [
        1430,
        1501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Or, for Azure PowerShell instructions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>this equivalent tutorial<ept id=\"p1\">](key-vault-get-started.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1502,
        1598
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1600,
        1699
      ],
      "content": "For overview information about Azure Key Vault, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>What is Azure Key Vault?<ept id=\"p1\">](key-vault-whatis.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        1704,
        1717
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To complete this tutorial, you must have the following:",
      "pos": [
        1719,
        1774
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A subscription to Microsoft Azure.",
      "pos": [
        1778,
        1812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not have one, you can sign up for a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>free trial<ept id=\"p1\">](../../../pricing/free-trial)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1813,
        1901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Command-Line Interface version 0.9.1 or later.",
      "pos": [
        1904,
        1950
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To install the latest version and connect to your Azure subscription, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Install and Configure the Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface<ept id=\"p1\">](xplat-cli.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1951,
        2111
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An application that will be configured to use the key or password that you create in this tutorial.",
      "pos": [
        2114,
        2213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A sample application is available from the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Download Center<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=45343)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2214,
        2342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For instructions, see the accompanying Readme file.",
      "pos": [
        2343,
        2394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting help with Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface",
      "pos": [
        2399,
        2460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tutorial assumes that you are familiar with the command-line interface (Bash, Terminal, Command prompt)",
      "pos": [
        2462,
        2570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The --help or -h parameter can be used to view help for specific commands.",
      "pos": [
        2572,
        2646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Alternately, The azure help [command] [options] format can also be used to return the same information.",
      "pos": [
        2647,
        2750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, the following commands all return the same information:",
      "pos": [
        2751,
        2819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When in doubt about the parameters needed by a command, refer to help using --help, -h or azure help [command].",
      "pos": [
        2905,
        3016
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also read the following tutorials to get familiar with Azure Resource Manager in Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface:",
      "pos": [
        3018,
        3151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to install and configure Azure Cross-Platform Command Line Interface",
      "pos": [
        3156,
        3228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface with Azure Resource Manager",
      "pos": [
        3247,
        3324
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connect to your subscriptions",
      "pos": [
        3368,
        3397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To log in using an organizational account, use the following command:",
      "pos": [
        3399,
        3468
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "or if you want to log in by typing interactively",
      "pos": [
        3511,
        3559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph>  The login method only works with organizational account.",
      "pos": [
        3579,
        3649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An organizational account is a user that is managed by your organization, and defined in your organization's Azure Active Directory tenant.",
      "pos": [
        3650,
        3789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not currently have an organizational account, and are using a Microsoft account to log in to your Azure subscription, you can easily create one using the following steps.",
      "pos": [
        3792,
        3972
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3978,
        4095
      ],
      "content": "Login to the Login to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://manage.windowsazure.com/)</ept>, and click on Active Directory."
    },
    {
      "content": "If no directory exists, select Create your directory and provide the requested information.",
      "pos": [
        4100,
        4191
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select your directory and add a new user.",
      "pos": [
        4196,
        4237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This new user is an organizational account.",
      "pos": [
        4238,
        4281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During the creation of the user, you will be supplied with both an e-mail address for the user and a temporary password.",
      "pos": [
        4282,
        4402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Save this information as it is used in another step.",
      "pos": [
        4403,
        4455
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From the portal, select Settings and then select Administrators.",
      "pos": [
        4460,
        4524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select Add, and add the new user as a co-administrator.",
      "pos": [
        4525,
        4580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This allows the organizational account to manage your Azure subscription.",
      "pos": [
        4581,
        4654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Finally, log out of the Azure portal and then log back in using the new organizational account.",
      "pos": [
        4659,
        4754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this is the first time logging in with this account, you will be prompted to change the password.",
      "pos": [
        4755,
        4855
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4857,
        5016
      ],
      "content": "For more information about using an organizational account with Microsoft Azure, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Sign up for Microsoft Azure as an Organization<ept id=\"p1\">](sign-up-organization.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have multiple subscriptions and want to specify a specific one to use for Azure Key Vault, type the following to see the subscriptions for your account:",
      "pos": [
        5018,
        5177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then, to specify the subscription to use, type:",
      "pos": [
        5203,
        5250
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5295,
        5472
      ],
      "content": "For more information about configuring Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Install and Configure Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface<ept id=\"p1\">](xplat-cli.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Switch to using Azure Resource Manager",
      "pos": [
        5478,
        5516
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Key Vault requires Azure Resource Manager, so type the following to switch to Azure Resource Manager mode:",
      "pos": [
        5518,
        5628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a new resource group",
      "pos": [
        5660,
        5687
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using Azure Resource Manager, all related resources are created inside a resource group.",
      "pos": [
        5689,
        5782
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We will create a new resource group 'ContosoResourceGroup' for this tutorial.",
      "pos": [
        5783,
        5860
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The first parameter is resource group name and the second parameter is the location.",
      "pos": [
        5921,
        6005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For location, use the command <ph id=\"ph1\">`azure location list`</ph> to identify how to specify an alternative location to the one in this example.",
      "pos": [
        6006,
        6136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need more information, type: <ph id=\"ph1\">`azure help location`</ph>",
      "pos": [
        6137,
        6194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a key vault",
      "pos": [
        6201,
        6219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`azure keyvault create`</ph> command to create a key vault.",
      "pos": [
        6221,
        6283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This script has three mandatory parameters: a resource group name, a key vault name, and the geographic location.",
      "pos": [
        6284,
        6397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you use the vault name of ContosoKeyVault, the resource group name of ContosoResourceGroup, and the location of East Asia, type:",
      "pos": [
        6399,
        6543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The output of this command shows properties of the key vault that you've just created.",
      "pos": [
        6666,
        6752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The two most important properties are:",
      "pos": [
        6753,
        6791
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: In the example this is ContosoKeyVault.",
      "pos": [
        6795,
        6844
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will use this name for other Key Vault cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        6845,
        6896
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>vaultUri<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: In the example this is https://contosokeyvault.vault.azure.net.",
      "pos": [
        6899,
        6976
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Applications that use your vault through its REST API must use this URI.",
      "pos": [
        6977,
        7049
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your Azure account is now authorized to perform any operations on this key vault.",
      "pos": [
        7051,
        7132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As yet, nobody else is.",
      "pos": [
        7133,
        7156
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add a key or secret to the key vault",
      "pos": [
        7162,
        7198
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7200,
        7331
      ],
      "content": "If you want Azure Key Vault to create a software-protected key for you, use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`azure key create`</ph> command, and type the following:"
    },
    {
      "content": "However, if you have an existing key in a .pem file saved as local file in a file named softkey.pem that you want to upload to Azure Key Vault, type the following to import the key from the .PEM file, which protects the key by software in the Key Vault service:",
      "pos": [
        7447,
        7708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can now reference the key that you created or uploaded to Azure Key Vault, by using its URI.",
      "pos": [
        7872,
        7968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use  <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>https://ContosoKeyVault.vault.azure.net/keys/ContosoFirstKey<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to always get the current version, and use <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>https://ContosoKeyVault.vault.azure.net/keys/ContosoFirstKey/cgacf4f763ar42ffb0a1gca546aygd87<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to get this specific version.",
      "pos": [
        7969,
        8209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To add a secret to the vault, which is a password named SQLPassword and that has the value of Pa$$w0rd to Azure Key Vault, type the following:",
      "pos": [
        8211,
        8353
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can now reference this password that you added to Azure Key Vault, by using its URI.",
      "pos": [
        8464,
        8552
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>https://ContosoVault.vault.azure.net/secrets/SQLPassword<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to always get the current version, and use <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>https://ContosoVault.vault.azure.net/secrets/SQLPassword/90018dbb96a84117a0d2847ef8e7189d<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to get this specific version.",
      "pos": [
        8553,
        8784
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let's view the key or secret that you just created:",
      "pos": [
        8786,
        8837
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8841,
        8921
      ],
      "content": "To view your key, type: <ph id=\"ph1\">`azure keyvault key list --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault'`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8924,
        9010
      ],
      "content": "To view your secret, type: <ph id=\"ph1\">`azure keyvault secret list -–vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault'`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Register an application with Azure Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        9016,
        9067
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This step would usually be done by a developer, on a separate computer.",
      "pos": [
        9069,
        9140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is not specific to Azure Key Vault but is included here, for completeness.",
      "pos": [
        9141,
        9218
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9222,
        9387
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> To complete the tutorial, your account, the vault, and the application that you will register in this step must all be in the same Azure directory."
    },
    {
      "content": "Applications that use a key vault must authenticate by using a token from Azure Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        9389,
        9486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, the owner of the application must first register the application in their Azure Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        9487,
        9596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At the end of registration, the application owner gets the following values:",
      "pos": [
        9597,
        9673
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Application ID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (also known as a Client ID) and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>authentication key<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> (also known as the shared secret).",
      "pos": [
        9678,
        9789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The application must present both of these values to Azure Active Directory, to get a token.",
      "pos": [
        9790,
        9882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How the application is configured to do this depends on the application.",
      "pos": [
        9883,
        9955
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the Key Vault sample application, the application owner sets these values in the app.config file.",
      "pos": [
        9956,
        10057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To register the application in Azure Active Directory:",
      "pos": [
        10061,
        10115
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign in to the Azure portal.",
      "pos": [
        10120,
        10148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the left, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active Directory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then select the directory in which you will register your application.",
      "pos": [
        10152,
        10267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note: You must select the same directory that contains the Azure subscription with which you created your key vault.",
      "pos": [
        10278,
        10394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not know which directory this is, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, identify the subscription with which you created your key vault, and note the name of the directory displayed in the last column.",
      "pos": [
        10395,
        10588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>APPLICATIONS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        10593,
        10616
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If no apps have been added to your directory, this page will show only the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add an App<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> link.",
      "pos": [
        10617,
        10712
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the link, or alternatively, you can click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ADD<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on the command bar.",
      "pos": [
        10713,
        10792
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10797,
        10932
      ],
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ADD APPLICATION<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> wizard, on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>What do you want to do?<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page, click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Add an application my organization is developing<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tell us about your application<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, specify a name for your application and select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>WEB APPLICATION AND/OR WEB API<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> (the default).",
      "pos": [
        10937,
        11081
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the Next icon.",
      "pos": [
        11082,
        11102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>App properties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, specify the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SIGN-ON URL<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>APP ID URI<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> for your web application.",
      "pos": [
        11107,
        11211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If your application does not have these values, you can make them up for this step (for example, you could specify http://test1.contoso.com for both boxes).",
      "pos": [
        11212,
        11368
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It does not matter if these sites exist; what is important is that the app ID URI for each application is different for every application in your directory.",
      "pos": [
        11369,
        11525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The directory uses this string to identify your app.",
      "pos": [
        11526,
        11578
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the Complete icon to save your changes in the wizard.",
      "pos": [
        11583,
        11642
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11647,
        11692
      ],
      "content": "On the Quick Start page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CONFIGURE<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Scroll to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>keys<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section, select the duration, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SAVE<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11697,
        11774
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The page refreshes and now shows a key value.",
      "pos": [
        11775,
        11820
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must configure your application with this key value and the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CLIENT ID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value.",
      "pos": [
        11821,
        11905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(Instructions for this configuration will be application-specific.)",
      "pos": [
        11906,
        11973
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the client ID value from this page, which you will use in the next step to set permissions on your vault.",
      "pos": [
        11978,
        12088
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authorize the application to use the key or secret",
      "pos": [
        12096,
        12146
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12148,
        12263
      ],
      "content": "To authorize the application to access the key or secret in the vault, use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`azure keyvault set-policy`</ph> command."
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if your vault name is ContosoKeyVault and the application you want to authorize has a client ID of 8f8c4bbd-485b-45fd-98f7-ec6300b7b4ed, and you want to authorize the application to decrypt and sign with keys in your vault, then run the following:",
      "pos": [
        12265,
        12525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to authorize that same application to read secrets in your vault, run the following:",
      "pos": [
        12672,
        12768
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to use a hardware security module (HSM)",
      "pos": [
        12906,
        12957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For added assurance, you can import or generate keys in hardware security modules (HSMs) that never leave the HSM boundary.",
      "pos": [
        12962,
        13085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The HSMs are FIPS 140-2 Level 2 validated.",
      "pos": [
        13086,
        13128
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this requirement doesn't apply to you, skip this section and go to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Delete the key vault and associated keys and secrets<ept id=\"p1\">](#delete-the-key-vault-and-associated-keys-and-secrets)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        13129,
        13309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create these HSM-protected keys, you must have a vault subscription that supports HSM-protected keys.",
      "pos": [
        13311,
        13415
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create the keyvault, add the 'sku' parameter:",
      "pos": [
        13417,
        13471
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can add software-protected keys (as shown earlier) and HSM-protected keys to this vault.",
      "pos": [
        13619,
        13711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create an HSM-protected key, set the Destination parameter to 'HSM':",
      "pos": [
        13712,
        13783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the following command to import a key from a .pem file on your computer.",
      "pos": [
        13902,
        13986
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command imports the key into HSMs in the Key Vault service:",
      "pos": [
        13987,
        14051
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The next command imports a “bring your own key\" (BYOK) package.",
      "pos": [
        14219,
        14282
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This lets you generate your key in your local HSM, and transfer it to HSMs in the Key Vault service, without the key leaving the HSM boundary:",
      "pos": [
        14283,
        14425
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        14572,
        14757
      ],
      "content": "For more detailed instructions about how to generate this BYOK package, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to use HSM-Protected Keys with Azure Key Vault<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn903624.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete the key vault and associated keys and secrets",
      "pos": [
        14763,
        14815
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you no longer need the key vault and the key or secret that it contains, you can delete the key vault by using the azure keyvault delete command:",
      "pos": [
        14817,
        14965
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Or, you can delete an entire Azure resource group, which includes the key vault and any other resources that you included in that group:",
      "pos": [
        15025,
        15161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Other Azure Cross-Platform Command-line Interface Commands",
      "pos": [
        15221,
        15279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Other commands that you might useful for managing Azure Key Vault.",
      "pos": [
        15281,
        15347
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command lists a tabular display of all keys and selected properties:",
      "pos": [
        15349,
        15422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command displays a full list of properties for the specified key:",
      "pos": [
        15484,
        15554
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command lists a tabular display of all secret names and selected properties:",
      "pos": [
        15645,
        15726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here's an example of how to remove a specific key:",
      "pos": [
        15791,
        15841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here's an example of how to remove a specific secret:",
      "pos": [
        15934,
        15987
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        16086,
        16096
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16098,
        16325
      ],
      "content": "For programming references, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Key Vault REST API Reference<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn903609.aspx)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure Key Vault C# Client API Reference<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn903628.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        16327,
        16331
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Manage Key Vault using CLI | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Use this tutorial to automate common tasks in Key Vault by using the CLI\"\n    services=\"key-vault\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"msmbaldwin\"\n    manager=\"mbaldwin\"tags=\"azure-resource-manager\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"key-vault\"\n    ms.workload=\"identity\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"06/25/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"bruceper\"/>\n\n# Manage Key Vault using CLI #\nAzure Key Vault is available in most regions. For more information, see the [Key Vault pricing page](../../../../pricing/details/key-vault/).\n\n## Introduction  \nUse this tutorial to help you get started with Azure Key Vault to create a hardened container (a vault) in Azure, to store and manage cryptographic keys and secrets in Azure. It walks you through the process of using Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface to create a vault that contains a key or password that you can then use with an Azure application. It then shows you how an application can then use that key or password.\n\n**Estimated time to complete:** 20 minutes\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE]  This tutorial does not include instructions on how to write the Azure application that one of the steps includes, which shows how to authorize an application to use a key or secret in the key vault.\n>\n>Currently, you cannot configure Azure Key Vault in the Azure portal. Instead, use these Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface  instructions. Or, for Azure PowerShell instructions, see [this equivalent tutorial](key-vault-get-started.md).\n\nFor overview information about Azure Key Vault, see [What is Azure Key Vault?](key-vault-whatis.md)\n\n## Prerequisites\n\nTo complete this tutorial, you must have the following:\n\n- A subscription to Microsoft Azure. If you do not have one, you can sign up for a [free trial](../../../pricing/free-trial).\n- Command-Line Interface version 0.9.1 or later. To install the latest version and connect to your Azure subscription, see [Install and Configure the Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface](xplat-cli.md).\n- An application that will be configured to use the key or password that you create in this tutorial. A sample application is available from the [Microsoft Download Center](http://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=45343). For instructions, see the accompanying Readme file.\n\n## Getting help with Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface\n\nThis tutorial assumes that you are familiar with the command-line interface (Bash, Terminal, Command prompt)\n\nThe --help or -h parameter can be used to view help for specific commands. Alternately, The azure help [command] [options] format can also be used to return the same information. For example, the following commands all return the same information:\n\n    azure account set --help\n\n    azure account set -h\n\n    azure help account set\n\nWhen in doubt about the parameters needed by a command, refer to help using --help, -h or azure help [command].\n\nYou can also read the following tutorials to get familiar with Azure Resource Manager in Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface:\n\n- [How to install and configure Azure Cross-Platform Command Line Interface](xplat-cli.md)\n- [Using Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface with Azure Resource Manager](xplat-cli-azure-resource-manager.md)\n\n\n## Connect to your subscriptions\n\nTo log in using an organizational account, use the following command:\n\n    azure login -u username -p password\n\nor if you want to log in by typing interactively\n\n    azure login\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE]  The login method only works with organizational account. An organizational account is a user that is managed by your organization, and defined in your organization's Azure Active Directory tenant.\n\n\nIf you do not currently have an organizational account, and are using a Microsoft account to log in to your Azure subscription, you can easily create one using the following steps.\n\n1.  Login to the Login to the [Azure Management Portal](https://manage.windowsazure.com/), and click on Active Directory.\n2.  If no directory exists, select Create your directory and provide the requested information.\n3.  Select your directory and add a new user. This new user is an organizational account. During the creation of the user, you will be supplied with both an e-mail address for the user and a temporary password. Save this information as it is used in another step.\n4.  From the portal, select Settings and then select Administrators. Select Add, and add the new user as a co-administrator. This allows the organizational account to manage your Azure subscription.\n5.  Finally, log out of the Azure portal and then log back in using the new organizational account. If this is the first time logging in with this account, you will be prompted to change the password.\n\nFor more information about using an organizational account with Microsoft Azure, see [Sign up for Microsoft Azure as an Organization](sign-up-organization.md).\n\nIf you have multiple subscriptions and want to specify a specific one to use for Azure Key Vault, type the following to see the subscriptions for your account:\n\n    azure account list\n\nThen, to specify the subscription to use, type:\n\n    azure account set <subscription name>\n\nFor more information about configuring Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface, see [How to Install and Configure Azure Cross-Platform Command-Line Interface](xplat-cli.md).\n\n\n## Switch to using Azure Resource Manager\n\nThe Key Vault requires Azure Resource Manager, so type the following to switch to Azure Resource Manager mode:\n\n    azure config mode arm\n\n## Create a new resource group\n\nWhen using Azure Resource Manager, all related resources are created inside a resource group. We will create a new resource group 'ContosoResourceGroup' for this tutorial.\n\n    azure group create 'ContosoResourceGroup' 'East Asia'\n\nThe first parameter is resource group name and the second parameter is the location. For location, use the command `azure location list` to identify how to specify an alternative location to the one in this example. If you need more information, type: `azure help location`\n\n\n\n## Create a key vault\n\nUse the `azure keyvault create` command to create a key vault. This script has three mandatory parameters: a resource group name, a key vault name, and the geographic location.\n\nFor example, if you use the vault name of ContosoKeyVault, the resource group name of ContosoResourceGroup, and the location of East Asia, type:\n\n    azure keyvault create --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault' --resource-group 'ContosoResourceGroup' --location 'East Asia'\n\nThe output of this command shows properties of the key vault that you've just created. The two most important properties are:\n\n- **Name**: In the example this is ContosoKeyVault. You will use this name for other Key Vault cmdlets.\n- **vaultUri**: In the example this is https://contosokeyvault.vault.azure.net. Applications that use your vault through its REST API must use this URI.\n\nYour Azure account is now authorized to perform any operations on this key vault. As yet, nobody else is.\n\n\n## Add a key or secret to the key vault\n\nIf you want Azure Key Vault to create a software-protected key for you, use the `azure key create` command, and type the following:\n\n    azure keyvault key create --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault' --key-name 'ContosoFirstKey' --destination software\n\nHowever, if you have an existing key in a .pem file saved as local file in a file named softkey.pem that you want to upload to Azure Key Vault, type the following to import the key from the .PEM file, which protects the key by software in the Key Vault service:\n\n    azure keyvault key import --vaultName 'ContosoKeyVault' --key-name 'ContosoFirstKey' --pem-file './softkey.pem' –-password 'PaSSWORD' --destination software\n\nYou can now reference the key that you created or uploaded to Azure Key Vault, by using its URI. Use  **https://ContosoKeyVault.vault.azure.net/keys/ContosoFirstKey** to always get the current version, and use **https://ContosoKeyVault.vault.azure.net/keys/ContosoFirstKey/cgacf4f763ar42ffb0a1gca546aygd87** to get this specific version.\n\nTo add a secret to the vault, which is a password named SQLPassword and that has the value of Pa$$w0rd to Azure Key Vault, type the following:\n\n    azure keyvault secret set --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault' --secret-name 'SQLPassword' --value 'Pa$$w0rd'\n\nYou can now reference this password that you added to Azure Key Vault, by using its URI. Use **https://ContosoVault.vault.azure.net/secrets/SQLPassword** to always get the current version, and use **https://ContosoVault.vault.azure.net/secrets/SQLPassword/90018dbb96a84117a0d2847ef8e7189d** to get this specific version.\n\nLet's view the key or secret that you just created:\n\n- To view your key, type: `azure keyvault key list --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault'`\n- To view your secret, type: `azure keyvault secret list -–vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault'`\n\n\n## Register an application with Azure Active Directory\n\nThis step would usually be done by a developer, on a separate computer. It is not specific to Azure Key Vault but is included here, for completeness.\n\n\n>[AZURE.IMPORTANT] To complete the tutorial, your account, the vault, and the application that you will register in this step must all be in the same Azure directory.\n\nApplications that use a key vault must authenticate by using a token from Azure Active Directory. To do this, the owner of the application must first register the application in their Azure Active Directory. At the end of registration, the application owner gets the following values:\n\n\n- An **Application ID** (also known as a Client ID) and **authentication key** (also known as the shared secret). The application must present both of these values to Azure Active Directory, to get a token. How the application is configured to do this depends on the application. For the Key Vault sample application, the application owner sets these values in the app.config file.\n\n\n\nTo register the application in Azure Active Directory:\n\n1. Sign in to the Azure portal.\n2. On the left, click **Active Directory**, and then select the directory in which you will register your application. <br> <br> Note: You must select the same directory that contains the Azure subscription with which you created your key vault. If you do not know which directory this is, click **Settings**, identify the subscription with which you created your key vault, and note the name of the directory displayed in the last column.\n\n3. Click **APPLICATIONS**. If no apps have been added to your directory, this page will show only the **Add an App** link. Click the link, or alternatively, you can click the **ADD** on the command bar.\n4.  In the **ADD APPLICATION** wizard, on the **What do you want to do?** page, click **Add an application my organization is developing**.\n5.  On the **Tell us about your application** page, specify a name for your application and select **WEB APPLICATION AND/OR WEB API** (the default). Click the Next icon.\n6.  On the **App properties** page, specify the **SIGN-ON URL** and **APP ID URI** for your web application. If your application does not have these values, you can make them up for this step (for example, you could specify http://test1.contoso.com for both boxes). It does not matter if these sites exist; what is important is that the app ID URI for each application is different for every application in your directory. The directory uses this string to identify your app.\n7.  Click the Complete icon to save your changes in the wizard.\n8.  On the Quick Start page, click **CONFIGURE**.\n9.  Scroll to the **keys** section, select the duration, and then click **SAVE**. The page refreshes and now shows a key value. You must configure your application with this key value and the **CLIENT ID** value. (Instructions for this configuration will be application-specific.)\n10. Copy the client ID value from this page, which you will use in the next step to set permissions on your vault.\n\n\n\n\n## Authorize the application to use the key or secret\n\nTo authorize the application to access the key or secret in the vault, use the `azure keyvault set-policy` command.\n\nFor example, if your vault name is ContosoKeyVault and the application you want to authorize has a client ID of 8f8c4bbd-485b-45fd-98f7-ec6300b7b4ed, and you want to authorize the application to decrypt and sign with keys in your vault, then run the following:\n\n    azure keyvault set-policy --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault' --spn 8f8c4bbd-485b-45fd-98f7-ec6300b7b4ed --perm-to-keys '[“decrypt”,”sign”]'\n    \nIf you want to authorize that same application to read secrets in your vault, run the following:\n\n    azure keyvault set-policy --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault' --spn 8f8c4bbd-485b-45fd-98f7-ec6300b7b4ed --perm-to-secrets '[\"Get\"]'\n\n## If you want to use a hardware security module (HSM) ##\n\nFor added assurance, you can import or generate keys in hardware security modules (HSMs) that never leave the HSM boundary. The HSMs are FIPS 140-2 Level 2 validated. If this requirement doesn't apply to you, skip this section and go to [Delete the key vault and associated keys and secrets](#delete-the-key-vault-and-associated-keys-and-secrets).\n\nTo create these HSM-protected keys, you must have a vault subscription that supports HSM-protected keys.\n\nWhen you create the keyvault, add the 'sku' parameter:\n\n    azure azure keyvault create --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVaultHSM' --resource-group 'ContosoResourceGroup' --location 'East Asia' --sku 'Premium'\n\nYou can add software-protected keys (as shown earlier) and HSM-protected keys to this vault. To create an HSM-protected key, set the Destination parameter to 'HSM':\n\n    azure keyvault key create --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVaultHSM' --key-name 'ContosoFirstHSMKey' --destination 'HSM'\n\nYou can use the following command to import a key from a .pem file on your computer. This command imports the key into HSMs in the Key Vault service:\n\n    azure keyvault key import --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVaultHSM' --key-name 'ContosoFirstHSMKey' --pem-file '/.softkey.pem' --destination 'HSM' –-password 'PaSSWORD'\n\nThe next command imports a “bring your own key\" (BYOK) package. This lets you generate your key in your local HSM, and transfer it to HSMs in the Key Vault service, without the key leaving the HSM boundary:\n\n    azure keyvault key import --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVaultHSM' --key-name 'ContosoFirstHSMKey' --byok-file './ITByok.byok' --destination 'HSM'\n\nFor more detailed instructions about how to generate this BYOK package, see [How to use HSM-Protected Keys with Azure Key Vault](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn903624.aspx).\n\n\n## Delete the key vault and associated keys and secrets\n\nIf you no longer need the key vault and the key or secret that it contains, you can delete the key vault by using the azure keyvault delete command:\n\n    azure keyvault delete --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault'\n\nOr, you can delete an entire Azure resource group, which includes the key vault and any other resources that you included in that group:\n\n    azure group delete --name 'ContosoResourceGroup'\n\n\n## Other Azure Cross-Platform Command-line Interface Commands\n\nOther commands that you might useful for managing Azure Key Vault.\n\nThis command lists a tabular display of all keys and selected properties:\n\n    azure keyvault key list --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault'\n\nThis command displays a full list of properties for the specified key:\n\n    azure keyvault key show --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault' –-key-name 'ContosoFirstKey'\n\nThis command lists a tabular display of all secret names and selected properties:\n\n    azure keyvault secret list --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault'\n\nHere's an example of how to remove a specific key:\n\n    azure keyvault key delete --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault' --key-name 'ContosoFirstKey'\n\nHere's an example of how to remove a specific secret:\n\n    azure keyvault secret delete --vault-name 'ContosoKeyVault' --secret-name 'SQLPassword'\n\n\n## Next steps\n\nFor programming references, see [Azure Key Vault REST API Reference](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn903609.aspx) and [Azure Key Vault C# Client API Reference](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn903628.aspx).\n\ntest\n"
}