{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Testability Action | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        62
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article talks about the testability actions found in Microsoft Azure Service Fabric.",
      "pos": [
        80,
        169
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Testability actions",
      "pos": [
        469,
        488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In order to simulate an unreliable infrastructure, Service Fabric provides developers with ways to simulate various real world failures and state transitions.",
      "pos": [
        489,
        647
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These are exposed as Testability actions.",
      "pos": [
        648,
        689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The actions are the low level APIs that cause a specific fault injection, state transition or validation.",
      "pos": [
        690,
        795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Combining these actions, a service developer can write comprehensive test scenarios for your services.",
      "pos": [
        796,
        898
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric provides some common test scenarios out of the box composed of these actions.",
      "pos": [
        900,
        992
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is highly recommended to utilize these built-in scenarios, which are carefully chosen to test common state transitions and failure cases.",
      "pos": [
        993,
        1133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, actions can be used to create custom test scenarios when you want to add coverage for scenarios that are either not covered by the built-in scenarios yet or custom tailored for your application.",
      "pos": [
        1134,
        1337
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "C# implementation of the actions are found in the System.Fabric.Testability.dll assembly.",
      "pos": [
        1339,
        1428
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Testability PowerShell module is found in the Microsoft.ServiceFabric.Testability.Powershell.dll assembly.",
      "pos": [
        1429,
        1539
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As part of runtime installation the ServiceFabricTestability PowerShell module is installed to allow for easy use.",
      "pos": [
        1540,
        1654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful vs. ungraceful fault actions",
      "pos": [
        1659,
        1696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Testability actions are classified into two major buckets:",
      "pos": [
        1697,
        1755
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ungraceful faults: These faults simulate failures like machine restarts and process crashes.",
      "pos": [
        1759,
        1851
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In such cases of failures, the execution context of process stops abruptly.",
      "pos": [
        1852,
        1927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means no cleanup of state can run before the application starts up again.",
      "pos": [
        1928,
        2006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful faults: These faults simulate graceful actions like replica moves and drops triggered by load balancing.",
      "pos": [
        2010,
        2123
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In such cases the service gets notification of close and can cleanup state before exiting.",
      "pos": [
        2124,
        2214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For better quality validation, run the service and business workload while inducing various graceful and ungraceful faults.",
      "pos": [
        2216,
        2339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ungraceful faults exercise scenarios where the service process abruptly exits in the middle of some workflow.",
      "pos": [
        2340,
        2449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tests  the recovery path once the service replica is restored by Service Fabric.",
      "pos": [
        2450,
        2535
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will help test data consistency and whether the service state is maintained correctly after failures.",
      "pos": [
        2536,
        2642
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The other set of failures i.e. the graceful failures test that the service correctly reacts to replicas being moved around by Service Fabric.",
      "pos": [
        2643,
        2784
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tests handling of cancellation in the RunAsync method.",
      "pos": [
        2785,
        2844
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The service needs to check for the Cancellation token being set, correctly save its state and exit the RunAsync method.",
      "pos": [
        2845,
        2964
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Testability actions list",
      "pos": [
        2969,
        2993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actions",
      "pos": [
        2997,
        3004
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        3007,
        3018
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Managed API",
      "pos": [
        3021,
        3032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Powershell Cmdlet",
      "pos": [
        3035,
        3052
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful/UnGraceful Faults",
      "pos": [
        3055,
        3081
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CleanTestState",
      "pos": [
        3176,
        3190
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Removes all the test state from the cluster in case of a bad shutdown of the test driver.",
      "pos": [
        3192,
        3281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CleanTestStateAsync",
      "pos": [
        3284,
        3303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remove-ServiceFabricTestState",
      "pos": [
        3306,
        3335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not Applicable",
      "pos": [
        3338,
        3352
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "InvokeDataLoss",
      "pos": [
        3357,
        3371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Induces data loss into a service partition.",
      "pos": [
        3374,
        3417
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "InvokeDataLossAsync",
      "pos": [
        3420,
        3439
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Invoke-ServiceFabricPartitionDataLoss",
      "pos": [
        3442,
        3479
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful",
      "pos": [
        3482,
        3490
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "InvokeQuorumLoss",
      "pos": [
        3495,
        3511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Puts a given stateful service partition in to quorum loss.",
      "pos": [
        3514,
        3572
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "InvokeQuorumLossAsync",
      "pos": [
        3575,
        3596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Invoke-ServiceFabricQuorumLoss",
      "pos": [
        3599,
        3629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful",
      "pos": [
        3632,
        3640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Move Primary",
      "pos": [
        3645,
        3657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Moves the specified primary replica of stateful service to the specified cluster node.",
      "pos": [
        3660,
        3746
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MovePrimaryAsync",
      "pos": [
        3749,
        3765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Move-ServiceFabricPrimaryReplica",
      "pos": [
        3768,
        3800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful",
      "pos": [
        3803,
        3811
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Move Secondary",
      "pos": [
        3816,
        3830
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Moves the current secondary replica of a stateful service to a different cluster node.",
      "pos": [
        3833,
        3919
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MoveSecondaryAsync",
      "pos": [
        3922,
        3940
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Move-ServiceFabricSecondaryReplica",
      "pos": [
        3943,
        3977
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful",
      "pos": [
        3980,
        3988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RemoveReplica",
      "pos": [
        3993,
        4006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Simulates a replica failure by removing a replica from a cluster.",
      "pos": [
        4009,
        4074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will close the replica and will transition it to role 'None', removing all of its state from the cluster.",
      "pos": [
        4075,
        4185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RemoveReplicaAsync",
      "pos": [
        4188,
        4206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remove-ServiceFabricReplica",
      "pos": [
        4209,
        4236
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful",
      "pos": [
        4239,
        4247
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RestartDeployedCodePackage",
      "pos": [
        4252,
        4278
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Simulates a code package process failure by restarting a code package deployed on a node in a cluster.",
      "pos": [
        4281,
        4383
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This aborts the code package process which will restart all the user service replicas hosted in that process.",
      "pos": [
        4384,
        4493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RestartDeployedCodePackageAsync",
      "pos": [
        4496,
        4527
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restart-ServiceFabricDeployedCodePackage",
      "pos": [
        4530,
        4570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ungraceful",
      "pos": [
        4573,
        4583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RestartNode",
      "pos": [
        4588,
        4599
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Simulates a Service Fabric cluster node failure by restarting a node.",
      "pos": [
        4602,
        4671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RestartNodeAsync",
      "pos": [
        4674,
        4690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restart-ServiceFabricNode",
      "pos": [
        4693,
        4718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ungraceful",
      "pos": [
        4721,
        4731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RestartPartition",
      "pos": [
        4736,
        4752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Simulates a data center blackout or cluster blackout scenario by restarting some or all replicas of a partition.",
      "pos": [
        4755,
        4867
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RestartPartitionAsync",
      "pos": [
        4870,
        4891
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restart-ServiceFabricPartition",
      "pos": [
        4894,
        4924
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful",
      "pos": [
        4927,
        4935
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RestartReplica",
      "pos": [
        4940,
        4954
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Simulates a replica failure by restarting a persisted replica in a cluster, closing the replica and then reopening it.",
      "pos": [
        4957,
        5075
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RestartReplicaAsync",
      "pos": [
        5078,
        5097
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restart-ServiceFabricReplica",
      "pos": [
        5100,
        5128
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graceful",
      "pos": [
        5131,
        5139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StartNode",
      "pos": [
        5144,
        5153
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starts a node in a cluster which is already stopped.",
      "pos": [
        5156,
        5208
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StartNodeAsync",
      "pos": [
        5211,
        5225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Start-ServiceFabricNode",
      "pos": [
        5228,
        5251
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not Applicable",
      "pos": [
        5254,
        5268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StopNode",
      "pos": [
        5273,
        5281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Simulates a node failure by stopping a node in a cluster.",
      "pos": [
        5284,
        5341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The node will stay down until StartNode is called.",
      "pos": [
        5342,
        5392
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StopNodeAsync",
      "pos": [
        5395,
        5408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stop-ServiceFabricNode",
      "pos": [
        5411,
        5433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ungraceful",
      "pos": [
        5436,
        5446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ValidateApplication",
      "pos": [
        5451,
        5470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Validates the availability and health of all Service Fabric services within an application, usually after inducing some fault into the system.",
      "pos": [
        5473,
        5615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ValidateApplicationAsync",
      "pos": [
        5618,
        5642
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test-ServiceFabricApplication",
      "pos": [
        5645,
        5674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not Applicable",
      "pos": [
        5677,
        5691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ValidateService",
      "pos": [
        5696,
        5711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Validates the availability and health of a Service Fabric service, usually after inducing some fault into the system.",
      "pos": [
        5714,
        5831
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ValidateServiceAsync",
      "pos": [
        5834,
        5854
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test-ServiceFabricService",
      "pos": [
        5857,
        5882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not Applicable",
      "pos": [
        5885,
        5899
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Running a testability action with Powershell",
      "pos": [
        5906,
        5950
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tutorial shows you how to run a Testability action with PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        5952,
        6024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will learn how to run a Testability action against a Local (aka.",
      "pos": [
        6025,
        6093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "one-box) cluster or an Azure cluster.",
      "pos": [
        6094,
        6131
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.Fabric.Testability.Powershell.dll - the Testability PowerShell module - is installed automatically when you install the Microsoft Service Fabric MSI; and, the module is loaded automatically when you open a PowerShell prompt.",
      "pos": [
        6132,
        6366
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tutorial segments:",
      "pos": [
        6368,
        6386
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run an action against a one-box cluster",
      "pos": [
        6391,
        6430
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run an action against an Azure cluster",
      "pos": [
        6477,
        6515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run an action against a one-box cluster",
      "pos": [
        6563,
        6602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To run a Testability action against a Local Cluster, first you need to connect to the cluster and you should open the PowerShell prompt in administrator mode.",
      "pos": [
        6604,
        6762
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let us look at the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Restart-ServiceFabricNode<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> action.",
      "pos": [
        6763,
        6819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here the action <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Restart-ServiceFabricNode<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is being run on a node named \"Node1\" and the completion mode specifies that it should not verify whether the restart action actually succeeded; specifying the completion mode as \"Verify\" will cause it to verify whether the restart action actually succeeded.",
      "pos": [
        6910,
        7213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instead of directly specifying the node by its name, you can specify via a partition key and the kind of replica, as follows:",
      "pos": [
        7214,
        7339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Restart-ServiceFabricNode<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> should be used to restart a Service Fabric node in a cluster.",
      "pos": [
        7663,
        7754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will kill the Fabric.exe process which will restart all of the system service and user service replicas hosted on that node.",
      "pos": [
        7755,
        7884
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using this API to test your service helps uncover bugs along the failover recovery paths.",
      "pos": [
        7885,
        7974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It helps simulate node failures in the cluster.",
      "pos": [
        7975,
        8022
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8024,
        8119
      ],
      "content": "The following screenshot shows the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Restart-ServiceFabricNode<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Testability command in action."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8198,
        8516
      ],
      "content": "The output of the first <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Get-ServiceFabricNode<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> (a cmdlet from the ServiceFabric PowerShell module) shows that the local cluster has five nodes: Node.1 to Node.5; then after executing the Testability action (cmdlet) <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Restart-ServiceFabricNode<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> on the node, named Node.4, we see that the node's uptime has been reset."
    },
    {
      "content": "Run an action against an Azure cluster",
      "pos": [
        8522,
        8560
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Running a Testability action (with PowerShell) against an Azure Cluster is similar to running the action against a local cluster; only difference being: before you can run the action, instead of connecting to the local cluster, you need to connect to the Azure Cluster first.",
      "pos": [
        8562,
        8837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Running a Testability action with C",
      "pos": [
        8842,
        8877
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To run a Testability action using C#, first you need to connect to the cluster using the FabricClient.",
      "pos": [
        8881,
        8983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then obtain the parameters needed to run the action.",
      "pos": [
        8984,
        9036
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Different parameters can be used to run the same action.",
      "pos": [
        9037,
        9093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Looking at the RestartServiceFabricNode action, one way to run it is by using the node information (Node Name and Node Instance ID) in the cluster.",
      "pos": [
        9094,
        9241
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Several parameter explanation:",
      "pos": [
        9357,
        9387
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CompleteMode<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - completion mode specifies that it should not verify whether the restart action actually succeeded; specifying the completion mode as \"Verify\" will cause it to verify whether the restart action actually succeeded.",
      "pos": [
        9389,
        9620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OperationTimeout<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - sets the amount of time for the operation to finish before a TimeoutException exception is thrown.",
      "pos": [
        9623,
        9744
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CancellationToken<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - enables a pending call to be canceled.",
      "pos": [
        9745,
        9807
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instead of directly specifying the node by its name, you can specify via a partition key and the kind of replica.",
      "pos": [
        9809,
        9922
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9924,
        10023
      ],
      "content": "For further information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Partition Selector and Replica Selector<ept id=\"p1\">](#partition_replica_selector)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Partition Selector and Replica Selector",
      "pos": [
        12433,
        12472
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Partition Selector",
      "pos": [
        12478,
        12496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PartitionSelector is a helper exposed in Testability and is used to select a specific partition on which to perform any of the Testability actions.",
      "pos": [
        12497,
        12644
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It can be used to select a specific partition if the partition ID is known beforehand.",
      "pos": [
        12645,
        12731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Or, you can provide the partition key and the operation will resolve the partition ID internally.",
      "pos": [
        12732,
        12829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You also have the option of selecting a random partition.",
      "pos": [
        12830,
        12887
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use, create the PartitionSelector object and select the partition using one of the Select* methods and then pass in the PartitionSelector object to the API that requires it.",
      "pos": [
        12889,
        13065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If no option is selected it defaults to random partition.",
      "pos": [
        13066,
        13123
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replica Selector",
      "pos": [
        13936,
        13952
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ReplicaSelector is a helper exposed in Testability and is used to help select a replica on which to perform any of the Testability actions.",
      "pos": [
        13953,
        14092
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It can be used to select a specific replica if the replica id is known beforehand.",
      "pos": [
        14093,
        14175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition, you have the option of selecting a primary replica or a random secondary as well.",
      "pos": [
        14176,
        14270
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ReplicaSelector derives from PartitionSelector, so you need to select both the replica and the partition on which you wish to perform the Testability operation.",
      "pos": [
        14271,
        14431
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use, create a ReplicaSelector object and set the way you want to select the replica and the partition.",
      "pos": [
        14433,
        14538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can then pass it into the API that requires it.",
      "pos": [
        14539,
        14590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If no option is selected it defaults to random replica and random partition.",
      "pos": [
        14591,
        14667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Guid partitionIdGuid = new Guid(\"8fb7ebcc-56ee-4862-9cc0-7c6421e68829\");",
      "pos": [
        14669,
        14741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PartitionSelector partitionSelector = PartitionSelector.PartitionIdOf(serviceName, partitionIdGuid);",
      "pos": [
        14742,
        14842
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "long replicaId = 130559876481875498;",
      "pos": [
        14843,
        14879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        15379,
        15389
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Testability Scenarios",
      "pos": [
        15394,
        15415
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to test your service",
      "pos": [
        15460,
        15484
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Simulate failures during service workloads",
      "pos": [
        15491,
        15533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service to service communication failures",
      "pos": [
        15587,
        15628
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Testability Action | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"This article talks about the testability actions found in Microsoft Azure Service Fabric.\"\n   services=\"service-fabric\"\n   documentationCenter=\".net\"\n   authors=\"heeldin\"\n   manager=\"timlt\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"service-fabric\"\n   ms.devlang=\"dotnet\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"NA\"\n   ms.date=\"08/31/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"heeldin;motanv\"/>\n\n# Testability actions\nIn order to simulate an unreliable infrastructure, Service Fabric provides developers with ways to simulate various real world failures and state transitions. These are exposed as Testability actions. The actions are the low level APIs that cause a specific fault injection, state transition or validation. Combining these actions, a service developer can write comprehensive test scenarios for your services.\n\nService Fabric provides some common test scenarios out of the box composed of these actions. It is highly recommended to utilize these built-in scenarios, which are carefully chosen to test common state transitions and failure cases. However, actions can be used to create custom test scenarios when you want to add coverage for scenarios that are either not covered by the built-in scenarios yet or custom tailored for your application.\n\nC# implementation of the actions are found in the System.Fabric.Testability.dll assembly. The Testability PowerShell module is found in the Microsoft.ServiceFabric.Testability.Powershell.dll assembly. As part of runtime installation the ServiceFabricTestability PowerShell module is installed to allow for easy use.\n\n## Graceful vs. ungraceful fault actions\nTestability actions are classified into two major buckets:\n\n* Ungraceful faults: These faults simulate failures like machine restarts and process crashes. In such cases of failures, the execution context of process stops abruptly. This means no cleanup of state can run before the application starts up again.\n\n* Graceful faults: These faults simulate graceful actions like replica moves and drops triggered by load balancing. In such cases the service gets notification of close and can cleanup state before exiting.\n\nFor better quality validation, run the service and business workload while inducing various graceful and ungraceful faults. Ungraceful faults exercise scenarios where the service process abruptly exits in the middle of some workflow. This tests  the recovery path once the service replica is restored by Service Fabric. This will help test data consistency and whether the service state is maintained correctly after failures. The other set of failures i.e. the graceful failures test that the service correctly reacts to replicas being moved around by Service Fabric. This tests handling of cancellation in the RunAsync method. The service needs to check for the Cancellation token being set, correctly save its state and exit the RunAsync method.\n\n## Testability actions list\n\n| Actions | Description | Managed API | Powershell Cmdlet | Graceful/UnGraceful Faults |\n|---------|-------------|-------------|-------------------|------------------------------|\n|CleanTestState| Removes all the test state from the cluster in case of a bad shutdown of the test driver. | CleanTestStateAsync | Remove-ServiceFabricTestState | Not Applicable |\n| InvokeDataLoss | Induces data loss into a service partition. | InvokeDataLossAsync | Invoke-ServiceFabricPartitionDataLoss | Graceful |\n| InvokeQuorumLoss | Puts a given stateful service partition in to quorum loss. | InvokeQuorumLossAsync | Invoke-ServiceFabricQuorumLoss | Graceful |\n| Move Primary | Moves the specified primary replica of stateful service to the specified cluster node. | MovePrimaryAsync | Move-ServiceFabricPrimaryReplica | Graceful |\n| Move Secondary | Moves the current secondary replica of a stateful service to a different cluster node. | MoveSecondaryAsync | Move-ServiceFabricSecondaryReplica | Graceful |\n| RemoveReplica | Simulates a replica failure by removing a replica from a cluster. This will close the replica and will transition it to role 'None', removing all of its state from the cluster. | RemoveReplicaAsync | Remove-ServiceFabricReplica | Graceful |\n| RestartDeployedCodePackage | Simulates a code package process failure by restarting a code package deployed on a node in a cluster. This aborts the code package process which will restart all the user service replicas hosted in that process. | RestartDeployedCodePackageAsync | Restart-ServiceFabricDeployedCodePackage | Ungraceful |\n| RestartNode | Simulates a Service Fabric cluster node failure by restarting a node. | RestartNodeAsync | Restart-ServiceFabricNode | Ungraceful |\n| RestartPartition | Simulates a data center blackout or cluster blackout scenario by restarting some or all replicas of a partition. | RestartPartitionAsync | Restart-ServiceFabricPartition | Graceful |\n| RestartReplica | Simulates a replica failure by restarting a persisted replica in a cluster, closing the replica and then reopening it. | RestartReplicaAsync | Restart-ServiceFabricReplica | Graceful |\n| StartNode | Starts a node in a cluster which is already stopped. | StartNodeAsync | Start-ServiceFabricNode | Not Applicable |\n| StopNode | Simulates a node failure by stopping a node in a cluster. The node will stay down until StartNode is called. | StopNodeAsync | Stop-ServiceFabricNode | Ungraceful |\n| ValidateApplication | Validates the availability and health of all Service Fabric services within an application, usually after inducing some fault into the system. | ValidateApplicationAsync | Test-ServiceFabricApplication | Not Applicable |\n| ValidateService | Validates the availability and health of a Service Fabric service, usually after inducing some fault into the system. | ValidateServiceAsync | Test-ServiceFabricService | Not Applicable |\n\n## Running a testability action with Powershell\n\nThis tutorial shows you how to run a Testability action with PowerShell. You will learn how to run a Testability action against a Local (aka. one-box) cluster or an Azure cluster. Microsoft.Fabric.Testability.Powershell.dll - the Testability PowerShell module - is installed automatically when you install the Microsoft Service Fabric MSI; and, the module is loaded automatically when you open a PowerShell prompt.\n\nTutorial segments:\n\n- [Run an action against a one-box cluster](#run-an-action-against-a-one-box-cluster)\n- [Run an action against an Azure cluster](#run-an-action-against-an-azure-cluster)\n\n### Run an action against a one-box cluster\n\nTo run a Testability action against a Local Cluster, first you need to connect to the cluster and you should open the PowerShell prompt in administrator mode. Let us look at the **Restart-ServiceFabricNode** action.\n\n```powershell\nRestart-ServiceFabricNode -NodeName Node1 -CompletionMode DoNotVerify\n```\n\nHere the action **Restart-ServiceFabricNode** is being run on a node named \"Node1\" and the completion mode specifies that it should not verify whether the restart action actually succeeded; specifying the completion mode as \"Verify\" will cause it to verify whether the restart action actually succeeded. Instead of directly specifying the node by its name, you can specify via a partition key and the kind of replica, as follows:\n\n```powershell\nRestart-ServiceFabricNode -ReplicaKindPrimary  -PartitionKindNamed -PartitionKey Partition3 -CompletionMode Verify\n```\n\n\n```powershell\n$connection = \"localhost:19000\"\n$nodeName = \"Node1\"\n\nConnect-ServiceFabricCluster $connection\nRestart-ServiceFabricNode -NodeName $nodeName -CompletionMode DoNotVerify\n```\n\n**Restart-ServiceFabricNode** should be used to restart a Service Fabric node in a cluster. This will kill the Fabric.exe process which will restart all of the system service and user service replicas hosted on that node. Using this API to test your service helps uncover bugs along the failover recovery paths. It helps simulate node failures in the cluster.\n\nThe following screenshot shows the **Restart-ServiceFabricNode** Testability command in action.\n\n![](media/service-fabric-testability-actions/Restart-ServiceFabricNode.png)\n\nThe output of the first *Get-ServiceFabricNode* (a cmdlet from the ServiceFabric PowerShell module) shows that the local cluster has five nodes: Node.1 to Node.5; then after executing the Testability action (cmdlet) **Restart-ServiceFabricNode** on the node, named Node.4, we see that the node's uptime has been reset.\n\n### Run an action against an Azure cluster\n\nRunning a Testability action (with PowerShell) against an Azure Cluster is similar to running the action against a local cluster; only difference being: before you can run the action, instead of connecting to the local cluster, you need to connect to the Azure Cluster first.\n\n## Running a Testability action with C# \n\nTo run a Testability action using C#, first you need to connect to the cluster using the FabricClient. Then obtain the parameters needed to run the action. Different parameters can be used to run the same action.\nLooking at the RestartServiceFabricNode action, one way to run it is by using the node information (Node Name and Node Instance ID) in the cluster.\n\n```csharp\nRestartNodeAsync(nodeName, nodeInstanceId, completeMode, operationTimeout, CancellationToken.None)\n```\n\nSeveral parameter explanation:\n\n**CompleteMode** - completion mode specifies that it should not verify whether the restart action actually succeeded; specifying the completion mode as \"Verify\" will cause it to verify whether the restart action actually succeeded.  \n**OperationTimeout** - sets the amount of time for the operation to finish before a TimeoutException exception is thrown.\n**CancellationToken** - enables a pending call to be canceled.\n\nInstead of directly specifying the node by its name, you can specify via a partition key and the kind of replica.\n\nFor further information see [Partition Selector and Replica Selector](#partition_replica_selector).\n\n\n```csharp\n// Add a reference to System.Fabric.Testability.dll and System.Fabric.dll.\nusing System;\nusing System.Collections.Generic;\nusing System.Linq;\nusing System.Text;\nusing System.Threading.Tasks;\nusing System.Fabric.Testability;\nusing System.Fabric;\nusing System.Threading;\nusing System.Numerics;\n\nclass Test\n{\n    public static int Main(string[] args)\n    {\n        string clusterConnection = \"localhost:19000\";\n        Uri serviceName = new Uri(\"fabric:/samples/PersistentToDoListApp/PersistentToDoListService\");\n        string nodeName = \"N0040\";\n        BigInteger nodeInstanceId = 130743013389060139;\n\n        Console.WriteLine(\"Starting RestartNode test\");\n        try\n        {\n            //RestartNode using the replicaSelector\n            RestartNodeAsync(clusterConnection, serviceName).Wait();\n\n            //Another way to Restart Node using Nodename and NodeInstanceID.\n            RestartNodeAsync(clusterConnection, nodeName, nodeInstanceId).Wait();\n        }\n        catch (AggregateException exAgg)\n        {\n            Console.WriteLine(\"RestartNode did not complete: \");\n            foreach (Exception ex in exAgg.InnerExceptions)\n            {\n                if (ex is FabricException)\n                {\n                    Console.WriteLine(\"HResult: {0} Message: {1}\", ex.HResult, ex.Message);\n                }\n            }\n            return -1;\n        }\n\n        Console.WriteLine(\"RestartNode completed.\");\n        return 0;\n    }\n\n    static async Task RestartNodeAsync(string clusterConnection, Uri serviceName)\n    {\n        PartitionSelector randomPartitionSelector = PartitionSelector.RandomOf(serviceName);\n        ReplicaSelector primaryofReplicaSelector = ReplicaSelector.PrimaryOf(randomPartitionSelector);\n\n        // Create FabricClient with connection & security information here.\n        FabricClient fabricclient = new FabricClient(clusterConnection);\n        await fabricclient.ClusterManager.RestartNodeAsync(primaryofReplicaSelector, CompletionMode.Verify);\n    }\n\n    static async Task RestartNodeAsync(string clusterConnection, string nodeName, BigInteger nodeInstanceId)\n    {\n        // Create FabricClient with connection & security information here.\n        FabricClient fabricclient = new FabricClient(clusterConnection);\n        await fabricclient.ClusterManager.RestartNodeAsync(nodeName, nodeInstanceId, CompletionMode.Verify);\n    }\n}\n```\n\n## Partition Selector and Replica Selector\n\n### Partition Selector\nPartitionSelector is a helper exposed in Testability and is used to select a specific partition on which to perform any of the Testability actions. It can be used to select a specific partition if the partition ID is known beforehand. Or, you can provide the partition key and the operation will resolve the partition ID internally. You also have the option of selecting a random partition.\n\nTo use, create the PartitionSelector object and select the partition using one of the Select* methods and then pass in the PartitionSelector object to the API that requires it. If no option is selected it defaults to random partition.\n\n```csharp\nUri serviceName = new Uri(\"fabric:/samples/InMemoryToDoListApp/InMemoryToDoListService\");\nGuid partitionIdGuid = new Guid(\"8fb7ebcc-56ee-4862-9cc0-7c6421e68829\");\nstring partitionName = \"Partition1\";\nInt64 partitionKeyUniformInt64 = 1;\n\n// Select Random partition\nPartitionSelector randomPartitionSelector = PartitionSelector.RandomOf(serviceName);\n\n// Select partition based on Id\nPartitionSelector partitionSelectorById = PartitionSelector.PartitionIdOf(serviceName, partitionIdGuid);\n\n// Select partition based on name\nPartitionSelector namedPartitionSelector = PartitionSelector.PartitionKeyOf(serviceName, partitionName);\n\n// Select partition based on partition key\nPartitionSelector uniformIntPartitionSelector = PartitionSelector.PartitionKeyOf(serviceName, partitionKeyUniformInt64);\n```\n\n### Replica Selector\nReplicaSelector is a helper exposed in Testability and is used to help select a replica on which to perform any of the Testability actions. It can be used to select a specific replica if the replica id is known beforehand. In addition, you have the option of selecting a primary replica or a random secondary as well. ReplicaSelector derives from PartitionSelector, so you need to select both the replica and the partition on which you wish to perform the Testability operation.\n\nTo use, create a ReplicaSelector object and set the way you want to select the replica and the partition. You can then pass it into the API that requires it. If no option is selected it defaults to random replica and random partition.\n\nGuid partitionIdGuid = new Guid(\"8fb7ebcc-56ee-4862-9cc0-7c6421e68829\");\nPartitionSelector partitionSelector = PartitionSelector.PartitionIdOf(serviceName, partitionIdGuid);\nlong replicaId = 130559876481875498;\n\n\n```csharp\n// Select Random replica\nReplicaSelector randomReplicaSelector = ReplicaSelector.RandomOf(partitionSelector);\n\n// Select primary replica\nReplicaSelector primaryReplicaSelector = ReplicaSelector.PrimaryOf(partitionSelector);\n\n// Select replica by Id\nReplicaSelector replicaByIdSelector = ReplicaSelector.ReplicaIdOf(partitionSelector, replicaId);\n\n// Select random secondary replica\nReplicaSelector secondaryReplicaSelector = ReplicaSelector.RandomSecondaryOf(partitionSelector);\n```\n\n## Next Steps\n\n- [Testability Scenarios](service-fabric-testability-scenarios.md)\n- How to test your service\n   - [Simulate failures during service workloads](service-fabric-testability-workload-tests.md)\n   - [Service to service communication failures](service-fabric-testability-scenarios-service-communication.md)\n \n"
}