{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "About the virtual machine agent and extensions | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        24,
        88
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gives an overview of the agent and extensions, and how to install the agent.",
      "pos": [
        104,
        180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "About the virtual machine agent and extensions",
      "pos": [
        476,
        522
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure Virtual Machine Agent (VM Agent) is used to install, configure, manage and run Azure Virtual Machine Extensions (VM Extensions).",
      "pos": [
        523,
        661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM Extensions provide dynamic features that Microsoft and other third parties provide.",
      "pos": [
        662,
        748
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The agent and extensions are added primarily through the Management Portal, but you can also use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Powershell<ept id=\"p1\">](../install-configure-powershell.md)</ept> cmdlets or the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>xplat-cli<ept id=\"p2\">](virtual-machines-command-line-tools.md)</ept> to add and configure either when you create a VM or with existing VMs.",
      "pos": [
        749,
        1036
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM Extensions include support for <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Remote Debugging in Visual Studio<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/y7f5zaaa.aspx)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>System Center 2012<ept id=\"p2\">](http://social.technet.microsoft.com/wiki/contents/articles/18274.system-center-2012-r2-virtual-machine-role-authoring-guide-resource-extension-package.aspx)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Microsoft Azure Diagnostics<ept id=\"p3\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/blog/2014/09/02/windows-azure-virtual-machine-monitoring-with-wad-extension/)</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Docker<ept id=\"p4\">](virtual-machines-docker-vm-extension.md)</ept> -- just to name a few.",
      "pos": [
        1037,
        1549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM extensions can help you:",
      "pos": [
        1551,
        1578
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Modify security and identity features, such as resetting account values and using antimalware",
      "pos": [
        1584,
        1677
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Start, stop, or configure monitoring and diagnostics",
      "pos": [
        1682,
        1734
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reset or install connectivity features, such as RDP and SSH",
      "pos": [
        1739,
        1798
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Diagnose, monitor, and manage your VMs",
      "pos": [
        1803,
        1841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are many other features as well; new VM Extension features are released regularly.",
      "pos": [
        1843,
        1931
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article describes the Azure VM Agents for Windows and Linux, and how they support VM Extension functionality.",
      "pos": [
        1932,
        2046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a listing of VM Extensions by feature category, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure VM Extensions and Features<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn606311.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2047,
        2188
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure VM Agents for Windows and Linux",
      "pos": [
        2192,
        2229
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure Virtual Machines Agent (VM Agent) is a secured, light-weight process that installs, configures, and removes VM extensions on instances of Azure Virtual Machines from the Image Gallery and on custom VM instances if they have the VM Agent installed.",
      "pos": [
        2231,
        2488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VM Agent acts as the secure local control service for your Azure VM.",
      "pos": [
        2489,
        2561
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The extensions that the agent loads provide specific features to increase your productivity using the instance.",
      "pos": [
        2562,
        2673
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two Azure VM Agents, one for Windows VMs and one for Linux VMs.",
      "pos": [
        2675,
        2748
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default, the VM Agent is automatically installed when you create a VM from the Image Gallery, but you can also install the VM agent after the instance is created or install it in a custom VM image that you then upload yourself.",
      "pos": [
        2749,
        2979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> These VM agents are very light-weight, services that enable secured administration of virtual machine instances.",
      "pos": [
        2982,
        3112
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There might be cases in which you do not want the VM Agent.",
      "pos": [
        3113,
        3172
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If so, be sure to create VMs that do not have the VM Agent installed.",
      "pos": [
        3173,
        3242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Although the VM Agent can be removed physically, the behavior of any VM Extensions on the instance is undefined.",
      "pos": [
        3243,
        3355
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result, removing the VM agent once it is installed is not supported at this time.",
      "pos": [
        3356,
        3442
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VM Agent is enabled in the following situations:",
      "pos": [
        3444,
        3496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create an instance of a Virtual Machine by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quick Create<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method in the Management Portal, or by using the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Custom Create<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> method in the Management Portal and making sure that the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Install the VM Agent<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> checkbox is selected (as shown in the image below).",
      "pos": [
        3502,
        3781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Create a Custom Virtual Machine<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-machines-create-custom.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3782,
        3884
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM Agent Checkbox",
      "pos": [
        3892,
        3909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create an instance of a Virtual Machine by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>New-AzureVM<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495254.aspx)</ept> or the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>New-AzureQuickVM<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495183.aspx)</ept> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        3998,
        4219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can create a VM without the VM Agent installed by adding the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>–DisableGuestAgent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter to the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Add-AzureProvisioningConfig<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495299.aspx)</ept> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        4220,
        4418
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By manually downloading and installing the VM Agent (either the Windows or Linux version) on an existing VM instance and then setting the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ProvisionGuestAgent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>true<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> using Powershell or a REST call.",
      "pos": [
        4424,
        4636
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(If you do not set this value after manually installing the VM Agent, the addition of the VM Agent is not detected properly.) The following code example shows how to do this using PowerShell where the <ph id=\"ph1\">`$svc`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`$name`</ph> arguments have already been determined.",
      "pos": [
        4637,
        4896
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By creating a VM image that has the VM agent installed prior to uploading it to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        5066,
        5152
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a Windows VM, download the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows VM Agent .msi file<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=394789&amp;clcid=0x409)</ept> and install the VM Agent.",
      "pos": [
        5153,
        5297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a Linux VM, you will install it from the located at <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;</bpt><ept id=\"p1\">https://github.com/Azure/WALinuxAgent&gt;</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5298,
        5394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information on how to install the VM Agent on Linux, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Linux VM Agent User Guide<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-machines-linux-agent-user-guide.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5395,
        5543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph>In PaaS, the VM agent is called <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GuestAgent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and is always available on Web and Worker Role VMs.",
      "pos": [
        5546,
        5657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Role Architecture<ept id=\"p1\">](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/kwill/archive/2011/05/05/windows-azure-role-architecture.aspx)</ept>.) The VM agent for Role VMs can now add extensions to the cloud service VMs in the same way that it does for persistent Virtual Machines.",
      "pos": [
        5658,
        5935
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The biggest difference between VM Extensions on role VMs and persistent VMs is that with role VMs, extensions are added to the cloud service first and then to the deployments within that cloud service.",
      "pos": [
        5936,
        6137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the",
      "pos": [
        6140,
        6147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get-AzureServiceAvailableExtension<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn722498.aspx)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        6148,
        6240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "cmdlet to list all available role VM extensions.",
      "pos": [
        6241,
        6289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Find, Add, Update, and Remove VM Extensions",
      "pos": [
        6293,
        6336
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6340,
        6474
      ],
      "content": "For details on these tasks, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Add, Find, Update, and Remove Azure VM Extensions<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn850373.aspx)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n pageTitle=\"About the virtual machine agent and extensions | Microsoft Azure\"\n description=\"Gives an overview of the agent and extensions, and how to install the agent.\"\n services=\"virtual-machines\"\n documentationCenter=\"\"\n authors=\"squillace\"\n manager=\"timlt\"\n editor=\"\"/>\n<tags\nms.service=\"virtual-machines\"\n ms.devlang=\"na\"\n ms.topic=\"article\"\n ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"vm-multiple\"\n ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n ms.date=\"03/10/2015\"\n ms.author=\"rasquill\"/>\n \n#About the virtual machine agent and extensions\nThe Azure Virtual Machine Agent (VM Agent) is used to install, configure, manage and run Azure Virtual Machine Extensions (VM Extensions). VM Extensions provide dynamic features that Microsoft and other third parties provide. The agent and extensions are added primarily through the Management Portal, but you can also use the [Powershell](../install-configure-powershell.md) cmdlets or the [xplat-cli](virtual-machines-command-line-tools.md) to add and configure either when you create a VM or with existing VMs. VM Extensions include support for [Remote Debugging in Visual Studio](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/y7f5zaaa.aspx), [System Center 2012](http://social.technet.microsoft.com/wiki/contents/articles/18274.system-center-2012-r2-virtual-machine-role-authoring-guide-resource-extension-package.aspx), [Microsoft Azure Diagnostics](http://azure.microsoft.com/blog/2014/09/02/windows-azure-virtual-machine-monitoring-with-wad-extension/), and [Docker](virtual-machines-docker-vm-extension.md) -- just to name a few.\n\nVM extensions can help you:\n\n-   Modify security and identity features, such as resetting account values and using antimalware\n-   Start, stop, or configure monitoring and diagnostics\n-   Reset or install connectivity features, such as RDP and SSH\n-   Diagnose, monitor, and manage your VMs\n\nThere are many other features as well; new VM Extension features are released regularly. This article describes the Azure VM Agents for Windows and Linux, and how they support VM Extension functionality. For a listing of VM Extensions by feature category, see [Azure VM Extensions and Features](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn606311.aspx).\n\n##Azure VM Agents for Windows and Linux\n\nThe Azure Virtual Machines Agent (VM Agent) is a secured, light-weight process that installs, configures, and removes VM extensions on instances of Azure Virtual Machines from the Image Gallery and on custom VM instances if they have the VM Agent installed. The VM Agent acts as the secure local control service for your Azure VM. The extensions that the agent loads provide specific features to increase your productivity using the instance.\n\nThere are two Azure VM Agents, one for Windows VMs and one for Linux VMs. By default, the VM Agent is automatically installed when you create a VM from the Image Gallery, but you can also install the VM agent after the instance is created or install it in a custom VM image that you then upload yourself.\n\n>[AZURE.IMPORTANT] These VM agents are very light-weight, services that enable secured administration of virtual machine instances. There might be cases in which you do not want the VM Agent. If so, be sure to create VMs that do not have the VM Agent installed. Although the VM Agent can be removed physically, the behavior of any VM Extensions on the instance is undefined. As a result, removing the VM agent once it is installed is not supported at this time.\n\nThe VM Agent is enabled in the following situations:\n\n-   When you create an instance of a Virtual Machine by using the **Quick Create** method in the Management Portal, or by using the **Custom Create** method in the Management Portal and making sure that the **Install the VM Agent** checkbox is selected (as shown in the image below). For more information, see [How to Create a Custom Virtual Machine](virtual-machines-create-custom.md).\n\n    ![VM Agent Checkbox](./media/virtual-machines-extensions-agent-about/IC719409.png \"VM Agent Checkbox\")\n\n-   When you create an instance of a Virtual Machine by using the [New-AzureVM](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495254.aspx) or the [New-AzureQuickVM](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495183.aspx) cmdlet. You can create a VM without the VM Agent installed by adding the **–DisableGuestAgent** parameter to the [Add-AzureProvisioningConfig](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495299.aspx) cmdlet.\n\n-   By manually downloading and installing the VM Agent (either the Windows or Linux version) on an existing VM instance and then setting the **ProvisionGuestAgent** value to **true** using Powershell or a REST call. (If you do not set this value after manually installing the VM Agent, the addition of the VM Agent is not detected properly.) The following code example shows how to do this using PowerShell where the `$svc` and `$name` arguments have already been determined.\n\n        $vm = Get-AzureVM –serviceName $svc –Name $name\n        $vm.VM.ProvisionGuestAgent = $TRUE\n        Update-AzureVM –Name $name –VM $vm.VM –ServiceName $svc\n\n-   By creating a VM image that has the VM agent installed prior to uploading it to Azure. For a Windows VM, download the [Windows VM Agent .msi file](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=394789&clcid=0x409) and install the VM Agent. For a Linux VM, you will install it from the located at <https://github.com/Azure/WALinuxAgent>. For more information on how to install the VM Agent on Linux, see the [Azure Linux VM Agent User Guide](virtual-machines-linux-agent-user-guide.md).\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE]In PaaS, the VM agent is called **GuestAgent**, and is always available on Web and Worker Role VMs. (For more information, see [Azure Role Architecture](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/kwill/archive/2011/05/05/windows-azure-role-architecture.aspx).) The VM agent for Role VMs can now add extensions to the cloud service VMs in the same way that it does for persistent Virtual Machines. The biggest difference between VM Extensions on role VMs and persistent VMs is that with role VMs, extensions are added to the cloud service first and then to the deployments within that cloud service.\n\n>Use the\n[Get-AzureServiceAvailableExtension](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn722498.aspx)\ncmdlet to list all available role VM extensions.\n\n##Find, Add, Update, and Remove VM Extensions  \n\nFor details on these tasks, see [Add, Find, Update, and Remove Azure VM Extensions](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn850373.aspx).\n"
}