{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Operational Insights solutions",
      "pos": [
        27,
        57
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operational Insights is an analysis service that enables IT administrators to gain deep insight across on-premises and cloud environments.",
      "pos": [
        76,
        214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It enables you to interact with real-time and historical machine data to rapidly develop custom insights, and provides Microsoft and community-developed patterns for analyzing data.",
      "pos": [
        215,
        396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Solutions in Operational Insights",
      "pos": [
        729,
        762
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Solutions are a collection of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>logic<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>visualization<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>data acquisition rules<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> that address key customer challenges today.",
      "pos": [
        864,
        997
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Solutions are powered by Operational Insights log search to bring you metrics pivoted around a particular problem area.",
      "pos": [
        998,
        1117
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They allow deeper insights to help investigate and resolve operational issues faster, collect and correlate various types of machine data and help you be proactive with activities such as capacity planning, patch status reporting and security auditing.",
      "pos": [
        1118,
        1370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This guide walks you through the various solutions available and what they are used for.",
      "pos": [
        1372,
        1460
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1463,
        1583
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> For more information on <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>adding<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> solutions, see <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Adding solutions<ept id=\"p2\">](operational-insights-setup-workspace.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Assessment",
      "pos": [
        1588,
        1602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Assessment solution assesses the risk and health of your SQL Server environments on a regular interval.",
      "pos": [
        1604,
        1711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default it will scan the SQL systems weekly, and information is presented as a monthly rollup.",
      "pos": [
        1712,
        1809
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It provides a prioritized list of recommendations tailored to your deployments.",
      "pos": [
        1810,
        1889
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These recommendations are categorized across six focus areas which allows you and your team to:",
      "pos": [
        1890,
        1985
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1989,
        2056
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>quickly<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> understand the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>risk and health<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> of your environments"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2059,
        2117
      ],
      "content": "easily take <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>action<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to decrease risk and improve health"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2120,
        2175
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>prioritize<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> your work and become more <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>productive<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Assessment requires .NET 4 to run on each agent.",
      "pos": [
        2177,
        2229
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It supports the Standard, Developer and Enterprise editions of SQL Server, all currently supported versions.",
      "pos": [
        2230,
        2338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Optimize your environment with Assessment solutions<ept id=\"p1\">](operational-insights-assessment.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2339,
        2433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration Assessment",
      "pos": [
        2439,
        2463
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration assessment provides you with detailed information about the current state of your server infrastructure.",
      "pos": [
        2465,
        2583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Unlike solutions, configuration assessment is available when you first start using Operational Insights with System Center Operations Manager.",
      "pos": [
        2585,
        2727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is not available if you only use Directly-connected agents.",
      "pos": [
        2728,
        2790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration data is gathered from monitored servers and then sent to the Operational Insights service in the cloud for processing.",
      "pos": [
        2792,
        2924
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Logic is applied to the received data and the cloud service records the data.",
      "pos": [
        2925,
        3002
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Processed data for the servers is shown for the following areas:",
      "pos": [
        3003,
        3067
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Alerts:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Shows the configuration-related, proactive alerts that have been raised for your monitored servers.",
      "pos": [
        3071,
        3182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These are produced by rules authored by Microsoft Customer and Support organization (CSS) with best practices from the field",
      "pos": [
        3183,
        3307
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3310,
        3553
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Knowledge Recommendations:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Shows the Microsoft Knowledge Base articles that are recommended for workloads that are found in your infrastructure; these are automatically suggested based on your configuration thru the use of machine learning"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3556,
        3672
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Servers and Workloads Analyzed:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Shows the servers and workloads that are being monitored by Operational Insights"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3675,
        3799
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Current Snapshot:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Shows the most recent information about servers that reported data to the Operational Insights service"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3802,
        3890
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change History:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Shows a list of configuration changes made to your monitored servers"
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> Configuration Assessment can only be enabled for computers managed by <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Operations Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3894,
        4005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For additional information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Connect Operations Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](operational-insights-connect-scom.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        4007,
        4105
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Malware Assessment",
      "pos": [
        4111,
        4129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If insufficient protection is found, servers with active threats and servers with insufficient protection are shown in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Malware<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  page.",
      "pos": [
        4130,
        4271
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By using the information on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Malware<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can develop a plan to apply protection to the servers that need it.",
      "pos": [
        4272,
        4393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> Malware Assessment currently only supports Windows Defender and System Center Endpoint Protection (SCEP) real-time clients.",
      "pos": [
        4397,
        4538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If none of these clients is found, it uses data from the Malicious Software Removal Tool and mark the server as not having real-time protection.",
      "pos": [
        4539,
        4683
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can read more <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p1\">](http://feedback.azure.com/forums/267889-azure-operational-insights/suggestions/6519202-support-other-antivirus-products-in-malware-assess)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4684,
        4848
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We are also tracking <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>an issue with Windows 7 and Windows Server 2008 R2 machines<ept id=\"p1\">](http://feedback.azure.com/forums/267889-azure-operational-insights/suggestions/6519211-windows-server-2008-r2-sp1-servers-are-shown-as-n)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        4849,
        5069
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Alert Management",
      "pos": [
        5078,
        5094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With the Alert Management solution, you can view your <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Operations Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Alerts across all your servers.",
      "pos": [
        5096,
        5204
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tool can help you to easily triage alerts, and identify root causes in your environment in a very fast and fluid way.",
      "pos": [
        5205,
        5327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can get insights into key scenarios, including:",
      "pos": [
        5329,
        5380
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How many alerts have been raised within a specified time frame?",
      "pos": [
        5384,
        5447
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Top sources with the most number of active alerts raised within a specified time frame.",
      "pos": [
        5450,
        5537
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Top active critical and warning alerts that are raised within a specified time frame.",
      "pos": [
        5540,
        5625
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ability to search through all alerts and view every alert in detail",
      "pos": [
        5628,
        5695
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> Alert Management can only be enabled when Operational Insights is used in conjunction with <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System Center Operations Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5699,
        5845
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This does not send any data from agents, but simply synchronizes Operations Manager alerts to the cloud to allow you to triage them in Operational Insights and use log search.",
      "pos": [
        5846,
        6021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For additional information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Connect Operations Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](operational-insights-connect-scom.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        6022,
        6120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Capacity Planning",
      "pos": [
        6126,
        6143
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the Capacity Management solution in Microsoft Azure Operational Insights to help you understand the capacity of your server infrastructure.",
      "pos": [
        6145,
        6296
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The solution reads performance counters on the monitored server and sends usage data to the Operational Insights service in the cloud for processing.",
      "pos": [
        6297,
        6446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Logic is applied to the usage data, and the cloud service records the data.",
      "pos": [
        6447,
        6522
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Over time, usage patterns are identified and capacity is projected, based on current consumption.",
      "pos": [
        6523,
        6620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, a projection might identify when additional processor cores or additional memory will be needed for an individual server.",
      "pos": [
        6622,
        6756
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example, the projection might indicate that in 30 days the server will need additional memory.",
      "pos": [
        6757,
        6859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This can help you plan for a memory upgrade during the server’s next maintenance window, which might occur once every two weeks.",
      "pos": [
        6860,
        6988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> Capacity management can only be enabled when Operational Insights is used in conjunction with <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System Center Operations Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and you must also enable the Operations Manager connector with Virtual Machine Manager (VMM).",
      "pos": [
        6991,
        7234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For additional information about connecting the systems, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to connect VMM with Operations Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh882396.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        7235,
        7394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information on using the Capacity Management solution, see:",
      "pos": [
        7396,
        7464
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to use the Compute page",
      "pos": [
        7469,
        7496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to use the Direct Attached Storage page",
      "pos": [
        7546,
        7589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Change Tracking",
      "pos": [
        7657,
        7672
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the Configuration Change Tracking solution to help you easily identify software and Windows Services changes that occur in your environment — identifying these configuration changes can help you pinpoint operational issues.",
      "pos": [
        7674,
        7909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By using the information on the Change Tracking page, you can easily see the changes that were made in your server infrastructure.",
      "pos": [
        7910,
        8040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can view changes to your infrastructure and then drill-into details for the following categories:",
      "pos": [
        8041,
        8142
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Changes by configuration type for software and windows services",
      "pos": [
        8146,
        8209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Software changes to applications and updates for individual servers",
      "pos": [
        8212,
        8279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Total number of software changes for each application",
      "pos": [
        8282,
        8335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows service changes for individual servers",
      "pos": [
        8338,
        8384
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "System Update Assessment",
      "pos": [
        8390,
        8414
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the System Updates solution in Microsoft Azure Operational Insights to help you apply missing updates to servers in your infrastructure.",
      "pos": [
        8416,
        8564
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If missing updates are found, they are shown on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Updates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.",
      "pos": [
        8565,
        8634
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Updates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to work with missing updates and develop a plan to apply them to the servers that need them.",
      "pos": [
        8635,
        8760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Updates page details the following categories:",
      "pos": [
        8762,
        8812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Servers that are missing security updates",
      "pos": [
        8816,
        8857
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Servers that haven't been updated recently",
      "pos": [
        8860,
        8902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Updates that should be applied to specific servers",
      "pos": [
        8905,
        8955
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Type of updates that are missing",
      "pos": [
        8958,
        8990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can click any tile or item to view its details in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Search<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to get more information about the missing update.",
      "pos": [
        8992,
        9115
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Search results include:",
      "pos": [
        9117,
        9140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server",
      "pos": [
        9144,
        9150
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update title",
      "pos": [
        9153,
        9165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Knowledge Base ID",
      "pos": [
        9168,
        9185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Product the update is for",
      "pos": [
        9188,
        9213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update severity",
      "pos": [
        9216,
        9231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Publication date",
      "pos": [
        9234,
        9250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server search results include:",
      "pos": [
        9252,
        9282
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server name",
      "pos": [
        9286,
        9297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operating system version name",
      "pos": [
        9300,
        9329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automatic update enabling method",
      "pos": [
        9332,
        9364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Days since last update",
      "pos": [
        9367,
        9389
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Update agent version",
      "pos": [
        9392,
        9420
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Operational Insights solutions\"\n    description=\"Operational Insights is an analysis service that enables IT administrators to gain deep insight across on-premises and cloud environments. It enables you to interact with real-time and historical machine data to rapidly develop custom insights, and provides Microsoft and community-developed patterns for analyzing data.\"\n    services=\"operational-insights\"\n    documentationCenter=\"n/a\"\n    authors=\"bandersmsft\"\n    manager=\"jwhit\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"operational-insights\"\n    ms.workload=\"operational-insights\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n    ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"08/05/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"alfran\"/>\n\n# Solutions in Operational Insights\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [operational-insights-note-moms](../../includes/operational-insights-note-moms.md)]\n\nSolutions are a collection of **logic**, **visualization** and **data acquisition rules** that address key customer challenges today. Solutions are powered by Operational Insights log search to bring you metrics pivoted around a particular problem area. They allow deeper insights to help investigate and resolve operational issues faster, collect and correlate various types of machine data and help you be proactive with activities such as capacity planning, patch status reporting and security auditing.\n\nThis guide walks you through the various solutions available and what they are used for.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] For more information on *adding* solutions, see [Adding solutions](operational-insights-setup-workspace.md)\n\n## SQL Assessment\n\nSQL Assessment solution assesses the risk and health of your SQL Server environments on a regular interval. By default it will scan the SQL systems weekly, and information is presented as a monthly rollup. It provides a prioritized list of recommendations tailored to your deployments. These recommendations are categorized across six focus areas which allows you and your team to:\n\n- **quickly** understand the **risk and health** of your environments\n- easily take **action** to decrease risk and improve health\n- **prioritize** your work and become more **productive**\n\nSQL Assessment requires .NET 4 to run on each agent. It supports the Standard, Developer and Enterprise editions of SQL Server, all currently supported versions. See [Optimize your environment with Assessment solutions](operational-insights-assessment.md).\n\n\n## Configuration Assessment\n\nConfiguration assessment provides you with detailed information about the current state of your server infrastructure.\n\nUnlike solutions, configuration assessment is available when you first start using Operational Insights with System Center Operations Manager. It is not available if you only use Directly-connected agents.\n\nConfiguration data is gathered from monitored servers and then sent to the Operational Insights service in the cloud for processing. Logic is applied to the received data and the cloud service records the data. Processed data for the servers is shown for the following areas:\n\n- **Alerts:** Shows the configuration-related, proactive alerts that have been raised for your monitored servers. These are produced by rules authored by Microsoft Customer and Support organization (CSS) with best practices from the field\n- **Knowledge Recommendations:** Shows the Microsoft Knowledge Base articles that are recommended for workloads that are found in your infrastructure; these are automatically suggested based on your configuration thru the use of machine learning\n- **Servers and Workloads Analyzed:** Shows the servers and workloads that are being monitored by Operational Insights\n- **Current Snapshot:** Shows the most recent information about servers that reported data to the Operational Insights service\n- **Change History:** Shows a list of configuration changes made to your monitored servers\n\n> [AZURE.IMPORTANT] Configuration Assessment can only be enabled for computers managed by **Operations Manager**.  For additional information, see [Connect Operations Manager](operational-insights-connect-scom.md)\n\n\n## Malware Assessment\nIf insufficient protection is found, servers with active threats and servers with insufficient protection are shown in the **Malware**  page. By using the information on the **Malware** page, you can develop a plan to apply protection to the servers that need it.\n\n> [AZURE.IMPORTANT] Malware Assessment currently only supports Windows Defender and System Center Endpoint Protection (SCEP) real-time clients. If none of these clients is found, it uses data from the Malicious Software Removal Tool and mark the server as not having real-time protection. You can read more [here](http://feedback.azure.com/forums/267889-azure-operational-insights/suggestions/6519202-support-other-antivirus-products-in-malware-assess). We are also tracking [an issue with Windows 7 and Windows Server 2008 R2 machines](http://feedback.azure.com/forums/267889-azure-operational-insights/suggestions/6519211-windows-server-2008-r2-sp1-servers-are-shown-as-n)\n\n\n\n\n\n## Alert Management\n\nWith the Alert Management solution, you can view your **Operations Manager** Alerts across all your servers. This tool can help you to easily triage alerts, and identify root causes in your environment in a very fast and fluid way.\n\nYou can get insights into key scenarios, including:\n\n- How many alerts have been raised within a specified time frame?\n- Top sources with the most number of active alerts raised within a specified time frame.\n- Top active critical and warning alerts that are raised within a specified time frame.\n- Ability to search through all alerts and view every alert in detail\n\n> [AZURE.IMPORTANT] Alert Management can only be enabled when Operational Insights is used in conjunction with **System Center Operations Manager**. This does not send any data from agents, but simply synchronizes Operations Manager alerts to the cloud to allow you to triage them in Operational Insights and use log search. For additional information, see [Connect Operations Manager](operational-insights-connect-scom.md)\n\n\n## Capacity Planning\n\nYou can use the Capacity Management solution in Microsoft Azure Operational Insights to help you understand the capacity of your server infrastructure. The solution reads performance counters on the monitored server and sends usage data to the Operational Insights service in the cloud for processing. Logic is applied to the usage data, and the cloud service records the data. Over time, usage patterns are identified and capacity is projected, based on current consumption.\n\nFor example, a projection might identify when additional processor cores or additional memory will be needed for an individual server. In this example, the projection might indicate that in 30 days the server will need additional memory. This can help you plan for a memory upgrade during the server’s next maintenance window, which might occur once every two weeks.\n\n>[AZURE.IMPORTANT] Capacity management can only be enabled when Operational Insights is used in conjunction with **System Center Operations Manager**, and you must also enable the Operations Manager connector with Virtual Machine Manager (VMM). For additional information about connecting the systems, see [How to connect VMM with Operations Manager](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh882396.aspx).\n\nFor more information on using the Capacity Management solution, see:\n\n- [How to use the Compute page](operational-insights-capacity/#compute-page)\n- [How to use the Direct Attached Storage page](operational-insights-capacity/#direct-attached-storage-page)\n\n\n## Change Tracking\n\nYou can use the Configuration Change Tracking solution to help you easily identify software and Windows Services changes that occur in your environment — identifying these configuration changes can help you pinpoint operational issues. By using the information on the Change Tracking page, you can easily see the changes that were made in your server infrastructure. You can view changes to your infrastructure and then drill-into details for the following categories:\n\n- Changes by configuration type for software and windows services\n- Software changes to applications and updates for individual servers\n- Total number of software changes for each application\n- Windows service changes for individual servers\n\n\n## System Update Assessment\n\nYou can use the System Updates solution in Microsoft Azure Operational Insights to help you apply missing updates to servers in your infrastructure. If missing updates are found, they are shown on the **Updates** page. You can use the **Updates** page to work with missing updates and develop a plan to apply them to the servers that need them.\n\nThe Updates page details the following categories:\n\n- Servers that are missing security updates\n- Servers that haven't been updated recently\n- Updates that should be applied to specific servers\n- Type of updates that are missing\n\nYou can click any tile or item to view its details in the **Search** page to get more information about the missing update.  Search results include:\n\n- Server\n- Update title\n- Knowledge Base ID\n- Product the update is for\n- Update severity\n- Publication date\n\nServer search results include:\n\n- Server name\n- Operating system version name\n- Automatic update enabling method\n- Days since last update\n- Windows Update agent version\n"
}