{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Set up protection between on-premises VMware virtual machines or physical servers and Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Describes up Azure Site Recovery to coordinate the replication, failover and recovery of on-premises VMware virtual machines or Windows/Linux physical servers to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        138,
        306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up protection between on-premises VMware virtual machines or physical servers and Azure",
      "pos": [
        621,
        712
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article describes how to deploy Site Recovery to:",
      "pos": [
        714,
        768
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        772,
        902
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protect VMware virtual machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Coordinate replication, failover, and recovery of on-premises VMware virtual machines to Azure"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        905,
        1078
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protect physical servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Coordinate replication, failover, and recovery of on-premises physical Windows and Linux servers to Azure using the Azure Site Recovery service."
    },
    {
      "content": "The article includes an overview, deployment prerequisites, and set up instructions.",
      "pos": [
        1080,
        1164
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At the end of the article your VMware virtual machines or physical servers will be replicating to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        1165,
        1269
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you run into problems, post your questions on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Recovery Services Forum<ept id=\"p1\">](https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/forums/azure/home?forum=hypervrecovmgr)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1270,
        1429
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Azure Site Recovery?",
      "pos": [
        1435,
        1463
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure Site Recovery contributes to your business continuity and disaster recovery (BCDR) strategy by orchestrating replication, failover and recovery of virtual machines and physical servers.",
      "pos": [
        1465,
        1660
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Machines can be replicated to Azure, or to a secondary on-premises data center.",
      "pos": [
        1661,
        1740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Read more about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Site Recovery<ept id=\"p1\">](site-recovery-overview.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1741,
        1806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How does it protect on-premises resources?",
      "pos": [
        1811,
        1853
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Site Recovery helps protect your on-premises resources by orchestrating, simplifying replication, failover and failback in a number of <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>deployment scenarios<ept id=\"p1\">](site-recovery-overview.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1855,
        2040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to protect your on-premises VMware virtual machines or Windows or Linux physical servers here's how Site Recovery can help:",
      "pos": [
        2041,
        2176
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Allows VMware users to replicate virtual machines to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        2180,
        2239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Allows the replication of physical on-premises servers to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        2242,
        2306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Provides a single location to setup and manage replication, failover, and recovery.",
      "pos": [
        2309,
        2392
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Provides easy failover from your on-premises infrastructure to Azure, and failback (restore) from Azure to on-premises.",
      "pos": [
        2395,
        2514
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Implements recovery plans for easy failover of workloads that are tiered over multiple machines.",
      "pos": [
        2517,
        2613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Provides multi VM consistency so that virtual machines and physical servers running specific workloads can be recovered together to a consistent data point.",
      "pos": [
        2616,
        2772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Supports data replication over the Internet, over a site-to-site VPN connection, or over Azure ExpressRoute.",
      "pos": [
        2775,
        2883
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Provides automated discovery of VMware virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        2886,
        2942
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What do I need?",
      "pos": [
        2948,
        2963
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This diagram shows the deployment components.",
      "pos": [
        2965,
        3010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "New vault",
      "pos": [
        3014,
        3023
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here's what you'll need:",
      "pos": [
        3084,
        3108
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Component",
      "pos": [
        3112,
        3121
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deployment",
      "pos": [
        3128,
        3138
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Details",
      "pos": [
        3145,
        3152
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration server",
      "pos": [
        3173,
        3193
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy as a Azure standard A3 virtual machine in the same subscription as Site Recovery.",
      "pos": [
        3201,
        3289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You set up in the Site Recovery portal",
      "pos": [
        3297,
        3335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This server coordinates communication between protected machines, the process server, and master target servers in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        3342,
        3463
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It sets up replication and coordinates recovery in Azure when failover occurs.",
      "pos": [
        3464,
        3542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Master target server",
      "pos": [
        3545,
        3565
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy as Azure virtual machine — Either a Windows server based on a Windows Server 2012 R2 gallery image (to protect Windows machines) or as a Linux server based on a OpenLogic CentOS 6.6 gallery image (to protect Linux machines).",
      "pos": [
        3573,
        3804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Three sizing options are available – Standard A4, Standard D14 and Standard DS4.",
      "pos": [
        3812,
        3892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The server is connected to the same Azure network as the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        3898,
        3976
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You set up in the Site Recovery portal",
      "pos": [
        3983,
        4021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It receives and retains replicated data from your protected machines using attached VHDs created on blob storage in your Azure storage account.",
      "pos": [
        4031,
        4174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select Standard DS4 specifically for configuring protection for workloads requiring consistent high performance and low latency using Premium Storage Account.",
      "pos": [
        4182,
        4340
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Process server",
      "pos": [
        4347,
        4361
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy as an on-premises virtual or physical server running Windows Server 2012 R2",
      "pos": [
        4369,
        4451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend it's placed on the same network and LAN segment as the machines that you want to protect, but it can run on a different network as long as protected machines have L3 network visibility to it.",
      "pos": [
        4459,
        4663
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You set it up and register it to the configuration server in the Site Recovery portal.",
      "pos": [
        4666,
        4752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Protected machines send replication data to the on-premises process server.",
      "pos": [
        4762,
        4837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It has a disk-based cache to cache replication data that it receives.",
      "pos": [
        4838,
        4907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It performs a number of actions on that data.",
      "pos": [
        4908,
        4953
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It optimizes data by caching, compressing, and encrypting it before sending it on to the master target server.",
      "pos": [
        4960,
        5070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It handles push installation of the Mobility Service.",
      "pos": [
        5077,
        5130
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It performs automatic discovery of VMware virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        5137,
        5196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On-premises machines",
      "pos": [
        5203,
        5223
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On-premises virtual  machines running on a VMware hypervisor, or physical servers running Windows or Linux.",
      "pos": [
        5228,
        5335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You set up replication settings that apply to virtual machines and servers.",
      "pos": [
        5338,
        5413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can fail over an individual machine or more commonly, as part of a recovery plan containing multiple virtual machines that fail over together.",
      "pos": [
        5414,
        5560
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Mobility service",
      "pos": [
        5563,
        5579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Installs on each virtual machine or physical server you want to protect",
      "pos": [
        5587,
        5658
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can be installed manually or pushed and installed automatically by the process server when protection is enabled for the server.",
      "pos": [
        5665,
        5793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Mobility service send data to the Process Server as part of initial replication (resync.) Once the server reaches a protected state(after resync is completed) the Mobility service performs an in-memory capture of writes to disk and sends it to the Process Server.",
      "pos": [
        5796,
        6063
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application consistency for Windows servers is achieved using the VSS framework.",
      "pos": [
        6064,
        6144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Site Recovery vault",
      "pos": [
        6147,
        6172
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up after you've subscribed to the Site Recovery service.",
      "pos": [
        6177,
        6237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You register servers in a Site Recovery vault.",
      "pos": [
        6240,
        6286
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The vault coordinates and orchestrates data replication, failover, and recovery between your on-premises site and Azure.",
      "pos": [
        6287,
        6407
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replication mechanism",
      "pos": [
        6410,
        6431
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Over the Internet<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Communicates and replicates data from protected on-premises servers and Azure using a secure SSL/TLS communication channel over a public internet connection.",
      "pos": [
        6439,
        6618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is the default option.",
      "pos": [
        6619,
        6646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>VPN/ExpressRoute<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Communicates and replicates data between on-premises servers and Azure over a VPN connection.",
      "pos": [
        6653,
        6767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need to set up a site-to-site VPN or an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ExpressRoute<ept id=\"p1\">](../expressroute-introduction.md)</ept> connection between the on-premises site and your Azure network.",
      "pos": [
        6768,
        6926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll select how you want to replicate during Site Recovery deployment.",
      "pos": [
        6933,
        7005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can't change the mechanism after it's configured without impacting protection on already protected servers.",
      "pos": [
        7006,
        7117
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Neither option requires you to open any inbound network ports on protected machines.",
      "pos": [
        7122,
        7206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All network communication is initiated from the on-premises site.",
      "pos": [
        7207,
        7272
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7279,
        7410
      ],
      "content": "You can learn more about Site Recovery components, Providers and agents in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Site Recovery Components<ept id=\"p1\">](site-recovery-components.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Capacity planning",
      "pos": [
        7415,
        7432
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Main areas for considerations are:",
      "pos": [
        7434,
        7468
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7472,
        7563
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Source environment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—The VMware infrastructure, source machine settings and requirements."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7566,
        7654
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Component servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—The process server, configuration server, and master target server"
    },
    {
      "content": "Considerations for the source environment",
      "pos": [
        7661,
        7702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Maximum disk size<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—The current maximum size of the disk that can be attached to a virtual machine is 1 TB.",
      "pos": [
        7706,
        7815
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Thus the maximum size of a source disk that can be replicated is also limited to 1 TB.",
      "pos": [
        7816,
        7902
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7905,
        8067
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Maximum size per source<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—The maximum size of a single source machine is 31 TB (with 31 disks) and with a D14 instance provisioned for the master target server."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Number of sources per master target server<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Multiple source machines can be protected with a single master target server.",
      "pos": [
        8071,
        8195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, a single source machine can’t be protected across multiple master target servers, because as disks replicate, a VHD that mirrors the size of the disk is created on Azure blob storage and attached as a data disk to the master target server.",
      "pos": [
        8196,
        8444
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Maximum daily change rate per source<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—There are three factors that need to be considered when considering the recommended change rate per source.",
      "pos": [
        8449,
        8597
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the target based considerations two IOPS are required on the target disk for each operation on the source.",
      "pos": [
        8598,
        8708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is because a read of old data and a write of the new data will happen on the target disk.",
      "pos": [
        8709,
        8803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Daily change rate supported by the process server<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—A source machine can't span multiple process servers.",
      "pos": [
        8811,
        8918
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A single process server can support up to 1 TB of daily change rate.",
      "pos": [
        8919,
        8987
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hence 1 TB is the maximum daily data change rate supported for a source machine.",
      "pos": [
        8988,
        9068
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Maximum throughput supported by the target disk<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Maximum churn per source disk can't be more than 144 GB/day (with 8K write size).",
      "pos": [
        9076,
        9209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the table in the master target section for the throughput and IOPs of the target for various write sizes.",
      "pos": [
        9210,
        9319
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This number must be divided by two because each source IOP generates 2 IOPS on the target disk.",
      "pos": [
        9320,
        9415
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Refer <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Scalability and Performance Targets when using Premium Storage<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-scalability-targets.md#scalability-targets-for-premium-storage-accounts)</ept> while configuring target for Premium Storage account.",
      "pos": [
        9416,
        9632
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Maximum throughput supported by the storage account<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—A source can't span multiple storage accounts.",
      "pos": [
        9639,
        9741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Given that a storage account takes a maximum of 20,000 requests per second and that each source IOP generates 2 IOPS at the master target server, we recommend you keep the number of IOPS across the source to 10,000.",
      "pos": [
        9742,
        9957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Refer <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Scalability and Performance Targets when using Premium Storage<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-scalability-targets.md#scalability-targets-for-premium-storage-accounts)</ept> while configuring source for Premium Storage account.",
      "pos": [
        9958,
        10174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Considerations for component servers",
      "pos": [
        10180,
        10216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Table 1 summarizes the virtual machine sizes for the configuration and master target servers.",
      "pos": [
        10218,
        10311
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Component",
      "pos": [
        10315,
        10324
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deployed Azure instances",
      "pos": [
        10331,
        10355
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cores",
      "pos": [
        10362,
        10367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Memory",
      "pos": [
        10374,
        10380
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Max disks",
      "pos": [
        10387,
        10396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Disk size",
      "pos": [
        10403,
        10412
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration server",
      "pos": [
        10449,
        10469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard A3",
      "pos": [
        10472,
        10483
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4",
      "pos": [
        10486,
        10487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "7 GB",
      "pos": [
        10490,
        10494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "8",
      "pos": [
        10497,
        10498
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1023 GB",
      "pos": [
        10501,
        10508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Master target server",
      "pos": [
        10509,
        10529
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard A4",
      "pos": [
        10532,
        10543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "8",
      "pos": [
        10546,
        10547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "14 GB",
      "pos": [
        10550,
        10555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "16",
      "pos": [
        10558,
        10560
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1023 GB",
      "pos": [
        10563,
        10570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard D14",
      "pos": [
        10574,
        10586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "16",
      "pos": [
        10589,
        10591
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "112 GB",
      "pos": [
        10594,
        10600
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "32",
      "pos": [
        10603,
        10605
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1023 GB",
      "pos": [
        10608,
        10615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard DS4",
      "pos": [
        10619,
        10631
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "8",
      "pos": [
        10634,
        10635
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "28 GB",
      "pos": [
        10638,
        10643
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "16",
      "pos": [
        10646,
        10648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1023 GB",
      "pos": [
        10651,
        10658
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Table 1",
      "pos": [
        10662,
        10669
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Process server considerations",
      "pos": [
        10678,
        10707
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Generally process server sizing depends on the daily change rate across all protected workloads.",
      "pos": [
        10709,
        10805
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary considerations include:",
      "pos": [
        10806,
        10837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You need sufficient compute to perform tasks such as inline compression and encryption.",
      "pos": [
        10843,
        10930
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Process server uses disk based cache.",
      "pos": [
        10935,
        10972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure the recommended cache space and disk throughput is available to facilitate the data changes stored in the event of network bottleneck or outage.",
      "pos": [
        10973,
        11127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure sufficient bandwidth  so that the process server can upload the data to the master target server to provide continuous data protection.",
      "pos": [
        11133,
        11275
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Table 2 provides a summary of the process server guidelines.",
      "pos": [
        11278,
        11338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data change rate",
      "pos": [
        11342,
        11358
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CPU",
      "pos": [
        11365,
        11368
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Memory",
      "pos": [
        11375,
        11381
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cache disk size",
      "pos": [
        11388,
        11403
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cache disk throughput",
      "pos": [
        11409,
        11430
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Bandwidth ingress/egress",
      "pos": [
        11437,
        11461
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "&lt; 300 GB",
      "pos": [
        11498,
        11506
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4 vCPUs (2 sockets * 2 cores @ 2.5GHz)",
      "pos": [
        11509,
        11547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4 GB",
      "pos": [
        11550,
        11554
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "600 GB",
      "pos": [
        11557,
        11563
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "7 to 10 MB per second",
      "pos": [
        11566,
        11587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "30 Mbps/21 Mbps",
      "pos": [
        11590,
        11605
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "300 to 600 GB",
      "pos": [
        11606,
        11619
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "8 vCPUs (2 sockets * 4 cores @ 2.5GHz)",
      "pos": [
        11622,
        11660
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "6 GB",
      "pos": [
        11663,
        11667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "600 GB",
      "pos": [
        11670,
        11676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "11 to 15 MB per second",
      "pos": [
        11679,
        11701
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "60 Mbps/42 Mbps",
      "pos": [
        11704,
        11719
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "600 GB to 1 TB",
      "pos": [
        11720,
        11734
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "12 vCPUs (2 sockets * 6 cores @ 2.5GHz)",
      "pos": [
        11737,
        11776
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "8 GB",
      "pos": [
        11779,
        11783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "600 GB",
      "pos": [
        11786,
        11792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "16 to 20 MB per second",
      "pos": [
        11795,
        11817
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100 Mbps/70 Mbps",
      "pos": [
        11820,
        11836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "&gt; 1 TB",
      "pos": [
        11837,
        11843
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy another process server",
      "pos": [
        11846,
        11875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Table 2",
      "pos": [
        11888,
        11895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Where:",
      "pos": [
        11899,
        11905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ingress is download bandwidth (intranet between the source and process server).",
      "pos": [
        11910,
        11989
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Egress is upload bandwidth (internet between the process server and master target server).",
      "pos": [
        11992,
        12082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Egress numbers presume average 30% process server compression.",
      "pos": [
        12083,
        12145
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For cache disk a separate OS disk of minimum 128 GB is recommended for all process servers.",
      "pos": [
        12148,
        12239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For cache disk throughput the following storage was used for benchmarking: 8 SAS drives of 10 K RPM with RAID 10 configuration.",
      "pos": [
        12242,
        12369
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration server considerations",
      "pos": [
        12376,
        12411
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each configuration server can support up to 100 source machines with 3-4 volumes.",
      "pos": [
        12413,
        12494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If these numbers are exceeded we recommend you deploy another configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        12495,
        12578
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See Table 1 for the default virtual machine properties of the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        12579,
        12662
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Master target server and storage account considerations",
      "pos": [
        12670,
        12725
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The storage for each master target server is comprised of an OS disk, a retention volume, and data disks.",
      "pos": [
        12727,
        12832
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The retention drive maintains the journal of disk changes for the duration of the retention window defined in the Site Recovery portal.",
      "pos": [
        12833,
        12968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Refer to Table 1 for the virtual machine properties of the master target server.",
      "pos": [
        12970,
        13050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Table 3 shows how the disks of A4 are used.",
      "pos": [
        13051,
        13094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instance",
      "pos": [
        13098,
        13106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "OS disk",
      "pos": [
        13113,
        13120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retention",
      "pos": [
        13127,
        13136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data disks",
      "pos": [
        13143,
        13153
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retention",
      "pos": [
        13185,
        13194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data disks",
      "pos": [
        13201,
        13211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard A4",
      "pos": [
        13214,
        13225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1 disk (1 * 1023 GB)",
      "pos": [
        13228,
        13248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1 disk ( 1 * 1023 GB)",
      "pos": [
        13251,
        13272
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "15 disks (15 * 1023 GB)",
      "pos": [
        13275,
        13298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard D14",
      "pos": [
        13299,
        13311
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1 disk (1 * 1023 GB)",
      "pos": [
        13315,
        13335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1 disk ( 1 * 1023 GB)",
      "pos": [
        13338,
        13359
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "31 disks (15 * 1023 GB)",
      "pos": [
        13362,
        13385
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard DS4",
      "pos": [
        13386,
        13398
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1 disk (1 * 1023 GB)",
      "pos": [
        13402,
        13422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1 disk ( 1 * 1023 GB)",
      "pos": [
        13425,
        13446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "15 disks (15 * 1023 GB)",
      "pos": [
        13449,
        13472
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Table 3",
      "pos": [
        13476,
        13483
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Capacity planning for the master target server depends on:",
      "pos": [
        13487,
        13545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure storage performance and limitations",
      "pos": [
        13549,
        13590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The maximum number of highly utilized disks for a Standard Tier VM, is about 40 (20,000/500 IOPS per disk) in a single storage account.",
      "pos": [
        13597,
        13732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Refer <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Scalability Targets for Standard Storage Accounts<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-scalability-targets.md#scalability-targets-for-standard-storage-accounts)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        13733,
        13905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Similarly refer <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Scalability Targets for Premium Storage Accounts<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-scalability-targets.md#scalability-targets-for-premium-storage-accounts)</ept> for more information about Premium Storage account.",
      "pos": [
        13906,
        14116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Daily change rate",
      "pos": [
        14121,
        14138
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retention volume storage.",
      "pos": [
        14144,
        14169
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that:",
      "pos": [
        14171,
        14181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One source can't span multiple storage accounts.",
      "pos": [
        14185,
        14233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This applies to the data disk that go to the storage accounts selected when you configure protection.",
      "pos": [
        14234,
        14335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The OS and the retention disks usually go to the automatically deployed storage account.",
      "pos": [
        14336,
        14424
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The retention storage volume required depends on the daily change rate and the number of retention days.",
      "pos": [
        14427,
        14531
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The retention storage required per master target server = total churn from source per day * number of retention days.",
      "pos": [
        14532,
        14649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each master target server has only one retention volume.",
      "pos": [
        14653,
        14709
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The retention volume is shared across the disks attached to the master target server.",
      "pos": [
        14710,
        14795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example:",
      "pos": [
        14796,
        14808
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If there's a source machine with 5 disks and each disk generates 120 IOPS (8K size) on the source, this translates to 240 IOPS per disk (2 operations on the target disk per source IO).",
      "pos": [
        14815,
        14999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "240 IOPS is within the Azure per disk IOPS limit of 500.",
      "pos": [
        15000,
        15056
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the retention volume, this becomes 120 * 5 = 600 IOPS and this can become a bottle neck.",
      "pos": [
        15063,
        15154
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this scenario, a good strategy would be to add more disks to the retention volume and span it across, as a RAID stripe configuration.",
      "pos": [
        15155,
        15291
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will improve performance because the IOPS are distributed across multiple drives.",
      "pos": [
        15292,
        15378
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The number of drives to be added to the retention volume will be as follows:",
      "pos": [
        15379,
        15455
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Total IOPS from source environment / 500",
      "pos": [
        15466,
        15506
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Total churn per day from source environment (uncompressed) / 287 GB.",
      "pos": [
        15517,
        15585
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "287 GB is the maximum throughput supported by a target disk per day.",
      "pos": [
        15586,
        15654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This metric will vary based on the write size with a factor of 8K, because in this case 8K is thee assumed write size.",
      "pos": [
        15655,
        15773
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if the write size is 4K then throughput will be 287/2.",
      "pos": [
        15774,
        15841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "And if the write size is 16K then throughput will be 287*2.",
      "pos": [
        15842,
        15901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The number of storage accounts required = total source IOPs/10000.",
      "pos": [
        15904,
        15970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you start",
      "pos": [
        15976,
        15992
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Component",
      "pos": [
        15996,
        16005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Requirements",
      "pos": [
        16012,
        16024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Details",
      "pos": [
        16031,
        16038
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure account",
      "pos": [
        16060,
        16073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/)</ept> account.",
      "pos": [
        16078,
        16147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can start with a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>free trial<ept id=\"p1\">](pricing/free-trial/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        16148,
        16203
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure storage",
      "pos": [
        16206,
        16219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need an Azure storage account to store replicated data",
      "pos": [
        16227,
        16288
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Either the account should be a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Standard Geo-redundant Storage Account<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-redundancy.md#geo-redundant-storage)</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Premium Storage Account<ept id=\"p2\">](../storage/storage-premium-storage-preview-portal.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        16295,
        16506
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It must in the same region as the Azure Site Recovery service, and be associated with the same subscription.",
      "pos": [
        16513,
        16621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To learn more read <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Introduction to Microsoft Azure Storage<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-introduction.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        16628,
        16724
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure virtual network",
      "pos": [
        16731,
        16752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need an Azure virtual network on which the configuration server and master target server will be deployed.",
      "pos": [
        16757,
        16870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It should be in the same subscription and region as the Azure Site Recovery vault.",
      "pos": [
        16871,
        16953
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you wish to replicate data over an ExpressRoute or VPN connection the Azure virtual network must be connected to your on-premises network over an ExpressRoute connection or a Site-to-Site VPN.",
      "pos": [
        16954,
        17149
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure resources",
      "pos": [
        17152,
        17167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure you have enough Azure resources to deploy all components.",
      "pos": [
        17172,
        17239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Read more in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Subscription Limits<ept id=\"p1\">](../azure-subscription-service-limits.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        17240,
        17322
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure virtual machines",
      "pos": [
        17325,
        17347
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual machines you want to protect should conform with <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure prerequisites<ept id=\"p1\">](site-recovery-best-practices.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        17355,
        17467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Disk count<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—A maximum of 31 disks can be supported on a single protected server",
      "pos": [
        17474,
        17556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Disk sizes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Individual disk capacity shouldn't be more than 1023 GB",
      "pos": [
        17563,
        17633
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Clustering<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Clustered servers aren't supported",
      "pos": [
        17640,
        17689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Boot<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Unified Extensible Firmware Interface(UEFI)/Extensible Firmware Interface(EFI) boot isn't supported",
      "pos": [
        17696,
        17804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Volumes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Bitlocker encrypted volumes aren't supported",
      "pos": [
        17811,
        17867
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Server names<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Names should contain between 1 and 63 characters (letters, numbers and hyphens).",
      "pos": [
        17875,
        17972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name must start with a letter or number and end with a letter or number.",
      "pos": [
        17973,
        18049
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After a machine is protected you can modify the Azure name.",
      "pos": [
        18050,
        18109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration server",
      "pos": [
        18116,
        18136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard A3 virtual machine based on an Azure Site Recovery Windows Server 2012 R2 gallery image will be created in your subscription for the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        18144,
        18307
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's created as the first instance in a new cloud service.",
      "pos": [
        18308,
        18366
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you select Public Internet as the connectivity type for the Configuration Server the cloud service will be created with a reserved public IP address.",
      "pos": [
        18367,
        18519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The installation path should be in English characters only.",
      "pos": [
        18526,
        18585
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Master target server",
      "pos": [
        18592,
        18612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure virtual machine, standard A4, D14 or DS4.",
      "pos": [
        18620,
        18667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The installation path  should be in English characters only.",
      "pos": [
        18674,
        18734
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example the path should be <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>/usr/local/ASR<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for a master target server running Linux.",
      "pos": [
        18735,
        18826
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Process server",
      "pos": [
        18837,
        18851
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can deploy the process server on physical or virtual machine running Windows Server 2012 R2 with the latest updates.",
      "pos": [
        18859,
        18979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install on C:/.",
      "pos": [
        18980,
        18995
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend you place the server on the same network and subnet as the machines you want to protect.",
      "pos": [
        19002,
        19103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install VMware vSphere CLI 5.5.0 on the process server.",
      "pos": [
        19110,
        19165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VMware vSphere CLI component is required on the process server in order to discover virtual machines managed by a vCenter server or virtual machines running on an ESXi host.",
      "pos": [
        19166,
        19343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The installation path should be in English characters only.",
      "pos": [
        19350,
        19409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VMware",
      "pos": [
        19416,
        19422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A VMware vCenter server managing your VMware vSphere hypervisors.",
      "pos": [
        19430,
        19495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It should be running vCenter version 5.1 or 5.5 with the latest updates.",
      "pos": [
        19496,
        19568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One or more vSphere hypervisors containing VMware virtual machines you want to protect.",
      "pos": [
        19575,
        19662
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The hypervisor should be running ESX/ESXi version 5.1 or 5.5 with the latest updates.",
      "pos": [
        19663,
        19748
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VMware virtual machines should have VMware tools installed and running.",
      "pos": [
        19755,
        19826
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows machines",
      "pos": [
        19833,
        19849
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Protected physical servers or VMware virtual machines running Windows have a number of requirements.",
      "pos": [
        19857,
        19957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A supported 64-bit operating system: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Windows Server 2012 R2<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Windows Server 2012<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Windows Server 2008 R2 with at least SP1<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        19964,
        20102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The host name, mount points, device names, Windows system path (eg: C:\\Windows) should be in English only.",
      "pos": [
        20109,
        20215
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The operating system should be installed on C:\\ drive.",
      "pos": [
        20222,
        20276
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only basic disks are supported.",
      "pos": [
        20283,
        20314
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Dynamic disks aren't supported.",
      "pos": [
        20315,
        20346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need to provide an administrator account (must be a local administrator on the Windows machine) to push install the Mobility Service on Windows servers.",
      "pos": [
        20476,
        20635
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the provided account is a non-domain account you'll need to disable Remote User Access control on the local machine.",
      "pos": [
        20636,
        20755
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this add the LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy DWORD registry entry with a value of 1 under HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Policies\\System.",
      "pos": [
        20756,
        20927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To add the registry entry from a CLI open cmd or powershell and enter <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`REG ADD HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Policies\\System /v LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy /t REG_DWORD /d 1`</ph><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        20928,
        21140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Learn more<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/aa826699.aspx)</ept> about access control.",
      "pos": [
        21141,
        21225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After failover, if you want connect to Windows virtual machines in Azure with Remote Desktop make sure that Remote Desktop is enabled for the on-premises machine.",
      "pos": [
        21232,
        21394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're not connecting over VPN, firewall rules should allow Remote Desktop connections over the internet.",
      "pos": [
        21395,
        21503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linux machines",
      "pos": [
        21510,
        21524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A supported 64 bit operating system: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Centos 6.4, 6.5, 6.6<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Oracle Enterprise Linux 6.4, 6.5 running either the Red Hat compatible kernel or Unbreakable Enterprise Kernel Release 3 (UEK3)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 11 SP3<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        21533,
        21769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Firewall rules on protected machines should allow them to reach the configuration and master target servers in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        21776,
        21893
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "/etc/hosts files on protected machines should  contain entries that map the local host name to IP addresses associated with all NICs",
      "pos": [
        21900,
        22032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to connect to an Azure virtual machine running Linux after failover using a Secure Shell client (ssh), ensure that the Secure Shell service on the protected machine is set to start automatically on system boot, and that firewall rules allow an ssh connection to it.",
      "pos": [
        22040,
        22317
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The host name, mount points, device names, and Linux system paths and file names (eg /etc/; /usr) should be in English only.",
      "pos": [
        22324,
        22448
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Protection can be enabled for on-premises machines with the following storage:-",
      "pos": [
        22455,
        22534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "File system: EXT3, ETX4, ReiserFS, XFS",
      "pos": [
        22538,
        22576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Multipath software-Device Mapper (multipath)",
      "pos": [
        22580,
        22624
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Volume manager: LVM2",
      "pos": [
        22628,
        22648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Physical servers with HP CCISS controller storage are not supported.",
      "pos": [
        22652,
        22720
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Third-party",
      "pos": [
        22727,
        22738
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some deployment components in this scenario depend on third-party software to function properly.",
      "pos": [
        22743,
        22839
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a complete list see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Third-party software notices and information<ept id=\"p1\">](#third-party)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        22840,
        22924
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deployment",
      "pos": [
        22929,
        22939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The graphic summarizes the deployment steps.",
      "pos": [
        22941,
        22985
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deployment steps",
      "pos": [
        22989,
        23005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network connectivity Type",
      "pos": [
        23072,
        23097
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You have two options to configure network connectivity between your on-premises site and the Azure virtual network on which your Infrastructure components (Configuration Server, Master target Servers) are deployed.",
      "pos": [
        23099,
        23313
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need to decide which network connectivity option to use before you can deploy your Configuration Server.",
      "pos": [
        23314,
        23425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is a deployment time choice, and cannot be changed later.",
      "pos": [
        23426,
        23488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Public Internet :<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Communication and replication of data between the on-premises servers (Process Server, Protected Servers) and the Azure Infrastructure component servers (Configuration Server, Master Target Server) happens over a secure SSL/TLS connection from on-premises to the Public endpoints on the Configuration Server and the Master Target server.",
      "pos": [
        23490,
        23849
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(The only exception is the connection between the Process Server and the Master Target server on TCP port 9080 which is un-encrypted.",
      "pos": [
        23850,
        23983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only control information related to the replication protocol related used to setup the replication is exchanged on this connection.)",
      "pos": [
        23984,
        24116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deployment diagram internet",
      "pos": [
        24120,
        24147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>VPN :<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Communication and replication of data between the on-premises servers (Process Server, Protected Servers) and the Azure Infrastructure component servers (Configuration Server, Master Target Server) happens over a VPN connection between your on-premises network and the Azure virtual network on which the Configuration server and Master Target servers are deployed.",
      "pos": [
        24222,
        24596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure that your on-premises network is connected to the Azure virtual network by an ExpressRoute connection or a site-to-site VPN connection.",
      "pos": [
        24597,
        24739
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deployment diagram VPN",
      "pos": [
        24743,
        24765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 1: Create a vault",
      "pos": [
        24839,
        24861
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        24866,
        24927
      ],
      "content": "Sign in to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://portal.azure.com)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        24933,
        25016
      ],
      "content": "Expand <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Site Recovery Vault<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        25022,
        25062
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Quick Create<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        25067,
        25124
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, enter a friendly name to identify the vault."
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Region<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select the geographic region for the vault.",
      "pos": [
        25129,
        25187
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To check supported regions see Geographic Availability in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Site Recovery Pricing Details<ept id=\"p1\">](pricing/details/site-recovery/)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        25188,
        25315
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        25320,
        25343
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create vault<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "New vault",
      "pos": [
        25351,
        25360
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check the status bar to confirm that the vault was successfully created.",
      "pos": [
        25428,
        25500
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The vault will be listed as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on the main <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.",
      "pos": [
        25501,
        25579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 2: Deploy a configuration server",
      "pos": [
        25584,
        25621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure server settings",
      "pos": [
        25627,
        25652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click the vault to open the Quick Start page.",
      "pos": [
        25657,
        25737
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Quick Start can also be opened at any time using the icon.",
      "pos": [
        25738,
        25796
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Quick Start Icon",
      "pos": [
        25804,
        25820
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        25894,
        25994
      ],
      "content": "In the dropdown list, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Between an on-premises site with VMware/physical servers and Azure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        25998,
        26075
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Prepare Target(Azure) Resources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Deploy Configuration Server<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy configuration server",
      "pos": [
        26083,
        26110
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        26179,
        26227
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New Configuration Server Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> specify:"
    },
    {
      "content": "A name for the configuration server and credentials to connect to it.",
      "pos": [
        26235,
        26304
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        26311,
        26480
      ],
      "content": "In the network connectivity type drop down select Public Internet or VPN.\n[AZURE.NOTE] This setting is a deployment time choice you make and cannot be changed later.",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "    "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "In the network connectivity type drop down select Public Internet or VPN.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            73
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> This setting is a deployment time choice you make and cannot be changed later.",
          "pos": [
            74,
            165
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the Azure network on which the server should be located.",
      "pos": [
        26489,
        26552
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you specified VPN as the network connectivity type ensure that this Azure vnet is connected to your on-premises site over an ExpressRoute connection or a site-to-site VPN.",
      "pos": [
        26553,
        26727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify the internal IP address and subnet to assign to the server.",
      "pos": [
        26734,
        26801
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the first four IP addresses in any subnet are reserved for internal Azure usage.",
      "pos": [
        26802,
        26892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use any other available IP address.",
      "pos": [
        26893,
        26928
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy configuration server",
      "pos": [
        26940,
        26967
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> a standard A3 virtual machine based on an Azure Site Recovery Windows Server 2012 R2 gallery image will be created in your subscription for the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        27037,
        27224
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's created as the first instance in a new cloud service.",
      "pos": [
        27225,
        27283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you specified the network connectivity type to be Public Internet the cloud service is created with a reserved public IP address.",
      "pos": [
        27284,
        27416
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can monitor progress in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Jobs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.",
      "pos": [
        27417,
        27462
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitor progress",
      "pos": [
        27470,
        27486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This step is applicable only if your connectivity type is Public Internet.",
      "pos": [
        27568,
        27642
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the configuration server is deployed note the public IP address assigned to it on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in the Azure portal.",
      "pos": [
        27645,
        27783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Endpoints<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab note the public HTTPS port mapped to private port 443.",
      "pos": [
        27784,
        27868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need this information later when you register the master target and process servers with the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        27869,
        27990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The configuration server is deployed with these endpoints:",
      "pos": [
        27991,
        28049
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "HTTPS: Public port is used to coordinate communication between component servers and Azure over the internet.",
      "pos": [
        28057,
        28166
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Private port 443 is used to coordinate communication between component servers and Azure over VPN.",
      "pos": [
        28167,
        28265
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Custom: Public port is used for failback tool communication over the inter",
      "pos": [
        28272,
        28346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "net.",
      "pos": [
        28353,
        28357
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Private port 9443 is used for failback tool communication over VPN.",
      "pos": [
        28358,
        28425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell: Private port 5986",
      "pos": [
        28432,
        28461
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remote desktop: Private port 3389",
      "pos": [
        28468,
        28501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM endpoints",
      "pos": [
        28513,
        28525
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        28598,
        28742
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.WARNING]</ph> Don't delete or change the public or private port number of any of the endpoints created during configuration server deployment."
    },
    {
      "content": "The configuration server is deployed in an automatically created Azure cloud service with a reserved IP address.",
      "pos": [
        28744,
        28856
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The reserved address is needed to ensure that the Configuration Server cloud service IP address remains the same across reboots of the virtual machines (including the configuration server) on the cloud service.",
      "pos": [
        28857,
        29067
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The reserved public IP address will need to be manually unreserved when the configuration server is decommissioned or it'll remain reserved.",
      "pos": [
        29068,
        29208
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There's a default limit of 20 reserved public IP addresses per subscription.",
      "pos": [
        29209,
        29285
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Find out more<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-network/virtual-networks-reserved-private-ip.md)</ept> about reserved IP addresses.",
      "pos": [
        29286,
        29390
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Register the configuration server in the vault",
      "pos": [
        29397,
        29443
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quick Start<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Prepare Target Resources<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Download a registration key<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        29448,
        29545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The key file is generated automatically.",
      "pos": [
        29546,
        29586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's valid for 5 days after it's generated.",
      "pos": [
        29587,
        29630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy it to the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        29631,
        29667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select the configuration server from the virtual machines list.",
      "pos": [
        29671,
        29758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Connect<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        29759,
        29808
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Open<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> the downloaded RDP file to log onto the configuration server using Remote Desktop.",
      "pos": [
        29809,
        29900
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If your Configuration server is deployed on a VPN network, use the internal IP address (this is the IP address you specified when you deployed the configuration server and can also be seen on the virtual machines dashboard page for the configuration server virtual machine) of the configuration server to Remote desktop to it from your on-premises network.",
      "pos": [
        29901,
        30257
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure Site Recovery Configuration Server Setup Wizard runs automatically when you log on for the first time.",
      "pos": [
        30258,
        30370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Registration",
      "pos": [
        30378,
        30390
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        30474,
        30564
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Third-Party Software Installation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>I Accept<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to download and install MySQL."
    },
    {
      "content": "MySQL install",
      "pos": [
        30572,
        30585
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        30666,
        30751
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>MySQL Server Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> create credentials to log onto the MySQL server instance."
    },
    {
      "content": "MySQL credentials",
      "pos": [
        30759,
        30776
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Internet Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> specify how the configuration server will connect to the internet.",
      "pos": [
        30856,
        30947
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that:",
      "pos": [
        30948,
        30958
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to use a custom proxy you should set it up before you install the Provider.",
      "pos": [
        30966,
        31053
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        31060,
        31130
      ],
      "content": "When you click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> a test will run to check the proxy connection."
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do use a custom proxy, or your default proxy requires authentication you'll need to enter the proxy details, including the address, port, and credentials.",
      "pos": [
        31137,
        31298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following URLs should be accessible via the proxy:",
      "pos": [
        31305,
        31359
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.hypervrecoverymanager.windowsazure.com",
      "pos": [
        31370,
        31410
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.accesscontrol.windows.net",
      "pos": [
        31421,
        31448
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.backup.windowsazure.com",
      "pos": [
        31459,
        31484
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.blob.core.windows.net",
      "pos": [
        31495,
        31518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.store.core.windows.net",
      "pos": [
        31529,
        31553
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have IP address-based firewall rules ensure that the rules are set to allow communication from the configuration server to the IP addresses described in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Datacenter IP Ranges<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/azure/dn175718.aspx)</ept> and HTTPS (443) protocol.",
      "pos": [
        31560,
        31836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You would have to white-list IP ranges of the Azure region that you plan to use, and that of West US.",
      "pos": [
        31837,
        31938
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Proxy registration",
      "pos": [
        31946,
        31964
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        32041,
        32153
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Provider Error Message Localization Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> specify in which language you want error messages to appear."
    },
    {
      "content": "Error message registration",
      "pos": [
        32161,
        32187
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        32265,
        32361
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Site Recovery Registration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> browse and select the key file you copied to the server."
    },
    {
      "content": "Key file registration",
      "pos": [
        32369,
        32390
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the completion page of the wizard select these options:",
      "pos": [
        32467,
        32525
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        32533,
        32660
      ],
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Launch Account Management Dialog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to specify that the Manage Accounts dialog should open after you finish the wizard."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        32667,
        32874
      ],
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create a desktop icon for Cspsconfigtool<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to add a desktop shortcut on the  configuration server so that you can open the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Manage Accounts<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> dialog at any time without needing to rerun the wizard."
    },
    {
      "content": "Complete registration",
      "pos": [
        32882,
        32903
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Finish<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to complete the wizard.",
      "pos": [
        32980,
        33020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A passphrase is generated.",
      "pos": [
        33021,
        33047
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy it to a secure location.",
      "pos": [
        33048,
        33077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need it to authenticate and register the process and master target servers with the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        33078,
        33190
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's also used to ensure channel integrity in configuration server communications.",
      "pos": [
        33191,
        33273
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can regenerate the passphrase but then you'll need to re-register the master target and process servers using the new passphrase.",
      "pos": [
        33274,
        33407
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Passphrase",
      "pos": [
        33415,
        33425
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        33482,
        33592
      ],
      "content": "After registration the configuration server will be listed on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configuration Servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in the vault."
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up and manage accounts",
      "pos": [
        33598,
        33624
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During deployment Site Recovery requests credentials for the following actions:",
      "pos": [
        33626,
        33705
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you add a vCenter server for automated discovery of virtual machines managed by the vCenter server.",
      "pos": [
        33709,
        33813
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A vCenter account is required for automated discovery of virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        33814,
        33888
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you add machines for protection, so that Site Recovery can install the Mobility service on them.",
      "pos": [
        33891,
        33992
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you've registered the configuration server you can open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Manage Accounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog to add and manage accounts that should be used for these actions.",
      "pos": [
        33994,
        34152
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are a couple of ways to do this:",
      "pos": [
        34153,
        34191
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open the shortcut you opted to created for the dialog on the last page of setup for the configuration server (cspsconfigtool).",
      "pos": [
        34195,
        34321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open the dialog on finish of configuration server setup.",
      "pos": [
        34324,
        34380
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Manage Accounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add Account<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        34385,
        34430
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also modify and delete existing accounts.",
      "pos": [
        34431,
        34480
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Manage accounts",
      "pos": [
        34488,
        34503
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        34576,
        34674
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Account Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> specify an account name to use in Azure and credentials (Domain/user name)."
    },
    {
      "content": "Manage accounts",
      "pos": [
        34683,
        34698
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connect to the configuration server",
      "pos": [
        34773,
        34808
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two ways to connect to the configuration server:",
      "pos": [
        34811,
        34869
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Over a VPN site-to-site or ExpressRoute connection",
      "pos": [
        34873,
        34923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Over the internet",
      "pos": [
        34926,
        34943
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that:",
      "pos": [
        34946,
        34956
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An internet connection uses the endpoints of the virtual machine in conjunction with the public virtual IP address of the server.",
      "pos": [
        34960,
        35089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A VPN connection uses the internal IP address of the server together with the endpoint private ports.",
      "pos": [
        35092,
        35193
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's a one-time decision to decide whether to connect (control and replication data) from your on-premises servers to the various component servers (configuration server, master target server) running in Azure over a VPN connection or the internet.",
      "pos": [
        35196,
        35444
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can't change this setting afterwards.",
      "pos": [
        35445,
        35486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do you'll need to redeploy the scenario and reprotect your machines.",
      "pos": [
        35487,
        35562
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 3: Deploy the master target server",
      "pos": [
        35570,
        35609
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        35614,
        35692
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Prepare Target(Azure) Resources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Deploy master target server<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify the master target server details and credentials.",
      "pos": [
        35696,
        35753
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The server will be deployed in the same Azure network as the configuration server you register it to.",
      "pos": [
        35754,
        35855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you click to complete an Azure virtual machine will be created with a Windows or Linux gallery image.",
      "pos": [
        35856,
        35962
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Target server settings",
      "pos": [
        35970,
        35992
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the first four IP addresses in any subnet are reserved for internal Azure usage.",
      "pos": [
        36058,
        36148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify any other available IP address.",
      "pos": [
        36149,
        36188
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        36191,
        36453
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Select Standard DS4 when configuring protection for workloads which require consistent high IO performance and low latency in order to host IO intensive workloads using <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Premium Storage Account<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-premium-storage-preview-portal.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "A Windows master target server virtual machine is created with these endpoints (Public endpoints are created only if your deployment type is Public Internet):",
      "pos": [
        36459,
        36617
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Custom: Public port is used by the process server to send replication data over the internet.",
      "pos": [
        36625,
        36718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Private port 9443 is used by the process server to send replication data to the master target server over VPN.",
      "pos": [
        36719,
        36829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Custom1: Public port is used by the process server to send control meta-data over the internet.",
      "pos": [
        36836,
        36931
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Private port 9080 is used by process server to send control meta-data to the master target server over VPN.",
      "pos": [
        36932,
        37039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell: Private port 5986",
      "pos": [
        37046,
        37075
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remote desktop: Private port 3389",
      "pos": [
        37082,
        37115
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A Linux master target server virtual machine is created with these endpoints (Public endpoints are created only if your deployment type is Public Internet):",
      "pos": [
        37120,
        37276
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Custom: Public port is used by the process server to send replication data over the internet.",
      "pos": [
        37284,
        37377
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Private port 9443 is used by the process server to send replication data to the master target server over VPN.",
      "pos": [
        37378,
        37488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Custom1: Public port is used by the process server to send control meta-data over the internet.",
      "pos": [
        37495,
        37590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Private port 9080 is used by the process server to send control data to the master target server over VPN",
      "pos": [
        37591,
        37696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SSH: Private port 22",
      "pos": [
        37703,
        37723
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        37730,
        37878
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.WARNING]</ph> Don't delete or change the public or private port number of any of the endpoints created during the master target server deployment."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        37883,
        37945
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> wait for the virtual machine to start."
    },
    {
      "content": "If you've configured the server with Windows note down the remote desktop details.",
      "pos": [
        37953,
        38035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you configured with Linux and you're connecting over VPN note the internal IP address of the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        38042,
        38154
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're connecting over the internet note the public IP address.",
      "pos": [
        38155,
        38221
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log onto the server to complete installation and register it with the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        38227,
        38318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're running Windows:",
      "pos": [
        38324,
        38350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Initiate a remote desktop connection to the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        38359,
        38419
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The first time you log on a script will run in a PowerShell window.",
      "pos": [
        38420,
        38487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Don't close it.",
      "pos": [
        38488,
        38503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When it finishes the Host Agent Config tool opens automatically to register the server.",
      "pos": [
        38504,
        38591
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Host Agent Config<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> specify the internal IP address of the configuration server and port 443.",
      "pos": [
        38599,
        38697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the internal address and private port 443 even if you're not connecting over VPN because the virtual machine is attached to the same Azure network as the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        38698,
        38885
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Leave <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use HTTPS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> enabled.",
      "pos": [
        38886,
        38914
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enter the passphrase for the configuration server that you noted earlier.",
      "pos": [
        38915,
        38988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to register server.",
      "pos": [
        38989,
        39021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that you can ignore the NAT options on the page.",
      "pos": [
        39022,
        39075
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They're not used.",
      "pos": [
        39076,
        39093
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        39101,
        39387
      ],
      "content": "If your estimated retention drive requirement is more than 1 TB you can configure the retention volume (R:) using a virtual disk and <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>storage spaces<ept id=\"p1\">](http://blogs.technet.com/b/askpfeplat/archive/2013/10/21/storage-spaces-how-to-configure-storage-tiers-with-windows-server-2012-r2.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows master target server",
      "pos": [
        39399,
        39427
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're running Linux:",
      "pos": [
        39497,
        39521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure that you have installed the latest Linux Integration Services (LIS) installed before you install the Master target server software.",
      "pos": [
        39529,
        39667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can find the latest version of LIS along with instructions on how to install <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=46842)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        39668,
        39820
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restart the machine after the LIS install.",
      "pos": [
        39821,
        39863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Prepare Target(Azure) Resources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Download and Install additional software (only for Linux Master Target Server)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to download the Linux master target server package.",
      "pos": [
        39871,
        40050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the downloaded tar file to the virtual machine using an sftp client.",
      "pos": [
        40051,
        40124
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Alternatively you can log in to the deployed linux master target server and use <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>wget http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=529757&amp;clcid=0x409<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> to download the the file.",
      "pos": [
        40125,
        40295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log into the server using a Secure Shell client.",
      "pos": [
        40303,
        40351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that if you're connected to the Azure network over VPN use the internal IP address.",
      "pos": [
        40352,
        40440
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Otherwise use the external IP address and the SSH public endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        40441,
        40507
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        40515,
        40718
      ],
      "content": "Extract the files from the gzipped installer by running: **tar –xvzf Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_RHEL6-64***\n![Linux master target server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_TSLinuxTar.png)",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "    "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Extract the files from the gzipped installer by running: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>tar –xvzf Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_RHEL6-64<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>*",
          "pos": [
            0,
            105
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Linux master target server<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_TSLinuxTar.png)</ph>",
          "pos": [
            106,
            199
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure you're in the directory to which you extracted the contents of the tar file.",
      "pos": [
        40726,
        40812
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        40820,
        40936
      ],
      "content": "Copy the configuration server passphrase to a local file using the command <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>echo <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`&lt;passphrase&gt;`</ph><ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> &gt;passphrase.txt<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        40944,
        41120
      ],
      "content": "Run the command “<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sudo ./install -t both -a host -R MasterTarget -d /usr/local/ASR -i <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`&lt;Configuration server internal IP address&gt;`</ph><ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> -p 443 -s y -c https -P passphrase.txt<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>”."
    },
    {
      "content": "Register target server",
      "pos": [
        41128,
        41150
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Wait for a few minutes (10-15) and on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configuration Servers<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page check that the master target server is listed as registered on the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Server Details<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> tab.",
      "pos": [
        41216,
        41393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're running Linux and  it didn't register run the host config tool again from /usr/local/ASR/Vx/bin/hostconfigcli.",
      "pos": [
        41394,
        41514
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need to set access permissions by running chmod as root.",
      "pos": [
        41515,
        41578
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify target server",
      "pos": [
        41586,
        41606
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Please note that it can take up to 15 minutes after registration is complete for the master target server to be listed under the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        41670,
        41833
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To update immediately, refresh the configuration server by clicking on the refresh button at the bottom of the configuration servers page.",
      "pos": [
        41834,
        41972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 4: Deploy the on-premises process server",
      "pos": [
        41977,
        42022
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        42025,
        42168
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> We recommend that you configure a static IP address on the process server so that it's guaranteed to be persistent across reboots."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        42173,
        42278
      ],
      "content": "Click Quick Start &gt; <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Install Process Server on-premises<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Download and install the process server<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Install process server",
      "pos": [
        42286,
        42308
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the downloaded zip file to the server on which you're going to install the process server.",
      "pos": [
        42377,
        42472
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The zip file contains two installation files:",
      "pos": [
        42473,
        42518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft-ASR_CX_TP_8.4.0.0_Windows*",
      "pos": [
        42526,
        42562
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft-ASR_CX_8.4.0.0_Windows*",
      "pos": [
        42569,
        42602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Unzip the archive and copy the installation files to a location on the server.",
      "pos": [
        42607,
        42685
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft-ASR_CX_TP_8.4.0.0_Windows<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>* installation file and follow the instructions.",
      "pos": [
        42689,
        42784
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This installs third-party components needed for the deployment.",
      "pos": [
        42785,
        42848
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        42852,
        42899
      ],
      "content": "Then run <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft-ASR_CX_8.4.0.0_Windows<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>*."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        42903,
        42957
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Server Mode<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Process Server<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Server Selection Mode",
      "pos": [
        42965,
        42986
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        43068,
        43121
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Environment Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page do the following:"
    },
    {
      "content": "Note the following when installing VMware vCLI:",
      "pos": [
        43467,
        43514
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Only VMware vSphere CLI 5.5.0 is supported<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        43522,
        43569
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The process server doesn't work with other versions or updates of vSphere CLI.",
      "pos": [
        43570,
        43648
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        43655,
        43772
      ],
      "content": "Download vSphere CLI 5.5.0 from <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>here.<ept id=\"p1\">](https://my.vmware.com/web/vmware/details?downloadGroup=VCLI550&amp;productId=352)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "If you installed vSphere CLI just before you started installing the process server, and setup doesn't detect it, wait up to five minutes before you try setup again.",
      "pos": [
        43779,
        43943
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This ensures that all the environment variables needed for vSphere CLI detection have been initialized correctly.",
      "pos": [
        43944,
        44057
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        44063,
        44165
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>NIC Selection for Process Server<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select the network adapter that the process server should use."
    },
    {
      "content": "Select adapter",
      "pos": [
        44173,
        44187
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        44273,
        44309
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configuration Server Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "content": "For the IP address and port, if you're connecting over VPN specify the internal IP address of the configuration server and 443 for the port.",
      "pos": [
        44317,
        44457
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Otherwise specify the public virtual IP address and mapped public HTTP endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        44458,
        44538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Type in the passphrase of the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        44545,
        44596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Clear <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Verify Mobility service software signature<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> if you want to disable verification when you use automatic push to install the service.",
      "pos": [
        44603,
        44743
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Signature verification needs internet connectivity from the process server.",
      "pos": [
        44744,
        44819
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        44826,
        44841
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Register configuration server",
      "pos": [
        44849,
        44878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select Installation Drive<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select a cache drive.",
      "pos": [
        44965,
        45019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The process server needs a cache drive with at least 600 GB of free space.",
      "pos": [
        45020,
        45094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Install<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        45095,
        45118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Register configuration server",
      "pos": [
        45127,
        45156
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that you might need to restart the server to complete the installation.",
      "pos": [
        45241,
        45317
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configuration Server<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Server Details<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> check that the process server appears and is registered successfully in the vault.",
      "pos": [
        45318,
        45449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph>It can take up to 15 minutes after registration is complete for the process server to appear as listed under the configuration server.",
      "pos": [
        45452,
        45598
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To update immediately, refresh the configuration server by clicking on the refresh button at the bottom of the configuration server page",
      "pos": [
        45599,
        45735
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Validate process server",
      "pos": [
        45740,
        45763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you didn't disable signature verification for the Mobility service when you registered the process server you can do it later as follows:",
      "pos": [
        45841,
        45981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log onto the process server as an administrator and open the file C:\\pushinstallsvc\\pushinstaller.conf for editing.",
      "pos": [
        45986,
        46101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under the section <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>[PushInstaller.transport]<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> add this line: <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SignatureVerificationChecks=”0”<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        46102,
        46201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Save and close the file.",
      "pos": [
        46202,
        46226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restart the InMage PushInstall service.",
      "pos": [
        46230,
        46269
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 5: Install latest updates",
      "pos": [
        46275,
        46305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before proceeding, ensure that you have the latest updates installed.",
      "pos": [
        46307,
        46376
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remember to install the updates in the following order:",
      "pos": [
        46377,
        46432
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration server",
      "pos": [
        46437,
        46457
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Process server",
      "pos": [
        46461,
        46475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Master target server",
      "pos": [
        46479,
        46499
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can get the updates on the Site Recovery **Dashboard **.",
      "pos": [
        46501,
        46561
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For Linux installation extract the files from the gzipped installer and run the command “sudo ./install” to install the update",
      "pos": [
        46562,
        46688
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are running virtual machines or physical servers that already have the Mobility service installed, you can get updates for the service as follows:",
      "pos": [
        46690,
        46843
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Either download updates for the service as follows:",
      "pos": [
        46847,
        46898
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server (64 bit only)",
      "pos": [
        46906,
        46934
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CentOS 6.4,6.5,6.6 (64 bit only)",
      "pos": [
        47084,
        47116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Oracle Enterprise Linux 6.4,6.5 (64 bit only)",
      "pos": [
        47270,
        47315
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SUSE Linux Enterprise Server SP3 (64 bit only)",
      "pos": [
        47467,
        47513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Alternatively after updating the process server you can get the updated version of the Mobility service from the  C:\\pushinstallsvc\\repository folder on the process server.",
      "pos": [
        47667,
        47839
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have a an already protected machine with an older version of the Mobility service installed, you could also automatically upgrade the Mobility service on the protected machines from the management portal.",
      "pos": [
        47842,
        48053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, select the protection group to which the machine belongs, highlight the protected machine and click on the Update Mobility service button at the bottom.",
      "pos": [
        48054,
        48218
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Update Mobility Service button will be activated only if a newer version of the Mobility Service is available.",
      "pos": [
        48219,
        48333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please ensure that the Process server is running the latest version of the Process server software before updating the mobility service.",
      "pos": [
        48334,
        48470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The protected server needs to meet all the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>automatic push-installation prerequisites<ept id=\"p1\">](#install-the-mobility-service-automatically)</ept> in order for update mobility service to work.",
      "pos": [
        48471,
        48648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select vCenter server",
      "pos": [
        48652,
        48673
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Select accounts specify the administrator account to be used to update the mobility service on the protected server.",
      "pos": [
        48745,
        48864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click OK and wait for the triggered job to complete.",
      "pos": [
        48865,
        48917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 6: Add vCenter servers or ESXi hosts",
      "pos": [
        48923,
        48964
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        48969,
        49122
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configuration Servers<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab select the configuration server and click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>ADD VCENTER SERVER<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> to add a vCenter server or ESXi host."
    },
    {
      "content": "Select vCenter server",
      "pos": [
        49130,
        49151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify details for the vCenter server or ESXi host and select the process server that will be used to discover it.",
      "pos": [
        49221,
        49336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the vCenter server isn't running on the default 443 port specify the port number on which the vCenter server is running.",
      "pos": [
        49344,
        49467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The process server must be on the same network as the vCenter server/ESXi host and should have VMware vSphere CLI 5.5.0 installed.",
      "pos": [
        49474,
        49604
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "vCenter server settings",
      "pos": [
        49612,
        49635
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After discovery is completed the vCenter server will be listed under the configuration server details.",
      "pos": [
        49707,
        49809
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "vCenter server settings",
      "pos": [
        49817,
        49840
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're using a non-administrator account to add the vCenter server or ESXi host, make sure the account has the following privileges:",
      "pos": [
        49911,
        50046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "vCenter accounts should have Datacenter, Datastore, Folder, Host, Network, Resource, Storage views, Virtual machine and vSphere Distributed Switch privileges enabled.",
      "pos": [
        50054,
        50220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESXi host accounts should have the Datacenter, Datastore, Folder, Host, Network, Resource, Virtual machine and vSphere Distributed Switch privileges enabled",
      "pos": [
        50227,
        50383
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 7: Create a protection group",
      "pos": [
        50390,
        50423
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        50428,
        50512
      ],
      "content": "Open <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protected Items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Protection Group<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and click to add a protection group."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create protection group",
      "pos": [
        50520,
        50543
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        50612,
        50765
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify Protection Group Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page specify a name for the group and select the configuration server on which you want to create the group."
    },
    {
      "content": "Protection group settings",
      "pos": [
        50773,
        50798
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        50867,
        50999
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify Replication Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page configure the replication settings that will be used for all the machines in the group."
    },
    {
      "content": "Protection group replication",
      "pos": [
        51007,
        51035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Settings:",
      "pos": [
        51104,
        51113
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Multi VM consistency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: If you turn this on it creates shared application-consistent recovery points across the machines in the protection group.",
      "pos": [
        51120,
        51267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This setting is most relevant when all of the machines in the protection group are running the same workload.",
      "pos": [
        51268,
        51377
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All machines will be recovered to the same data point.",
      "pos": [
        51378,
        51432
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only available for Windows servers.",
      "pos": [
        51433,
        51468
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        51475,
        51614
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>RPO threshold<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Alerts will be generated when the continuous data protection replication RPO exceeds the configured RPO threshold value."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery point retention<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Specifies the retention window.",
      "pos": [
        51621,
        51682
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Protected machines can be recovered to any point within this window.",
      "pos": [
        51683,
        51751
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        51758,
        51906
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Application-consistent snapshot frequency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Specifies how frequently recovery points containing application-consistent snapshots will be created."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        51908,
        51996
      ],
      "content": "You can monitor the protection group as they're created on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protected Items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page."
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 8: Set up machines you want to protect",
      "pos": [
        52001,
        52044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need to install the Mobility service on virtual machines and physical servers you want to protect.",
      "pos": [
        52046,
        52151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can do this in two ways:",
      "pos": [
        52152,
        52180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automatically push and install the service on each machine from the process server.",
      "pos": [
        52184,
        52267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Manually install the service.",
      "pos": [
        52270,
        52299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install the Mobility service automatically",
      "pos": [
        52306,
        52348
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you add machines to a protection group the Mobility service is automatically pushed and installed on each machine by the process server.",
      "pos": [
        52350,
        52491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automatically push install the mobility service on Windows servers:",
      "pos": [
        52496,
        52563
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        52571,
        52754
      ],
      "content": "Install the latest updates for the process server as described in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Step 5: Install latest updates<ept id=\"p1\">](#step-5-install-latest-updates)</ept>, and make sure that the process server is available."
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure there's network connectivity between the source machine and the process server, and that the source machine is accessible from the process server.",
      "pos": [
        52759,
        52912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure the Windows firewall to allow <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>File and Printer Sharing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Windows Management Instrumentation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        52918,
        53030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under Windows Firewall settings, select the option “Allow an app or feature through Firewall” and select the applications as shown in the picture below.",
      "pos": [
        53031,
        53183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For machines that belong to a domain you can configure the firewall policy with a Group Policy Object.",
      "pos": [
        53184,
        53286
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Firewall settings",
      "pos": [
        53294,
        53311
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The account used to perform the push installation must be in the Administrators group on the machine you want to protect.",
      "pos": [
        53390,
        53511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These credentials are only used for push installation of the Mobility service and you'll provide them when you add a machine to a protection group.",
      "pos": [
        53512,
        53659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the provided account isn't a domain account you'll need to disable Remote User Access control on the local machine.",
      "pos": [
        53663,
        53781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this add the LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy DWORD registry entry with a value of 1 under HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Policies\\System.",
      "pos": [
        53782,
        53953
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To add the registry entry from a CLI open cmd or powershell and enter <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`REG ADD HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Policies\\System /v LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy /t REG_DWORD /d 1`</ph><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        53954,
        54166
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automatically push install the mobility service on Linux servers:",
      "pos": [
        54171,
        54236
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        54243,
        54426
      ],
      "content": "Install the latest updates for the process server as described in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Step 5: Install latest updates<ept id=\"p1\">](#step-5-install-latest-updates)</ept>, and make sure that the process server is available."
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure there's network connectivity between the source machine and the process server, and that the source machine is accessible from the process server.",
      "pos": [
        54430,
        54583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure the account is a root user on the source Linux server.",
      "pos": [
        54589,
        54653
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure that the /etc/hosts file on the source Linux server contains entries that map the local host name to IP addresses associated with all NICs.",
      "pos": [
        54657,
        54803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install the latest openssh, openssh-server, openssl packages on the machine you want to protect.",
      "pos": [
        54807,
        54903
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure SSH is enabled and running on port 22.",
      "pos": [
        54907,
        54952
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enable SFTP subsystem and password authentication in the sshd_config file as follows:",
      "pos": [
        54957,
        55042
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "a) Log in as root.",
      "pos": [
        55051,
        55069
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        55076,
        55176
      ],
      "content": "b) In the file /etc/ssh/sshd_config file, find the line that begins with <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PasswordAuthentication<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "c) Uncomment the line and change the value from “no” to “yes”.",
      "pos": [
        55183,
        55245
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linux mobility",
      "pos": [
        55257,
        55271
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "d) Find the line that begins with Subsystem and uncomment the line.",
      "pos": [
        55352,
        55419
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linux push mobility",
      "pos": [
        55435,
        55454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure the source machine Linux variant is supported.",
      "pos": [
        55534,
        55587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install the Mobility service manually",
      "pos": [
        55595,
        55632
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The software packages used to install the Mobility service are on the process server in C:\\pushinstallsvc\\repository.",
      "pos": [
        55634,
        55751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log onto the process server and copy the appropriate installation package to the source machine based on the table below:-",
      "pos": [
        55752,
        55874
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Source operating system",
      "pos": [
        55878,
        55901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Mobility service package on process server",
      "pos": [
        55934,
        55976
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server (64 bit only)",
      "pos": [
        56202,
        56230
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CentOS 6.4, 6.5, 6.6 (64 bit only)",
      "pos": [
        56359,
        56393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 11 SP3 (64 bit only)",
      "pos": [
        56516,
        56565
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Oracle Enterprise Linux 6.4, 6.5 (64 bit only)",
      "pos": [
        56673,
        56719
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        56830,
        56913
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>To install the Mobility service manually on a Windows server<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, do the following:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        56918,
        57084
      ],
      "content": "Copy the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_Windows_GA_28Jul2015_release.exe<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> package from the process server directory path listed in the table above to the source machine."
    },
    {
      "content": "Install the Mobility service by running the executable on the source machine.",
      "pos": [
        57088,
        57165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Follow the installer instructions.",
      "pos": [
        57169,
        57203
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        57207,
        57266
      ],
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Mobility service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the role and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Install mobility service",
      "pos": [
        57278,
        57302
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        57385,
        57473
      ],
      "content": "Leave the installation directory as the default installation path and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Install<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        57477,
        57568
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Host Agent Config<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> specify the IP address and HTTPS port of the configuration server."
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're connecting over the internet specify the public virtual IP address and public HTTPS endpoint as the port.",
      "pos": [
        57576,
        57691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're connecting over VPN specify the internal IP address and 443 for the port.",
      "pos": [
        57698,
        57781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Leave <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use HTTPS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> checked.",
      "pos": [
        57782,
        57810
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install mobility service",
      "pos": [
        57818,
        57842
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        57925,
        58049
      ],
      "content": "Specify the configuration server passphrase and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to register the Mobility service with the configuration server."
    },
    {
      "content": "To run from the command line:",
      "pos": [
        58053,
        58082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the passphrase from the CX to the file \"C:\\connection.passphrase\" on the server and run this command.",
      "pos": [
        58089,
        58195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In our example CX i 104.40.75.37 and the HTTPS port is 62519:",
      "pos": [
        58196,
        58257
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        58579,
        58639
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Install the Mobility service manually on a Linux server<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the appropriate tar archive based on the table above, from the process server to the source machine.",
      "pos": [
        58644,
        58749
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        58753,
        58875
      ],
      "content": "Open a shell program and extract the zipped tar archive to a local path by executing <ph id=\"ph1\">`tar -xvzf Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.2.0.0*`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        58879,
        59047
      ],
      "content": "Create a passphrase.txt file in the local directory to which you extracted the contents of the tar archive by entering <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`echo &lt;passphrase&gt; &gt;passphrase.txt`</ph><ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> from shell."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        59051,
        59212
      ],
      "content": "Install the Mobility service by entering <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">`sudo ./install -t both -a host -R Agent -d /usr/local/ASR -i &lt;IP address&gt; -p &lt;port&gt; -s y -c https -P passphrase.txt`</ph><ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify the IP address and port:",
      "pos": [
        59216,
        59248
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        59256,
        59440
      ],
      "content": "If you are connecting to the configuration server over the internet specify the configuration server virtual public IP address and public HTTPS endpoint in <ph id=\"ph1\">`&lt;IP address&gt;`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`&lt;port&gt;`</ph>."
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're connecting over a VPN connection specify the internal IP address and 443.",
      "pos": [
        59447,
        59530
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        59532,
        59565
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>To run from the command line<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the passphrase from the CX to the file \"passphrase.txt\" on the server and run this commands.",
      "pos": [
        59570,
        59667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In our example CX i 104.40.75.37 and the HTTPS port is 62519:",
      "pos": [
        59668,
        59729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To install on a production server:",
      "pos": [
        59731,
        59765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To install on the target server:",
      "pos": [
        59883,
        59915
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        60041,
        60208
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> When you add machines to a protection group that are already running an appropriate version of the Mobility service then the push installation is skipped."
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 9: Enable protection",
      "pos": [
        60214,
        60239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To enable protection you add virtual machines and physical servers to a protection group.",
      "pos": [
        60241,
        60330
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you start,note that:",
      "pos": [
        60331,
        60358
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual machines are discovered every 15 minutes and it can take up to 15 minutes for them to appear in Azure Site Recovery after discovery.",
      "pos": [
        60362,
        60502
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Environment changes on the virtual machine (such as VMware tools installation) can also take up to 15 minutes to be updated in Site Recovery.",
      "pos": [
        60505,
        60646
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        60649,
        60792
      ],
      "content": "You can check the last discovered time in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>LAST CONTACT AT<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field for the vCenter server/ESXi host on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configuration Servers<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        60795,
        61054
      ],
      "content": "If you have a protection group already created and add a vCenter Server or ESXi host after that, it takes fifteen minutes for the Azure Site Recovery portal to refresh and for virtual machines to be listed in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add machines to a protection group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        61057,
        61269
      ],
      "content": "If you would like to proceed immediately with adding machines to protection group without waiting for the scheduled discovery, highlight the configuration server (don’t click it) and click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Refresh<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button."
    },
    {
      "content": "When you add virtual machines or physical machines to a protection group, the process server automatically pushes and installs the Mobility service on the source server if the it isn't already installed.",
      "pos": [
        61272,
        61475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the automatic push mechanism to work make sure you've set up your protected machines as described in the previous step.",
      "pos": [
        61478,
        61601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add machines as follows:",
      "pos": [
        61603,
        61627
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protected Items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Protection Group<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Machines<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> tab.",
      "pos": [
        61632,
        61694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ADD MACHINES<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        61695,
        61718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a best practice we recommend that protection groups should mirror your workloads so that you add machines running a specific application to the same group.",
      "pos": [
        61719,
        61877
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> if you're protecting physical servers, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add Physical Machines<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> wizard provide the IP address and friendly name.",
      "pos": [
        61881,
        62032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then select the operating system family.",
      "pos": [
        62033,
        62073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add V-Center server",
      "pos": [
        62081,
        62100
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        62175,
        62388
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> if you're protecting VMware virtual machines, select a vCenter server that's managing your virtual machines (or the EXSi host on which they're running), and then select the machines."
    },
    {
      "content": "Add V-Center server",
      "pos": [
        62396,
        62415
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify Target Resources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select the master target servers and storage to use for replication and select whether the settings should be used for all workloads.",
      "pos": [
        62487,
        62652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Premium Storage Account<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage/storage-premium-storage-preview-portal.md)</ept> while configuring protection for workloads which require consistent high IO performance and low latency in order to host IO intensive workloads.",
      "pos": [
        62653,
        62884
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to use a Premium Storage account for your workload disks, you need to use the Master Target of DS-series.",
      "pos": [
        62885,
        63002
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot use Premium Storage disks with Master Target of non-DS-series.",
      "pos": [
        63003,
        63076
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "vCenter server",
      "pos": [
        63084,
        63098
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify Accounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select the account you want to use for installing the Mobility service on protected machines.",
      "pos": [
        63175,
        63292
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The account credentials are needed for automatic installation of the Mobility service.",
      "pos": [
        63293,
        63379
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you can't select an account make sure you set one up as described in Step 2.",
      "pos": [
        63380,
        63459
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that this account can't be accessed by Azure.",
      "pos": [
        63460,
        63510
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For Windows server the account should have administrator privileges on the source server.",
      "pos": [
        63511,
        63600
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For Linux the account must be root.",
      "pos": [
        63601,
        63636
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linux credentials",
      "pos": [
        63644,
        63661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the check mark to finish adding machines to the protection group and to start initial replication for each machine.",
      "pos": [
        63738,
        63859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can monitor status on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Jobs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.",
      "pos": [
        63860,
        63904
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add V-Center server",
      "pos": [
        63912,
        63931
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition you can monitor protection status by clicking <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protected Items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; protection group name &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> .",
      "pos": [
        63998,
        64124
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After initial replication completes and the machines are synchronizing data they will show <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protected<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> status.",
      "pos": [
        64125,
        64237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual machine jobs",
      "pos": [
        64245,
        64265
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set protected machine properties",
      "pos": [
        64333,
        64365
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After a machine has a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protected<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> status you can configure its failover properties.",
      "pos": [
        64370,
        64455
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the protection group details select the machine and open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.",
      "pos": [
        64456,
        64538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can modify the name that will be given to the machine in Azure after failover and the Azure virtual machine size.",
      "pos": [
        64542,
        64659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also select the Azure network to which the machine will be connected after failover.",
      "pos": [
        64660,
        64752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set virtual machine properties",
      "pos": [
        64760,
        64790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that:",
      "pos": [
        64859,
        64869
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name of the Azure machine must comply with Azure requirements.",
      "pos": [
        64873,
        64939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default replicated virtual machines in Azure aren't connected to an Azure network.",
      "pos": [
        64942,
        65027
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want replicated virtual machines to communicate make sure to set the same Azure network for them.",
      "pos": [
        65028,
        65132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you resize a volume on a VMware virtual machine or physical server it goes into a critical state.",
      "pos": [
        65135,
        65235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do need to modify the size, do the following:",
      "pos": [
        65236,
        65288
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "a) Change the size setting.",
      "pos": [
        65296,
        65323
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        65330,
        65414
      ],
      "content": "b) In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, select the virtual machine and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Remove<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "c) In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Remove Virtual Machine<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select the option <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Disable protection (use for recovery drill and volume resize)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        65421,
        65538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This option disables protection but retains the recovery points in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        65539,
        65612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set virtual machine properties",
      "pos": [
        65624,
        65654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "d) Reenable protection for the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        65725,
        65772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you reenable protection the data for the resized volume will be transferred to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        65773,
        65863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 10: Run a failover",
      "pos": [
        65874,
        65897
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Currently you can only run unplanned failovers for protected VMware virtual machines and physical servers.",
      "pos": [
        65899,
        66005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note the following:",
      "pos": [
        66006,
        66025
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you initiate a failover, ensure that the configuration and master target servers are running and healthy.",
      "pos": [
        66031,
        66143
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Otherwise failover will fail.",
      "pos": [
        66144,
        66173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Source machines aren't shut down as part of an unplanned failover.",
      "pos": [
        66176,
        66242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Performing an unplanned failover stops data replication for the protected servers.",
      "pos": [
        66243,
        66325
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need to delete the machines from the protection group and add them again in order to start protecting machines again after the unplanned failover completes.",
      "pos": [
        66326,
        66489
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to fail over without losing any data, make sure that the primary site virtual machines are turned off before you initiate the failover.",
      "pos": [
        66492,
        66639
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery Plans<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page and add a recovery plan.",
      "pos": [
        66644,
        66699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify details for the plan and select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the target.",
      "pos": [
        66700,
        66764
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure recovery plan",
      "pos": [
        66772,
        66795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select Virtual Machine<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select a protection group and then select machines in the group to add to the recovery plan.",
      "pos": [
        66858,
        66980
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Read more<ept id=\"p1\">](site-recovery-create-recovery-plans.md)</ept> about recovery plans.",
      "pos": [
        66981,
        67054
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add virtual machines",
      "pos": [
        67062,
        67082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If needed you can customize the plan to create groups and sequence the order in which machines in the recovery plan are failed over.",
      "pos": [
        67145,
        67277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also add prompts for manual actions and scripts.",
      "pos": [
        67278,
        67334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The scripts when recovering to Azure can be added by using <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Automation Runbooks<ept id=\"p1\">](site-recovery-runbook-automation.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        67335,
        67459
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        67464,
        67544
      ],
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery Plans<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page select the plan and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Unplanned Failover<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        67548,
        67659
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirm Failover<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> verify the failover direction (To Azure) and select the recovery point to fail over to."
    },
    {
      "content": "Wait for the failover job to complete and then verify that the failover worked as expected and that the replicated virtual machines start successfully in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        67663,
        67823
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 11: Fail back failed over machines from Azure",
      "pos": [
        67831,
        67881
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        67883,
        68038
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Learn more<ept id=\"p1\">](site-recovery-failback-azure-to-vmware.md)</ept> about how to bring your failed over machines running in Azure back to your on-premises environment."
    },
    {
      "content": "Manage your process servers",
      "pos": [
        68044,
        68071
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The process server sends replication data to the master target server in Azure, and discovers new VMware virtual machines added to a vCenter server.",
      "pos": [
        68073,
        68221
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the following circumstances you might want to change the process server in your deployment:",
      "pos": [
        68222,
        68316
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the current process server goes down",
      "pos": [
        68320,
        68359
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If your recovery point objective (RPO) rises to an unacceptable level for your organization.",
      "pos": [
        68362,
        68454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If required you can move the replication of some or all of your on-premises VMware virtual machines and physical servers to a different process server.",
      "pos": [
        68456,
        68607
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example:",
      "pos": [
        68608,
        68620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Failure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—If a process server fails or isn't available you can move protected machine replication to another process server.",
      "pos": [
        68624,
        68750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Metadata of the source machine and replica machine will be moved to the new process server and data is resynchronized.",
      "pos": [
        68751,
        68869
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The new process server will automatically connect to the vCenter server to perform automatic discovery.",
      "pos": [
        68870,
        68973
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can monitor the state of process servers on the Site Recovery dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        68974,
        69050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Load balancing to adjust RPO<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—For improved load balancing you can select a different process server in the Site Recovery portal, and move replication of one or more machines to it for manual load balancing.",
      "pos": [
        69053,
        69262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case metadata of the selected source and replica machines is moved to the new process server.",
      "pos": [
        69263,
        69364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The original process server remains connected to the vCenter server.",
      "pos": [
        69365,
        69433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitor the process server",
      "pos": [
        69440,
        69466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a process server is in a critical state a status warning will be displayed on the Site Recovery Dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        69468,
        69577
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can click on the status to open the Events tab and then drill down to specific jobs on the Jobs tab.",
      "pos": [
        69578,
        69682
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Modify the process server used for replication",
      "pos": [
        69689,
        69735
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        69740,
        69798
      ],
      "content": "Go to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CONFIGURATION SERVERS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page under <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SERVERS<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        69802,
        69877
      ],
      "content": "Click on the name of the Configuration Server and go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Server Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        69881,
        70077
      ],
      "content": "In the **Process Servers** list click **Change Process Server** next to the server you want to modify.\n ![Change Process Server 1](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMware_ChangePS1.png)",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "   "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Process Servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> list click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Change Process Server<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> next to the server you want to modify.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            102
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\"> ![</ph>Change Process Server 1<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMware_ChangePS1.png)</ph>",
          "pos": [
            103,
            193
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        70081,
        70619
      ],
      "content": "In the **Change Process Server** dialog select the new server in **Target Process Server**, and then select the virtual machines that you want to replicate to the new server. click the information icon next to the server name to get information about it, including free space, used memory. The average space that will be required to replicate each selected virtual machine to the new process server is displayed to help you make load decisions.\n ![Change Process Server 2](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMware_ChangePS2.png)",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "   "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "In the **Change Process Server** dialog select the new server in **Target Process Server**, and then select the virtual machines that you want to replicate to the new server. click the information icon next to the server name to get information about it, including free space, used memory. The average space that will be required to replicate each selected virtual machine to the new process server is displayed to help you make load decisions.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            444
          ],
          "nodes": [
            {
              "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change Process Server<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog select the new server in <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Target Process Server<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then select the virtual machines that you want to replicate to the new server.",
              "pos": [
                0,
                174
              ]
            },
            {
              "content": "click the information icon next to the server name to get information about it, including free space, used memory.",
              "pos": [
                175,
                289
              ]
            },
            {
              "content": "The average space that will be required to replicate each selected virtual machine to the new process server is displayed to help you make load decisions.",
              "pos": [
                290,
                444
              ]
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\"> ![</ph>Change Process Server 2<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMware_ChangePS2.png)</ph>",
          "pos": [
            445,
            535
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the check mark to begin replicating to the new process server.",
      "pos": [
        70623,
        70691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you remove all virtual machines from a process server that was critical it should no longer display a critical warning in the dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        70692,
        70831
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Third-party software notices and information",
      "pos": [
        70837,
        70881
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Do Not Translate or Localize",
      "pos": [
        70883,
        70911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The software and firmware running in the Microsoft product or service is based on or incorporates material from the projects listed below (collectively, “Third Party Code”).",
      "pos": [
        70913,
        71086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft is the not original author of the Third Party Code.",
      "pos": [
        71088,
        71149
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The original copyright notice and license, under which Microsoft received such Third Party Code, are set forth below.",
      "pos": [
        71151,
        71268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The information in Section A is regarding Third Party Code components from the projects listed below.",
      "pos": [
        71270,
        71371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Such licenses and information are provided for informational purposes only.",
      "pos": [
        71372,
        71447
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This Third Party Code is being relicensed to you by Microsoft under Microsoft's software licensing terms for the Microsoft product or service.",
      "pos": [
        71449,
        71591
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The information in Section B is regarding Third Party Code components that are being made available to you by Microsoft under the original licensing terms.",
      "pos": [
        71595,
        71750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The complete file may be found on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Download Center<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=529428)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        71752,
        71865
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft reserves all rights not expressly granted herein, whether by implication, estoppel or otherwise.",
      "pos": [
        71866,
        71972
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Set up protection between on-premises VMware virtual machines or physical servers and Azure\" \n    description=\"Describes up Azure Site Recovery to coordinate the replication, failover and recovery of on-premises VMware virtual machines or Windows/Linux physical servers to Azure.\" \n    services=\"site-recovery\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"rayne-wiselman\"\n    manager=\"jwhit\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"site-recovery\"\n    ms.workload=\"backup-recovery\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"08/04/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"raynew\"/>\n\n# Set up protection between on-premises VMware virtual machines or physical servers and Azure\n\nThis article describes how to deploy Site Recovery to:\n\n- **Protect VMware virtual machines**—Coordinate replication, failover, and recovery of on-premises VMware virtual machines to Azure\n- **Protect physical servers**—Coordinate replication, failover, and recovery of on-premises physical Windows and Linux servers to Azure using the Azure Site Recovery service.\n\nThe article includes an overview, deployment prerequisites, and set up instructions. At the end of the article your VMware virtual machines or physical servers will be replicating to Azure.\nIf you run into problems, post your questions on the [Azure Recovery Services Forum](https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/forums/azure/home?forum=hypervrecovmgr).\n\n\n## What is Azure Site Recovery?\n\nThe Azure Site Recovery contributes to your business continuity and disaster recovery (BCDR) strategy by orchestrating replication, failover and recovery of virtual machines and physical servers. Machines can be replicated to Azure, or to a secondary on-premises data center. Read more about [Azure Site Recovery](site-recovery-overview.md).\n\n## How does it protect on-premises resources?\n\nSite Recovery helps protect your on-premises resources by orchestrating, simplifying replication, failover and failback in a number of [deployment scenarios](site-recovery-overview.md). If you want to protect your on-premises VMware virtual machines or Windows or Linux physical servers here's how Site Recovery can help:\n\n- Allows VMware users to replicate virtual machines to Azure.\n- Allows the replication of physical on-premises servers to Azure.\n- Provides a single location to setup and manage replication, failover, and recovery.\n- Provides easy failover from your on-premises infrastructure to Azure, and failback (restore) from Azure to on-premises.\n- Implements recovery plans for easy failover of workloads that are tiered over multiple machines.\n- Provides multi VM consistency so that virtual machines and physical servers running specific workloads can be recovered together to a consistent data point.\n- Supports data replication over the Internet, over a site-to-site VPN connection, or over Azure ExpressRoute.\n- Provides automated discovery of VMware virtual machines.\n\n\n## What do I need?\n\nThis diagram shows the deployment components.\n\n![New vault](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_Arch.png)\n\nHere's what you'll need:\n\n**Component** | **Deployment** | **Details**\n--- | --- | ---\n**Configuration server** | <p>Deploy as a Azure standard A3 virtual machine in the same subscription as Site Recovery.</p> <p>You set up in the Site Recovery portal</p> | This server coordinates communication between protected machines, the process server, and master target servers in Azure. It sets up replication and coordinates recovery in Azure when failover occurs.\n**Master target server** | <p>Deploy as Azure virtual machine — Either a Windows server based on a Windows Server 2012 R2 gallery image (to protect Windows machines) or as a Linux server based on a OpenLogic CentOS 6.6 gallery image (to protect Linux machines).</p> <p>Three sizing options are available – Standard A4, Standard D14 and Standard DS4.<p><p>The server is connected to the same Azure network as the configuration server.</p><p>You set up in the Site Recovery portal</p> | <p>It receives and retains replicated data from your protected machines using attached VHDs created on blob storage in your Azure storage account.</p> <p>Select Standard DS4 specifically for configuring protection for workloads requiring consistent high performance and low latency using Premium Storage Account.</p>\n**Process server** | <p>Deploy as an on-premises virtual or physical server running Windows Server 2012 R2</p> <p>We recommend it's placed on the same network and LAN segment as the machines that you want to protect, but it can run on a different network as long as protected machines have L3 network visibility to it.<p>You set it up and register it to the configuration server in the Site Recovery portal.</p> | <p>Protected machines send replication data to the on-premises process server. It has a disk-based cache to cache replication data that it receives. It performs a number of actions on that data.</p><p>It optimizes data by caching, compressing, and encrypting it before sending it on to the master target server.</p><p>It handles push installation of the Mobility Service.</p><p>It performs automatic discovery of VMware virtual machines.</p>\n**On-premises machines** | On-premises virtual  machines running on a VMware hypervisor, or physical servers running Windows or Linux. | You set up replication settings that apply to virtual machines and servers. You can fail over an individual machine or more commonly, as part of a recovery plan containing multiple virtual machines that fail over together.\n**Mobility service** | <p>Installs on each virtual machine or physical server you want to protect</p><p>Can be installed manually or pushed and installed automatically by the process server when protection is enabled for the server. | The Mobility service send data to the Process Server as part of initial replication (resync.) Once the server reaches a protected state(after resync is completed) the Mobility service performs an in-memory capture of writes to disk and sends it to the Process Server. Application consistency for Windows servers is achieved using the VSS framework.\n**Azure Site Recovery vault** | Set up after you've subscribed to the Site Recovery service. | You register servers in a Site Recovery vault. The vault coordinates and orchestrates data replication, failover, and recovery between your on-premises site and Azure.\n**Replication mechanism** | <p>**Over the Internet**—Communicates and replicates data from protected on-premises servers and Azure using a secure SSL/TLS communication channel over a public internet connection. This is the default option.</p><p>**VPN/ExpressRoute**—Communicates and replicates data between on-premises servers and Azure over a VPN connection. You'll need to set up a site-to-site VPN or an [ExpressRoute](../expressroute-introduction.md) connection between the on-premises site and your Azure network.</p><p>You'll select how you want to replicate during Site Recovery deployment. You can't change the mechanism after it's configured without impacting protection on already protected servers.| <p>Neither option requires you to open any inbound network ports on protected machines. All network communication is initiated from the on-premises site.</p> \n\nYou can learn more about Site Recovery components, Providers and agents in [Site Recovery Components](site-recovery-components.md).\n\n## Capacity planning\n\nMain areas for considerations are:\n\n- **Source environment**—The VMware infrastructure, source machine settings and requirements.\n- **Component servers**—The process server, configuration server, and master target server \n\n### Considerations for the source environment\n\n- **Maximum disk size**—The current maximum size of the disk that can be attached to a virtual machine is 1 TB. Thus the maximum size of a source disk that can be replicated is also limited to 1 TB.\n- **Maximum size per source**—The maximum size of a single source machine is 31 TB (with 31 disks) and with a D14 instance provisioned for the master target server. \n- **Number of sources per master target server**—Multiple source machines can be protected with a single master target server. However, a single source machine can’t be protected across multiple master target servers, because as disks replicate, a VHD that mirrors the size of the disk is created on Azure blob storage and attached as a data disk to the master target server.  \n- **Maximum daily change rate per source**—There are three factors that need to be considered when considering the recommended change rate per source. For the target based considerations two IOPS are required on the target disk for each operation on the source. This is because a read of old data and a write of the new data will happen on the target disk. \n    - **Daily change rate supported by the process server**—A source machine can't span multiple process servers. A single process server can support up to 1 TB of daily change rate. Hence 1 TB is the maximum daily data change rate supported for a source machine. \n    - **Maximum throughput supported by the target disk**—Maximum churn per source disk can't be more than 144 GB/day (with 8K write size). See the table in the master target section for the throughput and IOPs of the target for various write sizes. This number must be divided by two because each source IOP generates 2 IOPS on the target disk. Refer [Scalability and Performance Targets when using Premium Storage](../storage/storage-scalability-targets.md#scalability-targets-for-premium-storage-accounts) while configuring target for Premium Storage account.\n    - **Maximum throughput supported by the storage account**—A source can't span multiple storage accounts. Given that a storage account takes a maximum of 20,000 requests per second and that each source IOP generates 2 IOPS at the master target server, we recommend you keep the number of IOPS across the source to 10,000. Refer [Scalability and Performance Targets when using Premium Storage](../storage/storage-scalability-targets.md#scalability-targets-for-premium-storage-accounts) while configuring source for Premium Storage account.\n\n### Considerations for component servers\n\nTable 1 summarizes the virtual machine sizes for the configuration and master target servers.\n\n**Component** | **Deployed Azure instances** | **Cores** | **Memory** | **Max disks** | **Disk size**\n--- | --- | --- | --- | --- | ---\nConfiguration server | Standard A3 | 4 | 7 GB | 8 | 1023 GB\nMaster target server | Standard A4 | 8 | 14 GB | 16 | 1023 GB\n | Standard D14 | 16 | 112 GB | 32 | 1023 GB\n | Standard DS4 | 8 | 28 GB | 16 | 1023 GB\n\n**Table 1**\n\n#### Process server considerations\n\nGenerally process server sizing depends on the daily change rate across all protected workloads. Primary considerations include:\n\n-   You need sufficient compute to perform tasks such as inline compression and encryption.\n-   Process server uses disk based cache. Make sure the recommended cache space and disk throughput is available to facilitate the data changes stored in the event of network bottleneck or outage. \n-   Ensure sufficient bandwidth  so that the process server can upload the data to the master target server to provide continuous data protection. \n\nTable 2 provides a summary of the process server guidelines.\n\n**Data change rate** | **CPU** | **Memory** | **Cache disk size**| **Cache disk throughput** | **Bandwidth ingress/egress**\n--- | --- | --- | --- | --- | ---\n< 300 GB | 4 vCPUs (2 sockets * 2 cores @ 2.5GHz) | 4 GB | 600 GB | 7 to 10 MB per second | 30 Mbps/21 Mbps\n300 to 600 GB | 8 vCPUs (2 sockets * 4 cores @ 2.5GHz) | 6 GB | 600 GB | 11 to 15 MB per second | 60 Mbps/42 Mbps\n600 GB to 1 TB | 12 vCPUs (2 sockets * 6 cores @ 2.5GHz) | 8 GB | 600 GB | 16 to 20 MB per second | 100 Mbps/70 Mbps\n> 1 TB | Deploy another process server | | | | \n\n**Table 2**\n\nWhere: \n\n- Ingress is download bandwidth (intranet between the source and process server).\n- Egress is upload bandwidth (internet between the process server and master target server). Egress numbers presume average 30% process server compression.\n- For cache disk a separate OS disk of minimum 128 GB is recommended for all process servers.\n- For cache disk throughput the following storage was used for benchmarking: 8 SAS drives of 10 K RPM with RAID 10 configuration.\n\n#### Configuration server considerations\n\nEach configuration server can support up to 100 source machines with 3-4 volumes. If these numbers are exceeded we recommend you deploy another configuration server. See Table 1 for the default virtual machine properties of the configuration server. \n\n#### Master target server and storage account considerations\n\nThe storage for each master target server is comprised of an OS disk, a retention volume, and data disks. The retention drive maintains the journal of disk changes for the duration of the retention window defined in the Site Recovery portal.  Refer to Table 1 for the virtual machine properties of the master target server. Table 3 shows how the disks of A4 are used.\n\n**Instance** | **OS disk** | **Retention** | **Data disks**\n--- | --- | --- | ---\n | | **Retention** | **Data disks**\nStandard A4 | 1 disk (1 * 1023 GB) | 1 disk ( 1 * 1023 GB) | 15 disks (15 * 1023 GB)\nStandard D14 |  1 disk (1 * 1023 GB) | 1 disk ( 1 * 1023 GB) | 31 disks (15 * 1023 GB)\nStandard DS4 |  1 disk (1 * 1023 GB) | 1 disk ( 1 * 1023 GB) | 15 disks (15 * 1023 GB)\n\n**Table 3**\n\nCapacity planning for the master target server depends on:\n\n- Azure storage performance and limitations\n    - The maximum number of highly utilized disks for a Standard Tier VM, is about 40 (20,000/500 IOPS per disk) in a single storage account. Refer [Scalability Targets for Standard Storage Accounts](../storage/storage-scalability-targets.md#scalability-targets-for-standard-storage-accounts) for more information. Similarly refer [Scalability Targets for Premium Storage Accounts](../storage/storage-scalability-targets.md#scalability-targets-for-premium-storage-accounts) for more information about Premium Storage account.\n-   Daily change rate \n-   Retention volume storage.\n\nNote that:\n\n- One source can't span multiple storage accounts. This applies to the data disk that go to the storage accounts selected when you configure protection. The OS and the retention disks usually go to the automatically deployed storage account.\n- The retention storage volume required depends on the daily change rate and the number of retention days. The retention storage required per master target server = total churn from source per day * number of retention days. \n- Each master target server has only one retention volume. The retention volume is shared across the disks attached to the master target server. For example:\n    - If there's a source machine with 5 disks and each disk generates 120 IOPS (8K size) on the source, this translates to 240 IOPS per disk (2 operations on the target disk per source IO). 240 IOPS is within the Azure per disk IOPS limit of 500.\n    - On the retention volume, this becomes 120 * 5 = 600 IOPS and this can become a bottle neck. In this scenario, a good strategy would be to add more disks to the retention volume and span it across, as a RAID stripe configuration. This will improve performance because the IOPS are distributed across multiple drives. The number of drives to be added to the retention volume will be as follows:\n        - Total IOPS from source environment / 500\n        - Total churn per day from source environment (uncompressed) / 287 GB. 287 GB is the maximum throughput supported by a target disk per day. This metric will vary based on the write size with a factor of 8K, because in this case 8K is thee assumed write size. For example, if the write size is 4K then throughput will be 287/2. And if the write size is 16K then throughput will be 287*2.\n- The number of storage accounts required = total source IOPs/10000.\n\n\n## Before you start\n\n**Component** | **Requirements** | **Details**\n--- | --- | --- \n**Azure account** | You'll need a [Microsoft Azure](http://azure.microsoft.com/) account. You can start with a [free trial](pricing/free-trial/).\n**Azure storage** | <p>You'll need an Azure storage account to store replicated data</p><p>Either the account should be a [Standard Geo-redundant Storage Account](../storage/storage-redundancy.md#geo-redundant-storage) or [Premium Storage Account](../storage/storage-premium-storage-preview-portal.md).</p><p>It must in the same region as the Azure Site Recovery service, and be associated with the same subscription.</p><p>To learn more read [Introduction to Microsoft Azure Storage](../storage/storage-introduction.md)</p>\n**Azure virtual network** | You'll need an Azure virtual network on which the configuration server and master target server will be deployed. It should be in the same subscription and region as the Azure Site Recovery vault. If you wish to replicate data over an ExpressRoute or VPN connection the Azure virtual network must be connected to your on-premises network over an ExpressRoute connection or a Site-to-Site VPN.\n**Azure resources** | Make sure you have enough Azure resources to deploy all components. Read more in [Azure Subscription Limits](../azure-subscription-service-limits.md).\n**Azure virtual machines** | <p>Virtual machines you want to protect should conform with [Azure prerequisites](site-recovery-best-practices.md).</p><p>**Disk count**—A maximum of 31 disks can be supported on a single protected server</p><p>**Disk sizes**—Individual disk capacity shouldn't be more than 1023 GB</p><p>**Clustering**—Clustered servers aren't supported</p><p>**Boot**—Unified Extensible Firmware Interface(UEFI)/Extensible Firmware Interface(EFI) boot isn't supported</p><p>**Volumes**—Bitlocker encrypted volumes aren't supported</p><p> **Server names**—Names should contain between 1 and 63 characters (letters, numbers and hyphens). The name must start with a letter or number and end with a letter or number. After a machine is protected you can modify the Azure name.</p>\n**Configuration server** | <p>Standard A3 virtual machine based on an Azure Site Recovery Windows Server 2012 R2 gallery image will be created in your subscription for the configuration server. It's created as the first instance in a new cloud service. If you select Public Internet as the connectivity type for the Configuration Server the cloud service will be created with a reserved public IP address.</p><p>The installation path should be in English characters only.</p>\n**Master target server** | <p>Azure virtual machine, standard A4, D14 or DS4.</p><p>The installation path  should be in English characters only. For example the path should be **/usr/local/ASR** for a master target server running Linux.</p></p>\n**Process server** | <p>You can deploy the process server on physical or virtual machine running Windows Server 2012 R2 with the latest updates. Install on C:/.</p><p>We recommend you place the server on the same network and subnet as the machines you want to protect.</p><p>Install VMware vSphere CLI 5.5.0 on the process server. The VMware vSphere CLI component is required on the process server in order to discover virtual machines managed by a vCenter server or virtual machines running on an ESXi host.</p><p>The installation path should be in English characters only.</p>\n**VMware** | <p>A VMware vCenter server managing your VMware vSphere hypervisors. It should be running vCenter version 5.1 or 5.5 with the latest updates.</p><p>One or more vSphere hypervisors containing VMware virtual machines you want to protect. The hypervisor should be running ESX/ESXi version 5.1 or 5.5 with the latest updates.</p><p>VMware virtual machines should have VMware tools installed and running.</p>\n**Windows machines** | <p>Protected physical servers or VMware virtual machines running Windows have a number of requirements.</p><p>A supported 64-bit operating system: **Windows Server 2012 R2**, **Windows Server 2012**, or **Windows Server 2008 R2 with at least SP1**.</p><p>The host name, mount points, device names, Windows system path (eg: C:\\Windows) should be in English only.</p><p>The operating system should be installed on C:\\ drive.</p><p>Only basic disks are supported. Dynamic disks aren't supported.</p><p><Firewall rules on protected machines should allow them to reach the configuration and master target servers in Azure.p><p>You'll need to provide an administrator account (must be a local administrator on the Windows machine) to push install the Mobility Service on Windows servers. If the provided account is a non-domain account you'll need to disable Remote User Access control on the local machine. To do this add the LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy DWORD registry entry with a value of 1 under HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Policies\\System. To add the registry entry from a CLI open cmd or powershell and enter **`REG ADD HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Policies\\System /v LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy /t REG_DWORD /d 1`**. [Learn more](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/aa826699.aspx) about access control.</p><p>After failover, if you want connect to Windows virtual machines in Azure with Remote Desktop make sure that Remote Desktop is enabled for the on-premises machine. If you're not connecting over VPN, firewall rules should allow Remote Desktop connections over the internet.</p>\n**Linux machines** | <p> A supported 64 bit operating system: **Centos 6.4, 6.5, 6.6**; **Oracle Enterprise Linux 6.4, 6.5 running either the Red Hat compatible kernel or Unbreakable Enterprise Kernel Release 3 (UEK3)**, **SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 11 SP3**.</p><p>Firewall rules on protected machines should allow them to reach the configuration and master target servers in Azure.</p><p>/etc/hosts files on protected machines should  contain entries that map the local host name to IP addresses associated with all NICs </p><p>If you want to connect to an Azure virtual machine running Linux after failover using a Secure Shell client (ssh), ensure that the Secure Shell service on the protected machine is set to start automatically on system boot, and that firewall rules allow an ssh connection to it.</p><p>The host name, mount points, device names, and Linux system paths and file names (eg /etc/; /usr) should be in English only.</p><p>Protection can be enabled for on-premises machines with the following storage:-<br>File system: EXT3, ETX4, ReiserFS, XFS<br>Multipath software-Device Mapper (multipath)<br>Volume manager: LVM2<br>Physical servers with HP CCISS controller storage are not supported.</p>\n**Third-party** | Some deployment components in this scenario depend on third-party software to function properly. For a complete list see [Third-party software notices and information](#third-party)\n\n## Deployment\n\nThe graphic summarizes the deployment steps.\n\n![Deployment steps](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/VMWare2AzureSteps.png)\n\n## Network connectivity Type\n\nYou have two options to configure network connectivity between your on-premises site and the Azure virtual network on which your Infrastructure components (Configuration Server, Master target Servers) are deployed. You'll need to decide which network connectivity option to use before you can deploy your Configuration Server. This is a deployment time choice, and cannot be changed later.\n\n**Public Internet :** Communication and replication of data between the on-premises servers (Process Server, Protected Servers) and the Azure Infrastructure component servers (Configuration Server, Master Target Server) happens over a secure SSL/TLS connection from on-premises to the Public endpoints on the Configuration Server and the Master Target server. (The only exception is the connection between the Process Server and the Master Target server on TCP port 9080 which is un-encrypted. Only control information related to the replication protocol related used to setup the replication is exchanged on this connection.)\n\n![Deployment diagram internet](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVmware_deploymentInternet.png)\n\n**VPN :** Communication and replication of data between the on-premises servers (Process Server, Protected Servers) and the Azure Infrastructure component servers (Configuration Server, Master Target Server) happens over a VPN connection between your on-premises network and the Azure virtual network on which the Configuration server and Master Target servers are deployed. Ensure that your on-premises network is connected to the Azure virtual network by an ExpressRoute connection or a site-to-site VPN connection.\n\n![Deployment diagram VPN](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVmware_deploymentVPN.png)\n\n\n## Step 1: Create a vault\n\n1. Sign in to the [Management Portal](https://portal.azure.com).\n\n\n2. Expand **Data Services** > **Recovery Services** and click **Site Recovery Vault**.\n\n\n3. Click **Create New** > **Quick Create**.\n\n4. In **Name**, enter a friendly name to identify the vault.\n\n5. In **Region**, select the geographic region for the vault. To check supported regions see Geographic Availability in [Azure Site Recovery Pricing Details](pricing/details/site-recovery/)\n\n6. Click **Create vault**.\n\n    ![New vault](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_CreateVault.png)\n\nCheck the status bar to confirm that the vault was successfully created. The vault will be listed as **Active** on the main **Recovery Services** page.\n\n## Step 2: Deploy a configuration server\n\n### Configure server settings\n\n1. In the **Recovery Services** page, click the vault to open the Quick Start page. Quick Start can also be opened at any time using the icon.\n\n    ![Quick Start Icon](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_QuickStartIcon.png)\n\n2. In the dropdown list, select **Between an on-premises site with VMware/physical servers and Azure**.\n3. In **Prepare Target(Azure) Resources** click **Deploy Configuration Server**.\n\n    ![Deploy configuration server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_DeployCS2.png)\n\n4. In **New Configuration Server Details** specify:\n\n    - A name for the configuration server and credentials to connect to it.\n    - In the network connectivity type drop down select Public Internet or VPN.\n    [AZURE.NOTE] This setting is a deployment time choice you make and cannot be changed later.  \n    - Select the Azure network on which the server should be located. If you specified VPN as the network connectivity type ensure that this Azure vnet is connected to your on-premises site over an ExpressRoute connection or a site-to-site VPN.\n    - Specify the internal IP address and subnet to assign to the server. Note that the first four IP addresses in any subnet are reserved for internal Azure usage. Use any other available IP address.\n    \n    ![Deploy configuration server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMware_CSDetails2.png)\n\n5. When you click **OK** a standard A3 virtual machine based on an Azure Site Recovery Windows Server 2012 R2 gallery image will be created in your subscription for the configuration server. It's created as the first instance in a new cloud service. If you specified the network connectivity type to be Public Internet the cloud service is created with a reserved public IP address. You can monitor progress in the **Jobs** tab.\n\n    ![Monitor progress](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_MonitorConfigServer.png)\n\n6.  **This step is applicable only if your connectivity type is Public Internet.** After the configuration server is deployed note the public IP address assigned to it on the **Virtual Machines** page in the Azure portal. Then on the **Endpoints** tab note the public HTTPS port mapped to private port 443. You'll need this information later when you register the master target and process servers with the configuration server. The configuration server is deployed with these endpoints:\n\n    - HTTPS: Public port is used to coordinate communication between component servers and Azure over the internet. Private port 443 is used to coordinate communication between component servers and Azure over VPN.\n    - Custom: Public port is used for failback tool communication over the inter\n    - net. Private port 9443 is used for failback tool communication over VPN.\n    - PowerShell: Private port 5986\n    - Remote desktop: Private port 3389\n    \n    ![VM endpoints](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_VMEndpoints.png)\n\n    >[AZURE.WARNING] Don't delete or change the public or private port number of any of the endpoints created during configuration server deployment.\n\nThe configuration server is deployed in an automatically created Azure cloud service with a reserved IP address. The reserved address is needed to ensure that the Configuration Server cloud service IP address remains the same across reboots of the virtual machines (including the configuration server) on the cloud service. The reserved public IP address will need to be manually unreserved when the configuration server is decommissioned or it'll remain reserved. There's a default limit of 20 reserved public IP addresses per subscription. [Find out more](../virtual-network/virtual-networks-reserved-private-ip.md) about reserved IP addresses. \n\n### Register the configuration server in the vault\n\n1. In the **Quick Start** page click **Prepare Target Resources** > **Download a registration key**. The key file is generated automatically. It's valid for 5 days after it's generated. Copy it to the configuration server.\n2. In **Virtual Machines** select the configuration server from the virtual machines list. Open the **Dashboard** tab and click **Connect**. **Open** the downloaded RDP file to log onto the configuration server using Remote Desktop. If your Configuration server is deployed on a VPN network, use the internal IP address (this is the IP address you specified when you deployed the configuration server and can also be seen on the virtual machines dashboard page for the configuration server virtual machine) of the configuration server to Remote desktop to it from your on-premises network. The Azure Site Recovery Configuration Server Setup Wizard runs automatically when you log on for the first time.\n\n    ![Registration](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RegistrationSplashscreen.png)\n\n3. In **Third-Party Software Installation** click **I Accept** to download and install MySQL.\n\n    ![MySQL install](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RegistrationMySQLEULA.png)\n\n4. In **MySQL Server Details** create credentials to log onto the MySQL server instance.\n\n    ![MySQL credentials](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RegistrationMySQLPWD.png)\n\n5. In **Internet Settings** specify how the configuration server will connect to the internet. Note that:\n\n    - If you want to use a custom proxy you should set it up before you install the Provider.\n    - When you click **Next** a test will run to check the proxy connection.\n    - If you do use a custom proxy, or your default proxy requires authentication you'll need to enter the proxy details, including the address, port, and credentials.\n    - The following URLs should be accessible via the proxy:\n        - *.hypervrecoverymanager.windowsazure.com\n        - *.accesscontrol.windows.net\n        - *.backup.windowsazure.com\n        - *.blob.core.windows.net\n        - *.store.core.windows.net\n    - If you have IP address-based firewall rules ensure that the rules are set to allow communication from the configuration server to the IP addresses described in [Azure Datacenter IP Ranges](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/azure/dn175718.aspx) and HTTPS (443) protocol. You would have to white-list IP ranges of the Azure region that you plan to use, and that of West US.\n\n    ![Proxy registration](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RegistrationProxy.png)\n\n6. In **Provider Error Message Localization Settings** specify in which language you want error messages to appear.\n\n    ![Error message registration](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RegistrationLocale.png)\n\n7. In **Azure Site Recovery Registration** browse and select the key file you copied to the server.\n\n    ![Key file registration](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RegistrationVault.png)\n\n8. On the completion page of the wizard select these options:\n\n    - Select **Launch Account Management Dialog** to specify that the Manage Accounts dialog should open after you finish the wizard.\n    - Select **Create a desktop icon for Cspsconfigtool** to add a desktop shortcut on the  configuration server so that you can open the **Manage Accounts** dialog at any time without needing to rerun the wizard.\n\n    ![Complete registration](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RegistrationFinal.png)\n\n9. Click **Finish** to complete the wizard. A passphrase is generated. Copy it to a secure location. You'll need it to authenticate and register the process and master target servers with the configuration server. It's also used to ensure channel integrity in configuration server communications. You can regenerate the passphrase but then you'll need to re-register the master target and process servers using the new passphrase.\n\n    ![Passphrase](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/passphrase.png)\n\nAfter registration the configuration server will be listed on the **Configuration Servers** page in the vault.\n\n### Set up and manage accounts\n\nDuring deployment Site Recovery requests credentials for the following actions:\n\n- When you add a vCenter server for automated discovery of virtual machines managed by the vCenter server. A vCenter account is required for automated discovery of virtual machines.\n- When you add machines for protection, so that Site Recovery can install the Mobility service on them.\n\nAfter you've registered the configuration server you can open the **Manage Accounts** dialog to add and manage accounts that should be used for these actions. There are a couple of ways to do this:\n\n- Open the shortcut you opted to created for the dialog on the last page of setup for the configuration server (cspsconfigtool).\n- Open the dialog on finish of configuration server setup.\n\n1. In **Manage Accounts** click **Add Account**. You can also modify and delete existing accounts.\n\n    ![Manage accounts](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_ManageAccount.png)\n\n2. In **Account Details** specify an account name to use in Azure and credentials (Domain/user name). \n\n    ![Manage accounts](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_AccountDetails.png)\n\n### Connect to the configuration server \n\nThere are two ways to connect to the configuration server:\n\n- Over a VPN site-to-site or ExpressRoute connection\n- Over the internet \n\nNote that:\n\n- An internet connection uses the endpoints of the virtual machine in conjunction with the public virtual IP address of the server.\n- A VPN connection uses the internal IP address of the server together with the endpoint private ports.\n- It's a one-time decision to decide whether to connect (control and replication data) from your on-premises servers to the various component servers (configuration server, master target server) running in Azure over a VPN connection or the internet. You can't change this setting afterwards. If you do you'll need to redeploy the scenario and reprotect your machines.  \n\n\n## Step 3: Deploy the master target server\n\n1. In **Prepare Target(Azure) Resources**, click **Deploy master target server**.\n2. Specify the master target server details and credentials. The server will be deployed in the same Azure network as the configuration server you register it to. When you click to complete an Azure virtual machine will be created with a Windows or Linux gallery image.\n\n    ![Target server settings](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_TSDetails.png)\n\nNote that the first four IP addresses in any subnet are reserved for internal Azure usage. Specify any other available IP address.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] Select Standard DS4 when configuring protection for workloads which require consistent high IO performance and low latency in order to host IO intensive workloads using [Premium Storage Account](../storage/storage-premium-storage-preview-portal.md).\n\n\n3. A Windows master target server virtual machine is created with these endpoints (Public endpoints are created only if your deployment type is Public Internet):\n\n    - Custom: Public port is used by the process server to send replication data over the internet. Private port 9443 is used by the process server to send replication data to the master target server over VPN.\n    - Custom1: Public port is used by the process server to send control meta-data over the internet. Private port 9080 is used by process server to send control meta-data to the master target server over VPN.\n    - PowerShell: Private port 5986\n    - Remote desktop: Private port 3389\n\n4. A Linux master target server virtual machine is created with these endpoints (Public endpoints are created only if your deployment type is Public Internet):\n\n    - Custom: Public port is used by the process server to send replication data over the internet. Private port 9443 is used by the process server to send replication data to the master target server over VPN.\n    - Custom1: Public port is used by the process server to send control meta-data over the internet. Private port 9080 is used by the process server to send control data to the master target server over VPN\n    - SSH: Private port 22\n\n    >[AZURE.WARNING] Don't delete or change the public or private port number of any of the endpoints created during the master target server deployment.\n\n5. In **Virtual Machines** wait for the virtual machine to start.\n\n    - If you've configured the server with Windows note down the remote desktop details.\n    - If you configured with Linux and you're connecting over VPN note the internal IP address of the virtual machine. If you're connecting over the internet note the public IP address.\n\n6.  Log onto the server to complete installation and register it with the configuration server. \n7.  If you're running Windows:\n\n    1. Initiate a remote desktop connection to the virtual machine. The first time you log on a script will run in a PowerShell window. Don't close it. When it finishes the Host Agent Config tool opens automatically to register the server.\n    2. In **Host Agent Config** specify the internal IP address of the configuration server and port 443. You can use the internal address and private port 443 even if you're not connecting over VPN because the virtual machine is attached to the same Azure network as the configuration server. Leave **Use HTTPS** enabled. Enter the passphrase for the configuration server that you noted earlier. Click **OK** to register server. Note that you can ignore the NAT options on the page. They're not used.\n    3. If your estimated retention drive requirement is more than 1 TB you can configure the retention volume (R:) using a virtual disk and [storage spaces](http://blogs.technet.com/b/askpfeplat/archive/2013/10/21/storage-spaces-how-to-configure-storage-tiers-with-windows-server-2012-r2.aspx)\n    \n    ![Windows master target server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_TSRegister.png)\n\n8. If you're running Linux:\n    1. Ensure that you have installed the latest Linux Integration Services (LIS) installed before you install the Master target server software. You can find the latest version of LIS along with instructions on how to install [here](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=46842). Restart the machine after the LIS install.\n    2. In **Prepare Target(Azure) Resources** click **Download and Install additional software (only for Linux Master Target Server)** to download the Linux master target server package. Copy the downloaded tar file to the virtual machine using an sftp client. Alternatively you can log in to the deployed linux master target server and use *wget http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=529757&clcid=0x409* to download the the file.\n    2. Log into the server using a Secure Shell client. Note that if you're connected to the Azure network over VPN use the internal IP address. Otherwise use the external IP address and the SSH public endpoint.\n    3. Extract the files from the gzipped installer by running: **tar –xvzf Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_RHEL6-64***\n    ![Linux master target server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_TSLinuxTar.png)\n    4. Make sure you're in the directory to which you extracted the contents of the tar file.\n    5. Copy the configuration server passphrase to a local file using the command **echo *`<passphrase>`* >passphrase.txt**\n    6. Run the command “**sudo ./install -t both -a host -R MasterTarget -d /usr/local/ASR -i *`<Configuration server internal IP address>`* -p 443 -s y -c https -P passphrase.txt**”.\n\n    ![Register target server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/Linux-MT-install.png)\n\n9. Wait for a few minutes (10-15) and on the **Servers** > **Configuration Servers** page check that the master target server is listed as registered on the **Server Details** tab. If you're running Linux and  it didn't register run the host config tool again from /usr/local/ASR/Vx/bin/hostconfigcli. You'll need to set access permissions by running chmod as root.\n\n    ![Verify target server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_TSList.png)\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] Please note that it can take up to 15 minutes after registration is complete for the master target server to be listed under the configuration server. To update immediately, refresh the configuration server by clicking on the refresh button at the bottom of the configuration servers page.\n\n## Step 4: Deploy the on-premises process server\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] We recommend that you configure a static IP address on the process server so that it's guaranteed to be persistent across reboots.\n\n1. Click Quick Start > **Install Process Server on-premises** > **Download and install the process server**.\n\n    ![Install process server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_PSDeploy.png)\n\n2.  Copy the downloaded zip file to the server on which you're going to install the process server. The zip file contains two installation files:\n\n    - Microsoft-ASR_CX_TP_8.4.0.0_Windows*\n    - Microsoft-ASR_CX_8.4.0.0_Windows*\n\n3. Unzip the archive and copy the installation files to a location on the server.\n4. Run the **Microsoft-ASR_CX_TP_8.4.0.0_Windows*** installation file and follow the instructions. This installs third-party components needed for the deployment.\n5. Then run **Microsoft-ASR_CX_8.4.0.0_Windows***.\n6. On the **Server Mode** page select **Process Server**.\n\n    ![Server Selection Mode](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_ProcessServerSelection.png)\n\n7. On the **Environment Details** page do the following:\n\n\n    - If you want to protect VMware virtual machines click **Yes**\n    - If  you only want to protect physical servers and thus don't need VMware vCLI installed on the process server. Click **No** and continue.\n        \n    ![Register configuration server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_ProcessServerVirtualPhysical.png)\n\n8. Note the following when installing VMware vCLI:\n\n    - **Only VMware vSphere CLI 5.5.0 is supported**. The process server doesn't work with other versions or updates of vSphere CLI.\n    - Download vSphere CLI 5.5.0 from [here.](https://my.vmware.com/web/vmware/details?downloadGroup=VCLI550&productId=352)\n    - If you installed vSphere CLI just before you started installing the process server, and setup doesn't detect it, wait up to five minutes before you try setup again. This ensures that all the environment variables needed for vSphere CLI detection have been initialized correctly.\n\n9.  In **NIC Selection for Process Server** select the network adapter that the process server should use.\n\n    ![Select adapter](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_ProcessServerNICSelection.png)\n\n10. In **Configuration Server Details**:\n\n    - For the IP address and port, if you're connecting over VPN specify the internal IP address of the configuration server and 443 for the port. Otherwise specify the public virtual IP address and mapped public HTTP endpoint.\n    - Type in the passphrase of the configuration server.\n    - Clear **Verify Mobility service software signature** if you want to disable verification when you use automatic push to install the service. Signature verification needs internet connectivity from the process server.\n    - Click **Next**.\n\n    ![Register configuration server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_ProcessServerConfigServer.png)\n\n\n11. In **Select Installation Drive** select a cache drive. The process server needs a cache drive with at least 600 GB of free space. Then click **Install**. \n\n    ![Register configuration server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_ProcessServerCacheConfig.png)\n\n12. Note that you might need to restart the server to complete the installation. In **Configuration Server** > **Server Details** check that the process server appears and is registered successfully in the vault.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE]It can take up to 15 minutes after registration is complete for the process server to appear as listed under the configuration server. To update immediately, refresh the configuration server by clicking on the refresh button at the bottom of the configuration server page\n \n![Validate process server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_ProcessServerRegister.png)\n\nIf you didn't disable signature verification for the Mobility service when you registered the process server you can do it later as follows:\n\n1. Log onto the process server as an administrator and open the file C:\\pushinstallsvc\\pushinstaller.conf for editing. Under the section **[PushInstaller.transport]** add this line: **SignatureVerificationChecks=”0”**. Save and close the file.\n2. Restart the InMage PushInstall service.\n\n\n## Step 5: Install latest updates\n\nBefore proceeding, ensure that you have the latest updates installed. Remember to install the updates in the following order:\n\n1. Configuration server\n2. Process server\n3. Master target server\n\nYou can get the updates on the Site Recovery **Dashboard **. For Linux installation extract the files from the gzipped installer and run the command “sudo ./install” to install the update\n\nIf you are running virtual machines or physical servers that already have the Mobility service installed, you can get updates for the service as follows:\n\n- Either download updates for the service as follows:\n    - [Windows Server (64 bit only)](http://download.microsoft.com/download/8/4/8/8487F25A-E7D9-4810-99E4-6C18DF13A6D3/Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_Windows_GA_28Jul2015_release.exe)\n    - [CentOS 6.4,6.5,6.6 (64 bit only)](http://download.microsoft.com/download/7/E/D/7ED50614-1FE1-41F8-B4D2-25D73F623E9B/Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_RHEL6-64_GA_28Jul2015_release.tar.gz)\n    - [Oracle Enterprise Linux 6.4,6.5 (64 bit only)](http://download.microsoft.com/download/5/2/6/526AFE4B-7280-4DC6-B10B-BA3FD18B8091/Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_OL6-64_GA_28Jul2015_release.tar.gz)\n    - [SUSE Linux Enterprise Server SP3 (64 bit only)](http://download.microsoft.com/download/B/4/2/B4229162-C25C-4DB2-AD40-D0AE90F92305/Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_SLES11-SP3-64_GA_28Jul2015_release.tar.gz)\n- Alternatively after updating the process server you can get the updated version of the Mobility service from the  C:\\pushinstallsvc\\repository folder on the process server.\n- If you have a an already protected machine with an older version of the Mobility service installed, you could also automatically upgrade the Mobility service on the protected machines from the management portal. To do this, select the protection group to which the machine belongs, highlight the protected machine and click on the Update Mobility service button at the bottom. The Update Mobility Service button will be activated only if a newer version of the Mobility Service is available. Please ensure that the Process server is running the latest version of the Process server software before updating the mobility service. The protected server needs to meet all the [automatic push-installation prerequisites](#install-the-mobility-service-automatically) in order for update mobility service to work.\n\n![Select vCenter server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVmware_UpdateMobility1.png)\n\nIn Select accounts specify the administrator account to be used to update the mobility service on the protected server. Click OK and wait for the triggered job to complete.\n\n\n## Step 6: Add vCenter servers or ESXi hosts\n\n1. On the **Servers** > **Configuration Servers** tab select the configuration server and click **ADD VCENTER SERVER** to add a vCenter server or ESXi host.\n\n    ![Select vCenter server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_AddVCenter.png)\n\n2. Specify details for the vCenter server or ESXi host and select the process server that will be used to discover it.\n\n    - If the vCenter server isn't running on the default 443 port specify the port number on which the vCenter server is running.\n    - The process server must be on the same network as the vCenter server/ESXi host and should have VMware vSphere CLI 5.5.0 installed.\n\n    ![vCenter server settings](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_AddVCenter4.png)\n\n\n3. After discovery is completed the vCenter server will be listed under the configuration server details.\n\n    ![vCenter server settings](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_AddVCenter2.png)\n\n4. If you're using a non-administrator account to add the vCenter server or ESXi host, make sure the account has the following privileges:\n\n    - vCenter accounts should have Datacenter, Datastore, Folder, Host, Network, Resource, Storage views, Virtual machine and vSphere Distributed Switch privileges enabled.\n    - ESXi host accounts should have the Datacenter, Datastore, Folder, Host, Network, Resource, Virtual machine and vSphere Distributed Switch privileges enabled\n\n\n\n## Step 7: Create a protection group\n\n1. Open **Protected Items** > **Protection Group** and click to add a protection group.\n\n    ![Create protection group](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_CreatePG1.png)\n\n2. On the **Specify Protection Group Settings** page specify a name for the group and select the configuration server on which you want to create the group.\n\n    ![Protection group settings](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_CreatePG2.png)\n\n3. On the **Specify Replication Settings** page configure the replication settings that will be used for all the machines in the group.\n\n    ![Protection group replication](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_CreatePG3.png)\n\n4. Settings:\n    - **Multi VM consistency**: If you turn this on it creates shared application-consistent recovery points across the machines in the protection group. This setting is most relevant when all of the machines in the protection group are running the same workload. All machines will be recovered to the same data point. Only available for Windows servers.\n    - **RPO threshold**: Alerts will be generated when the continuous data protection replication RPO exceeds the configured RPO threshold value.\n    - **Recovery point retention**: Specifies the retention window. Protected machines can be recovered to any point within this window.\n    - **Application-consistent snapshot frequency**: Specifies how frequently recovery points containing application-consistent snapshots will be created.\n\nYou can monitor the protection group as they're created on the **Protected Items** page.\n\n## Step 8: Set up machines you want to protect\n\nYou'll need to install the Mobility service on virtual machines and physical servers you want to protect. You can do this in two ways:\n\n- Automatically push and install the service on each machine from the process server.\n- Manually install the service. \n\n### Install the Mobility service automatically\n\nWhen you add machines to a protection group the Mobility service is automatically pushed and installed on each machine by the process server. \n\n**Automatically push install the mobility service on Windows servers:** \n\n1. Install the latest updates for the process server as described in [Step 5: Install latest updates](#step-5-install-latest-updates), and make sure that the process server is available. \n2. Ensure there's network connectivity between the source machine and the process server, and that the source machine is accessible from the process server.  \n3. Configure the Windows firewall to allow **File and Printer Sharing** and **Windows Management Instrumentation**. Under Windows Firewall settings, select the option “Allow an app or feature through Firewall” and select the applications as shown in the picture below. For machines that belong to a domain you can configure the firewall policy with a Group Policy Object.\n\n    ![Firewall settings](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_PushInstallFirewall.png)\n\n4. The account used to perform the push installation must be in the Administrators group on the machine you want to protect. These credentials are only used for push installation of the Mobility service and you'll provide them when you add a machine to a protection group.\n5. If the provided account isn't a domain account you'll need to disable Remote User Access control on the local machine. To do this add the LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy DWORD registry entry with a value of 1 under HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Policies\\System. To add the registry entry from a CLI open cmd or powershell and enter **`REG ADD HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Policies\\System /v LocalAccountTokenFilterPolicy /t REG_DWORD /d 1`**. \n\n**Automatically push install the mobility service on Linux servers:**\n\n1. Install the latest updates for the process server as described in [Step 5: Install latest updates](#step-5-install-latest-updates), and make sure that the process server is available.\n2. Ensure there's network connectivity between the source machine and the process server, and that the source machine is accessible from the process server.  \n3. Make sure the account is a root user on the source Linux server.\n4. Ensure that the /etc/hosts file on the source Linux server contains entries that map the local host name to IP addresses associated with all NICs.\n5. Install the latest openssh, openssh-server, openssl packages on the machine you want to protect.\n6. Ensure SSH is enabled and running on port 22. \n7. Enable SFTP subsystem and password authentication in the sshd_config file as follows: \n\n    - a) Log in as root.\n    - b) In the file /etc/ssh/sshd_config file, find the line that begins with **PasswordAuthentication**.\n    - c) Uncomment the line and change the value from “no” to “yes”.\n\n        ![Linux mobility](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_LinuxPushMobility1.png)\n\n    - d) Find the line that begins with Subsystem and uncomment the line.\n    \n        ![Linux push mobility](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_LinuxPushMobility2.png)  \n\n8. Ensure the source machine Linux variant is supported. \n \n### Install the Mobility service manually\n\nThe software packages used to install the Mobility service are on the process server in C:\\pushinstallsvc\\repository. Log onto the process server and copy the appropriate installation package to the source machine based on the table below:-\n\n| Source operating system                               | Mobility service package on process server                                                            |\n|---------------------------------------------------    |------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ |\n| Windows Server (64 bit only)                          | `C:\\pushinstallsvc\\repository\\Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_Windows_GA_28Jul2015_release.exe`         |\n| CentOS 6.4, 6.5, 6.6 (64 bit only)                    | `C:\\pushinstallsvc\\repository\\Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_RHEL6-64_GA_28Jul2015_release.tar.gz`     |\n| SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 11 SP3 (64 bit only)     | `C:\\pushinstallsvc\\repository\\Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_SLES11-SP3-64_GA_28Jul2015_release.tar.gz`|\n| Oracle Enterprise Linux 6.4, 6.5 (64 bit only)        | `C:\\pushinstallsvc\\repository\\Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_OL6-64_GA_28Jul2015_release.tar.gz`       |\n\n\n**To install the Mobility service manually on a Windows server**, do the following:\n\n1. Copy the **Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.4.0.0_Windows_GA_28Jul2015_release.exe** package from the process server directory path listed in the table above to the source machine.\n2. Install the Mobility service by running the executable on the source machine.\n3. Follow the installer instructions.\n4. Select **Mobility service** as the role and click **Next**.\n    \n    ![Install mobility service](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_MobilityServiceInstall1.png)\n\n5. Leave the installation directory as the default installation path and click **Install**.\n6. In **Host Agent Config** specify the IP address and HTTPS port of the configuration server.\n\n    - If you're connecting over the internet specify the public virtual IP address and public HTTPS endpoint as the port.\n    - If you're connecting over VPN specify the internal IP address and 443 for the port. Leave **Use HTTPS** checked.\n\n    ![Install mobility service](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_MobilityServiceInstall2.png)\n\n7. Specify the configuration server passphrase and click **OK** to register the Mobility service with the configuration server.\n\n**To run from the command line:**\n\n1. Copy the passphrase from the CX to the file \"C:\\connection.passphrase\" on the server and run this command. In our example CX i 104.40.75.37 and the HTTPS port is 62519:\n\n    `C:\\Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.2.0.0_Windows_PREVIEW_20Mar2015_Release.exe\" -ip 104.40.75.37 -port 62519 -mode UA /LOG=\"C:\\stdout.txt\" /DIR=\"C:\\Program Files (x86)\\Microsoft Azure Site Recovery\" /VERYSILENT  /SUPPRESSMSGBOXES /norestart  -usesysvolumes  /CommunicationMode https /PassphrasePath \"C:\\connection.passphrase\"`\n\n**Install the Mobility service manually on a Linux server**:\n\n1. Copy the appropriate tar archive based on the table above, from the process server to the source machine.\n2. Open a shell program and extract the zipped tar archive to a local path by executing `tar -xvzf Microsoft-ASR_UA_8.2.0.0*`\n3. Create a passphrase.txt file in the local directory to which you extracted the contents of the tar archive by entering *`echo <passphrase> >passphrase.txt`* from shell.\n4. Install the Mobility service by entering *`sudo ./install -t both -a host -R Agent -d /usr/local/ASR -i <IP address> -p <port> -s y -c https -P passphrase.txt`*.\n5. Specify the IP address and port:\n\n    - If you are connecting to the configuration server over the internet specify the configuration server virtual public IP address and public HTTPS endpoint in `<IP address>` and `<port>`.\n    - If you're connecting over a VPN connection specify the internal IP address and 443.\n\n**To run from the command line**:\n\n1. Copy the passphrase from the CX to the file \"passphrase.txt\" on the server and run this commands. In our example CX i 104.40.75.37 and the HTTPS port is 62519:\n\nTo install on a production server:\n\n    ./install -t both -a host -R Agent -d /usr/local/ASR -i 104.40.75.37 -p 62519 -s y -c https -P passphrase.txt\n \nTo install on the target server:\n\n\n    ./install -t both -a host -R MasterTarget -d /usr/local/ASR -i 104.40.75.37 -p 62519 -s y -c https -P passphrase.txt\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] When you add machines to a protection group that are already running an appropriate version of the Mobility service then the push installation is skipped.\n\n\n## Step 9: Enable protection\n\nTo enable protection you add virtual machines and physical servers to a protection group. Before you start,note that:\n\n- Virtual machines are discovered every 15 minutes and it can take up to 15 minutes for them to appear in Azure Site Recovery after discovery.\n- Environment changes on the virtual machine (such as VMware tools installation) can also take up to 15 minutes to be updated in Site Recovery.\n- You can check the last discovered time in the **LAST CONTACT AT** field for the vCenter server/ESXi host on the **Configuration Servers** page.\n- If you have a protection group already created and add a vCenter Server or ESXi host after that, it takes fifteen minutes for the Azure Site Recovery portal to refresh and for virtual machines to be listed in the **Add machines to a protection group** dialog.\n- If you would like to proceed immediately with adding machines to protection group without waiting for the scheduled discovery, highlight the configuration server (don’t click it) and click the **Refresh** button.\n- When you add virtual machines or physical machines to a protection group, the process server automatically pushes and installs the Mobility service on the source server if the it isn't already installed.\n- For the automatic push mechanism to work make sure you've set up your protected machines as described in the previous step.\n\nAdd machines as follows:\n\n1. **Protected Items** > **Protection Group** > **Machines** tab. Click **ADD MACHINES**. As a best practice we recommend that protection groups should mirror your workloads so that you add machines running a specific application to the same group.\n2. In **Select Virtual Machines** if you're protecting physical servers, in the **Add Physical Machines** wizard provide the IP address and friendly name. Then select the operating system family.\n\n    ![Add V-Center server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_PhysicalProtect.png)\n\n3. In **Select Virtual Machines** if you're protecting VMware virtual machines, select a vCenter server that's managing your virtual machines (or the EXSi host on which they're running), and then select the machines.\n\n    ![Add V-Center server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_SelectVMs.png)   \n\n4. In **Specify Target Resources** select the master target servers and storage to use for replication and select whether the settings should be used for all workloads. Select [Premium Storage Account](../storage/storage-premium-storage-preview-portal.md) while configuring protection for workloads which require consistent high IO performance and low latency in order to host IO intensive workloads. If you want to use a Premium Storage account for your workload disks, you need to use the Master Target of DS-series. You cannot use Premium Storage disks with Master Target of non-DS-series.\n\n    ![vCenter server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_MachinesResources.png)\n\n5. In **Specify Accounts** select the account you want to use for installing the Mobility service on protected machines. The account credentials are needed for automatic installation of the Mobility service. If you can't select an account make sure you set one up as described in Step 2. Note that this account can't be accessed by Azure. For Windows server the account should have administrator privileges on the source server. For Linux the account must be root.\n\n    ![Linux credentials](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_VMMobilityInstall.png)\n\n6. Click the check mark to finish adding machines to the protection group and to start initial replication for each machine. You can monitor status on the **Jobs** page.\n\n    ![Add V-Center server](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_PGJobs2.png)\n\n7. In addition you can monitor protection status by clicking **Protected Items** > protection group name > **Virtual Machines** . After initial replication completes and the machines are synchronizing data they will show **Protected** status.\n\n    ![Virtual machine jobs](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_PGJobs.png)\n\n\n### Set protected machine properties\n\n1. After a machine has a **Protected** status you can configure its failover properties. In the protection group details select the machine and open the **Configure** tab.\n2. You can modify the name that will be given to the machine in Azure after failover and the Azure virtual machine size. You can also select the Azure network to which the machine will be connected after failover.\n\n    ![Set virtual machine properties](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_VMProperties.png)\n\nNote that:\n\n- The name of the Azure machine must comply with Azure requirements.\n- By default replicated virtual machines in Azure aren't connected to an Azure network. If you want replicated virtual machines to communicate make sure to set the same Azure network for them.\n- If you resize a volume on a VMware virtual machine or physical server it goes into a critical state. If you do need to modify the size, do the following:\n\n    - a) Change the size setting.\n    - b) In the **Virtual Machines** tab, select the virtual machine and click **Remove**.\n    - c) In **Remove Virtual Machine** select the option **Disable protection (use for recovery drill and volume resize)**. This option disables protection but retains the recovery points in Azure.\n\n        ![Set virtual machine properties](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RemoveVM.png)\n\n    - d) Reenable protection for the virtual machine. When you reenable protection the data for the resized volume will be transferred to Azure.\n\n    \n\n## Step 10: Run a failover\n\nCurrently you can only run unplanned failovers for protected VMware virtual machines and physical servers. Note the following:\n\n\n\n- Before you initiate a failover, ensure that the configuration and master target servers are running and healthy. Otherwise failover will fail.\n- Source machines aren't shut down as part of an unplanned failover. Performing an unplanned failover stops data replication for the protected servers. You'll need to delete the machines from the protection group and add them again in order to start protecting machines again after the unplanned failover completes.\n- If you want to fail over without losing any data, make sure that the primary site virtual machines are turned off before you initiate the failover.\n\n1. On the **Recovery Plans** page and add a recovery plan. Specify details for the plan and select **Azure** as the target.\n\n    ![Configure recovery plan](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RP1.png)\n\n2. In **Select Virtual Machine** select a protection group and then select machines in the group to add to the recovery plan. [Read more](site-recovery-create-recovery-plans.md) about recovery plans.\n\n    ![Add virtual machines](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMWare_RP2.png)\n\n3. If needed you can customize the plan to create groups and sequence the order in which machines in the recovery plan are failed over. You can also add prompts for manual actions and scripts. The scripts when recovering to Azure can be added by using [Azure Automation Runbooks](site-recovery-runbook-automation.md).\n\n4. In the **Recovery Plans** page select the plan and click **Unplanned Failover**.\n5. In **Confirm Failover** verify the failover direction (To Azure) and select the recovery point to fail over to.\n6. Wait for the failover job to complete and then verify that the failover worked as expected and that the replicated virtual machines start successfully in Azure.\n\n\n\n\n## Step 11: Fail back failed over machines from Azure\n\n[Learn more](site-recovery-failback-azure-to-vmware.md) about how to bring your failed over machines running in Azure back to your on-premises environment.\n\n\n## Manage your process servers\n\nThe process server sends replication data to the master target server in Azure, and discovers new VMware virtual machines added to a vCenter server. In the following circumstances you might want to change the process server in your deployment:\n\n- If the current process server goes down\n- If your recovery point objective (RPO) rises to an unacceptable level for your organization.\n\nIf required you can move the replication of some or all of your on-premises VMware virtual machines and physical servers to a different process server. For example:\n\n- **Failure**—If a process server fails or isn't available you can move protected machine replication to another process server. Metadata of the source machine and replica machine will be moved to the new process server and data is resynchronized. The new process server will automatically connect to the vCenter server to perform automatic discovery. You can monitor the state of process servers on the Site Recovery dashboard.\n- **Load balancing to adjust RPO**—For improved load balancing you can select a different process server in the Site Recovery portal, and move replication of one or more machines to it for manual load balancing. In this case metadata of the selected source and replica machines is moved to the new process server. The original process server remains connected to the vCenter server. \n\n### Monitor the process server\n\nIf a process server is in a critical state a status warning will be displayed on the Site Recovery Dashboard. You can click on the status to open the Events tab and then drill down to specific jobs on the Jobs tab. \n\n### Modify the process server used for replication\n\n1. Go to the **CONFIGURATION SERVERS** page under **SERVERS**\n2. Click on the name of the Configuration Server and go to **Server Details**.\n3. In the **Process Servers** list click **Change Process Server** next to the server you want to modify.\n    ![Change Process Server 1](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMware_ChangePS1.png)\n4. In the **Change Process Server** dialog select the new server in **Target Process Server**, and then select the virtual machines that you want to replicate to the new server. click the information icon next to the server name to get information about it, including free space, used memory. The average space that will be required to replicate each selected virtual machine to the new process server is displayed to help you make load decisions.\n    ![Change Process Server 2](./media/site-recovery-vmware-to-azure/ASRVMware_ChangePS2.png)\n5. Click the check mark to begin replicating to the new process server. If you remove all virtual machines from a process server that was critical it should no longer display a critical warning in the dashboard.\n\n\n## Third-party software notices and information\n\nDo Not Translate or Localize\n\nThe software and firmware running in the Microsoft product or service is based on or incorporates material from the projects listed below (collectively, “Third Party Code”).  Microsoft is the not original author of the Third Party Code.  The original copyright notice and license, under which Microsoft received such Third Party Code, are set forth below.\n\nThe information in Section A is regarding Third Party Code components from the projects listed below. Such licenses and information are provided for informational purposes only.  This Third Party Code is being relicensed to you by Microsoft under Microsoft's software licensing terms for the Microsoft product or service.  \n\nThe information in Section B is regarding Third Party Code components that are being made available to you by Microsoft under the original licensing terms.\n\nThe complete file may be found on the [Microsoft Download Center](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=529428). Microsoft reserves all rights not expressly granted herein, whether by implication, estoppel or otherwise.\n"
}