{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Reliable Collections",
      "pos": [
        26,
        46
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Collections enable you to write highly available, scalable, and low latency cloud applications.",
      "pos": [
        64,
        168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Collections",
      "pos": [
        487,
        507
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Collections enable you to write highly available, scalable, and low latency",
      "pos": [
        509,
        593
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "cloud applications as though you are writing single machine applications.",
      "pos": [
        594,
        667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The classes in the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Microsoft.ServiceFabric.Data.Collections`</ph> namespace provide a set of out-of-the-box",
      "pos": [
        668,
        771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "collections that automatically make your state highly available.",
      "pos": [
        772,
        836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Developers need only to program to the Reliable Collection APIs and let Reliable Collections",
      "pos": [
        837,
        929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "manage the replicated and local state.",
      "pos": [
        930,
        968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The key difference between Reliable Collections and other high-availability technologies",
      "pos": [
        970,
        1058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(such as Redis, Azure Table service, and Azure Queue service) is that the state is",
      "pos": [
        1059,
        1141
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "kept locally in the service instance while also being made highly available.",
      "pos": [
        1142,
        1218
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that:",
      "pos": [
        1219,
        1235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All reads are local, which results in low latency and high throughput reads.",
      "pos": [
        1240,
        1316
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All writes incur the minimum number of network IOs, which results in low latency and high throughput writes.",
      "pos": [
        1320,
        1428
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Image of Evolution of Collections.",
      "pos": [
        1432,
        1466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Collections can be thought of as the natural evolution of the <ph id=\"ph1\">`System.Collections`</ph>",
      "pos": [
        1563,
        1654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "classes: a new set of collections that are designed for the cloud and multi-machine",
      "pos": [
        1655,
        1738
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "applications without increasing complexity for the developer.",
      "pos": [
        1739,
        1800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As such, they are:",
      "pos": [
        1801,
        1819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replicated: State changes are replicated for high availability.",
      "pos": [
        1824,
        1887
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Persisted: Data is persisted to disk for durability against large-scale outages (for example, a datacenter power outage).",
      "pos": [
        1891,
        2012
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Asynchronous: APIs are asynchronous to ensure threads are not blocked when incurring IO.",
      "pos": [
        2016,
        2104
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Transactional: APIs utilize the abstraction of transactions to allow you to manage multiple Reliable Collections within a service easily.",
      "pos": [
        2108,
        2245
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Collections provide strong consistency guarantees out of the box in order",
      "pos": [
        2247,
        2329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "to make reasoning about application state easier.",
      "pos": [
        2330,
        2379
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Strong consistency is achieved by ensuring transaction commits only complete after the entire transaction",
      "pos": [
        2380,
        2485
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "has been applied on a quorum of replicas including the primary.",
      "pos": [
        2486,
        2549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To achieve weaker consistency, application can acknowledge back to the client / requester",
      "pos": [
        2550,
        2639
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "before the asynchronous commit returns.",
      "pos": [
        2640,
        2679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Reliable Collections APIs are an evolution of concurrent collections APIs",
      "pos": [
        2681,
        2758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(found in the <ph id=\"ph1\">`System.Collections.Concurrent`</ph> namespace):",
      "pos": [
        2759,
        2816
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Asynchronous: Returns a Task since, unlike Reliable Collections, the operations are replicated and persisted.",
      "pos": [
        2821,
        2930
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No out parameters: Uses <ph id=\"ph1\">`ConditionalResult&lt;T&gt;`</ph> to return a bool and a value instead of out parameters.",
      "pos": [
        2934,
        3036
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">`ConditionalResult&lt;T&gt;`</ph> is like <ph id=\"ph2\">`Nullable&lt;T&gt;`</ph> but does not require T to be a struct.",
      "pos": [
        3037,
        3120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Transactions: Uses a transaction object to enable the user to group actions on multiple Reliable Collections in a transaction.",
      "pos": [
        3124,
        3250
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3252,
        3327
      ],
      "content": "Today, <ph id=\"ph1\">`Microsoft.ServiceFabric.Data.Collections`</ph> contains two collections:"
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Reliable Dictionary<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn971511.aspx)</ept>: Represents a replicated, transactional, and asynchronous collection of key/value pairs.",
      "pos": [
        3332,
        3498
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Similar to <ph id=\"ph1\">`ConcurrentDictionary`</ph>, both the key and the value can be of any type.",
      "pos": [
        3499,
        3580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Reliable Queue<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn971527.aspx)</ept>: Represents a replicated, transactional, and asynchronous strict first-in first-out (FIFO) queue.",
      "pos": [
        3584,
        3754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Similar to <ph id=\"ph1\">`ConcurrentQueue`</ph>, the value can be of any type.",
      "pos": [
        3755,
        3814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Isolation Levels",
      "pos": [
        3819,
        3835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Isolation level is a measure of the degree isolation is achieved.",
      "pos": [
        3836,
        3901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Isolation means that a transaction behaves as it would in a system that only allows",
      "pos": [
        3902,
        3985
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "one transaction to be in-flight at any given point of time.",
      "pos": [
        3986,
        4045
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Collections automatically choose the isolation level to use for a given",
      "pos": [
        4047,
        4127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "read operation depending on the operation and the role of the replica.",
      "pos": [
        4128,
        4198
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two isolation levels that are supported in Reliable Collections:",
      "pos": [
        4200,
        4274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Repeatable Read<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: \"Specifies that statements cannot read data that has been modified but not yet committed by other transactions and that no other transactions can modify data that has been read by the current transaction until the current transaction completes.",
      "pos": [
        4278,
        4543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms173763.aspx)\"",
      "pos": [
        4544,
        4601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Snapshot<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: \"Specifies that data read by any statement in a transaction will be the transactionally consistent version of the data that existed at the start of the transaction.",
      "pos": [
        4604,
        4782
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The transaction can only recognize data modifications that were committed before the start of the transaction.",
      "pos": [
        4783,
        4893
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data modifications made by other transactions after the start of the current transaction are not visible to statements executing in the current transaction.",
      "pos": [
        4894,
        5050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The effect is as if the statements in a transaction get a snapshot of the committed data as it existed at the start of the transaction.",
      "pos": [
        5051,
        5186
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms173763.aspx)\"",
      "pos": [
        5187,
        5244
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both the Reliable Dictionary and the Reliable Queue support Read Your Writes.",
      "pos": [
        5246,
        5323
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In other words, any write within a transaction will be visible to a following read",
      "pos": [
        5324,
        5406
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "that belongs to the same transaction.",
      "pos": [
        5407,
        5444
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Dictionary",
      "pos": [
        5450,
        5469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation \\ Role",
      "pos": [
        5472,
        5488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary",
      "pos": [
        5496,
        5503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Secondary",
      "pos": [
        5515,
        5524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Single Entity Read",
      "pos": [
        5600,
        5618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Repeatable Read",
      "pos": [
        5624,
        5639
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshot",
      "pos": [
        5643,
        5651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enumeration \\ Count",
      "pos": [
        5664,
        5683
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshot",
      "pos": [
        5688,
        5696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshot",
      "pos": [
        5707,
        5715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Queue",
      "pos": [
        5731,
        5745
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation \\ Role",
      "pos": [
        5748,
        5764
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary",
      "pos": [
        5772,
        5779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Secondary",
      "pos": [
        5791,
        5800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Single Entity Read",
      "pos": [
        5876,
        5894
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshot",
      "pos": [
        5900,
        5908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshot",
      "pos": [
        5919,
        5927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enumeration \\ Count",
      "pos": [
        5940,
        5959
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshot",
      "pos": [
        5964,
        5972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshot",
      "pos": [
        5983,
        5991
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Persistence Model",
      "pos": [
        6006,
        6023
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable State Manager and Reliable Collections follow a persistence model that is called Log and Checkpoint.",
      "pos": [
        6024,
        6133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is a model where each state change is logged on disk and only applied in memory.",
      "pos": [
        6134,
        6219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The complete state itself is only persisted occasionally (aka.",
      "pos": [
        6220,
        6282
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Checkpoint).",
      "pos": [
        6283,
        6295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The benefit it provides is:",
      "pos": [
        6296,
        6323
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deltas are turned into sequential append-only writes on disk for improved performance.",
      "pos": [
        6327,
        6413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To better understand the log and checkpoint model, let’s first look at the infinite disk scenario.",
      "pos": [
        6415,
        6513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable State Manager logs every operation before it is replicated.",
      "pos": [
        6514,
        6582
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This allows the Reliable Collection to only apply the operation in memory.",
      "pos": [
        6583,
        6657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since logs are persisted, even when the replica fails and needs to be restarted, the Reliable State Manager",
      "pos": [
        6658,
        6765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "has enough information in its logs to replay all the operations the replica has lost.",
      "pos": [
        6766,
        6851
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As disk is infinite, log records never need to be removed and the Reliable Collection only needs to manage the in-memory state.",
      "pos": [
        6852,
        6979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Now let’s look at the finite disk scenario.",
      "pos": [
        6981,
        7024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At one point the Reliable State Manager will run out of disk space.",
      "pos": [
        7025,
        7092
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before that happens the Reliable State Manager needs to truncate its log to make room for the newer records.",
      "pos": [
        7093,
        7201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It will request the Reliable Collections to checkpoint their in-memory state.",
      "pos": [
        7202,
        7279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is the Reliable Collection's responsibility to persist its state up to that point.",
      "pos": [
        7280,
        7365
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the Reliable Collections complete their checkpoints, the Reliable State Manager can truncate the log to free up disk space.",
      "pos": [
        7366,
        7494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This way, when the replica needs to be restarted, Reliable Collections will recover their",
      "pos": [
        7495,
        7584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "checkpointed state, and the Reliable State Manager will recover and play back all the state changes that occurred",
      "pos": [
        7585,
        7698
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "since the checkpoint.",
      "pos": [
        7699,
        7720
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Locking",
      "pos": [
        7725,
        7732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Reliable Collections, all transactions are two-phased: a transaction does not release",
      "pos": [
        7733,
        7821
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "the locks it has acquired until the transaction terminates with either an abort or commit.",
      "pos": [
        7822,
        7912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Collections always take Exclusive locks.",
      "pos": [
        7914,
        7963
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For reads, the locking is dependent on couple of factors.",
      "pos": [
        7964,
        8021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any read operation done using Shapshot Isolation is lock free.",
      "pos": [
        8022,
        8084
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any Repeatable read operation by default takes Shared locks.",
      "pos": [
        8085,
        8145
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, for any read operation that supports Repeatable Read, user can ask for an",
      "pos": [
        8146,
        8228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update lock instead of the Shared lock.",
      "pos": [
        8229,
        8268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update lock is an asymmetric lock used to prevent a common form of deadlock that",
      "pos": [
        8269,
        8349
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "occurs when multiple transactions lock resources for potential update at a later time.",
      "pos": [
        8350,
        8436
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The lock compatibility matrix can be found below:",
      "pos": [
        8438,
        8487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Request \\ Granted",
      "pos": [
        8491,
        8508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "None",
      "pos": [
        8511,
        8515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Shared",
      "pos": [
        8526,
        8532
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update",
      "pos": [
        8541,
        8547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exclusive",
      "pos": [
        8555,
        8564
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Shared",
      "pos": [
        8653,
        8659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8673,
        8684
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8688,
        8699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8703,
        8711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8717,
        8725
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update",
      "pos": [
        8734,
        8740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8754,
        8765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8769,
        8780
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8784,
        8792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8798,
        8806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exclusive",
      "pos": [
        8815,
        8824
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8835,
        8846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8850,
        8858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8865,
        8873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conflict",
      "pos": [
        8879,
        8887
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that timeout argument in the Reliable Collections APIs are used as a deadlock detection.",
      "pos": [
        8895,
        8988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, two transactions (T1 and T2) are trying to read and update K1.",
      "pos": [
        8989,
        9064
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is possible for them to deadlock, because they both end up having the Shared lock.",
      "pos": [
        9065,
        9150
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, one or both of the operations will timeout.",
      "pos": [
        9151,
        9208
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the above deadlock scenario is a great example of how Update lock can prevent deadlocks.",
      "pos": [
        9210,
        9308
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Recommendations",
      "pos": [
        9313,
        9328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DO NOT<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> modify an object of custom type returned by read operations (e.g <ph id=\"ph1\">`TryPeekAsync`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`TryGetAsync`</ph>).",
      "pos": [
        9332,
        9441
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Collections, just like Concurrent Collections, return a reference to the objects and not a copy.",
      "pos": [
        9442,
        9547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DO<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> deep copy returned object of custom type before modifying it.",
      "pos": [
        9550,
        9618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since, structs and built-in types are pass-by-value, you do not need to do a deep copy on them.",
      "pos": [
        9619,
        9714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DO NOT<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> use <ph id=\"ph1\">`TimeSpan.MaxValue`</ph> for timeouts.",
      "pos": [
        9717,
        9765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Timeouts should be used to detect deadlocks.",
      "pos": [
        9766,
        9810
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9813,
        9923
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DO NOT<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> create a transaction within another transaction’s <ph id=\"ph1\">`using`</ph> statement because it can cause deadlocks."
    },
    {
      "content": "Here are some things to keep in mind:",
      "pos": [
        9925,
        9962
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The default timeout is 4 seconds for all the Reliable Collection APIs.",
      "pos": [
        9966,
        10036
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Most users should not override this.",
      "pos": [
        10037,
        10073
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10076,
        10168
      ],
      "content": "The default cancellation token is <ph id=\"ph1\">`CancellationToken.None`</ph> in all Reliable Collections APIs."
    },
    {
      "content": "Enumerations are snapshot consistent within a collection.",
      "pos": [
        10171,
        10228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, enumerations of multiple collections are not consistent across collections.",
      "pos": [
        10229,
        10313
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To achieve high availability for the Reliable Collections, each service should have at least a target and minimum replica set size of 3.",
      "pos": [
        10316,
        10452
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        10457,
        10467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Services Quick Start",
      "pos": [
        10472,
        10501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting Started with Service Fabric Web API services",
      "pos": [
        10555,
        10607
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Advanced usage of the Reliable Services programming model",
      "pos": [
        10670,
        10727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Developer reference for Reliable Collections",
      "pos": [
        10802,
        10846
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Reliable Collections\"\n   description=\"Reliable Collections enable you to write highly available, scalable, and low latency cloud applications.\"\n   services=\"service-fabric\"\n   documentationCenter=\".net\"\n   authors=\"mcoskun\"\n   manager=\"timlt\"\n   editor=\"masnider,jessebenson\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"service-fabric\"\n   ms.devlang=\"dotnet\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"required\"\n   ms.date=\"08/05/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"mcoskun\"/>\n\n# Reliable Collections\n\nReliable Collections enable you to write highly available, scalable, and low latency\ncloud applications as though you are writing single machine applications.\nThe classes in the `Microsoft.ServiceFabric.Data.Collections` namespace provide a set of out-of-the-box\ncollections that automatically make your state highly available.\nDevelopers need only to program to the Reliable Collection APIs and let Reliable Collections\nmanage the replicated and local state.\n\nThe key difference between Reliable Collections and other high-availability technologies\n(such as Redis, Azure Table service, and Azure Queue service) is that the state is\nkept locally in the service instance while also being made highly available.\nThis means that:\n\n1. All reads are local, which results in low latency and high throughput reads.\n2. All writes incur the minimum number of network IOs, which results in low latency and high throughput writes.\n\n![Image of Evolution of Collections.](media/service-fabric-reliable-services-reliable-collections/ReliableCollectionsEvolution.png)\n\nReliable Collections can be thought of as the natural evolution of the `System.Collections`\nclasses: a new set of collections that are designed for the cloud and multi-machine\napplications without increasing complexity for the developer.\nAs such, they are:\n\n1. Replicated: State changes are replicated for high availability.\n2. Persisted: Data is persisted to disk for durability against large-scale outages (for example, a datacenter power outage).\n3. Asynchronous: APIs are asynchronous to ensure threads are not blocked when incurring IO.\n4. Transactional: APIs utilize the abstraction of transactions to allow you to manage multiple Reliable Collections within a service easily.\n\nReliable Collections provide strong consistency guarantees out of the box in order\nto make reasoning about application state easier.\nStrong consistency is achieved by ensuring transaction commits only complete after the entire transaction\nhas been applied on a quorum of replicas including the primary.\nTo achieve weaker consistency, application can acknowledge back to the client / requester\nbefore the asynchronous commit returns.\n\nThe Reliable Collections APIs are an evolution of concurrent collections APIs\n(found in the `System.Collections.Concurrent` namespace):\n\n1. Asynchronous: Returns a Task since, unlike Reliable Collections, the operations are replicated and persisted.\n2. No out parameters: Uses `ConditionalResult<T>` to return a bool and a value instead of out parameters. `ConditionalResult<T>` is like `Nullable<T>` but does not require T to be a struct.\n3. Transactions: Uses a transaction object to enable the user to group actions on multiple Reliable Collections in a transaction.\n\nToday, `Microsoft.ServiceFabric.Data.Collections` contains two collections:\n\n1. [Reliable Dictionary](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn971511.aspx): Represents a replicated, transactional, and asynchronous collection of key/value pairs. Similar to `ConcurrentDictionary`, both the key and the value can be of any type.\n2. [Reliable Queue](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn971527.aspx): Represents a replicated, transactional, and asynchronous strict first-in first-out (FIFO) queue. Similar to `ConcurrentQueue`, the value can be of any type.\n\n## Isolation Levels\nIsolation level is a measure of the degree isolation is achieved.\nIsolation means that a transaction behaves as it would in a system that only allows\none transaction to be in-flight at any given point of time.\n\nReliable Collections automatically choose the isolation level to use for a given\nread operation depending on the operation and the role of the replica.\n\nThere are two isolation levels that are supported in Reliable Collections:\n\n- **Repeatable Read**: \"Specifies that statements cannot read data that has been modified but not yet committed by other transactions and that no other transactions can modify data that has been read by the current transaction until the current transaction completes. (https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms173763.aspx)\"\n- **Snapshot**: \"Specifies that data read by any statement in a transaction will be the transactionally consistent version of the data that existed at the start of the transaction. The transaction can only recognize data modifications that were committed before the start of the transaction. Data modifications made by other transactions after the start of the current transaction are not visible to statements executing in the current transaction. The effect is as if the statements in a transaction get a snapshot of the committed data as it existed at the start of the transaction. (https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms173763.aspx)\"\n\nBoth the Reliable Dictionary and the Reliable Queue support Read Your Writes.\nIn other words, any write within a transaction will be visible to a following read\nthat belongs to the same transaction.\n\n### Reliable Dictionary\n| Operation \\ Role      | Primary          | Secondary        |\n| --------------------- | :--------------- | :--------------- |\n| Single Entity Read    | Repeatable Read  | Snapshot         |\n| Enumeration \\ Count   | Snapshot         | Snapshot         |\n\n### Reliable Queue\n| Operation \\ Role      | Primary          | Secondary        |\n| --------------------- | :--------------- | :--------------- |\n| Single Entity Read    | Snapshot         | Snapshot         |\n| Enumeration \\ Count   | Snapshot         | Snapshot         |\n\n## Persistence Model\nReliable State Manager and Reliable Collections follow a persistence model that is called Log and Checkpoint.\nThis is a model where each state change is logged on disk and only applied in memory.\nThe complete state itself is only persisted occasionally (aka. Checkpoint).\nThe benefit it provides is:\n\n- Deltas are turned into sequential append-only writes on disk for improved performance.\n\nTo better understand the log and checkpoint model, let’s first look at the infinite disk scenario.\nReliable State Manager logs every operation before it is replicated.\nThis allows the Reliable Collection to only apply the operation in memory.\nSince logs are persisted, even when the replica fails and needs to be restarted, the Reliable State Manager\nhas enough information in its logs to replay all the operations the replica has lost.\nAs disk is infinite, log records never need to be removed and the Reliable Collection only needs to manage the in-memory state.\n\nNow let’s look at the finite disk scenario.\nAt one point the Reliable State Manager will run out of disk space.\nBefore that happens the Reliable State Manager needs to truncate its log to make room for the newer records.\nIt will request the Reliable Collections to checkpoint their in-memory state.\nIt is the Reliable Collection's responsibility to persist its state up to that point.\nOnce the Reliable Collections complete their checkpoints, the Reliable State Manager can truncate the log to free up disk space.\nThis way, when the replica needs to be restarted, Reliable Collections will recover their\ncheckpointed state, and the Reliable State Manager will recover and play back all the state changes that occurred\nsince the checkpoint.\n\n## Locking\nIn Reliable Collections, all transactions are two-phased: a transaction does not release\nthe locks it has acquired until the transaction terminates with either an abort or commit.\n\nReliable Collections always take Exclusive locks.\nFor reads, the locking is dependent on couple of factors.\nAny read operation done using Shapshot Isolation is lock free.\nAny Repeatable read operation by default takes Shared locks.\nHowever, for any read operation that supports Repeatable Read, user can ask for an\nUpdate lock instead of the Shared lock.\nUpdate lock is an asymmetric lock used to prevent a common form of deadlock that\noccurs when multiple transactions lock resources for potential update at a later time.\n\nThe lock compatibility matrix can be found below:\n\n| Request \\ Granted | None         | Shared       | Update      | Exclusive    |\n| ----------------- | :----------- | :----------- | :---------- | :----------- |\n| Shared            | No Conflict  | No Conflict  | Conflict    | Conflict     |\n| Update            | No Conflict  | No Conflict  | Conflict    | Conflict     |\n| Exclusive         | No Conflict  | Conflict     | Conflict    | Conflict     |\n\nNote that timeout argument in the Reliable Collections APIs are used as a deadlock detection.\nFor example, two transactions (T1 and T2) are trying to read and update K1.\nIt is possible for them to deadlock, because they both end up having the Shared lock.\nIn this case, one or both of the operations will timeout.\n\nNote that the above deadlock scenario is a great example of how Update lock can prevent deadlocks.\n\n## Recommendations\n\n- **DO NOT** modify an object of custom type returned by read operations (e.g `TryPeekAsync` or `TryGetAsync`). Reliable Collections, just like Concurrent Collections, return a reference to the objects and not a copy.\n- **DO** deep copy returned object of custom type before modifying it. Since, structs and built-in types are pass-by-value, you do not need to do a deep copy on them.\n- **DO NOT** use `TimeSpan.MaxValue` for timeouts. Timeouts should be used to detect deadlocks.\n- **DO NOT** create a transaction within another transaction’s `using` statement because it can cause deadlocks.\n\nHere are some things to keep in mind:\n\n- The default timeout is 4 seconds for all the Reliable Collection APIs. Most users should not override this.\n- The default cancellation token is `CancellationToken.None` in all Reliable Collections APIs.\n- Enumerations are snapshot consistent within a collection. However, enumerations of multiple collections are not consistent across collections.\n- To achieve high availability for the Reliable Collections, each service should have at least a target and minimum replica set size of 3.\n\n## Next Steps\n\n- [Reliable Services Quick Start](service-fabric-reliable-services-quick-start.md)\n- [Getting Started with Service Fabric Web API services](service-fabric-reliable-services-communication-webapi.md)\n- [Advanced usage of the Reliable Services programming model](../Service-Fabric/service-fabric-reliable-services-advanced-usage.md)\n- [Developer reference for Reliable Collections](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.servicefabric.data.collections.aspx)\n"
}