{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Internet facing load balancer overview | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        28,
        84
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview for Internet facing load balancer and its features.",
      "pos": [
        103,
        163
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How a load balancer works for Azure using virtual machines and cloud services.",
      "pos": [
        164,
        242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Internet Facing load balancer between multiple Virtual Machines or services",
      "pos": [
        556,
        631
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One use for endpoints is the configuration of the Azure Load Balancer to distribute a specific type of traffic between multiple virtual machines or services.",
      "pos": [
        633,
        790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, you can spread the load of web request traffic across multiple web servers or web roles.",
      "pos": [
        791,
        892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Load Balancer maps the public IP address and port number of incoming traffic to the private IP address and port number of the virtual machine and vice versa for the response traffic from the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        894,
        1107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> When you configure load balancing of traffic among multiple virtual machines or services using default settings, it will provide a random distribution of the incoming traffic.",
      "pos": [
        1110,
        1298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are looking for session affinity, check out <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>load balancer distribution mode<ept id=\"p1\">](load-balancer-distribution-mode.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        1299,
        1419
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a cloud service that contains instances of web roles or worker roles, you can define a public endpoint in the service definition (.csdef).",
      "pos": [
        1421,
        1563
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The servicedefinition.csdef file will contain the endpoint configuration and when you have multiple role instances for a web or worker role deployment, the load balancer will be setup for it.",
      "pos": [
        1566,
        1757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The way to add instances to your cloud deployement is changing the instance count on the service configuration file (.csfg).",
      "pos": [
        1758,
        1882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following figure shows a load-balanced endpoint for encrypted web traffic that is shared among three virtual machines for the public and private TCP port of 443.",
      "pos": [
        1886,
        2051
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These three virtual machines are in a load-balanced set.",
      "pos": [
        2052,
        2108
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "public load balancer example",
      "pos": [
        2113,
        2141
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ")",
      "pos": [
        2196,
        2197
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When Internet clients send web page requests to the public IP address of the cloud service and TCP port 443, the Azure Load Balancer performs a random balancing of those requests between the three virtual machines in the load-balanced set.",
      "pos": [
        2201,
        2440
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        2446,
        2456
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Internal load balancer overview",
      "pos": [
        2459,
        2490
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get started Configuring an Internet facing load balancer",
      "pos": [
        2530,
        2586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure a Load balancer distribution mode",
      "pos": [
        2628,
        2671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure idle TCP timeout settings for your load balancer",
      "pos": [
        2711,
        2769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        2810,
        2814
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "\n<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Internet facing load balancer overview | Microsoft Azure \"\n   description=\"Overview for Internet facing load balancer and its features. How a load balancer works for Azure using virtual machines and cloud services.\"\n   services=\"load-balancer\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   authors=\"joaoma\"\n   manager=\"adinah\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"load-balancer\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"07/09/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"joaoma\" />\n\n\n# Internet Facing load balancer between multiple Virtual Machines or services\n\nOne use for endpoints is the configuration of the Azure Load Balancer to distribute a specific type of traffic between multiple virtual machines or services. For example, you can spread the load of web request traffic across multiple web servers or web roles.\n\nAzure Load Balancer maps the public IP address and port number of incoming traffic to the private IP address and port number of the virtual machine and vice versa for the response traffic from the virtual machine.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] When you configure load balancing of traffic among multiple virtual machines or services using default settings, it will provide a random distribution of the incoming traffic. If you are looking for session affinity, check out [load balancer distribution mode](load-balancer-distribution-mode.md)\n\nFor a cloud service that contains instances of web roles or worker roles, you can define a public endpoint in the service definition (.csdef).\n \nThe servicedefinition.csdef file will contain the endpoint configuration and when you have multiple role instances for a web or worker role deployment, the load balancer will be setup for it. The way to add instances to your cloud deployement is changing the instance count on the service configuration file (.csfg).  \n\nThe following figure shows a load-balanced endpoint for encrypted web traffic that is shared among three virtual machines for the public and private TCP port of 443. These three virtual machines are in a load-balanced set.\n\n\n![public load balancer example](./media/load-balancer-internet-overview/IC727496.png))\n\n\n\nWhen Internet clients send web page requests to the public IP address of the cloud service and TCP port 443, the Azure Load Balancer performs a random balancing of those requests between the three virtual machines in the load-balanced set.\n\n\n## Next Steps\n\n[Internal load balancer overview](load-balancer-internal-overview.md)\n\n[Get started Configuring an Internet facing load balancer](load-balancer-internet-getstarted.md)\n\n[Configure a Load balancer distribution mode](load-balancer-distribution-mode.md)\n\n[Configure idle TCP timeout settings for your load balancer](load-balancer-tcp-idle-timeout.md)\n\n\n \ntest\n"
}