{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Getting started with Azure Active Directory Premium",
      "pos": [
        27,
        78
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A topic that explains how to sign up for Azure Active Directory Premium edition.",
      "pos": [
        97,
        177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting started with Azure Active Directory Premium",
      "pos": [
        543,
        594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory comes in three editions: Free, Basic, and Premium.",
      "pos": [
        596,
        669
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Free edition is included with an Azure or Office 365 subscription.",
      "pos": [
        670,
        740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Basic and Premium editions are available through a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Enterprise Agreement<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/licensing/licensing-programs/enterprise.aspx)</ept> or the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Open Volume License<ept id=\"p2\">](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/licensing/licensing-programs/open-license.aspx)</ept> program.",
      "pos": [
        741,
        1024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure and Office 365 subscribers can also buy Active Directory Premium online.",
      "pos": [
        1025,
        1103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Sign in here<ept id=\"p1\">](https://portal.office.com/Commerce/Catalog.aspx)</ept> to buy it.",
      "pos": [
        1104,
        1178
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Premium and Basic editions are available for customers in China using the worldwide instance of Azure Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        1195,
        1337
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Premium and Basic editions are not currently supported in the Microsoft Azure service operated by 21Vianet in China.",
      "pos": [
        1338,
        1477
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, contact us at the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Active Directory Forum<ept id=\"p1\">](http://feedback.azure.com/forums/169401-azure-active-directory)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1478,
        1613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory Premium is also included in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enterprise Mobility Suite<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1615,
        1700
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enterprise Mobility Suite is a cost effective way for organizations to use Microsoft Intune, Azure Rights Management and the Active Directory Premium services together under one licensing plan.",
      "pos": [
        1701,
        1894
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Enterprise Mobility Suite<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/enterprise-mobility/overview.aspx)</ept> web site.",
      "pos": [
        1895,
        2042
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To start using Azure Active Directory Premium features today, follow the steps below.",
      "pos": [
        2044,
        2129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The same steps apply to the Azure Active Directory Basic edition.",
      "pos": [
        2130,
        2195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 1: Sign up for Active Directory Premium",
      "pos": [
        2200,
        2244
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2246,
        2363
      ],
      "content": "To sign up, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Volume Licensing<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/licensing/how-to-buy/how-to-buy.aspx)</ept> web site."
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 2: Activate your license plan",
      "pos": [
        2368,
        2402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this is the first time you have purchased a license plan through Microsoft’s Enterprise Volume Licensing program, you will need to first activate your license plan before you can start assigning licenses from within your Azure Active Directory directory.",
      "pos": [
        2404,
        2661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, you must click on either the Sign In or Sign Up link found in the confirmation email (see below) you will receive after your very first license plan purchase has been completed.",
      "pos": [
        2662,
        2851
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On any subsequent purchase for this directory the licenses will automatically be activated in the same directory.",
      "pos": [
        2852,
        2965
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][1]",
      "pos": [
        2967,
        2973
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have an existing tenant, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sign In<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> link to sign in with your existing administrator account.",
      "pos": [
        2975,
        3087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It’s important that you sign in with the global administrator credentials from the directory where the licenses must be activated.",
      "pos": [
        3088,
        3218
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3220,
        3398
      ],
      "content": "If you want to create a new Azure Active Directory tenant to use with your licensing plan then you should select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sign Up<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> link which will take you to the following screen."
    },
    {
      "content": "![][2]",
      "pos": [
        3400,
        3406
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you are done with either the sign up process or the sign in process that was initiated from the email, you will see the following screen confirming that the license plan is being activated for your tenant.",
      "pos": [
        3408,
        3618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][3]",
      "pos": [
        3620,
        3626
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 3: Activate your Azure Active Directory access",
      "pos": [
        3631,
        3682
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the licenses are provisioned to your directory you will be receive a Welcome email (see below) that confirms you can start managing your Azure Active Directory Premium or Enterprise Mobility Suite licenses and features.",
      "pos": [
        3684,
        3908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have used Microsoft Azure before, you can proceed to http://manage.windowsazure.com to assign the new licenses (see Step 4 below for further instructions).",
      "pos": [
        3909,
        4071
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are new to Microsoft Azure, selecting the Sign In link on the email, or going to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Access to Azure Active Directory activation page<ept id=\"p1\">](https://account.windowsazure.com/signup?offer=MS-AZR-0110P)</ept> will take you through a series of steps to help you access your directory through the Azure Management Portal.",
      "pos": [
        4072,
        4385
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][4]",
      "pos": [
        4387,
        4393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have signed in successfully, you will need to complete a 2nd factor authentication screen (below) by providing a mobile phone number and validating it.",
      "pos": [
        4395,
        4555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After this you will be able to activate your access to Azure Active Directory by selecting <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sign Up<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4556,
        4659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][5]",
      "pos": [
        4661,
        4667
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4669,
        4933
      ],
      "content": "The activation may take a few minutes, as illustrated below, once your access is active the brown bar will disappear and you will be able to click the Portal link in the top right corner or navigate to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://manage.windowsazure.com)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "![][6]",
      "pos": [
        4935,
        4941
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, your Azure access will be limited to Azure Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        4943,
        5017
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][7]",
      "pos": [
        5019,
        5025
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You may already have had access to Azure from prior usage; in addition, you can upgrade your Access Azure Active Directory to full Azure access by activating additional Azure subscriptions.",
      "pos": [
        5027,
        5216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In these cases the Management Portal will have more capabilities as in the following.",
      "pos": [
        5217,
        5302
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][8]",
      "pos": [
        5304,
        5310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you attempt to activate your access to Azure Active Directory prior to receiving the Welcome email above you may experience the following error message.",
      "pos": [
        5312,
        5467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please try again in a few minutes once you have received the email.",
      "pos": [
        5468,
        5535
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][9]",
      "pos": [
        5537,
        5543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "New administrators in your subscription can also activate their access to the Management Portal through this link.",
      "pos": [
        5545,
        5659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 4: Assign license to user accounts",
      "pos": [
        5664,
        5703
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you can start using the plan you purchased, you’ll need to manually assign licenses to user accounts within your organization so that they can use the rich features provided with Premium.",
      "pos": [
        5705,
        5899
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following steps to assign licenses to users so they can use Azure Active Directory Premium features.",
      "pos": [
        5900,
        6008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To assign licenses to users:",
      "pos": [
        6010,
        6038
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign into the Management Portal as the global administrator of the directory you wish to customize.",
      "pos": [
        6043,
        6142
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6146,
        6238
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active Directory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then select the directory where you want to assign licenses."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6242,
        6367
      ],
      "content": "Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Licenses<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Active Directory Premium<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Enterprise Mobility Suite<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Assign<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "![][10]",
      "pos": [
        6373,
        6380
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the dialog box, select the users you want to assign licenses to, and then click the check mark icon to save the changes.",
      "pos": [
        6385,
        6508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][11]",
      "pos": [
        6514,
        6521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "License restrictions",
      "pos": [
        6526,
        6546
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some license plans are subsets or supersets of other license plans.",
      "pos": [
        6548,
        6615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In most cases, a user cannot be assigned a license plan that has already been assigned to them.",
      "pos": [
        6616,
        6711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If it’s your intention to assign a license plan that is a superset, you’ll need to first remove the subset license plan.",
      "pos": [
        6712,
        6832
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "License requirements",
      "pos": [
        6837,
        6857
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you assign a license to a user, you can specify a primary usage location in the properties of their account as shown below.",
      "pos": [
        6859,
        6987
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a usage location is not specified, the tenant’s location is automatically assigned to the user.",
      "pos": [
        6988,
        7086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][12]",
      "pos": [
        7088,
        7095
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The availability of services and features for a Microsoft cloud service varies by country or region.",
      "pos": [
        7097,
        7197
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A service, such as Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP), may be available in one country or region, and not available in another.",
      "pos": [
        7198,
        7326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Features within a service can be restricted for legal reasons in certain countries or regions.",
      "pos": [
        7327,
        7421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To see if a service or feature is available with or without restrictions, look for your country or region on the service’s license restrictions site.",
      "pos": [
        7422,
        7571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What's next",
      "pos": [
        7576,
        7587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add company branding to your Sign In and Access Panel pages",
      "pos": [
        7592,
        7651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "View your access and usage reports",
      "pos": [
        7698,
        7732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        8646,
        8650
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Getting started with Azure Active Directory Premium\"\n    description=\"A topic that explains how to sign up for Azure Active Directory Premium edition.\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"MarkusVi\"\n    writer=\"markvi\"\n    manager=\"stevenpo\" \n    editor=\"LisaToft\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n    ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"get-started-article\"\n    ms.date=\"08/14/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"markvi\"/>\n\n# Getting started with Azure Active Directory Premium\n\nAzure Active Directory comes in three editions: Free, Basic, and Premium. The Free edition is included with an Azure or Office 365 subscription. The Basic and Premium editions are available through a [Microsoft Enterprise Agreement](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/licensing/licensing-programs/enterprise.aspx) or the [Open Volume License](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/licensing/licensing-programs/open-license.aspx) program. Azure and Office 365 subscribers can also buy Active Directory Premium online. [Sign in here](https://portal.office.com/Commerce/Catalog.aspx) to buy it.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE]\nAzure Active Directory Premium and Basic editions are available for customers in China using the worldwide instance of Azure Active Directory. Azure Active Directory Premium and Basic editions are not currently supported in the Microsoft Azure service operated by 21Vianet in China. For more information, contact us at the [Azure Active Directory Forum](http://feedback.azure.com/forums/169401-azure-active-directory).\n\nAzure Active Directory Premium is also included in the **Enterprise Mobility Suite**. Enterprise Mobility Suite is a cost effective way for organizations to use Microsoft Intune, Azure Rights Management and the Active Directory Premium services together under one licensing plan. For more information, see the [Enterprise Mobility Suite](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/server-cloud/enterprise-mobility/overview.aspx) web site.\n\nTo start using Azure Active Directory Premium features today, follow the steps below. The same steps apply to the Azure Active Directory Basic edition.\n\n## Step 1: Sign up for Active Directory Premium\n\nTo sign up, see the [Volume Licensing](http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/licensing/how-to-buy/how-to-buy.aspx) web site.\n\n## Step 2: Activate your license plan\n\nIf this is the first time you have purchased a license plan through Microsoft’s Enterprise Volume Licensing program, you will need to first activate your license plan before you can start assigning licenses from within your Azure Active Directory directory. To do this, you must click on either the Sign In or Sign Up link found in the confirmation email (see below) you will receive after your very first license plan purchase has been completed. On any subsequent purchase for this directory the licenses will automatically be activated in the same directory.\n\n![][1]\n\nIf you have an existing tenant, select the **Sign In** link to sign in with your existing administrator account. It’s important that you sign in with the global administrator credentials from the directory where the licenses must be activated.\n\nIf you want to create a new Azure Active Directory tenant to use with your licensing plan then you should select the **Sign Up** link which will take you to the following screen.\n\n![][2]\n\nOnce you are done with either the sign up process or the sign in process that was initiated from the email, you will see the following screen confirming that the license plan is being activated for your tenant.\n\n![][3]\n\n## Step 3: Activate your Azure Active Directory access\n\nOnce the licenses are provisioned to your directory you will be receive a Welcome email (see below) that confirms you can start managing your Azure Active Directory Premium or Enterprise Mobility Suite licenses and features. If you have used Microsoft Azure before, you can proceed to http://manage.windowsazure.com to assign the new licenses (see Step 4 below for further instructions). If you are new to Microsoft Azure, selecting the Sign In link on the email, or going to the [Access to Azure Active Directory activation page](https://account.windowsazure.com/signup?offer=MS-AZR-0110P) will take you through a series of steps to help you access your directory through the Azure Management Portal.\n\n![][4]\n\nOnce you have signed in successfully, you will need to complete a 2nd factor authentication screen (below) by providing a mobile phone number and validating it. After this you will be able to activate your access to Azure Active Directory by selecting **Sign Up**.\n\n![][5]\n\nThe activation may take a few minutes, as illustrated below, once your access is active the brown bar will disappear and you will be able to click the Portal link in the top right corner or navigate to the [Azure Management Portal](http://manage.windowsazure.com).\n\n![][6]\n\nIn this case, your Azure access will be limited to Azure Active Directory.\n\n![][7]\n\nYou may already have had access to Azure from prior usage; in addition, you can upgrade your Access Azure Active Directory to full Azure access by activating additional Azure subscriptions. In these cases the Management Portal will have more capabilities as in the following.\n\n![][8]\n\nIf you attempt to activate your access to Azure Active Directory prior to receiving the Welcome email above you may experience the following error message. Please try again in a few minutes once you have received the email.\n\n![][9]\n\nNew administrators in your subscription can also activate their access to the Management Portal through this link.\n\n## Step 4: Assign license to user accounts\n\nBefore you can start using the plan you purchased, you’ll need to manually assign licenses to user accounts within your organization so that they can use the rich features provided with Premium. Use the following steps to assign licenses to users so they can use Azure Active Directory Premium features.\n\nTo assign licenses to users:\n\n1. Sign into the Management Portal as the global administrator of the directory you wish to customize.\n2. Click **Active Directory**, and then select the directory where you want to assign licenses.\n3. Select the **Licenses** tab, select **Active Directory Premium** or **Enterprise Mobility Suite**, and then click **Assign**.\n\n    ![][10]\n\n4. In the dialog box, select the users you want to assign licenses to, and then click the check mark icon to save the changes.\n\n    ![][11]\n\n## License restrictions\n\nSome license plans are subsets or supersets of other license plans. In most cases, a user cannot be assigned a license plan that has already been assigned to them. If it’s your intention to assign a license plan that is a superset, you’ll need to first remove the subset license plan.\n\n## License requirements\n\nWhen you assign a license to a user, you can specify a primary usage location in the properties of their account as shown below. If a usage location is not specified, the tenant’s location is automatically assigned to the user.\n\n![][12]\n\nThe availability of services and features for a Microsoft cloud service varies by country or region. A service, such as Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP), may be available in one country or region, and not available in another. Features within a service can be restricted for legal reasons in certain countries or regions. To see if a service or feature is available with or without restrictions, look for your country or region on the service’s license restrictions site.\n\n## What's next\n\n- [Add company branding to your Sign In and Access Panel pages](active-directory-add-company-branding.md)\n- [View your access and usage reports](active-directory-view-access-usage-reports.md)\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/MOLSEmail.png\n[2]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/MOLSAccountProfile.png\n[3]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/MOLSThankYou.png\n[4]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/AADEmail.png\n[5]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/SignUppage.png\n[6]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/Subscriptionspage.png\n[7]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/Premiuminportal.png\n[8]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/Premiuminportal_large.png\n[9]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/Signuppage_oops.png\n[10]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/contosolicenseplan.png\n[11]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/Assignlicensespicker.png\n[12]: ./media/active-directory-get-started-premium/Usagelocation.png\n\ntest\n"
}