{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "When you no longer need a data disk that's attached to a virtual machine, you can easily detach it.",
      "pos": [
        66,
        165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This removes the disk from the virtual machine, but doesn't remove it from storage.",
      "pos": [
        166,
        249
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to use the existing data on the disk again, you can reattach it to the same virtual machine, or another one.",
      "pos": [
        250,
        370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> A virtual machine in Azure uses different types of disks -- an operating system disk, a local temporary disk, and optional data disks.",
      "pos": [
        376,
        523
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data disks are the recommended way to store data for a virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        524,
        595
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About Disks and VHDs for Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">](../../virtual-machines-disks-vhds.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        596,
        695
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's not possible to detach an operating system disk unless you also delete the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        696,
        792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Find the disk",
      "pos": [
        797,
        810
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don't know the name of the disk or want to verify it before you detach it, follow these steps.",
      "pos": [
        814,
        915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Azure automatically assigns a name to the disk when you attach it.",
      "pos": [
        919,
        998
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name consists of the cloud service name, the virtual machine name, and a number.",
      "pos": [
        999,
        1083
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1088,
        1182
      ],
      "content": "If you haven't already done so, sign in to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://manage.windowsazure.com)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1187,
        1279
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, click the name of virtual machine, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Disks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, the table lists the name and type of all attached disks.",
      "pos": [
        1284,
        1357
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, this screen shows a virtual machine with one operating system (OS) disk and one data disk:",
      "pos": [
        1358,
        1461
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Find data disk",
      "pos": [
        1469,
        1483
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Detach the disk",
      "pos": [
        1549,
        1564
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you find the name of the disk, you're ready to detach it:",
      "pos": [
        1568,
        1631
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1636,
        1774
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, click the name of the virtual machine that has the data disk you want to detach, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1778,
        1822
      ],
      "content": "From the command bar, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Detach Disk<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the data disk, and then click the check mark to detach it.",
      "pos": [
        1827,
        1892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Detach disk details",
      "pos": [
        1900,
        1919
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The disk remains in storage but is no longer attached to a virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        1985,
        2060
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties writer=\"kathydav\" editor=\"tysonn\" manager=\"timlt\" />\n\nWhen you no longer need a data disk that's attached to a virtual machine, you can easily detach it. This removes the disk from the virtual machine, but doesn't remove it from storage. If you want to use the existing data on the disk again, you can reattach it to the same virtual machine, or another one.  \n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] A virtual machine in Azure uses different types of disks -- an operating system disk, a local temporary disk, and optional data disks. Data disks are the recommended way to store data for a virtual machine. For details, see [About Disks and VHDs for Virtual Machines](../../virtual-machines-disks-vhds.md). It's not possible to detach an operating system disk unless you also delete the virtual machine.\n\n## Find the disk##\n\nIf you don't know the name of the disk or want to verify it before you detach it, follow these steps.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Azure automatically assigns a name to the disk when you attach it. The name consists of the cloud service name, the virtual machine name, and a number.\n\n1. If you haven't already done so, sign in to the [Azure Portal](http://manage.windowsazure.com).\n\n2. Click **Virtual Machines**, click the name of virtual machine, and then click **Dashboard**.\n\n3. Under **Disks**, the table lists the name and type of all attached disks. For example, this screen shows a virtual machine with one operating system (OS) disk and one data disk:\n\n    ![Find data disk](./media/howto-detach-disk-windows-linux/FindDataDisks.png)\n\n\n## Detach the disk##\n\nAfter you find the name of the disk, you're ready to detach it:\n\n1. Click **Virtual Machines**, click the name of the virtual machine that has the data disk you want to detach, and then click **Dashboard**.\n2. From the command bar, click **Detach Disk**.\n\n3. Select the data disk, and then click the check mark to detach it.\n\n    ![Detach disk details](./media/howto-detach-disk-windows-linux/DetachDiskDetails.png)\n\nThe disk remains in storage but is no longer attached to a virtual machine.\n"
}