{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Manage your StorSimple backup policies | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        83
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Explains how you can use the StorSimple Manager service to create and manage manual backups, backup schedules, and backup retention.",
      "pos": [
        101,
        233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the StorSimple Manager service to manage backup policies",
      "pos": [
        513,
        573
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        578,
        586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tutorial explains how to use the StorSimple Manager service <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Backup Policies<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to control backup processes and backup retention for your StorSimple volumes.",
      "pos": [
        588,
        755
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It also describes how to complete a manual backup.",
      "pos": [
        756,
        806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Backup Policies<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page allows you to manage backup policies and schedule local and cloud snapshots.",
      "pos": [
        808,
        913
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(Backup policies are used to configure backup schedules and backup retention for a collection of volumes.) Backup policies enable you to take a snapshot of multiple volumes simultaneously.",
      "pos": [
        914,
        1102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that the backups created by a backup policy will be crash-consistent copies.",
      "pos": [
        1103,
        1190
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This page lists the backup policies, their types, the associated volumes, the number of backups retained, and the option to enable these policies.",
      "pos": [
        1191,
        1337
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1339,
        1462
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Backup Policies<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page also allows you to filter the existing backup policies by one or more of the following fields:"
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Policy name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The name associated with the policy.",
      "pos": [
        1466,
        1520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The different types of policies include:",
      "pos": [
        1521,
        1561
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduled policies, which are explicitly created by the user.",
      "pos": [
        1568,
        1629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automatic policies, which are created when the default backup for this volume option was enabled at the time of volume creation.",
      "pos": [
        1635,
        1763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These policies are named as VolumeName_Default where Volume name refers to the name of the StorSimple volume configured by the user in the Management Portal.",
      "pos": [
        1764,
        1921
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The automatic policies result in daily cloud snapshots beginning at 22:30 device time.",
      "pos": [
        1922,
        2008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Imported policies, which were originally created in the StorSimple Snapshot Manager.",
      "pos": [
        2014,
        2098
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These have a tag that describes the StorSimple Snapshot Manager host that the policies were imported from.",
      "pos": [
        2099,
        2205
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Volumes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The volumes associated with the policy.",
      "pos": [
        2209,
        2262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All the volumes associated with a backup policy are grouped together when backups are created.",
      "pos": [
        2263,
        2357
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2361,
        2470
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Last successful backup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The date and time of the last successful backup that was taken with this policy."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2474,
        2577
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next backup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The date and time of the next scheduled backup that will be initiated by this policy."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2581,
        2655
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Schedules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The number of schedules associated with the backup policy."
    },
    {
      "content": "The frequently used operations that you can perform from this page are:",
      "pos": [
        2657,
        2728
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add a backup policy",
      "pos": [
        2732,
        2751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add or modify a schedule",
      "pos": [
        2755,
        2779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete a backup policy",
      "pos": [
        2783,
        2805
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Take a manual backup",
      "pos": [
        2809,
        2829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a custom backup policy with multiple volumes and schedules",
      "pos": [
        2833,
        2898
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add a backup policy",
      "pos": [
        2904,
        2923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add a backup policy to automatically schedule your backups.",
      "pos": [
        2925,
        2984
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Perform the following steps in the Management Portal to add a backup policy for your StorSimple device.",
      "pos": [
        2985,
        3088
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you add the policy, you can define a schedule (see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Add or modify a schedule<ept id=\"p1\">](#add-or-modify-a-schedule)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3089,
        3200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add or modify a schedule",
      "pos": [
        3302,
        3326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can add or modify a schedule that is attached to an existing backup policy on your StorSimple device.",
      "pos": [
        3328,
        3433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Perform the following steps in the Management Portal to add or modify a schedule.",
      "pos": [
        3434,
        3515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete a backup policy",
      "pos": [
        3634,
        3656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Perform the following steps in the Management Portal to delete a backup policy on your StorSimple device.",
      "pos": [
        3658,
        3763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Take a manual backup",
      "pos": [
        3871,
        3891
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Perform the following steps in the Management Portal to create an on-demand (manual) backup for a single volume.",
      "pos": [
        3893,
        4005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a custom backup policy with multiple volumes and schedules",
      "pos": [
        4112,
        4177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Perform the following steps in the Management Portal to create a custom backup policy that has multiple volumes and schedules.",
      "pos": [
        4179,
        4305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        4427,
        4437
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4439,
        4568
      ],
      "content": "Learn how to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Use StorSimple Snapshot Manager to view and manage backup jobs<ept id=\"p1\">](storsimple-snapshot-manager-manage-backup-jobs.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Manage your StorSimple backup policies | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Explains how you can use the StorSimple Manager service to create and manage manual backups, backup schedules, and backup retention.\"\n   services=\"storsimple\"\n   documentationCenter=\"NA\"\n   authors=\"SharS\"\n   manager=\"carolz\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"storsimple\"\n   ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"TBD\"\n   ms.date=\"08/27/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"v-sharos\"/>\n\n# Use the StorSimple Manager service to manage backup policies\n\n## Overview\n\nThis tutorial explains how to use the StorSimple Manager service **Backup Policies** page to control backup processes and backup retention for your StorSimple volumes. It also describes how to complete a manual backup.\n\nThe **Backup Policies** page allows you to manage backup policies and schedule local and cloud snapshots. (Backup policies are used to configure backup schedules and backup retention for a collection of volumes.) Backup policies enable you to take a snapshot of multiple volumes simultaneously. This means that the backups created by a backup policy will be crash-consistent copies. This page lists the backup policies, their types, the associated volumes, the number of backups retained, and the option to enable these policies.\n\nThe **Backup Policies** page also allows you to filter the existing backup policies by one or more of the following fields:\n\n- **Policy name** – The name associated with the policy. The different types of policies include:\n\n   - Scheduled policies, which are explicitly created by the user.\n   - Automatic policies, which are created when the default backup for this volume option was enabled at the time of volume creation. These policies are named as VolumeName_Default where Volume name refers to the name of the StorSimple volume configured by the user in the Management Portal. The automatic policies result in daily cloud snapshots beginning at 22:30 device time.\n   - Imported policies, which were originally created in the StorSimple Snapshot Manager. These have a tag that describes the StorSimple Snapshot Manager host that the policies were imported from.\n\n- **Volumes** – The volumes associated with the policy. All the volumes associated with a backup policy are grouped together when backups are created.\n\n- **Last successful backup** – The date and time of the last successful backup that was taken with this policy.\n\n- **Next backup** – The date and time of the next scheduled backup that will be initiated by this policy.\n\n- **Schedules** – The number of schedules associated with the backup policy.\n\nThe frequently used operations that you can perform from this page are:\n\n- Add a backup policy \n- Add or modify a schedule \n- Delete a backup policy \n- Take a manual backup \n- Create a custom backup policy with multiple volumes and schedules \n\n## Add a backup policy\n\nAdd a backup policy to automatically schedule your backups. Perform the following steps in the Management Portal to add a backup policy for your StorSimple device. After you add the policy, you can define a schedule (see [Add or modify a schedule](#add-or-modify-a-schedule).\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [storsimple-add-backup-policy](../../includes/storsimple-add-backup-policy.md)]\n\n\n## Add or modify a schedule\n\nYou can add or modify a schedule that is attached to an existing backup policy on your StorSimple device. Perform the following steps in the Management Portal to add or modify a schedule.\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [storsimple-add-modify-backup-schedule](../../includes/storsimple-add-modify-backup-schedule.md)]\n\n## Delete a backup policy\n\nPerform the following steps in the Management Portal to delete a backup policy on your StorSimple device.\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [storsimple-delete-backup-policy](../../includes/storsimple-delete-backup-policy.md)]\n\n\n## Take a manual backup\n\nPerform the following steps in the Management Portal to create an on-demand (manual) backup for a single volume.\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [storsimple-create-manual-backup](../../includes/storsimple-create-manual-backup.md)]\n\n## Create a custom backup policy with multiple volumes and schedules\n\nPerform the following steps in the Management Portal to create a custom backup policy that has multiple volumes and schedules.\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [storsimple-create-custom-backup-policy](../../includes/storsimple-create-custom-backup-policy.md)]\n\n\n## Next steps\n\nLearn how to [Use StorSimple Snapshot Manager to view and manage backup jobs](storsimple-snapshot-manager-manage-backup-jobs.md). "
}