{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Using Twilio for Voice, VoIP, and SMS Messaging in Azure",
      "pos": [
        28,
        84
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to make a phone call and send a SMS message with the Twilio API service on Azure.",
      "pos": [
        104,
        195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Code samples written in Node.js.",
      "pos": [
        196,
        228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Twilio for Voice, VoIP, and SMS Messaging in Azure",
      "pos": [
        534,
        590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This guide demonstrates how to build apps that communicate with Twilio and node.js on Azure.",
      "pos": [
        592,
        684
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Twilio?",
      "pos": [
        706,
        721
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Twilio is an API platform that makes it easy for developers to make and receive phone calls, send and receive text messages, and embed VoIP calling into browser-based and native mobile applications.",
      "pos": [
        723,
        921
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let's briefly go over how this works before diving in.",
      "pos": [
        923,
        977
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Receiving Calls and Text Messages",
      "pos": [
        983,
        1016
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Twilio allows developers to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>purchase programmable phone numbers<ept id=\"p1\">][purchase_phone]</ept> which can be used to both send and receive calls and text messages.",
      "pos": [
        1018,
        1167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a Twilio number receives an inbound call or text, Twilio will send your web application an HTTP POST or GET request, asking you for instructions on how to handle the call or text.",
      "pos": [
        1169,
        1353
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your server will respond to Twilio's HTTP request with <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>TwiML<ept id=\"p1\">][twiml]</ept>, a simple set of XML tags that contain instructions on how to handle a call or text.",
      "pos": [
        1355,
        1509
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We will see examples of TwiML in just a moment.",
      "pos": [
        1511,
        1558
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Making Calls and Sending Text Messages",
      "pos": [
        1564,
        1602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By making HTTP requests to the Twilio web service API, developers can send text messages or initiate outbound phone calls.",
      "pos": [
        1604,
        1726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For outbound calls, the developer must also specify a URL that returns TwiML instructions for how to handle the outbound call once it is connected.",
      "pos": [
        1728,
        1875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Embedding VoIP Capabilities in UI code (JavaScript, iOS, or Android)",
      "pos": [
        1881,
        1949
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Twilio provides a client-side SDK which can turn any desktop web browser, iOS app, or Android app into a VoIP phone.",
      "pos": [
        1951,
        2067
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this article, we will focus on how to use VoIP calling in the browser.",
      "pos": [
        2069,
        2142
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition to the Twilio JavaScript SDK running in the browser, a server-side application (our node.js application) must be used to issue a \"capability token\" to the JavaScript client.",
      "pos": [
        2144,
        2329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can read more about using VoIP with node.js <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>on the Twilio dev blog<ept id=\"p1\">][voipnode]</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2331,
        2414
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign Up For Twilio (Microsoft Discount)",
      "pos": [
        2436,
        2475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before using Twilio services, you must first <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>sign up for an account<ept id=\"p1\">][signup]</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2477,
        2555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Azure customers receive a special discount - <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>be sure to sign up here<ept id=\"p1\">][signup]</ept>!",
      "pos": [
        2557,
        2646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create and Deploy a node.js Azure Website",
      "pos": [
        2671,
        2712
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, you will need to create a node.js website running on Azure.",
      "pos": [
        2714,
        2779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>The official documentation for doing this is located here<ept id=\"p1\">][azure_new_site]</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2781,
        2857
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At a high level, you will be doing the following:",
      "pos": [
        2859,
        2908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Signing up for an Azure account, if you don't have one already",
      "pos": [
        2912,
        2974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using the Azure admin console to create a new website",
      "pos": [
        2977,
        3030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adding source control support (we will assume you used git)",
      "pos": [
        3033,
        3092
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3095,
        3160
      ],
      "content": "Creating a file <ph id=\"ph1\">`server.js`</ph> with a simple node.js web application"
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploying this simple application to Azure",
      "pos": [
        3163,
        3205
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure the Twilio Module",
      "pos": [
        3233,
        3260
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, we will begin to write a simple node.js application which makes use of the Twilio API.",
      "pos": [
        3262,
        3354
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before we begin, we need to configure our Twilio account credentials.",
      "pos": [
        3356,
        3425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuring Twilio Credentials in System Environment Variables",
      "pos": [
        3433,
        3495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In order to make authenticated requests against the Twilio back end, we need our account SID and auth token, which function as the username and password set for our Twilio account.",
      "pos": [
        3497,
        3677
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The most secure way to configure these for use with the node module in Azure is via system environment variables, which you can set directly in the Azure admin console.",
      "pos": [
        3678,
        3846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select your node.js website, and click the \"CONFIGURE\" link.",
      "pos": [
        3848,
        3908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you scroll down a bit, you will see an area where you can set configuration properties for your application.",
      "pos": [
        3910,
        4021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enter your Twilio account credentials (<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>found on your Twilio dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">][twilio_dashboard]</ept>) as shown - make sure to name them \"TWILIO_ACCOUNT_SID\" and \"TWILIO_AUTH_TOKEN\", respectively:",
      "pos": [
        4023,
        4207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure admin console",
      "pos": [
        4211,
        4230
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have configured these variables, restart your application in the Azure console.",
      "pos": [
        4254,
        4342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Declaring the Twilio module in package.json",
      "pos": [
        4348,
        4391
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, we need to create a package.json to manage our node module dependencies via <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p1\">npm]</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4393,
        4481
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At the same level as the \"server.js\" file you created in the Azure/node.js tutorial, create a file named \"package.json\".",
      "pos": [
        4483,
        4603
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inside this file, place the following:",
      "pos": [
        4605,
        4643
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "{",
      "pos": [
        4647,
        4648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\"name\": \"application-name\",",
      "pos": [
        4653,
        4680
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\"version\": \"0.0.1\",",
      "pos": [
        4685,
        4704
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\"private\": true,",
      "pos": [
        4709,
        4725
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\"scripts\": {",
      "pos": [
        4730,
        4742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\"start\": \"node server\"",
      "pos": [
        4749,
        4771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "},",
      "pos": [
        4776,
        4778
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\"dependencies\": {",
      "pos": [
        4783,
        4800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\"express\": \"3.1.0\",",
      "pos": [
        4807,
        4826
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\"ejs\": \"<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>\",\n      \"twilio\":\"<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>\"",
      "pos": [
        4833,
        4863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "}",
      "pos": [
        4868,
        4869
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "}",
      "pos": [
        4872,
        4873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This declares the twilio module as a dependency, as well as the popular <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>express web framework<ept id=\"p1\">][express]</ept> and the EJS template engine.",
      "pos": [
        4875,
        5008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Okay, now we're all set - let's write some code!",
      "pos": [
        5010,
        5058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make an Outbound Call",
      "pos": [
        5082,
        5103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let's create a simple form that will place a call to a number we choose.",
      "pos": [
        5105,
        5177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open up server.js, and enter the following code.",
      "pos": [
        5179,
        5227
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note where it says \"CHANGE_ME\" - put the name of your azure website there:",
      "pos": [
        5229,
        5303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, create a directory called \"views\" - inside this directory, create a file named \"index.ejs\" with the following contents:",
      "pos": [
        7470,
        7595
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Now, deploy your website to Azure and open your home .",
      "pos": [
        8064,
        8118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should be able to enter your phone number in the text field, and receive a call from your Twilio number!",
      "pos": [
        8120,
        8228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Send an SMS Message",
      "pos": [
        8255,
        8274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Now, let's set up a user interface and form handling logic to send a text message.",
      "pos": [
        8276,
        8358
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open up \"server.js\", and add the following code after the last call to \"app.post\":",
      "pos": [
        8360,
        8442
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In \"views/index.ejs\", add another form under the first one to submit a number and a text message:",
      "pos": [
        8987,
        9084
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Redeploy your application to Azure, and you should now be able to submit that form and send yourself (or any of your closest friends) a text message!",
      "pos": [
        9361,
        9510
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        9535,
        9545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You have now learned the basics of using node.js and Twilio to build apps that communicate.",
      "pos": [
        9547,
        9638
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "But these examples barely scratch the surface of what's possible with Twilio and node.js.",
      "pos": [
        9640,
        9729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information using Twilio with node.js, check out the following resources:",
      "pos": [
        9731,
        9813
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Official module docs",
      "pos": [
        9818,
        9838
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tutorial on VoIP with node.js applications",
      "pos": [
        9849,
        9891
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Votr - a real-time SMS voting application with node.js and CouchDB (three parts)",
      "pos": [
        9906,
        9986
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pair programming in the browser with node.js",
      "pos": [
        9997,
        10041
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We hope you love hacking node.js and Twilio on Azure!",
      "pos": [
        10050,
        10103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        10912,
        10916
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Using Twilio for Voice, VoIP, and SMS Messaging in Azure\" \n    description=\"Learn how to make a phone call and send a SMS message with the Twilio API service on Azure. Code samples written in Node.js.\" \n    services=\"\" \n    documentationCenter=\"nodejs\" \n    authors=\"MikeWasson\" \n    manager=\"wpickett\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"multiple\" \n    ms.workload=\"na\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"nodejs\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"11/25/2014\" \n    ms.author=\"mwasson\"/>\n\n\n# Using Twilio for Voice, VoIP, and SMS Messaging in Azure\n\nThis guide demonstrates how to build apps that communicate with Twilio and node.js on Azure.\n\n<a id=\"whatis\"/>\n## What is Twilio?\n\nTwilio is an API platform that makes it easy for developers to make and receive phone calls, send and receive text messages, and embed VoIP calling into browser-based and native mobile applications.  Let's briefly go over how this works before diving in.\n\n### Receiving Calls and Text Messages\n\nTwilio allows developers to [purchase programmable phone numbers][purchase_phone] which can be used to both send and receive calls and text messages.  When a Twilio number receives an inbound call or text, Twilio will send your web application an HTTP POST or GET request, asking you for instructions on how to handle the call or text.  Your server will respond to Twilio's HTTP request with [TwiML][twiml], a simple set of XML tags that contain instructions on how to handle a call or text.  We will see examples of TwiML in just a moment.\n\n### Making Calls and Sending Text Messages\n\nBy making HTTP requests to the Twilio web service API, developers can send text messages or initiate outbound phone calls.  For outbound calls, the developer must also specify a URL that returns TwiML instructions for how to handle the outbound call once it is connected.\n\n### Embedding VoIP Capabilities in UI code (JavaScript, iOS, or Android)\n\nTwilio provides a client-side SDK which can turn any desktop web browser, iOS app, or Android app into a VoIP phone.  In this article, we will focus on how to use VoIP calling in the browser.  In addition to the Twilio JavaScript SDK running in the browser, a server-side application (our node.js application) must be used to issue a \"capability token\" to the JavaScript client.  You can read more about using VoIP with node.js [on the Twilio dev blog][voipnode].\n\n<a id=\"signup\"/>\n## Sign Up For Twilio (Microsoft Discount)\n\nBefore using Twilio services, you must first [sign up for an account][signup].  Microsoft Azure customers receive a special discount - [be sure to sign up here][signup]!\n\n<a id=\"azuresite\"/>\n## Create and Deploy a node.js Azure Website\n\nNext, you will need to create a node.js website running on Azure.  [The official documentation for doing this is located here][azure_new_site].  At a high level, you will be doing the following:\n\n* Signing up for an Azure account, if you don't have one already\n* Using the Azure admin console to create a new website\n* Adding source control support (we will assume you used git)\n* Creating a file `server.js` with a simple node.js web application\n* Deploying this simple application to Azure\n\n<a id=\"twiliomodule\"/>\n## Configure the Twilio Module\n\nNext, we will begin to write a simple node.js application which makes use of the Twilio API.  Before we begin, we need to configure our Twilio account credentials.  \n\n### Configuring Twilio Credentials in System Environment Variables\n\nIn order to make authenticated requests against the Twilio back end, we need our account SID and auth token, which function as the username and password set for our Twilio account. The most secure way to configure these for use with the node module in Azure is via system environment variables, which you can set directly in the Azure admin console.\n\nSelect your node.js website, and click the \"CONFIGURE\" link.  If you scroll down a bit, you will see an area where you can set configuration properties for your application.  Enter your Twilio account credentials ([found on your Twilio dashboard][twilio_dashboard]) as shown - make sure to name them \"TWILIO_ACCOUNT_SID\" and \"TWILIO_AUTH_TOKEN\", respectively:\n\n![Azure admin console][azure-admin-console]\n\nOnce you have configured these variables, restart your application in the Azure console.\n\n### Declaring the Twilio module in package.json\n\nNext, we need to create a package.json to manage our node module dependencies via [npm].  At the same level as the \"server.js\" file you created in the Azure/node.js tutorial, create a file named \"package.json\".  Inside this file, place the following:\n\n  {\n    \"name\": \"application-name\",\n    \"version\": \"0.0.1\",\n    \"private\": true,\n    \"scripts\": {\n      \"start\": \"node server\"\n    },\n    \"dependencies\": {\n      \"express\": \"3.1.0\",\n      \"ejs\": \"*\",\n      \"twilio\":\"*\"\n    }\n  }\n\nThis declares the twilio module as a dependency, as well as the popular [express web framework][express] and the EJS template engine.  Okay, now we're all set - let's write some code!\n\n<a id=\"makecall\"/>\n## Make an Outbound Call\n\nLet's create a simple form that will place a call to a number we choose.  Open up server.js, and enter the following code.  Note where it says \"CHANGE_ME\" - put the name of your azure website there:\n\n    // Module dependencies\n    var express = require('express'), \n      path = require('path'), \n      http = require('http'), \n      twilio = require('twilio');\n\n    // Create Express web application\n    var app = express();\n\n    // Express configuration\n    app.configure(function(){\n      app.set('port', process.env.PORT || 3000);\n      app.set('views', __dirname + '/views');\n      app.set('view engine', 'ejs');\n      app.use(express.favicon());\n      app.use(express.logger('dev'));\n      app.use(express.bodyParser());\n      app.use(express.methodOverride());\n      app.use(app.router);\n      app.use(express.static(path.join(__dirname, 'public')));\n    });\n    app.configure('development', function(){\n      app.use(express.errorHandler());\n    });\n\n    // Render an HTML user interface for the application's home page\n    app.get('/', function(request, response) {\n      response.render('index');\n    });\n\n    // Handle the form POST to place a call\n    app.post('/call', function(request, response) {\n      var client = twilio();\n      client.makeCall({\n          // make a call to this number\n          to:request.body.number,\n\n          // Change to a Twilio number you bought - see:\n          // https://www.twilio.com/user/account/phone-numbers/incoming\n          from:'+15558675309',\n\n          // A URL in our app which generates TwiML\n          // Change \"CHANGE_ME\" to your app's name\n          url:'https://CHANGE_ME.azurewebsites.net/outbound_call'\n      }, function(error, data) {\n          // Go back to the home page\n          response.redirect('/');\n      });\n    });\n\n    // Generate TwiML to handle an outbound call\n    app.post('/outbound_call', function(request, response) {\n      var twiml = new twilio.TwimlResponse();\n\n      // Say a message to the call's receiver \n      twiml.say('hello - thanks for checking out Twilio and Azure', {\n          voice:'woman'\n      });\n\n      response.set('Content-Type', 'text/xml');\n      response.send(twiml.toString());\n    });\n\n    // Start server\n    http.createServer(app).listen(app.get('port'), function(){\n      console.log(\"Express server listening on port \" + app.get('port'));\n    });\n\nNext, create a directory called \"views\" - inside this directory, create a file named \"index.ejs\" with the following contents:\n\n    <!DOCTYPE html>\n    <html>\n    <head>\n      <title>Twilio Test</title>\n      <style>\n        input { height:20px; width:300px; font-size:18px; margin:5px; padding:5px; }\n      </style>\n    </head>\n    <body>\n      <h1>Twilio Test</h1>\n      <form action=\"/call\" method=\"POST\">\n          <input placeholder=\"Enter a phone number\" name=\"number\"/>\n          <br/>\n          <input type=\"submit\" value=\"Call the number above\"/>\n      </form>\n    </body>\n    </html>\n\nNow, deploy your website to Azure and open your home .  You should be able to enter your phone number in the text field, and receive a call from your Twilio number!\n\n<a id=\"sendmessage\"/>\n## Send an SMS Message\n\nNow, let's set up a user interface and form handling logic to send a text message.  Open up \"server.js\", and add the following code after the last call to \"app.post\":\n\n    app.post('/sms', function(request, response) {\n      var client = twilio();\n      client.sendSms({\n          // send a text to this number\n          to:request.body.number,\n\n          // A Twilio number you bought - see:\n          // https://www.twilio.com/user/account/phone-numbers/incoming\n          from:'+15558675309',\n\n          // The body of the text message\n          body: request.body.message\n          \n      }, function(error, data) {\n          // Go back to the home page\n          response.redirect('/');\n      });\n    });\n\nIn \"views/index.ejs\", add another form under the first one to submit a number and a text message:\n\n    <form action=\"/sms\" method=\"POST\">\n      <input placeholder=\"Enter a phone number\" name=\"number\"/>\n      <br/>\n      <input placeholder=\"Enter a message to send\" name=\"message\"/>\n      <br/>\n      <input type=\"submit\" value=\"Send text to the number above\"/>\n    </form>\n\nRedeploy your application to Azure, and you should now be able to submit that form and send yourself (or any of your closest friends) a text message!\n\n<a id=\"nextsteps\"/>\n## Next Steps\n\nYou have now learned the basics of using node.js and Twilio to build apps that communicate.  But these examples barely scratch the surface of what's possible with Twilio and node.js.  For more information using Twilio with node.js, check out the following resources:\n\n* [Official module docs][docs]\n* [Tutorial on VoIP with node.js applications][voipnode]\n* [Votr - a real-time SMS voting application with node.js and CouchDB (three parts)][votr]\n* [Pair programming in the browser with node.js][pair]\n\nWe hope you love hacking node.js and Twilio on Azure!\n\n[purchase_phone]: https://www.twilio.com/user/account/phone-numbers/available/local\n[twiml]: https://www.twilio.com/docs/api/twiml\n[signup]: http://ahoy.twilio.com/azure\n[azure_new_site]: http://www.windowsazure.com/develop/nodejs/tutorials/create-a-website-(mac)/\n[twilio_dashboard]: https://www.twilio.com/user/account\n[npm]: http://npmjs.org\n[express]: http://expressjs.com\n[voipnode]: http://www.twilio.com/blog/2013/04/introduction-to-twilio-client-with-node-js.html\n[docs]: http://twilio.github.io/twilio-node/\n[votr]: http://www.twilio.com/blog/2012/09/building-a-real-time-sms-voting-app-part-1-node-js-couchdb.html\n[pair]: http://www.twilio.com/blog/2013/06/pair-programming-in-the-browser-with-twilio.html\n[azure-admin-console]: ./media/partner-twilio-nodejs-how-to-use-voice-sms/twilio_1.png\n\n\n\n\ntest\n"
}