{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Troubleshoot issues with Operational Insights",
      "pos": [
        26,
        71
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn about troubleshooting issues with Operational Insights",
      "pos": [
        89,
        149
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Troubleshoot issues with Operational Insights",
      "pos": [
        456,
        501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the information in the following sections to help you troubleshoot problems.",
      "pos": [
        603,
        691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the issue you're having isn't in this article, you can try the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Operational Insights team blog<ept id=\"p1\">](http://blogs.technet.com/b/momteam/archive/2014/05/29/advisor-error-3000-unable-to-register-to-the-advisor-service-amp-onboarding-troubleshooting-steps.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        692,
        949
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Diagnose connection issues for Operational Insights",
      "pos": [
        954,
        1005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because Microsoft Azure Operational Insights relies on data that is moved to and from the cloud, connection issues can be crippling.",
      "pos": [
        1007,
        1139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following information to understand and solve your connection issues.",
      "pos": [
        1140,
        1217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Error message:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The Internet connectivity was verified, but connection to Operational Insights service could not be established.",
      "pos": [
        1220,
        1351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please try again later.",
      "pos": [
        1352,
        1375
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Possible causes:",
      "pos": [
        1379,
        1395
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Operational Insights service is under maintenance.",
      "pos": [
        1400,
        1454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Wait until the Operational Insights maintenance is done.",
      "pos": [
        1455,
        1511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your network has blocked Operational Insights.",
      "pos": [
        1514,
        1560
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Contact your network administrator and request access to Operational Insights, or use another server as your gateway.",
      "pos": [
        1561,
        1678
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Error message:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Internet connection could not be established.",
      "pos": [
        1680,
        1744
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please check your proxy settings.",
      "pos": [
        1745,
        1778
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Possible causes:",
      "pos": [
        1782,
        1798
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This server is not connected to the Internet.",
      "pos": [
        1803,
        1848
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check the Internet connectivity status, and connect the server to the Internet.",
      "pos": [
        1849,
        1928
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The proxy setting is not correct.",
      "pos": [
        1931,
        1964
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configure proxy and firewall settings<ept id=\"p1\">](operational-insights-proxy-firewall.md)</ept> for information about how to set or change your proxy settings.",
      "pos": [
        1965,
        2112
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The proxy server requires authentication.",
      "pos": [
        2115,
        2156
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configure proxy and firewall settings<ept id=\"p1\">](operational-insights-proxy-firewall.md)</ept> to learn about how to configure Operations Manager to use a proxy server.",
      "pos": [
        2157,
        2314
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Troubleshoot SQL Server discovery",
      "pos": [
        2320,
        2353
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are running Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2, and despite deploying the Operations Manager agent, you do not see alerts for this server, you might have a discovery issue.",
      "pos": [
        2355,
        2528
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To confirm if this is the source of your trouble, check for the following two issues:",
      "pos": [
        2530,
        2615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the Operations Manager event log, you see Event ID 4001.",
      "pos": [
        2619,
        2678
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This event indicates that there is an invalid class.",
      "pos": [
        2679,
        2731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In SQL Server Configuration Manager, when you view SQL Server Services, you see the error message, “The remote procedure call failed.",
      "pos": [
        2735,
        2868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[0x0800706be]”",
      "pos": [
        2869,
        2883
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If both issues are true, you need to install SQL Server 2008 R2 Service Pack 2.",
      "pos": [
        2885,
        2964
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To download this service pack, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SQL Server 2008 R2 Service Pack 2<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=271310)</ept> in the Microsoft Download Center.",
      "pos": [
        2965,
        3116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you install the service pack, you should see Operational Insights data for the server within 24 hours.",
      "pos": [
        3118,
        3226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Troubleshoot agents or Operations Manager data flow to Operational Insights",
      "pos": [
        3231,
        3306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following set of procedures is meant as a guide to help you troubleshoot your directly-connected agents or Operations Manager deployments configured to report data to Azure Operational Insights.",
      "pos": [
        3308,
        3506
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Procedure 1: Validate if the right Management Packs get downloaded to your Operations Manager Environment",
      "pos": [
        3512,
        3617
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3619,
        3697
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> If you only use Direct Agent, you can skip to the next procedure."
    },
    {
      "content": "Depending on which solutions (previously called intelligence packs) you have enabled from the OpInsights Portal will you see more or less of these MPs.",
      "pos": [
        3699,
        3850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Search for keyword ‘Advisor’ or ‘Intelligence’ in their name.",
      "pos": [
        3851,
        3912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can check for these MPs using OpsMgr PowerShell:",
      "pos": [
        3913,
        3965
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4178,
        4593
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> If you are troubleshooting the Capacity solution, check <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>how many<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> management packs with the name containing ‘capacity’ you have: there are two management packs that have the same display name (but different internal ID’s) that come in the same MP bundle; if one of the two does not get imported (often due to missing VMM dependency) the other MP does not get imported and the operation does not retry."
    },
    {
      "content": "You should see the following three management packs related to ‘capacity’",
      "pos": [
        4595,
        4668
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft System Center Advisor Capacity Intelligence Pack",
      "pos": [
        4671,
        4729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft System Center Advisor Capacity Intelligence Pack",
      "pos": [
        4732,
        4790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft System Center Advisor Capacity Storage Data",
      "pos": [
        4793,
        4846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you only see one or two of them but not all three, remove it and wait 5/10 minutes for Operations Manager to download and import it again – check the event logs for errors during this period.",
      "pos": [
        4848,
        5042
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Procedure 2: Validate if the right solutions get downloaded to your Direct Agent",
      "pos": [
        5048,
        5128
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5130,
        5209
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> If you only use Operations Manager, you can ignore this procedure."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5211,
        5383
      ],
      "content": "In Direct Agent you should see the solution collection policy being cached under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>C:\\Program Files\\Microsoft Monitoring Agent\\Agent\\Health Service State\\Management Packs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Procedure 3: Validate if data is being sent up to the Advisor service (or at last attempted)",
      "pos": [
        5390,
        5482
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Depending if you are using Directly-connected agents or Operations Manager, you can perform the following procedure on the direct agent machine or on the Operations Manager management server:",
      "pos": [
        5483,
        5674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open ‘Performance Monitor’",
      "pos": [
        5681,
        5707
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select ‘Health Service Management Groups’",
      "pos": [
        5713,
        5754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add all the counters that start with ‘HTTP’",
      "pos": [
        5760,
        5803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If things are configured right you should see activity for these counters, as events and other data items (based on the solutions onboarded in the portal, and the configured log collection policy) are uploaded.",
      "pos": [
        5805,
        6015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Those counters don’t necessarily have to be continuously ‘busy’ - if you see little to no activity it might be that you are not onboarded on many solutions or have a very lightweight collection policy.",
      "pos": [
        6016,
        6217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Procedure 4: Check for Errors on the Management Server or Direct Agent Event Logs",
      "pos": [
        6223,
        6304
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6305,
        6453
      ],
      "content": "As a final step if all of the above fails but you still see no data received by the service, check if you are seeing any errors in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Event Viewer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6455,
        6694
      ],
      "content": "Open <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Event Viewer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> –&gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Application and Services<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> –&gt; <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Operations Manager<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> and filter by Event Sources: <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Advisor<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Health Service Modules<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>HealthService<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt>Service Connector<ept id=\"p7\">**</ept> (this last one applies to Direct Agent only)."
    },
    {
      "content": "Most of these events would be similar in either Operations Manager and on Direct Agent and the steps for troubleshooting would be similar for either.",
      "pos": [
        6696,
        6845
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The only part that differs between Operations Manager and Direct Agent is the registration process (GUI in Operations Manager; workspace Id/Key combination in Direct agent) but, after initial registration, certificates are exchanges and used and everything else about the communication with the service is the same.",
      "pos": [
        6846,
        7161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hence, many of these events apply to both types of reporting infrastructure.",
      "pos": [
        7163,
        7239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here's a list of the common ones you might see.",
      "pos": [
        7240,
        7287
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Events from source 'Health Service Modules'",
      "pos": [
        7293,
        7336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 2138",
      "pos": [
        7343,
        7355
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means your proxy requires authentication.",
      "pos": [
        7356,
        7402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please follow the steps to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>configure proxy servers<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn884643.aspx)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        7403,
        7511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 2137",
      "pos": [
        7519,
        7531
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operations Manager cannot read the authentication certificate.",
      "pos": [
        7532,
        7594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Re-running the Advisor registration wizard will fix certificates/runas accounts",
      "pos": [
        7595,
        7674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 2132",
      "pos": [
        7682,
        7694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Means <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Not Authorized<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        7695,
        7720
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Could be an issue with the certificate and/or registration to the service; try re-running the registration wizard that will fix certificates and RunAs accounts.",
      "pos": [
        7721,
        7881
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additionally, verify the proxy has been set to allow exclusions.",
      "pos": [
        7882,
        7946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>configure proxy servers<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn884643.aspx)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        7947,
        8053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 2129",
      "pos": [
        8061,
        8073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is a failed connection due to failed SSL negotiation.",
      "pos": [
        8074,
        8132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify that your systems are configured to use TLS and not SSL.",
      "pos": [
        8133,
        8196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There could be some strange SSL settings on this server with regards to chipers, either in the Internet Explorer <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Advanced<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> options, or in the Windows registry under the key",
      "pos": [
        8197,
        8372
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 2127",
      "pos": [
        8464,
        8476
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Failure sending data received error code.",
      "pos": [
        8477,
        8518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this only happens once in a while, it could be just a glitch.",
      "pos": [
        8519,
        8583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Keep an eye on it, to understand how often it happens.",
      "pos": [
        8584,
        8638
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the same appears very often (every 10 minutes or so for an extended period of time), then it could be a real issue – check your network configuration, proxy settings described above, and re-run registration wizard.",
      "pos": [
        8639,
        8856
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "But if it only happens sporadically (i.e. a couple of times per day) then everything should be fine, as data will be queued and retransmitted.",
      "pos": [
        8857,
        8999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's probably just a network timeout if that's the frequency at which it occurs.",
      "pos": [
        9000,
        9080
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some of the HTTP error codes have some special meanings, i.e.:",
      "pos": [
        9082,
        9144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "the FIRST time that a MMA direct agent or management server tries to send data to our service, it will get a 500 error with an inner 404 error code – 404 means not found; this indicates that the storage area we’ll use for this new workspace of yours isn’t quite ready yet – it is being provisioned.",
      "pos": [
        9148,
        9446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On next retry, this will however be ready and flow will start working (under normal conditions).",
      "pos": [
        9447,
        9543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "403 might indicate a permission/credential issue, and so forth.",
      "pos": [
        9546,
        9609
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 2128",
      "pos": [
        9617,
        9629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DNS name resolution failed.",
      "pos": [
        9630,
        9657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You server can’t resolve our internet address it is supposed to send data to.",
      "pos": [
        9658,
        9735
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This might be DNS resolver settings on your machine, incorrect proxy settings, or a (temporary) issue with DNS at your provider.",
      "pos": [
        9736,
        9864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Like the previous event, depending if it happens constantly or ‘once in a while’ it could indicate a real issue – or not.",
      "pos": [
        9865,
        9986
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 2130",
      "pos": [
        9994,
        10006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Timeout.",
      "pos": [
        10007,
        10015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Like the previous event, depending if it happens constantly or ‘once in a while’ it could be an issue – or not.",
      "pos": [
        10016,
        10127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Events from source 'HealthService'",
      "pos": [
        10133,
        10167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 4511",
      "pos": [
        10174,
        10186
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cannot load module \"System.PublishDataToEndPoint\" – file not found.",
      "pos": [
        10187,
        10254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Initialization of a module of type \"System.PublishDataToEndPoint\" (CLSID \"{D407D659-65E4-4476-BF40-924E56841465}\") failed with error code The system cannot find the file specified.",
      "pos": [
        10255,
        10435
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This error indicates you have old DLLs on your machine, that don’t contain the required modules.",
      "pos": [
        10438,
        10534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The fix is to update your Management Servers to the latest Update Rollup.",
      "pos": [
        10535,
        10608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 4502",
      "pos": [
        10616,
        10628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Module crashed.",
      "pos": [
        10629,
        10644
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you see this for workflows with names such as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CollectInstanceSpace<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>CollectTypeSpace<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> it might mean the server is having issues to send some configuration data.",
      "pos": [
        10645,
        10817
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Depending on how often it happens - constantly or ‘once in a while’ - it could be an issue or not.",
      "pos": [
        10818,
        10916
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If it happens more that every hour it is definitely an issue.",
      "pos": [
        10917,
        10978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If only fails this operation once or twice per day, it will be fine an able to recover.",
      "pos": [
        10979,
        11066
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Depending on how the module actually fails (description will have more details) this could be an on-premises issue – i.e. to collect to DB – or an issue sending to the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        11067,
        11241
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify your network and proxy settings, and worst case try restarting the HealthService.",
      "pos": [
        11242,
        11330
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 4501",
      "pos": [
        11338,
        11350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Module \"System.PublishDataToEndPoint\" crashed.",
      "pos": [
        11351,
        11397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A module of type \"System.PublishDataToEndPoint\" reported an error 87L which was running as part of rule \"Microsoft.SystemCenter.CollectAlertChangeDataToCloud\" running for instance \"Operations Manager Management Group\" with id:\"{6B1D1BE8-EBB4-B425-08DC-2385C5930B04}\" in management group \"SCOMTEST\".",
      "pos": [
        11398,
        11696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>not<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> see this with this exact workflow, module and error anymore, it used to be <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>a bug <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>now fixed<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept><ept id=\"p2\">](http://feedback.azure.com/forums/267889-azure-operational-insights/suggestions/6714689-alert-management-intelligence-pack-not-sending-ale)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11697,
        11948
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you see this again please report it thru your preferred Microsoft support channel.",
      "pos": [
        11949,
        12034
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Events from source 'Service Connector'",
      "pos": [
        12041,
        12079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EventID 4002",
      "pos": [
        12086,
        12098
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The service returned HTTP status code 403 in response to a query.",
      "pos": [
        12099,
        12164
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please check with the service administrator for the health of the service.",
      "pos": [
        12166,
        12240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The query will be retried later.",
      "pos": [
        12241,
        12273
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can get a 403 during the agent’s initial registration phase, you’ll see a URL like https://",
      "pos": [
        12274,
        12369
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ".oms.opinsights.azure.com/ AgentService.svc/AgentTopologyRequest",
      "pos": [
        12386,
        12450
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Error code 403 means ‘fordbidden’ – this is typically a wrongly-copied WorkspaceId or key, or the clock is not synced on the machine.",
      "pos": [
        12451,
        12584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Try synchronising with a reliable time source and use the connectivity check in the Control Panel applet for Microsoft Monitoring Agent to verify you have the right workspace Id and Key.",
      "pos": [
        12585,
        12771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Procedure 5: Look for your agents to send their data and have it indexed in the Portal",
      "pos": [
        12778,
        12864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check in the OpInsights Portal, from Overview page navigate to the small tile <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Servers and Usage<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – this will show if management groups (and their agents) and direct agents are reporting data into log search.",
      "pos": [
        12865,
        13075
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The number of agents on the tile is derived from data – if machines don’t report for 2 weeks they’ll drop off the radar.",
      "pos": [
        13076,
        13196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The drill downs take you to log search and show the last indexed data’s timestamp for each machine.",
      "pos": [
        13198,
        13297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From there you can explore what data it is.",
      "pos": [
        13298,
        13341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Depending on the amount of data collection configured and which solutions, data upload schedule and speed can vary.",
      "pos": [
        13342,
        13457
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This page also features metering information (this does not use the log search index but the billing system, it’s refreshed every couple of hours) about the amounts of data sent to the service broken down by solution.",
      "pos": [
        13459,
        13676
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Troubleshoot issues with Operational Insights\"\n   description=\"Learn about troubleshooting issues with Operational Insights\"\n   services=\"operational-insights\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"bandersmsft\"\n   manager=\"jwhit\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"operational-insights\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"na\"\n   ms.date=\"07/02/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"banders\" />\n\n#Troubleshoot issues with Operational Insights\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [operational-insights-note-moms](../../includes/operational-insights-note-moms.md)]\n\nYou can use the information in the following sections to help you troubleshoot problems. If the issue you're having isn't in this article, you can try the [Operational Insights team blog](http://blogs.technet.com/b/momteam/archive/2014/05/29/advisor-error-3000-unable-to-register-to-the-advisor-service-amp-onboarding-troubleshooting-steps.aspx).\n\n## Diagnose connection issues for Operational Insights\n\nBecause Microsoft Azure Operational Insights relies on data that is moved to and from the cloud, connection issues can be crippling. Use the following information to understand and solve your connection issues.\n\n\n**Error message:** The Internet connectivity was verified, but connection to Operational Insights service could not be established. Please try again later.\n\n**Possible causes:**\n- The Operational Insights service is under maintenance. Wait until the Operational Insights maintenance is done.\n- Your network has blocked Operational Insights. Contact your network administrator and request access to Operational Insights, or use another server as your gateway.\n\n**Error message:** Internet connection could not be established. Please check your proxy settings.\n\n**Possible causes:**\n- This server is not connected to the Internet. Check the Internet connectivity status, and connect the server to the Internet.\n- The proxy setting is not correct. See [Configure proxy and firewall settings](operational-insights-proxy-firewall.md) for information about how to set or change your proxy settings.\n- The proxy server requires authentication. See [Configure proxy and firewall settings](operational-insights-proxy-firewall.md) to learn about how to configure Operations Manager to use a proxy server.\n\n\n## Troubleshoot SQL Server discovery\n\nIf you are running Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2, and despite deploying the Operations Manager agent, you do not see alerts for this server, you might have a discovery issue.\n\nTo confirm if this is the source of your trouble, check for the following two issues:\n\n- In the Operations Manager event log, you see Event ID 4001. This event indicates that there is an invalid class.\n\n- In SQL Server Configuration Manager, when you view SQL Server Services, you see the error message, “The remote procedure call failed. [0x0800706be]”\n\nIf both issues are true, you need to install SQL Server 2008 R2 Service Pack 2. To download this service pack, see [SQL Server 2008 R2 Service Pack 2](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=271310) in the Microsoft Download Center.\n\nAfter you install the service pack, you should see Operational Insights data for the server within 24 hours.\n\n## Troubleshoot agents or Operations Manager data flow to Operational Insights\n\nThe following set of procedures is meant as a guide to help you troubleshoot your directly-connected agents or Operations Manager deployments configured to report data to Azure Operational Insights.\n\n### Procedure 1: Validate if the right Management Packs get downloaded to your Operations Manager Environment\n>[AZURE.NOTE] If you only use Direct Agent, you can skip to the next procedure.\n\nDepending on which solutions (previously called intelligence packs) you have enabled from the OpInsights Portal will you see more or less of these MPs. Search for keyword ‘Advisor’ or ‘Intelligence’ in their name.\nYou can check for these MPs using OpsMgr PowerShell:\n\n```Powershell\nGet-SCOMManagementPack | where {$_.DisplayName -match 'Advisor'} | Select Name,Sealed,Version\nGet-SCOMManagementPack | where {$_.Name -match 'IntelligencePacks'} | Select Name,Sealed,Version\n```\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] If you are troubleshooting the Capacity solution, check *how many* management packs with the name containing ‘capacity’ you have: there are two management packs that have the same display name (but different internal ID’s) that come in the same MP bundle; if one of the two does not get imported (often due to missing VMM dependency) the other MP does not get imported and the operation does not retry.\n\nYou should see the following three management packs related to ‘capacity’\n- Microsoft System Center Advisor Capacity Intelligence Pack\n- Microsoft System Center Advisor Capacity Intelligence Pack\n- Microsoft System Center Advisor Capacity Storage Data\n\nIf you only see one or two of them but not all three, remove it and wait 5/10 minutes for Operations Manager to download and import it again – check the event logs for errors during this period.\n\n### Procedure 2: Validate if the right solutions get downloaded to your Direct Agent\n>[AZURE.NOTE] If you only use Operations Manager, you can ignore this procedure.\n\nIn Direct Agent you should see the solution collection policy being cached under **C:\\Program Files\\Microsoft Monitoring Agent\\Agent\\Health Service State\\Management Packs**\n\n\n### Procedure 3: Validate if data is being sent up to the Advisor service (or at last attempted)\nDepending if you are using Directly-connected agents or Operations Manager, you can perform the following procedure on the direct agent machine or on the Operations Manager management server:\n\n1. - Open ‘Performance Monitor’\n2. - Select ‘Health Service Management Groups’\n3. - Add all the counters that start with ‘HTTP’\n\nIf things are configured right you should see activity for these counters, as events and other data items (based on the solutions onboarded in the portal, and the configured log collection policy) are uploaded. Those counters don’t necessarily have to be continuously ‘busy’ - if you see little to no activity it might be that you are not onboarded on many solutions or have a very lightweight collection policy.\n\n### Procedure 4: Check for Errors on the Management Server or Direct Agent Event Logs\nAs a final step if all of the above fails but you still see no data received by the service, check if you are seeing any errors in **Event Viewer**.\n\nOpen **Event Viewer** –> **Application and Services** –> **Operations Manager** and filter by Event Sources: **Advisor**, **Health Service Modules**, **HealthService** and **Service Connector** (this last one applies to Direct Agent only).\n\nMost of these events would be similar in either Operations Manager and on Direct Agent and the steps for troubleshooting would be similar for either.\nThe only part that differs between Operations Manager and Direct Agent is the registration process (GUI in Operations Manager; workspace Id/Key combination in Direct agent) but, after initial registration, certificates are exchanges and used and everything else about the communication with the service is the same.\n\nHence, many of these events apply to both types of reporting infrastructure. Here's a list of the common ones you might see.\n\n### Events from source 'Health Service Modules'\n##### EventID 2138\nThis means your proxy requires authentication. Please follow the steps to [configure proxy servers](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn884643.aspx)\n\n##### EventID 2137\nOperations Manager cannot read the authentication certificate. Re-running the Advisor registration wizard will fix certificates/runas accounts\n\n##### EventID 2132\nMeans **Not Authorized**. Could be an issue with the certificate and/or registration to the service; try re-running the registration wizard that will fix certificates and RunAs accounts. Additionally, verify the proxy has been set to allow exclusions. For more information see [configure proxy servers](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn884643.aspx)\n\n##### EventID 2129\nThis is a failed connection due to failed SSL negotiation. Verify that your systems are configured to use TLS and not SSL. There could be some strange SSL settings on this server with regards to chipers, either in the Internet Explorer **Advanced** options, or in the Windows registry under the key\n\n    HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SYSTEM\\CurrentControlSet\\Control\\SecurityProviders\\SCHANNEL\n\n##### EventID 2127\nFailure sending data received error code. If this only happens once in a while, it could be just a glitch. Keep an eye on it, to understand how often it happens. If the same appears very often (every 10 minutes or so for an extended period of time), then it could be a real issue – check your network configuration, proxy settings described above, and re-run registration wizard. But if it only happens sporadically (i.e. a couple of times per day) then everything should be fine, as data will be queued and retransmitted. It's probably just a network timeout if that's the frequency at which it occurs.\n\nSome of the HTTP error codes have some special meanings, i.e.:\n\n- the FIRST time that a MMA direct agent or management server tries to send data to our service, it will get a 500 error with an inner 404 error code – 404 means not found; this indicates that the storage area we’ll use for this new workspace of yours isn’t quite ready yet – it is being provisioned. On next retry, this will however be ready and flow will start working (under normal conditions).\n- 403 might indicate a permission/credential issue, and so forth.\n\n##### EventID 2128\nDNS name resolution failed. You server can’t resolve our internet address it is supposed to send data to. This might be DNS resolver settings on your machine, incorrect proxy settings, or a (temporary) issue with DNS at your provider. Like the previous event, depending if it happens constantly or ‘once in a while’ it could indicate a real issue – or not.\n\n##### EventID 2130\nTimeout. Like the previous event, depending if it happens constantly or ‘once in a while’ it could be an issue – or not.\n\n### Events from source 'HealthService'\n##### EventID 4511\nCannot load module \"System.PublishDataToEndPoint\" – file not found. Initialization of a module of type \"System.PublishDataToEndPoint\" (CLSID \"{D407D659-65E4-4476-BF40-924E56841465}\") failed with error code The system cannot find the file specified.  \nThis error indicates you have old DLLs on your machine, that don’t contain the required modules. The fix is to update your Management Servers to the latest Update Rollup.\n\n##### EventID 4502\nModule crashed. If you see this for workflows with names such as **CollectInstanceSpace** or **CollectTypeSpace** it might mean the server is having issues to send some configuration data. Depending on how often it happens - constantly or ‘once in a while’ - it could be an issue or not. If it happens more that every hour it is definitely an issue. If only fails this operation once or twice per day, it will be fine an able to recover. Depending on how the module actually fails (description will have more details) this could be an on-premises issue – i.e. to collect to DB – or an issue sending to the cloud. Verify your network and proxy settings, and worst case try restarting the HealthService.\n\n##### EventID 4501\nModule \"System.PublishDataToEndPoint\" crashed. A module of type \"System.PublishDataToEndPoint\" reported an error 87L which was running as part of rule \"Microsoft.SystemCenter.CollectAlertChangeDataToCloud\" running for instance \"Operations Manager Management Group\" with id:\"{6B1D1BE8-EBB4-B425-08DC-2385C5930B04}\" in management group \"SCOMTEST\".\nYou should *not* see this with this exact workflow, module and error anymore, it used to be [a bug *now fixed*](http://feedback.azure.com/forums/267889-azure-operational-insights/suggestions/6714689-alert-management-intelligence-pack-not-sending-ale). If you see this again please report it thru your preferred Microsoft support channel.\n\n\n### Events from source 'Service Connector'\n##### EventID 4002\nThe service returned HTTP status code 403 in response to a query.  Please check with the service administrator for the health of the service. The query will be retried later. You can get a 403 during the agent’s initial registration phase, you’ll see a URL like https://<YourWorkspaceID>.oms.opinsights.azure.com/ AgentService.svc/AgentTopologyRequest\nError code 403 means ‘fordbidden’ – this is typically a wrongly-copied WorkspaceId or key, or the clock is not synced on the machine. Try synchronising with a reliable time source and use the connectivity check in the Control Panel applet for Microsoft Monitoring Agent to verify you have the right workspace Id and Key.\n\n\n### Procedure 5: Look for your agents to send their data and have it indexed in the Portal\nCheck in the OpInsights Portal, from Overview page navigate to the small tile **Servers and Usage** – this will show if management groups (and their agents) and direct agents are reporting data into log search. The number of agents on the tile is derived from data – if machines don’t report for 2 weeks they’ll drop off the radar.\n\nThe drill downs take you to log search and show the last indexed data’s timestamp for each machine. From there you can explore what data it is. Depending on the amount of data collection configured and which solutions, data upload schedule and speed can vary.\n\nThis page also features metering information (this does not use the log search index but the billing system, it’s refreshed every couple of hours) about the amounts of data sent to the service broken down by solution.\n"
}