{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Media Services Overview and Common Scenarios",
      "pos": [
        28,
        78
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic gives an overview of Azure Media Services",
      "pos": [
        98,
        150
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Media Services Overview and Common Scenarios",
      "pos": [
        461,
        511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Azure Media Services is an extensible cloud-based platform that enables developers to build scalable media management and delivery applications.",
      "pos": [
        513,
        667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Media Services is based on REST APIs that enable you to securely upload, store, encode and package video or audio content for both on-demand and live streaming delivery to various clients (for example, TV, PC, and mobile devices).",
      "pos": [
        668,
        898
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can build end-to-end workflows using entirely Media Services.",
      "pos": [
        900,
        965
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also choose to use third-party components for some parts of your workflow.",
      "pos": [
        966,
        1048
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, encode using a third-party encoder.",
      "pos": [
        1049,
        1097
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then, upload, protect, package, deliver using Media Services.",
      "pos": [
        1098,
        1159
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following poster depicts Azure Media Services workflows, from media creation through consumption.",
      "pos": [
        1162,
        1263
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download the poster from here: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Media Services poster<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=38195)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1264,
        1390
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![Overview][overview]",
      "pos": [
        1392,
        1413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can choose to stream your content live or deliver content on demand.",
      "pos": [
        1415,
        1487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic shows common scenarios for delivering your content <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>live<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-overview.md#live_scenarios)</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>on demand<ept id=\"p2\">](media-services-overview.md#vod_scenarios)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1488,
        1657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The topic also links to other relevant topics.",
      "pos": [
        1658,
        1704
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To build Media Services solutions, you can use:",
      "pos": [
        1706,
        1753
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Media Services REST API",
      "pos": [
        1758,
        1781
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1841,
        2173
      ],
      "content": "One of the available client SDKs: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Media Services SDK for .NET<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-media-services)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure SDK for Java<ept id=\"p2\">](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-java)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Azure Media Services for Node.js<ept id=\"p3\">](https://github.com/fritzy/node-azure-media)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>Azure PHP SDK<ept id=\"p4\">](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-php)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2176,
        2342
      ],
      "content": "Existing tools: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://manage.windowsazure.com/)</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure-Media-Services-Explorer<ept id=\"p2\">](https://github.com/Azure/Azure-Media-Services-Explorer)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        2347,
        2360
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To start using Azure Media Services, you should have the following:",
      "pos": [
        2362,
        2429
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Azure account.",
      "pos": [
        2435,
        2452
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don't have an account, you can create a free trial account in just a couple of minutes.",
      "pos": [
        2453,
        2547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Free Trial<ept id=\"p1\">](azure.microsoft.com)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2548,
        2605
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Azure Media Services account.",
      "pos": [
        2609,
        2641
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use Azure Management Portal, .NET, or REST API to create Azure Media Services account.",
      "pos": [
        2642,
        2728
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create Account<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-create-account.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2729,
        2806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(Optional) Set up development environment.",
      "pos": [
        2810,
        2852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose .NET or REST API for your development environment.",
      "pos": [
        2853,
        2910
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up environment<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-dotnet-how-to-use.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2911,
        2995
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3002,
        3108
      ],
      "content": "Also, learn how to connect  programmatically <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Connect<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-dotnet-connect_programmatically.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "(Recommended) Allocate one or more scale units.",
      "pos": [
        3112,
        3159
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is recommended to allocate one or more scale units for applications in production environment.",
      "pos": [
        3160,
        3257
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Managing streaming endpoints<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-manage-origins.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3260,
        3351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Concepts",
      "pos": [
        3355,
        3363
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3365,
        3430
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Concepts<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-concepts.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3435,
        3541
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a id=\"vod_scenarios\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Delivering Media on-Demand with Azure Media Services: common scenarios and tasks"
    },
    {
      "content": "This section describes common scenarios and provides links to relevant topics.",
      "pos": [
        3543,
        3621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following diagram shows the major parts of the Media Services platform that are involved in delivering content on demand.",
      "pos": [
        3622,
        3747
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![VoD workflow][vod-overview]",
      "pos": [
        3750,
        3779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Protect content in storage and deliver streaming media in the clear (non-encrypted)",
      "pos": [
        3785,
        3868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Upload a high-quality mezzanine file into an asset.",
      "pos": [
        3873,
        3924
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is recommended to apply storage encryption option to your asset in order to protect your content during upload and while at rest in storage.",
      "pos": [
        3934,
        4077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Encode to adaptive bitrate MP4 set.",
      "pos": [
        4083,
        4118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is recommended to apply storage encryption option to the output asset in order to protect your content at rest.",
      "pos": [
        4125,
        4239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure asset delivery policy (used by dynamic packaging).",
      "pos": [
        4248,
        4308
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4319,
        4400
      ],
      "content": "If your asset is storage encrypted, you <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>must<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> configure asset delivery policy."
    },
    {
      "content": "Publish the asset by creating an OnDemand locator.",
      "pos": [
        4406,
        4456
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure to have at least one streaming reserved unit on the streaming endpoint from which you want to stream content.",
      "pos": [
        4462,
        4581
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stream published content.",
      "pos": [
        4586,
        4611
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Protect content in storage, deliver dynamically encrypted streaming media",
      "pos": [
        4616,
        4689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To be able to use dynamic encryption, you must first get at least one streaming reserved unit on the streaming endpoint from which you want to stream encrypted content.",
      "pos": [
        4693,
        4861
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Upload a high-quality mezzanine file into an asset.",
      "pos": [
        4866,
        4917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Apply storage encryption option to the asset.",
      "pos": [
        4918,
        4963
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Encode to adaptive bitrate MP4 set.",
      "pos": [
        4967,
        5002
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Apply storage encryption option to the output asset.",
      "pos": [
        5003,
        5055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create encryption content key for the asset you want to be dynamically encrypted during playback.",
      "pos": [
        5059,
        5156
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure content key authorization policy.",
      "pos": [
        5160,
        5203
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure asset delivery policy (used by dynamic packaging and dynamic encryption).",
      "pos": [
        5207,
        5290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Publish the asset by creating an OnDemand locator.",
      "pos": [
        5294,
        5344
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stream published content.",
      "pos": [
        5348,
        5373
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Index content",
      "pos": [
        5379,
        5392
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Upload a high-quality mezzanine file into an Asset.",
      "pos": [
        5397,
        5448
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Index content.",
      "pos": [
        5452,
        5466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The indexing job generates files that can be used as Closed Captions (CC) in video playback.",
      "pos": [
        5472,
        5564
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It also generates files that enable you to do in-video search and jump to the exact location of the video.",
      "pos": [
        5565,
        5671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Consume indexed content.",
      "pos": [
        5677,
        5701
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deliver progressive download",
      "pos": [
        5707,
        5735
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Upload a high-quality mezzanine file into an asset.",
      "pos": [
        5741,
        5792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Encode to adaptive bitrate MP4 set or a single MP4.",
      "pos": [
        5796,
        5847
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Publish the asset by creating an OnDemand or SAS locator.",
      "pos": [
        5851,
        5908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If using OnDemand locator, make sure to have at least one streaming reserved unit on the streaming endpoint from which you plan to progressively download content.",
      "pos": [
        5914,
        6076
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If using SAS locator, the content is downloaded from the Azure blob storage.",
      "pos": [
        6082,
        6158
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, you do not need to have streaming reserved units.",
      "pos": [
        6159,
        6222
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Progressively download content.",
      "pos": [
        6229,
        6260
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Also See",
      "pos": [
        6265,
        6273
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to upload content",
      "pos": [
        6278,
        6299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to get media processor",
      "pos": [
        6345,
        6371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to encode content",
      "pos": [
        6415,
        6436
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to monitor jobs",
      "pos": [
        6482,
        6501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to index content",
      "pos": [
        6551,
        6571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to protect content",
      "pos": [
        6616,
        6638
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to protect publish",
      "pos": [
        6685,
        6707
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to scale encoding",
      "pos": [
        6754,
        6775
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6821,
        6906
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a id=\"live_scenarios\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Delivering Live Streaming Events with Azure Media Services"
    },
    {
      "content": "When working with Live Streaming the following components are commonly involved:",
      "pos": [
        6908,
        6988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A camera that is used to broadcast an event.",
      "pos": [
        6993,
        7037
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A live video encoder that converts signals from the camera to streams that are sent to a live streaming service.",
      "pos": [
        7040,
        7152
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Optionally, multiple live encoders.",
      "pos": [
        7161,
        7196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For certain critical live events that demand very high availability and quality of experience, it is recommended to employ active-active redundant encoders to achieve seamless failover with no data loss.",
      "pos": [
        7197,
        7400
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A live streaming service that enables you to do the following:",
      "pos": [
        7403,
        7465
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ingest live content using various live streaming protocols (for example RTMP or Smooth Streaming),",
      "pos": [
        7473,
        7571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "encode your stream into adaptive bitrate stream",
      "pos": [
        7579,
        7626
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "preview your live stream,",
      "pos": [
        7633,
        7658
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "store the ingested content in order to be streamed later (Video-on-Demand)",
      "pos": [
        7665,
        7739
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "deliver the content through common streaming protocols (for example, MPEG DASH, Smooth, HLS, HDS) directly to your customers, or to a Content Delivery Network (CDN) for further distribution.",
      "pos": [
        7746,
        7936
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7952,
        8090
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Azure Media Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (AMS) provides the ability to ingest,  encode, preview, store, and deliver your live streaming content."
    },
    {
      "content": "When delivering your content to customers your goal is to deliver a high quality video to various devices under different network conditions.",
      "pos": [
        8092,
        8233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To take care of quality and network conditions, use live encoders to encode your stream to multi-bitrate (adaptive bitrate) video stream.",
      "pos": [
        8234,
        8371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To take care of streaming on different devices, use Media Services <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>dynamic packaging<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-dynamic-packaging-overview.md)</ept> to dynamically re-package your stream to different protocols.",
      "pos": [
        8373,
        8567
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Media Services supports delivery of the following adaptive bitrate streaming technologies: HTTP Live Streaming (HLS), Smooth Streaming, MPEG DASH, and HDS (for Adobe PrimeTime/Access licensees only).",
      "pos": [
        8568,
        8767
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8769,
        8967
      ],
      "content": "In Azure Media Services, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Channels<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Programs<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>StreamingEndpoints<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> handle all the live streaming functionalities including ingest, formatting, DVR, security, scalability and redundancy."
    },
    {
      "content": "A <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Channel<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> represents a pipeline for processing live streaming content.",
      "pos": [
        8970,
        9044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Currently, a Channel can receive a live input streams in the following way:",
      "pos": [
        9045,
        9120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An on-premises live encoder sends a single-bitrate stream to the Channel that is enabled to perform live encoding with Media Services in one of the following formats: RTP (MPEG-TS), RTMP, or Smooth Streaming (Fragmented MP4).",
      "pos": [
        9125,
        9350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Channel then performs live encoding of the incoming single bitrate stream to a multi-bitrate (adaptive) video stream.",
      "pos": [
        9351,
        9472
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When requested, Media Services delivers the stream to customers.",
      "pos": [
        9473,
        9537
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9543,
        9604
      ],
      "content": "Encoding a live stream with Media Services is in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Preview<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "An on-premises live encoder sends a multi-bitrate <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>RTMP<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Smooth Streaming<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> (Fragmented MP4) to the Channel.",
      "pos": [
        9607,
        9722
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the following live encoders that output multi-bitrate Smooth Streaming: Elemental, Envivio, Cisco.",
      "pos": [
        9723,
        9833
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following live encoders output RTMP: Adobe Flash Live, Telestream Wirecast, and Tricaster transcoders.",
      "pos": [
        9835,
        9941
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The ingested streams pass through <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Channel<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>s without any further processing.",
      "pos": [
        9942,
        10020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your live encoder can also send a single bitrate stream to a channel that is not enabled for live encoding, but that is not recommended.",
      "pos": [
        10021,
        10157
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When requested, Media Services delivers the stream to customers.",
      "pos": [
        10158,
        10222
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Working with Channels that are enabled to perform live encoding with Azure Media Services",
      "pos": [
        10228,
        10317
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following diagram shows the major parts of the AMS platform that are involved in Live Streaming workflow where a Channel is enabled to perform live encoding with Media Services.",
      "pos": [
        10320,
        10501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![Live workflow][live-overview1]",
      "pos": [
        10505,
        10537
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10539,
        10713
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Working with Channels that are Enabled to Perform Live Encoding with Azure Media Services<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-manage-live-encoder-enabled-channels.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Working with Channels that receive multi-bitrate live stream from on-premises Encoders",
      "pos": [
        10720,
        10806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following diagram shows the major parts of the AMS platform that are involved in this Live Streaming workflow.",
      "pos": [
        10809,
        10923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![Live workflow][live-overview2]",
      "pos": [
        10925,
        10957
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10959,
        11119
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Working with Channels that Receive Multi-bitrate Live Stream from On-premises Encoders\n<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-manage-channels-overview.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Consuming content",
      "pos": [
        11124,
        11141
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Media Services provides the tools you need to create rich, dynamic client player applications for most platforms including: iOS Devices, Android Devices, Windows, Windows Phone, Xbox, and Set-top boxes.",
      "pos": [
        11143,
        11351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following topic provides links to SDKs and Player Frameworks that you can use to develop your own client applications that can consume streaming media from Media Services.",
      "pos": [
        11352,
        11527
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Developing Video Player Applications",
      "pos": [
        11530,
        11566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enabling Azure CDN",
      "pos": [
        11612,
        11630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Media Services supports integration with Azure CDN.",
      "pos": [
        11632,
        11683
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information on how to enable Azure CDN, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Manage Streaming Endpoints in a Media Services Account<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-manage-origins.md#enable_cdn)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11684,
        11841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scaling a Media Services account",
      "pos": [
        11845,
        11877
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11879,
        12057
      ],
      "content": "You can scale <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Media Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> by specifying the number of <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Streaming Reserved Units<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Encoding Reserved Units<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> that you would like your account to be provisioned with."
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also scale your Media Services account by adding storage accounts to it.",
      "pos": [
        12060,
        12140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each storage account is limited to 500 TB.",
      "pos": [
        12141,
        12183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To expand your storage beyond the default limitations, you can choose to attach multiple storage accounts to a single Media Services account.",
      "pos": [
        12184,
        12325
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12327,
        12397
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>This<ept id=\"p1\">](media-services-how-to-scale.md)</ept> topic links to relevant topics."
    },
    {
      "content": "Support",
      "pos": [
        12401,
        12408
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12410,
        12532
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Support<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/support/options/)</ept> provides support options for Azure, including Media Services."
    },
    {
      "content": "Patterns &amp; practices guidance",
      "pos": [
        12536,
        12565
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Patterns and practices guidance<ept id=\"p1\">](https://wamsg.codeplex.com/)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        12567,
        12629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Online documentation<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn735912.aspx)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        12630,
        12702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Downloadable eBook<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=42629)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        12703,
        12781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Level Agreement (SLA)",
      "pos": [
        12786,
        12815
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For Media Services Encoding, we guarantee 99.9% availability of REST API transactions.",
      "pos": [
        12819,
        12905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For Streaming, we will successfully service requests with a 99.9% availability guarantee for existing media content when at least one Streaming Unit is purchased.",
      "pos": [
        12908,
        13070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For Live Channels, we guarantee that running Channels will have external connectivity at least 99.9% of the time.",
      "pos": [
        13073,
        13186
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For Content Protection, we guarantee that we will successfully fulfill key requests at least 99.9% of the time.",
      "pos": [
        13189,
        13300
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For Indexer, we will successfully service Indexer Task requests processed with an Encoding Reserved Unit 99.9% of the time.",
      "pos": [
        13303,
        13426
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13432,
        13527
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Azure SLA<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/support/legal/sla/)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        13931,
        13935
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Azure Media Services Overview and Common Scenarios\" \n    description=\"This topic gives an overview of Azure Media Services\" \n    services=\"media-services\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"Juliako\" \n    manager=\"dwrede\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"media-services\" \n    ms.workload=\"media\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"08/20/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"juliako\"/>\n\n#Azure Media Services Overview and Common Scenarios\n\nMicrosoft Azure Media Services is an extensible cloud-based platform that enables developers to build scalable media management and delivery applications. Media Services is based on REST APIs that enable you to securely upload, store, encode and package video or audio content for both on-demand and live streaming delivery to various clients (for example, TV, PC, and mobile devices).\n\nYou can build end-to-end workflows using entirely Media Services. You can also choose to use third-party components for some parts of your workflow. For example, encode using a third-party encoder. Then, upload, protect, package, deliver using Media Services.\n\n\nThe following poster depicts Azure Media Services workflows, from media creation through consumption. You can download the poster from here: [Azure Media Services poster](http://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=38195).\n\n![Overview][overview]\n\nYou can choose to stream your content live or deliver content on demand. This topic shows common scenarios for delivering your content [live](media-services-overview.md#live_scenarios) or [on demand](media-services-overview.md#vod_scenarios). The topic also links to other relevant topics.\n\nTo build Media Services solutions, you can use:\n\n- [Media Services REST API](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh973617.aspx)\n- One of the available client SDKs: [Azure Media Services SDK for .NET](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-media-services), [Azure SDK for Java](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-java), [Azure Media Services for Node.js](https://github.com/fritzy/node-azure-media), [Azure PHP SDK](https://github.com/Azure/azure-sdk-for-php)\n- Existing tools: [Azure Management Portal](http://manage.windowsazure.com/) or [Azure-Media-Services-Explorer](https://github.com/Azure/Azure-Media-Services-Explorer).\n\n\n##Prerequisites\n\nTo start using Azure Media Services, you should have the following:\n \n3. An Azure account. If you don't have an account, you can create a free trial account in just a couple of minutes. For details, see [Azure Free Trial](azure.microsoft.com).\n2. An Azure Media Services account. Use Azure Management Portal, .NET, or REST API to create Azure Media Services account. For more information, see [Create Account](media-services-create-account.md).\n3. (Optional) Set up development environment. Choose .NET or REST API for your development environment. For more information, see [Set up environment](media-services-dotnet-how-to-use.md). \n\n    Also, learn how to connect  programmatically [Connect](media-services-dotnet-connect_programmatically.md).\n4. (Recommended) Allocate one or more scale units. It is recommended to allocate one or more scale units for applications in production environment.   For more information, see [Managing streaming endpoints](media-services-manage-origins.md).\n\n##Concepts\n\nFor more information, see [Concepts](media-services-concepts.md).\n\n\n##<a id=\"vod_scenarios\"></a>Delivering Media on-Demand with Azure Media Services: common scenarios and tasks\n\nThis section describes common scenarios and provides links to relevant topics. The following diagram shows the major parts of the Media Services platform that are involved in delivering content on demand. \n\n![VoD workflow][vod-overview]\n\n\n###Protect content in storage and deliver streaming media in the clear (non-encrypted)\n\n1. Upload a high-quality mezzanine file into an asset.\n    \n    It is recommended to apply storage encryption option to your asset in order to protect your content during upload and while at rest in storage.\n \n1. Encode to adaptive bitrate MP4 set. \n\n    It is recommended to apply storage encryption option to the output asset in order to protect your content at rest.\n    \n1. Configure asset delivery policy (used by dynamic packaging). \n    \n    If your asset is storage encrypted, you **must** configure asset delivery policy. \n\n1. Publish the asset by creating an OnDemand locator.\n\n    Make sure to have at least one streaming reserved unit on the streaming endpoint from which you want to stream content.\n\n1. Stream published content.\n\n###Protect content in storage, deliver dynamically encrypted streaming media  \n\nTo be able to use dynamic encryption, you must first get at least one streaming reserved unit on the streaming endpoint from which you want to stream encrypted content.\n\n1. Upload a high-quality mezzanine file into an asset. Apply storage encryption option to the asset.\n1. Encode to adaptive bitrate MP4 set. Apply storage encryption option to the output asset.\n1. Create encryption content key for the asset you want to be dynamically encrypted during playback.\n2. Configure content key authorization policy.\n1. Configure asset delivery policy (used by dynamic packaging and dynamic encryption).\n1. Publish the asset by creating an OnDemand locator.\n1. Stream published content. \n\n###Index content\n\n1. Upload a high-quality mezzanine file into an Asset.\n1. Index content.\n\n    The indexing job generates files that can be used as Closed Captions (CC) in video playback. It also generates files that enable you to do in-video search and jump to the exact location of the video. \n\n1. Consume indexed content.\n\n\n###Deliver progressive download \n\n1. Upload a high-quality mezzanine file into an asset.\n1. Encode to adaptive bitrate MP4 set or a single MP4.\n1. Publish the asset by creating an OnDemand or SAS locator.\n\n    If using OnDemand locator, make sure to have at least one streaming reserved unit on the streaming endpoint from which you plan to progressively download content.\n\n    If using SAS locator, the content is downloaded from the Azure blob storage. In this case, you do not need to have streaming reserved units.\n  \n1. Progressively download content.\n\n###Also See\n\n- [How to upload content](media-services-manage-content.md#upload)\n- [How to get media processor](media-services-get-media-processor.md)\n- [How to encode content](media-services-manage-content.md#encode)\n- [How to monitor jobs](media-services-portal-check-job-progress.md)\n- [How to index content](media-services-manage-content.md#index)\n- [How to protect content](media-services-manage-content.md#encrypt)\n- [How to protect publish](media-services-manage-content.md#publish)\n- [How to scale encoding](media-services-portal-encoding-units.md)\n\n##<a id=\"live_scenarios\"></a>Delivering Live Streaming Events with Azure Media Services\n\nWhen working with Live Streaming the following components are commonly involved: \n\n- A camera that is used to broadcast an event.\n- A live video encoder that converts signals from the camera to streams that are sent to a live streaming service. \n  \n    Optionally, multiple live encoders. For certain critical live events that demand very high availability and quality of experience, it is recommended to employ active-active redundant encoders to achieve seamless failover with no data loss.\n- A live streaming service that enables you to do the following: \n    - ingest live content using various live streaming protocols (for example RTMP or Smooth Streaming), \n    - encode your stream into adaptive bitrate stream\n    - preview your live stream,\n    - store the ingested content in order to be streamed later (Video-on-Demand)\n    - deliver the content through common streaming protocols (for example, MPEG DASH, Smooth, HLS, HDS) directly to your customers, or to a Content Delivery Network (CDN) for further distribution. \n    \n        \n**Microsoft Azure Media Services** (AMS) provides the ability to ingest,  encode, preview, store, and deliver your live streaming content.\n\nWhen delivering your content to customers your goal is to deliver a high quality video to various devices under different network conditions. To take care of quality and network conditions, use live encoders to encode your stream to multi-bitrate (adaptive bitrate) video stream.  To take care of streaming on different devices, use Media Services [dynamic packaging](media-services-dynamic-packaging-overview.md) to dynamically re-package your stream to different protocols. Media Services supports delivery of the following adaptive bitrate streaming technologies: HTTP Live Streaming (HLS), Smooth Streaming, MPEG DASH, and HDS (for Adobe PrimeTime/Access licensees only).\n\nIn Azure Media Services, **Channels**, **Programs**, and **StreamingEndpoints** handle all the live streaming functionalities including ingest, formatting, DVR, security, scalability and redundancy. \n\nA **Channel** represents a pipeline for processing live streaming content. Currently, a Channel can receive a live input streams in the following way:\n\n\n- An on-premises live encoder sends a single-bitrate stream to the Channel that is enabled to perform live encoding with Media Services in one of the following formats: RTP (MPEG-TS), RTMP, or Smooth Streaming (Fragmented MP4). The Channel then performs live encoding of the incoming single bitrate stream to a multi-bitrate (adaptive) video stream. When requested, Media Services delivers the stream to customers.\n\n    Encoding a live stream with Media Services is in **Preview**.\n- An on-premises live encoder sends a multi-bitrate **RTMP** or **Smooth Streaming** (Fragmented MP4) to the Channel. You can use the following live encoders that output multi-bitrate Smooth Streaming: Elemental, Envivio, Cisco.  The following live encoders output RTMP: Adobe Flash Live, Telestream Wirecast, and Tricaster transcoders. The ingested streams pass through **Channel**s without any further processing. Your live encoder can also send a single bitrate stream to a channel that is not enabled for live encoding, but that is not recommended. When requested, Media Services delivers the stream to customers.\n\n\n###Working with Channels that are enabled to perform live encoding with Azure Media Services\n\n\nThe following diagram shows the major parts of the AMS platform that are involved in Live Streaming workflow where a Channel is enabled to perform live encoding with Media Services.  \n\n![Live workflow][live-overview1]\n\nFor more information, see [Working with Channels that are Enabled to Perform Live Encoding with Azure Media Services](media-services-manage-live-encoder-enabled-channels.md). \n\n\n###Working with Channels that receive multi-bitrate live stream from on-premises Encoders\n\n\nThe following diagram shows the major parts of the AMS platform that are involved in this Live Streaming workflow.\n\n![Live workflow][live-overview2]\n\nFor more information, see [Working with Channels that Receive Multi-bitrate Live Stream from On-premises Encoders\n](media-services-manage-channels-overview.md). \n\n##Consuming content\n\nAzure Media Services provides the tools you need to create rich, dynamic client player applications for most platforms including: iOS Devices, Android Devices, Windows, Windows Phone, Xbox, and Set-top boxes. The following topic provides links to SDKs and Player Frameworks that you can use to develop your own client applications that can consume streaming media from Media Services.\n\n[Developing Video Player Applications](media-services-develop-video-players.md)\n\n##Enabling Azure CDN\n\nMedia Services supports integration with Azure CDN. For information on how to enable Azure CDN, see [How to Manage Streaming Endpoints in a Media Services Account](media-services-manage-origins.md#enable_cdn).\n\n##Scaling a Media Services account\n\nYou can scale **Media Services** by specifying the number of **Streaming Reserved Units** and **Encoding Reserved Units** that you would like your account to be provisioned with. \n\nYou can also scale your Media Services account by adding storage accounts to it. Each storage account is limited to 500 TB. To expand your storage beyond the default limitations, you can choose to attach multiple storage accounts to a single Media Services account.\n\n[This](media-services-how-to-scale.md) topic links to relevant topics.\n\n##Support\n\n[Azure Support](http://azure.microsoft.com/support/options/) provides support options for Azure, including Media Services.\n\n##Patterns & practices guidance\n\n[Patterns and practices guidance](https://wamsg.codeplex.com/)\n[Online documentation](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn735912.aspx)\n[Downloadable eBook](https://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=42629)\n\n\n##Service Level Agreement (SLA)\n\n- For Media Services Encoding, we guarantee 99.9% availability of REST API transactions.\n- For Streaming, we will successfully service requests with a 99.9% availability guarantee for existing media content when at least one Streaming Unit is purchased.\n- For Live Channels, we guarantee that running Channels will have external connectivity at least 99.9% of the time.\n- For Content Protection, we guarantee that we will successfully fulfill key requests at least 99.9% of the time.\n- For Indexer, we will successfully service Indexer Task requests processed with an Encoding Reserved Unit 99.9% of the time.\n\n    For more information, see [Microsoft Azure SLA](http://azure.microsoft.com/support/legal/sla/).\n\n\n\n<!-- Images -->\n[overview]: ./media/media-services-overview/media-services-overview.png\n[vod-overview]: ./media/media-services-video-on-demand-workflow/media-services-video-on-demand.png\n[live-overview1]: ./media/media-services-live-streaming-workflow/media-services-live-streaming-new.png\n[live-overview2]: ./media/media-services-live-streaming-workflow/media-services-live-streaming-current.png\n \n\ntest\n"
}