{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "How to Create a Custom Virtual Machine",
      "pos": [
        71,
        109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>custom<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> virtual machine refers to a virtual machine you create using the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>From Gallery<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> method because it lets you configure more options than the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Quick Create<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> method.",
      "pos": [
        111,
        287
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These options include:",
      "pos": [
        288,
        310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "More choices for the image to use to create the virtual machine (VM)",
      "pos": [
        314,
        382
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connecting the VM to a virtual network",
      "pos": [
        385,
        423
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adding the VM to an existing cloud service",
      "pos": [
        427,
        469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adding the VM to an availability set",
      "pos": [
        473,
        509
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: If you want your virtual machine to use a virtual network so you can connect to it directly by hostname or set up cross-premises connections, make sure you specify the virtual network when you create the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        511,
        746
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A virtual machine can be configured to join a virtual network only when you create the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        747,
        850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about virtual networks, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Virtual Network Overview<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=294063)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        851,
        982
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        987,
        1060
      ],
      "content": "Sign in to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://manage.windowsazure.com)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1065,
        1099
      ],
      "content": "On the command bar, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1104,
        1182
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Compute<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Virtual Machine<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>From Gallery<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose the image you want to use, and then click the arrow to continue.",
      "pos": [
        1187,
        1258
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1263,
        1374
      ],
      "content": "If multiple versions of the image are available, in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Version Release Date<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, pick the version you want to use."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1380,
        1468
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machine Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, type the name that you want to use for the virtual machine."
    },
    {
      "content": "Use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tier<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Size<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to select the appropriate size for the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        1473,
        1554
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The size you select affects the maximum configuration of the virtual machine, as well as the pricing.",
      "pos": [
        1555,
        1656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For configuration details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Virtual Machine and Cloud Service Sizes for Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=389844)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1657,
        1789
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1794,
        1901
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New User Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, type a name for the administrative account that you want to use to manage the server."
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New Password<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, type a strong password for the administrative account.",
      "pos": [
        1907,
        1982
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirm Password<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, retype the same password.",
      "pos": [
        1983,
        2033
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the arrow to continue.",
      "pos": [
        2039,
        2067
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2073,
        2119
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud Service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, do one of the following:"
    },
    {
      "content": "If this is the first or only virtual machine in the cloud service, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create a New Cloud Service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2131,
        2236
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then, in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud Service DNS Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, type a name that uses between 3 and 24 lowercase letters and numbers.",
      "pos": [
        2237,
        2343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This name becomes part of the URI that is used to contact the virtual machine through the cloud service.",
      "pos": [
        2344,
        2448
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this virtual machine is being added to a cloud service, select it in the list.",
      "pos": [
        2455,
        2536
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2542,
        2774
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: For more information about placing virtual machines in the same cloud service, see <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>How to connect virtual machines in a cloud service<ept id=\"p2\">](http://www.windowsazure.com/manage/windows/how-to-guides/connect-to-a-cloud-service/)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Region/Affinity Group/Virtual Network<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select region, affinity group, or virtual network that you want to use for the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        2780,
        2921
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about affinity groups, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About Affinity Groups for Virtual Network<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-network/virtual-networks-migrate-to-regional-vnet.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2922,
        3079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Storage Account<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select an existing storage account for the VHD file, or use an automatically generated storage account.",
      "pos": [
        3085,
        3212
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only one storage account per region is automatically created.",
      "pos": [
        3213,
        3274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All other virtual machines that you create with this setting are located in this storage account.",
      "pos": [
        3275,
        3372
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You are limited to 20 storage accounts.",
      "pos": [
        3373,
        3412
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3418,
        3586
      ],
      "content": "If you want the virtual machine to belong to an availability set, in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Availability Set<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Create availability set<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> or add it to an existing availability set."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Virtual machine that are members of an availability set are deployed to different fault domains.",
      "pos": [
        3593,
        3699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Placing multiple virtual machines in an availability set helps ensure that your application is available during network failures, local disk hardware failures, and any planned downtime.",
      "pos": [
        3700,
        3885
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Endpoints<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, review the new endpoints that will be created to allow connections to the virtual machine, such through Remote Desktop or a Secure Shell (SSH) client.",
      "pos": [
        3892,
        4063
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You also can add endpoints now, or create them later.",
      "pos": [
        4064,
        4117
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For instructions on creating them later, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Set Up Endpoints to a Virtual Machine<ept id=\"p1\">](../articles/virtual-machines/virtual-machines-set-up-endpoints.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4118,
        4277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>VM Agent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, decide whether to install the VM Agent.",
      "pos": [
        4285,
        4344
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This agent provides the environment for you to install extensions that can help you interact with the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        4345,
        4463
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage Extensions<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/FWLink/p/?LinkID=390493)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4464,
        4550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the arrow to create the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        4556,
        4602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        4711,
        4721
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the virtual machine is created, it's started automatically.",
      "pos": [
        4724,
        4789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When the portal shows the status as running, you can log in to the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        4790,
        4873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For instructions, see one of the following articles:",
      "pos": [
        4874,
        4926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to Log on to a Virtual Machine Running Linux",
      "pos": [
        4931,
        4979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to Log on to a Virtual Machine Running Windows Server",
      "pos": [
        5054,
        5111
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties authors=\"kathydav\" editor=\"tysonn\" manager=\"jeffreyg\" />\n\n#How to Create a Custom Virtual Machine\n\nA *custom* virtual machine refers to a virtual machine you create using the **From Gallery** method because it lets you configure more options than the **Quick Create** method. These options include:\n\n- More choices for the image to use to create the virtual machine (VM)\n- Connecting the VM to a virtual network \n- Adding the VM to an existing cloud service \n- Adding the VM to an availability set\n\n**Important**: If you want your virtual machine to use a virtual network so you can connect to it directly by hostname or set up cross-premises connections, make sure you specify the virtual network when you create the virtual machine. A virtual machine can be configured to join a virtual network only when you create the virtual machine. For more information about virtual networks, see [Azure Virtual Network Overview](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=294063).\n\n1. Sign in to the [Azure Management Portal](http://manage.windowsazure.com).\n\n2. On the command bar, click **New**.\n\n3. Click **Compute**, click **Virtual Machine**, and then click **From Gallery**.\n\n4. Choose the image you want to use, and then click the arrow to continue.\n\n5. If multiple versions of the image are available, in **Version Release Date**, pick the version you want to use. \n\n6. In **Virtual Machine Name**, type the name that you want to use for the virtual machine.\n\n7. Use **Tier** and **Size** to select the appropriate size for the virtual machine. The size you select affects the maximum configuration of the virtual machine, as well as the pricing. For configuration details, see [Virtual Machine and Cloud Service Sizes for Azure](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=389844).\n\n8. In **New User Name**, type a name for the administrative account that you want to use to manage the server. \n\n9. In **New Password**, type a strong password for the administrative account. In **Confirm Password**, retype the same password.\n\n10. Click the arrow to continue.\n\n11. In **Cloud Service**, do one of the following:\n    \n    - If this is the first or only virtual machine in the cloud service, select **Create a New Cloud Service**. Then, in **Cloud Service DNS Name**, type a name that uses between 3 and 24 lowercase letters and numbers. This name becomes part of the URI that is used to contact the virtual machine through the cloud service.\n    - If this virtual machine is being added to a cloud service, select it in the list.\n\n    **Note**: For more information about placing virtual machines in the same cloud service, see [How to connect virtual machines in a cloud service](http://www.windowsazure.com/manage/windows/how-to-guides/connect-to-a-cloud-service/).\n\n12. In **Region/Affinity Group/Virtual Network**, select region, affinity group, or virtual network that you want to use for the virtual machine. For more information about affinity groups, see [About Affinity Groups for Virtual Network](../virtual-network/virtual-networks-migrate-to-regional-vnet.md).\n\n13. In **Storage Account**, select an existing storage account for the VHD file, or use an automatically generated storage account. Only one storage account per region is automatically created. All other virtual machines that you create with this setting are located in this storage account. You are limited to 20 storage accounts.\n\n14. If you want the virtual machine to belong to an availability set, in **Availability Set**, select **Create availability set** or add it to an existing availability set. \n\n    **Note**: Virtual machine that are members of an availability set are deployed to different fault domains. Placing multiple virtual machines in an availability set helps ensure that your application is available during network failures, local disk hardware failures, and any planned downtime.\n\n15.  Under **Endpoints**, review the new endpoints that will be created to allow connections to the virtual machine, such through Remote Desktop or a Secure Shell (SSH) client. You also can add endpoints now, or create them later. For instructions on creating them later, see [How to Set Up Endpoints to a Virtual Machine](../articles/virtual-machines/virtual-machines-set-up-endpoints.md). \n\n16.  Under **VM Agent**, decide whether to install the VM Agent. This agent provides the environment for you to install extensions that can help you interact with the virtual machine. For details, see [Manage Extensions](http://go.microsoft.com/FWLink/p/?LinkID=390493).\n\n17. Click the arrow to create the virtual machine.\n\n\n    ![Custom virtual machine creation successful](./media/howto-custom-create-vm/VMSuccessWindows.png)\n\n##Next Steps##\nAfter the virtual machine is created, it's started automatically. When the portal shows the status as running, you can log in to the virtual machine. For instructions, see one of the following articles:\n\n- [How to Log on to a Virtual Machine Running Linux](../articles/virtual-machines/virtual-machines-linux-how-to-log-on.md)\n- [How to Log on to a Virtual Machine Running Windows Server](../articles/virtual-machines/virtual-machines-log-on-windows-server.md)\n"
}