{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Sharing an ExpressRoute Circuit Across Multiple Subscriptions | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article walks you through sharing your ExpressRoute circuit across multiple Azure subscriptions.",
      "pos": [
        124,
        225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sharing an ExpressRoute circuit across multiple subscriptions",
      "pos": [
        539,
        600
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A single ExpressRoute circuit can be shared across multiple subscriptions.",
      "pos": [
        602,
        676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Figure 1<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> shows a simple schematic of how sharing ExpressRoute circuits across multiple subscriptions works.",
      "pos": [
        677,
        788
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each of the smaller clouds within the large cloud is used to represent subscriptions belonging to different departments within an organization.",
      "pos": [
        790,
        933
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each of the departments within the organization can use their own subscription for deploying their services but can share a single ExpressRoute dedicated circuit to connect back to the corporate network.",
      "pos": [
        934,
        1137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A single department (in this example: IT) can own the ExpressRoute dedicated circuit.",
      "pos": [
        1138,
        1223
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connectivity and bandwidth charges for the dedicated circuit will be applied to the dedicated circuit owner.",
      "pos": [
        1224,
        1332
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Other subscriptions within the organization can use the ExpressRoute circuit.",
      "pos": [
        1333,
        1410
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure 1",
      "pos": [
        1414,
        1422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Subscription Sharing",
      "pos": [
        1428,
        1448
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Administration",
      "pos": [
        1503,
        1517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>circuit owner<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is the administrator/co-administrator of the subscription in which the ExpressRoute dedicated circuit is created.",
      "pos": [
        1519,
        1652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The circuit owner can authorize administrators/co-administrators of other subscriptions (referred to as <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>circuit user<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> in the Workflow diagram) to use the dedicated circuit they own.",
      "pos": [
        1653,
        1835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Circuit users authorized to use the organization's dedicated circuit can link VNet in their subscription to the dedicated circuit once they are authorized.",
      "pos": [
        1836,
        1991
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The circuit owner has the power to modify and revoke authorizations at any time.",
      "pos": [
        1993,
        2073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Revoking an authorization will result in all links being deleted from the subscription whose access was revoked.",
      "pos": [
        2074,
        2186
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Workflow",
      "pos": [
        2191,
        2199
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The circuit owner authorizes the administrators of other subscriptions to use the specified circuit.",
      "pos": [
        2204,
        2304
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the example below, the administrator of the circuit (Contoso IT) enables the administrator of another subscription (Contoso Sales), by specifying their Microsoft ID, to link up to 2 VNETs to the circuit.",
      "pos": [
        2305,
        2511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cmdlet doesn't send email to the specified Microsoft ID.",
      "pos": [
        2512,
        2572
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The circuit owner need to explicitly notify the other subscription owner that the authorization is complete.",
      "pos": [
        2573,
        2681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once notified by the circuit owner, the administrator of the authorized subscription can run the following cmdlet to retrieve the service key of the circuit.",
      "pos": [
        3107,
        3264
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example, the administrator of Contoso Sales must first sign in using the specified Microsoft ID, salesadmin@contoso.com.",
      "pos": [
        3265,
        3393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The administrator of the authorized subscription runs the following cmdlet to complete the link operation.",
      "pos": [
        3948,
        4054
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "And that's it.",
      "pos": [
        4276,
        4290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conto's Sales VNet on Azure is now linked to a circuit created/owned by ContosoIT.",
      "pos": [
        4291,
        4373
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Managing authorization",
      "pos": [
        4378,
        4400
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The circuit owner can share a circuit with up to 10 Azure subscriptions.",
      "pos": [
        4402,
        4474
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The circuit owner can view who has been authorized to the circuit.",
      "pos": [
        4475,
        4541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The owner can revoke the authorization at any time.",
      "pos": [
        4542,
        4593
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When the circuit owner revokes an authorization, identified by LinkAuthorizationId, all links permitted by that authorization will be deleted immediately.",
      "pos": [
        4595,
        4749
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The linked VNETs will lose connectivity to the on-premises network through the ExpressRoute circuit.",
      "pos": [
        4750,
        4850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The diagram below shows the Authorization Workflow:",
      "pos": [
        5784,
        5835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Subscription Sharing Workflow",
      "pos": [
        5839,
        5868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        5923,
        5933
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5935,
        6038
      ],
      "content": "For more information about ExpressRoute, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ExpressRoute Overview<ept id=\"p1\">](expressroute-introduction.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        6041,
        6045
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Sharing an ExpressRoute Circuit Across Multiple Subscriptions | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"This article walks you through sharing your ExpressRoute circuit across multiple Azure subscriptions.\"\n   services=\"expressroute\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   authors=\"cherylmc\"\n   manager=\"jdial\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"expressroute\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"07/20/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"cherylmc\" />\n\n# Sharing an ExpressRoute circuit across multiple subscriptions\n\nA single ExpressRoute circuit can be shared across multiple subscriptions. **Figure 1** shows a simple schematic of how sharing ExpressRoute circuits across multiple subscriptions works.\n\nEach of the smaller clouds within the large cloud is used to represent subscriptions belonging to different departments within an organization. Each of the departments within the organization can use their own subscription for deploying their services but can share a single ExpressRoute dedicated circuit to connect back to the corporate network. A single department (in this example: IT) can own the ExpressRoute dedicated circuit. Connectivity and bandwidth charges for the dedicated circuit will be applied to the dedicated circuit owner. Other subscriptions within the organization can use the ExpressRoute circuit.\n\n**Figure 1**\n\n![Subscription Sharing](./media/expressroute-share-circuit/IC766124.png)\n\n## Administration\n\nThe *circuit owner* is the administrator/co-administrator of the subscription in which the ExpressRoute dedicated circuit is created. The circuit owner can authorize administrators/co-administrators of other subscriptions (referred to as *circuit user* in the Workflow diagram) to use the dedicated circuit they own. Circuit users authorized to use the organization's dedicated circuit can link VNet in their subscription to the dedicated circuit once they are authorized.\n\nThe circuit owner has the power to modify and revoke authorizations at any time. Revoking an authorization will result in all links being deleted from the subscription whose access was revoked.\n\n## Workflow\n\n1. The circuit owner authorizes the administrators of other subscriptions to use the specified circuit. In the example below, the administrator of the circuit (Contoso IT) enables the administrator of another subscription (Contoso Sales), by specifying their Microsoft ID, to link up to 2 VNETs to the circuit. The cmdlet doesn't send email to the specified Microsoft ID. The circuit owner need to explicitly notify the other subscription owner that the authorization is complete.\n\n        PS C:\\> New-AzureDedicatedCircuitLinkAuthorization -ServiceKey '6ed7e310-1a02-4261-915f-6ccfedc416f1' -Description 'SalesTeam' -Limit 2 -MicrosoftIds 'salesadmin@contoso.com'\n        \n        Description         : SalesTeam \n        Limit               : 2 \n        LinkAuthorizationId : e2bc2645-6fd4-44a4-94f5-f2e43e6953ed \n        MicrosoftIds        : salesadmin@contoso.com \n        Used                : 0\n\n1. Once notified by the circuit owner, the administrator of the authorized subscription can run the following cmdlet to retrieve the service key of the circuit. In this example, the administrator of Contoso Sales must first sign in using the specified Microsoft ID, salesadmin@contoso.com.\n\n        PS C:\\> Get-AzureAuthorizedDedicatedCircuit\n        \n        Bandwidth                        : 100\n        CircuitName                      : ContosoIT\n        Location                         : Washington DC\n        MaximumAllowedLinks              : 2\n        ServiceKey                       : 6ed7e310-1a02-4261-915f-6ccfedc416f1\n        ServiceProviderName              : ###########\n        ServiceProviderProvisioningState : Provisioned\n        Status                           : Enabled\n        UsedLinks                        : 0\n\n1. The administrator of the authorized subscription runs the following cmdlet to complete the link operation.\n\n        PS C:\\> New-AzureDedicatedCircuitLink –servicekey 6ed7e310-1a02-4261-915f-6ccfedc416f1 –VnetName 'SalesVNET1' \n        \n            State VnetName \n            ----- -------- \n            Provisioned SalesVNET1\n\nAnd that's it. Conto's Sales VNet on Azure is now linked to a circuit created/owned by ContosoIT.\n\n## Managing authorization\n\nThe circuit owner can share a circuit with up to 10 Azure subscriptions. The circuit owner can view who has been authorized to the circuit. The owner can revoke the authorization at any time.  When the circuit owner revokes an authorization, identified by LinkAuthorizationId, all links permitted by that authorization will be deleted immediately. The linked VNETs will lose connectivity to the on-premises network through the ExpressRoute circuit.\n\n    PS C:\\> Get-AzureDedicatedCircuitLinkAuthorization -ServiceKey: 6ed7e310-1a02-4261-915f-6ccfedc416f1 \n    \n    Description         : EngineeringTeam \n    Limit               : 3 \n    LinkAuthorizationId : cc958457-c8c1-4f16-af09-e7f099da64bf \n    MicrosoftIds        : engadmin@contoso.com \n    Used                : 1 \n    \n    Description         : MarketingTeam \n    Limit               : 1 \n    LinkAuthorizationId : d972726f-c7b9-4658-8598-ad3208ac9348 \n    MicrosoftIds        : marketingadmin@contoso.com \n    Used                : 0 \n    \n    Description         : SalesTeam \n    Limit               : 2 \n    LinkAuthorizationId : e2bc2645-6fd4-44a4-94f5-f2e43e6953ed \n    MicrosoftIds        : salesadmin@contoso.com \n    Used                : 2 \n    \n    PS C:\\> Remove-AzureDedicatedCircuitLinkAuthorization -ServiceKey '6ed7e310-1a02-4261-915f-6ccfedc416f1' -AuthorizationId 'e2bc2645-6fd4-44a4-94f5-f2e43e6953ed'\n\n\nThe diagram below shows the Authorization Workflow:\n\n![Subscription Sharing Workflow](./media/expressroute-share-circuit/IC759525.png)\n\n## Next Steps\n\nFor more information about ExpressRoute, see the [ExpressRoute Overview](expressroute-introduction.md).\n\n\ntest\n"
}