{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "How to Create an Azure Virtual Machine with the Azure CLI | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic describes how to install the Azure CLI on any platform, how to use it to connect to your Azure account, and how to create a VM from the Azure CLI.",
      "pos": [
        119,
        276
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating a VM by using the Azure Command-Line Interface (Azure CLI)",
      "pos": [
        626,
        693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure CLI is a great way to manage your Azure infrastructure from any platform.",
      "pos": [
        694,
        777
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only installing the Azure CLI and having an Azure subscription will prevent you from creating a VM immediately, so let's take care of those steps.",
      "pos": [
        779,
        925
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don't have an Azure account, <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>go get a free one<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        926,
        1030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Installing the Azure CLI",
      "pos": [
        1035,
        1059
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1061,
        1141
      ],
      "content": "Follow the instructions for <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>installing the Azure CLI<ept id=\"p1\">](../xplat-cli.md#install)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Connecting to Azure by using the Azure CLI",
      "pos": [
        1146,
        1188
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can connect your Azure CLI installation with a personal Azure account, or with a work or school Azure account.",
      "pos": [
        1190,
        1304
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To understand the differences and choose, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to connect to your Azure subscription<ept id=\"p1\">](../xplat-cli.md#configure)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1305,
        1422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating and connecting to a VM in Azure",
      "pos": [
        1427,
        1467
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1469,
        1568
      ],
      "content": "Creating a VM starts with choosing (or uploading) an image and using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`azure vm create`</ph> command."
    },
    {
      "content": "To choose an image from the command line, you can list the available VM images by using the command <ph id=\"ph1\">`azure vm image list`</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        1573,
        1695
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because there are so many images, you'll want to page the results by using <ph id=\"ph1\">`more`</ph> or filter by using <ph id=\"ph2\">`grep`</ph> (Linux) or <ph id=\"ph3\">`findstr`</ph> (Windows).",
      "pos": [
        1696,
        1835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you're looking for Ubuntu images on Linux, use a command like this:",
      "pos": [
        1836,
        1919
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This would still result in a long list of images, which you could further narrow down by version:",
      "pos": [
        1968,
        2065
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2120,
        2219
      ],
      "content": "From here you can choose an image and use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`show`</ph> command to view its properties in more detail:"
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have chosen a VM image, use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`vm create`</ph> command to create the image.",
      "pos": [
        2333,
        2414
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command has a lot of options, which you can list by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`help`</ph> command:",
      "pos": [
        2415,
        2497
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Along with the image from step 1, the key arguments you need to create a VM are location, DNS name, and user name.",
      "pos": [
        2529,
        2643
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For authentication you can choose to specify a password (on the command line or interactively), or to authenticate by using a certificate.",
      "pos": [
        2649,
        2787
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you choose a password, it needs to be at least 8 characters, contain both uppercase and lowercase letters, and contain a special character (e.g. one of !@#$%^&amp;+=).",
      "pos": [
        2788,
        2954
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's a good idea to put the password in quotes and escape special characters if you're passing it on the command line.",
      "pos": [
        2955,
        3073
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3079,
        3170
      ],
      "content": "To choose a location, you can use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`vm location list`</ph> command to pick a region near you."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3174,
        3366
      ],
      "content": "The DNS name you choose needs to be unique (it will map to <ph id=\"ph1\">`dnsname.cloudapp.net`</ph>), and will be the same as the machine name if you don't specify a machine name on the command line separately."
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        3684,
        3694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let's go do something with your VM.",
      "pos": [
        3696,
        3731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since the example above opened the default SSH port, connecting to the VM once it's up and running is straightforward.",
      "pos": [
        3733,
        3851
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From a Linux command line:",
      "pos": [
        3852,
        3878
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3928,
        4107
      ],
      "content": "A great place to see more examples of using the Azure CLI to manage your Azure infrastructure is <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>the Azure CLI command reference page<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-machines-command-line-tools.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"How to Create an Azure Virtual Machine with the Azure CLI | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"This topic describes how to install the Azure CLI on any platform, how to use it to connect to your Azure account, and how to create a VM from the Azure CLI.\"\n   services=\"virtual-machines\"\n   documentationCenter=\"virtual-machines\"\n   authors=\"dlepow\"\n   manager=\"timlt\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"virtual-machines\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"command-line-interface\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"06/09/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"danlep\"/>\n\n# Creating a VM by using the Azure Command-Line Interface (Azure CLI)\nThe Azure CLI is a great way to manage your Azure infrastructure from any platform.\n\nOnly installing the Azure CLI and having an Azure subscription will prevent you from creating a VM immediately, so let's take care of those steps. If you don't have an Azure account, [go get a free one](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/).\n\n## Installing the Azure CLI\n\nFollow the instructions for [installing the Azure CLI](../xplat-cli.md#install).\n\n## Connecting to Azure by using the Azure CLI\n\nYou can connect your Azure CLI installation with a personal Azure account, or with a work or school Azure account. To understand the differences and choose, see [How to connect to your Azure subscription](../xplat-cli.md#configure).\n\n## Creating and connecting to a VM in Azure\n\nCreating a VM starts with choosing (or uploading) an image and using the `azure vm create` command.\n\n1. To choose an image from the command line, you can list the available VM images by using the command `azure vm image list`. Because there are so many images, you'll want to page the results by using `more` or filter by using `grep` (Linux) or `findstr` (Windows). For example, if you're looking for Ubuntu images on Linux, use a command like this:\n\n        azure vm image list | grep Ubuntu\n\n    This would still result in a long list of images, which you could further narrow down by version:\n\n        azure vm image list | grep Ubuntu-14_10\n\n    From here you can choose an image and use the `show` command to view its properties in more detail:\n\n        azure vm image show b39f27a8b8c64d52b05eac6a62ebad85__Ubuntu-14_10-amd64-server-20150202-en-us-30GB\n\n2. Once you have chosen a VM image, use the `vm create` command to create the image. This command has a lot of options, which you can list by using the `help` command:\n\n        vm create --help\n\n    Along with the image from step 1, the key arguments you need to create a VM are location, DNS name, and user name.\n\n    For authentication you can choose to specify a password (on the command line or interactively), or to authenticate by using a certificate. If you choose a password, it needs to be at least 8 characters, contain both uppercase and lowercase letters, and contain a special character (e.g. one of !@#$%^&+=). It's a good idea to put the password in quotes and escape special characters if you're passing it on the command line.\n\n    To choose a location, you can use the `vm location list` command to pick a region near you.\n\n  The DNS name you choose needs to be unique (it will map to `dnsname.cloudapp.net`), and will be the same as the machine name if you don't specify a machine name on the command line separately.  \n\n    The Linux example below creates a VM in West US, opens the default SSH port 22 (the -e argument), and creates a user called `myadminuser`:\n\n        azure vm create -e -l \"West US\"  my-new-cli-vm b39f27a8b8c64d52b05eac6a62ebad85__Ubuntu-14_10-amd64-server-20150202-en-us-30GB \"myadminuser\" \"myAdm1n@passwd\"\n\n## Next steps\n\nLet's go do something with your VM.\n\nSince the example above opened the default SSH port, connecting to the VM once it's up and running is straightforward. From a Linux command line:\n\n    ssh myadminuser@my-new-cli-vm.cloudapp.net\n\nA great place to see more examples of using the Azure CLI to manage your Azure infrastructure is [the Azure CLI command reference page](../virtual-machines-command-line-tools.md).\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[5]: ./media/markdown-template-for-new-articles/octocats.png\n"
}