{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Sign up for Azure as an organization",
      "pos": [
        27,
        63
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how you can use a work or school account to leverage the existing user accounts, policies, settings, or on-premise server deployments you already have and improve efficiency between your organization's on-premises identity infrastructure and Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        82,
        339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign up for Azure as an organization",
      "pos": [
        648,
        684
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Until recently, you could only sign up for a new Microsoft Azure subscription using your Microsoft account (Windows Live ID).",
      "pos": [
        686,
        811
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure now supports using either of the following two account methods to sign up:",
      "pos": [
        812,
        892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft accounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (created by you for personal use) - Provide access to all consumer-oriented Microsoft products and cloud services, such as Outlook (Hotmail), Messenger, OneDrive, MSN, Xbox LIVE, or Office 365.",
      "pos": [
        896,
        1112
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Signing up for an Outlook.com mailbox automatically creates a Microsoft account.",
      "pos": [
        1113,
        1193
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After a Microsoft account is created, it can be used to access consumer-related Microsoft cloud services or Azure.",
      "pos": [
        1194,
        1308
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Learn more<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.microsoft.com/account/default.aspx)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        1309,
        1368
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Work or school accounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (issued by an admin for business/academic use) - Provide access to all small, medium, and enterprise business-level Microsoft cloud services, such as Azure, Microsoft Intune, or Office 365.",
      "pos": [
        1372,
        1589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you sign up to one of these services as an organization, a cloud-based directory is automatically provisioned in Azure Active Directory to represent your organization.",
      "pos": [
        1590,
        1762
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Learn more<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-administer.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        1763,
        1807
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After this directory has been created, an admin can then create users and assign licenses to them based on which cloud service subscriptions they need access to, such as Azure.",
      "pos": [
        1813,
        1989
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Want to sign up for Azure as an organization?",
      "pos": [
        1991,
        2036
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Sign up now<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept><ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/purchase-options/)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        2037,
        2109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additional Resources",
      "pos": [
        2113,
        2133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Azure blog",
      "pos": [
        2140,
        2160
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Azure AD?",
      "pos": [
        2199,
        2216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use your on-premises identity infrastructure in the cloud",
      "pos": [
        2249,
        2306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        2341,
        2345
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Sign up for Azure as an organization\"\n    description=\"Learn how you can use a work or school account to leverage the existing user accounts, policies, settings, or on-premise server deployments you already have and improve efficiency between your organization's on-premises identity infrastructure and Azure AD.\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"markvi\"\n    manager=\"stevenpo\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n    ms.workload=\"identity\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"07/30/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"markvi\"/>\n\n\n# Sign up for Azure as an organization\n\nUntil recently, you could only sign up for a new Microsoft Azure subscription using your Microsoft account (Windows Live ID). Azure now supports using either of the following two account methods to sign up:\n\n* **Microsoft accounts** (created by you for personal use) - Provide access to all consumer-oriented Microsoft products and cloud services, such as Outlook (Hotmail), Messenger, OneDrive, MSN, Xbox LIVE, or Office 365. Signing up for an Outlook.com mailbox automatically creates a Microsoft account. After a Microsoft account is created, it can be used to access consumer-related Microsoft cloud services or Azure. [Learn more](http://www.microsoft.com/account/default.aspx)\n\n* **Work or school accounts** (issued by an admin for business/academic use) - Provide access to all small, medium, and enterprise business-level Microsoft cloud services, such as Azure, Microsoft Intune, or Office 365. When you sign up to one of these services as an organization, a cloud-based directory is automatically provisioned in Azure Active Directory to represent your organization. [Learn more](active-directory-administer.md)\n\n    After this directory has been created, an admin can then create users and assign licenses to them based on which cloud service subscriptions they need access to, such as Azure.\n\nWant to sign up for Azure as an organization? [**Sign up now**](https://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/purchase-options/)\n\n**Additional Resources**\n\n* [Microsoft Azure blog](http://azure.microsoft.com/blog/)\n* [What is Azure AD?](active-directory-whatis.md)\n* [Use your on-premises identity infrastructure in the cloud](active-directory-aadconnect.md)\n\ntest\n"
}