{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Configure Traffic Manager round robin traffic routing method | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        104
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article will help you configure round robin load balancing for your Traffic Manager endpoints.",
      "pos": [
        122,
        221
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure Round Robin routing method",
      "pos": [
        536,
        572
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A common traffic routing method pattern is to provide a set of identical endpoints, which include cloud services and websites, and send traffic to each in a round-robin fashion.",
      "pos": [
        574,
        751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The steps below outline how to configure Traffic Manager in order to perform this type of traffic routing method.",
      "pos": [
        752,
        865
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information on the different traffic routing methods, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About Traffic Manager traffic routing methods<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-load-balancing-methods.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        866,
        1024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Azure Websites already provides round-robin load balancing functionality for websites within a datacenter (also known as a region).",
      "pos": [
        1027,
        1171
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traffic Manager allows you to specify round-robin traffic routing method for websites in different datacenters.",
      "pos": [
        1172,
        1283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Routing traffic equally (round robin) across a set of endpoints:",
      "pos": [
        1288,
        1352
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the Management Portal, in the left pane, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Traffic Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> icon to open the Traffic Manager pane.",
      "pos": [
        1357,
        1469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have not yet created your Traffic Manager profile, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage Traffic Manager Profiles<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-manage-profiles.md)</ept> for steps to create a basic Traffic Manager profile.",
      "pos": [
        1470,
        1654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the Management Portal, on the Traffic Manager pane, locate the Traffic Manager profile that contains the settings that you want to modify, and then click the arrow to the right of the profile name.",
      "pos": [
        1658,
        1858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will open the settings page for the profile.",
      "pos": [
        1859,
        1908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the page for your profile, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Endpoints<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the top of the page and verify that the service endpoints that you want to include in your configuration are present.",
      "pos": [
        1912,
        2082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For steps to add or remove endpoints, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage Endpoints in Traffic Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-endpoints.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2083,
        2193
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2197,
        2281
      ],
      "content": "On your profile page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the top to open the configuration page."
    },
    {
      "content": "For <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>traffic routing method Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, verify that the traffic routing method is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Round Robin<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2285,
        2384
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If it is not, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Round Robin<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the dropdown list.",
      "pos": [
        2385,
        2442
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Monitoring Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> are configured appropriately.",
      "pos": [
        2446,
        2515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitoring ensures that endpoints that are offline are not sent traffic.",
      "pos": [
        2516,
        2588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In order to monitor endpoints, you must specify a path and filename.",
      "pos": [
        2589,
        2657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that a forward slash “/“ is a valid entry for the relative path and implies that the file is in the root directory (default).",
      "pos": [
        2658,
        2788
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about monitoring, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About Traffic Manager Monitoring<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-monitoring.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2789,
        2898
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2902,
        2990
      ],
      "content": "After you complete your configuration changes, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the bottom of the page."
    },
    {
      "content": "Test the changes in your configuration.",
      "pos": [
        2994,
        3033
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Testing Traffic Manager Settings<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-testing-settings.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3034,
        3132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once your Traffic Manager profile is setup and working, edit the DNS record on your authoritative DNS server to point your company domain name to the Traffic Manager domain name.",
      "pos": [
        3136,
        3314
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about how to do this, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Point a Company Internet Domain to a Traffic Manager Domain<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-point-internet-domain.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3315,
        3466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        3471,
        3481
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "About Traffic Manager traffic routing Methods",
      "pos": [
        3484,
        3529
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traffic Manager - Disable, enable or delete a profile",
      "pos": [
        3576,
        3629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traffic Manager - Disable or enable an endpoint",
      "pos": [
        3672,
        3719
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Traffic Manager?",
      "pos": [
        3757,
        3781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cloud Services",
      "pos": [
        3817,
        3831
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Websites",
      "pos": [
        3882,
        3890
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operations on Traffic Manager (REST API Reference)",
      "pos": [
        3943,
        3993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Traffic Manager Cmdlets",
      "pos": [
        4044,
        4073
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Configure Traffic Manager round robin traffic routing method | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"This article will help you configure round robin load balancing for your Traffic Manager endpoints.\"\n   services=\"traffic-manager\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"joaoma\"\n   manager=\"adinah\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"traffic-manager\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"08/19/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"joaoma\" />\n\n# Configure Round Robin routing method\n\nA common traffic routing method pattern is to provide a set of identical endpoints, which include cloud services and websites, and send traffic to each in a round-robin fashion. The steps below outline how to configure Traffic Manager in order to perform this type of traffic routing method. For more information on the different traffic routing methods, see [About Traffic Manager traffic routing methods](traffic-manager-load-balancing-methods.md).\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] Azure Websites already provides round-robin load balancing functionality for websites within a datacenter (also known as a region). Traffic Manager allows you to specify round-robin traffic routing method for websites in different datacenters.\n\n## Routing traffic equally (round robin) across a set of endpoints:\n\n1. In the Management Portal, in the left pane, click the **Traffic Manager** icon to open the Traffic Manager pane. If you have not yet created your Traffic Manager profile, see [Manage Traffic Manager Profiles](traffic-manager-manage-profiles.md) for steps to create a basic Traffic Manager profile.\n2. In the Management Portal, on the Traffic Manager pane, locate the Traffic Manager profile that contains the settings that you want to modify, and then click the arrow to the right of the profile name. This will open the settings page for the profile.\n3. On the page for your profile, click **Endpoints** at the top of the page and verify that the service endpoints that you want to include in your configuration are present. For steps to add or remove endpoints, see [Manage Endpoints in Traffic Manager](traffic-manager-endpoints.md).\n4. On your profile page, click **Configure** at the top to open the configuration page.\n5. For **traffic routing method Settings**, verify that the traffic routing method is **Round Robin**. If it is not, click **Round Robin** in the dropdown list.\n6. Verify that the **Monitoring Settings** are configured appropriately. Monitoring ensures that endpoints that are offline are not sent traffic. In order to monitor endpoints, you must specify a path and filename. Note that a forward slash “/“ is a valid entry for the relative path and implies that the file is in the root directory (default). For more information about monitoring, see [About Traffic Manager Monitoring](traffic-manager-monitoring.md).\n7. After you complete your configuration changes, click **Save** at the bottom of the page.\n8. Test the changes in your configuration. For more information, see [Testing Traffic Manager Settings](traffic-manager-testing-settings.md).\n9. Once your Traffic Manager profile is setup and working, edit the DNS record on your authoritative DNS server to point your company domain name to the Traffic Manager domain name. For more information about how to do this, see [Point a Company Internet Domain to a Traffic Manager Domain](traffic-manager-point-internet-domain.md).\n\n## Next steps\n\n[About Traffic Manager traffic routing Methods](traffic-manager-load-balancing-methods.md)\n\n[Traffic Manager - Disable, enable or delete a profile](disable-enable-or-delete-a-profile.md)\n\n[Traffic Manager - Disable or enable an endpoint](disable-or-enable-an-endpoint.md)\n\n[What is Traffic Manager?](../traffic-manager-overview.md)\n\n[Cloud Services](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=314074)\n\n[Websites](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=393327)\n\n[Operations on Traffic Manager (REST API Reference)](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=313584)\n\n[Azure Traffic Manager Cmdlets](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=400769)\n "
}