{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Health Operations.",
      "pos": [
        28,
        63
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is the Azure AD Connect Health page that describes additional operations that can be performed once you have Azure AD Connect Health deployed..",
      "pos": [
        83,
        231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Health Operations",
      "pos": [
        562,
        596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following topic describes the various operations that can be performed using Azure AD Connect Health.",
      "pos": [
        598,
        703
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enable Email Notifications",
      "pos": [
        708,
        734
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can configure the Azure AD Connect Health Service to send email notifications when alerts are generated indicating your Federation Service Infrastructure is not healthy.",
      "pos": [
        735,
        908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will occur when an alert is generated, as well as when it is marked as resolved.",
      "pos": [
        909,
        994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Follow the instructions below to configure email notifications.",
      "pos": [
        995,
        1058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please note that by default email notifications are disabled.",
      "pos": [
        1059,
        1120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To enable Azure AD Connect Health Email Notifications",
      "pos": [
        1128,
        1181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open the Alerts Blade for the farm for which you wish to receive email notification.",
      "pos": [
        1186,
        1270
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click on the \"Notification Settings\" button from the action bar.",
      "pos": [
        1274,
        1338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Turn the Email Notification switch to ON.",
      "pos": [
        1342,
        1383
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the check box to configure all the Global Tenant Admins to receive email notifications.",
      "pos": [
        1387,
        1481
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you wish to receive email notifications on any other email addresses, you can specify them in the Additional Email Recipients boxes.",
      "pos": [
        1485,
        1620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To remove an email address from this list, right click on the entry and select Delete.",
      "pos": [
        1621,
        1707
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To finalize the changes click on \"Save\".",
      "pos": [
        1711,
        1751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All changes will take effects only after you select \"Save\".",
      "pos": [
        1752,
        1811
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete a server from Azure AD Connect Health Service",
      "pos": [
        1821,
        1873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In some instances, you may wish to remove a server from being monitored.",
      "pos": [
        1875,
        1947
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Follow the instructions below to remove a server from Azure AD Connect Health Service.",
      "pos": [
        1948,
        2034
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When deleting a server, be aware of the following:",
      "pos": [
        2036,
        2086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This action will STOP collecting any further data from that server.",
      "pos": [
        2090,
        2157
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This server will be removed from the monitoring service.",
      "pos": [
        2158,
        2214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After this action, you will not be able to view new alerts, monitoring or usage analytics data for this server.",
      "pos": [
        2215,
        2326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This action will NOT uninstall or remove the Health Agent from your server.",
      "pos": [
        2329,
        2404
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have not uninstalled the Health Agent before performing this step, you may see error events on the server related to the Health Agent.",
      "pos": [
        2405,
        2546
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This action will NOT delete the data already collected from this server.",
      "pos": [
        2549,
        2621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "That data will be deleted as per the Microsoft Azure Data Retention Policy.",
      "pos": [
        2622,
        2697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After performing this action, if you wish to start monitoring the same server again, you will need to uninstall and re-install the health agent on this server.",
      "pos": [
        2701,
        2860
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To delete a server from Azure AD Connect Health Service",
      "pos": [
        2868,
        2923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open the Server Blade from the Server List Blade by selecting the server name to be removed.",
      "pos": [
        2928,
        3020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the Server Blade, click on the \"Delete\" button from the action bar.",
      "pos": [
        3025,
        3095
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Confirm the action to delete the server by typing the server name in the confirmation box.",
      "pos": [
        3099,
        3189
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click on the \"Delete\" button.",
      "pos": [
        3193,
        3222
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete a service instance from Azure AD Connect Health Service",
      "pos": [
        3233,
        3295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In some instances, you may wish to remove a service instance.",
      "pos": [
        3297,
        3358
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Follow the instructions below to remove a service instance from Azure AD Connect Health Service.",
      "pos": [
        3359,
        3455
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When deleting a service instance, be aware of the following:",
      "pos": [
        3457,
        3517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This action will remove the current service instance from the monitoring service.",
      "pos": [
        3521,
        3602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This action will NOT uninstall or remove the Health Agent from any of the servers that were monitored as part of this service instance.",
      "pos": [
        3606,
        3741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have not uninstalled the Health Agent before performing this step, you may see error events on the server(s) related to the Health Agent.",
      "pos": [
        3742,
        3886
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All data from this service instance will be deleted as per the Microsoft Azure Data Retention Policy.",
      "pos": [
        3890,
        3991
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After performing this action, if you wish to start monitoring the service, please uninstall and re-install the health agent on all the servers that will be monitored.",
      "pos": [
        3995,
        4161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After performing this action, if you wish to start monitoring the same server again, you will need to uninstall and re-install the health agent on this server.",
      "pos": [
        4162,
        4321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To delete a service instance from Azure AD Connect Health Service",
      "pos": [
        4328,
        4393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open the Service Blade from the Service List Blade by selecting the service identifier (farm name) that you wish to remove.",
      "pos": [
        4398,
        4521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the Server Blade, click on the \"Delete\" button from the action bar.",
      "pos": [
        4526,
        4596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Confirm the service name by typing it in the confirmation box.",
      "pos": [
        4600,
        4662
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(for example: sts.contoso.com)",
      "pos": [
        4663,
        4693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click on the \"Delete\" button.",
      "pos": [
        4698,
        4727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enable Auditing for AD FS",
      "pos": [
        4732,
        4757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In order for the Usage Analytics feature to gather data and analyze the Azure AD Connect Health agent needs the information in the AD FS Audit Logs.",
      "pos": [
        4759,
        4907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These logs are not enabled by default.",
      "pos": [
        4908,
        4946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This only applies to AD FS federation servers.",
      "pos": [
        4947,
        4993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You do not need to enable auditing on AD FS Proxy servers or Web Application Proxy servers.",
      "pos": [
        4994,
        5085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following procedures to enable AD FS auditing and to locate the AD FS audit logs.",
      "pos": [
        5086,
        5175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To enable auditing for AD FS 2.0",
      "pos": [
        5182,
        5214
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5219,
        5335
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Start<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, point to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Programs<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, point to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Administrative Tools<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Local Security Policy<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5339,
        5470
      ],
      "content": "Navigate to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Security Settings\\Local Policies\\User Rights Management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> folder, and then double-click Generate security audits."
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Local Security Setting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, verify that the AD FS 2.0 service account is listed.",
      "pos": [
        5474,
        5565
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If it is not present, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add User or Group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and add it to the list, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5566,
        5662
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5666,
        5861
      ],
      "content": "Open a command prompt with elevated privileges and run the following command to enable auditing.<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">auditpol.exe /set /subcategory:\"Application Generated\" /failure:enable /success:enable</ph><ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;/code&gt;</ph>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Close Local Security Policy, and then open the Management snap-in.",
      "pos": [
        5865,
        5931
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To open the Management snap-in, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Start<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, point to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Programs<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, point to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Administrative Tools<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and then click AD FS 2.0 Management.",
      "pos": [
        5933,
        6076
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the Actions pane, click Edit Federation Service Properties.",
      "pos": [
        6080,
        6142
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6146,
        6224
      ],
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Federation Service Properties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box, click the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Events<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6228,
        6293
      ],
      "content": "Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Success audits<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Failure audits<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> check boxes."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6297,
        6310
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "To enable auditing for AD FS on Windows Server 2012 R2",
      "pos": [
        6317,
        6371
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6376,
        6550
      ],
      "content": "Open <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Local Security Policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> by opening <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Server Manager<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> on the Start screen, or Server Manager in the taskbar on the desktop, then click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Tools/Local Security Policy<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6554,
        6689
      ],
      "content": "Navigate to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Security Settings\\Local Policies\\User Rights Assignment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> folder, and then double-click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Generate security audits<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Local Security Setting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, verify that the AD FS service account is listed.",
      "pos": [
        6693,
        6780
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If it is not present, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add User or Group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and add it to the list, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6781,
        6877
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6881,
        7078
      ],
      "content": "Open a command prompt with elevated privileges and run the following command to enable auditing: <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">auditpol.exe /set /subcategory:\"Application Generated\" /failure:enable /success:enable.</ph><ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;/code&gt;</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7082,
        7229
      ],
      "content": "Close <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Local Security Policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then open the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>AD FS Management<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> snap-in (in Server Manager, click Tools, and then select AD FS Management)."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7233,
        7299
      ],
      "content": "In the Actions pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit Federation Service Properties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7303,
        7377
      ],
      "content": "In the Federation Service Properties dialog box, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Events<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7381,
        7464
      ],
      "content": "Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Success audits and Failure audits<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> check boxes and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "To locate the AD FS audit logs",
      "pos": [
        7476,
        7506
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7512,
        7534
      ],
      "content": "Open <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Event Viewer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7538,
        7581
      ],
      "content": "Go to Windows Logs and select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Security<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7585,
        7629
      ],
      "content": "On the right, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Filter Current Logs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7633,
        7679
      ],
      "content": "Under Event Source, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AD FS Auditing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "AD FS audit logs",
      "pos": [
        7683,
        7699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.WARNING]</ph> If you have a group policy that is disabling AD FS auditing then the Azure AD Connect Health Agent will not be able to collect information.",
      "pos": [
        7775,
        7930
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure that you don’t have a group policy that may be disabling auditing.",
      "pos": [
        7931,
        8004
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Related links",
      "pos": [
        8010,
        8023
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Health",
      "pos": [
        8028,
        8051
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD Connect Health Agent Installation for AD FS",
      "pos": [
        8095,
        8147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Azure AD Connect Health with AD FS",
      "pos": [
        8210,
        8250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure AD Connect Health FAQ<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-aadconnect-health-faq.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        8298,
        8370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        8371,
        8375
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Azure AD Connect Health Operations.\" \n    description=\"This is the Azure AD Connect Health page that describes additional operations that can be performed once you have Azure AD Connect Health deployed..\" \n    services=\"active-directory\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"billmath\" \n    manager=\"stevenpo\" \n    editor=\"curtand\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"active-directory\" \n    ms.workload=\"identity\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"08/14/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"billmath\"/> \n\n# Azure AD Connect Health Operations\n\nThe following topic describes the various operations that can be performed using Azure AD Connect Health.\n\n## Enable Email Notifications\nYou can configure the Azure AD Connect Health Service to send email notifications when alerts are generated indicating your Federation Service Infrastructure is not healthy. This will occur when an alert is generated, as well as when it is marked as resolved. Follow the instructions below to configure email notifications. Please note that by default email notifications are disabled. \n\n\n### To enable Azure AD Connect Health Email Notifications\n\n1. Open the Alerts Blade for the farm for which you wish to receive email notification.\n2. Click on the \"Notification Settings\" button from the action bar.\n3. Turn the Email Notification switch to ON.\n4. Select the check box to configure all the Global Tenant Admins to receive email notifications.\n5. If you wish to receive email notifications on any other email addresses, you can specify them in the Additional Email Recipients boxes. To remove an email address from this list, right click on the entry and select Delete.\n6. To finalize the changes click on \"Save\". All changes will take effects only after you select \"Save\".\n\n\n\n\n\n\n## Delete a server from Azure AD Connect Health Service\n\nIn some instances, you may wish to remove a server from being monitored. Follow the instructions below to remove a server from Azure AD Connect Health Service.\n\nWhen deleting a server, be aware of the following:\n\n- This action will STOP collecting any further data from that server. This server will be removed from the monitoring service. After this action, you will not be able to view new alerts, monitoring or usage analytics data for this server.\n- This action will NOT uninstall or remove the Health Agent from your server. If you have not uninstalled the Health Agent before performing this step, you may see error events on the server related to the Health Agent.\n- This action will NOT delete the data already collected from this server. That data will be deleted as per the Microsoft Azure Data Retention Policy. \n- After performing this action, if you wish to start monitoring the same server again, you will need to uninstall and re-install the health agent on this server. \n\n\n### To delete a server from Azure AD Connect Health Service\n\n1. Open the Server Blade from the Server List Blade by selecting the server name to be removed. \n2. On the Server Blade, click on the \"Delete\" button from the action bar.\n3. Confirm the action to delete the server by typing the server name in the confirmation box.\n4. Click on the \"Delete\" button.\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n## Delete a service instance from Azure AD Connect Health Service\n\nIn some instances, you may wish to remove a service instance. Follow the instructions below to remove a service instance from Azure AD Connect Health Service.\n\nWhen deleting a service instance, be aware of the following:\n\n- This action will remove the current service instance from the monitoring service. \n- This action will NOT uninstall or remove the Health Agent from any of the servers that were monitored as part of this service instance. If you have not uninstalled the Health Agent before performing this step, you may see error events on the server(s) related to the Health Agent. \n- All data from this service instance will be deleted as per the Microsoft Azure Data Retention Policy. \n- After performing this action, if you wish to start monitoring the service, please uninstall and re-install the health agent on all the servers that will be monitored. After performing this action, if you wish to start monitoring the same server again, you will need to uninstall and re-install the health agent on this server.\n\n\n### To delete a service instance from Azure AD Connect Health Service\n\n1. Open the Service Blade from the Service List Blade by selecting the service identifier (farm name) that you wish to remove. \n2. On the Server Blade, click on the \"Delete\" button from the action bar.\n3. Confirm the service name by typing it in the confirmation box. (for example: sts.contoso.com) \n4. Click on the \"Delete\" button.\n\n## Enable Auditing for AD FS\n\nIn order for the Usage Analytics feature to gather data and analyze the Azure AD Connect Health agent needs the information in the AD FS Audit Logs. These logs are not enabled by default. This only applies to AD FS federation servers. You do not need to enable auditing on AD FS Proxy servers or Web Application Proxy servers. Use the following procedures to enable AD FS auditing and to locate the AD FS audit logs.\n\n#### To enable auditing for AD FS 2.0\n\n1. Click **Start**, point to **Programs**, point to **Administrative Tools**, and then click **Local Security Policy**.\n2. Navigate to the **Security Settings\\Local Policies\\User Rights Management** folder, and then double-click Generate security audits.\n3. On the **Local Security Setting** tab, verify that the AD FS 2.0 service account is listed. If it is not present, click **Add User or Group** and add it to the list, and then click **OK**.\n4. Open a command prompt with elevated privileges and run the following command to enable auditing.<code>auditpol.exe /set /subcategory:\"Application Generated\" /failure:enable /success:enable</code>\n5. Close Local Security Policy, and then open the Management snap-in.  To open the Management snap-in, click **Start**, point to **Programs**, point to **Administrative Tools**, and then click AD FS 2.0 Management.\n6. In the Actions pane, click Edit Federation Service Properties.\n7. In the **Federation Service Properties** dialog box, click the **Events** tab.\n8. Select the **Success audits** and **Failure audits** check boxes.\n9. Click **OK**.\n\n#### To enable auditing for AD FS on Windows Server 2012 R2\n\n1. Open **Local Security Policy** by opening **Server Manager** on the Start screen, or Server Manager in the taskbar on the desktop, then click **Tools/Local Security Policy**.\n2. Navigate to the **Security Settings\\Local Policies\\User Rights Assignment** folder, and then double-click **Generate security audits**.\n3. On the **Local Security Setting** tab, verify that the AD FS service account is listed. If it is not present, click **Add User or Group** and add it to the list, and then click **OK**.\n4. Open a command prompt with elevated privileges and run the following command to enable auditing: <code>auditpol.exe /set /subcategory:\"Application Generated\" /failure:enable /success:enable.</code>\n5. Close **Local Security Policy**, and then open the **AD FS Management** snap-in (in Server Manager, click Tools, and then select AD FS Management).\n6. In the Actions pane, click **Edit Federation Service Properties**.\n7. In the Federation Service Properties dialog box, click the **Events** tab.\n8. Select the **Success audits and Failure audits** check boxes and then click **OK**.\n\n\n\n\n\n\n#### To locate the AD FS audit logs\n\n\n1. Open **Event Viewer**.\n2. Go to Windows Logs and select **Security**.\n3. On the right, click **Filter Current Logs**.\n4. Under Event Source, select **AD FS Auditing**.\n\n![AD FS audit logs](./media/active-directory-aadconnect-health-requirements/adfsaudit.png)\n\n> [AZURE.WARNING] If you have a group policy that is disabling AD FS auditing then the Azure AD Connect Health Agent will not be able to collect information. Ensure that you don’t have a group policy that may be disabling auditing.\n\n\n## Related links\n\n* [Azure AD Connect Health](active-directory-aadconnect-health.md)\n* [Azure AD Connect Health Agent Installation for AD FS](active-directory-aadconnect-health-agent-install-adfs.md)\n* [Using Azure AD Connect Health with AD FS](active-directory-aadconnect-health-adfs.md)\n* [Azure AD Connect Health FAQ](active-directory-aadconnect-health-faq.md)\ntest\n"
}