{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Track B2B messages",
      "pos": [
        27,
        45
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic covers tracking of B2B processing",
      "pos": [
        64,
        108
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Track B2B messages",
      "pos": [
        436,
        454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "B2B Tracking Information",
      "pos": [
        459,
        483
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "B2B communication involves message processing between trading partners.",
      "pos": [
        484,
        555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The relationships are defined as agreements between two trading partners.",
      "pos": [
        556,
        629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the communication is established then there needs to be a way to monitor if the communication is happening as expected.",
      "pos": [
        630,
        754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As part of bringing B2B API Apps as part of Azure App Services we have enabled tracking data and the same is also surfaced via Azure Portal.",
      "pos": [
        756,
        896
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AS2",
      "pos": [
        902,
        905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have created an instance of an AS2 API App then browse to that instance and go to the Tracking part.",
      "pos": [
        906,
        1015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Herein one will be able to view all the AS2 tracking information and also filter it via the filter blades surfaced.",
      "pos": [
        1016,
        1131
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][1]",
      "pos": [
        1133,
        1139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EDIFACT",
      "pos": [
        1146,
        1153
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have created an instance of an EDIFACT API App then browse to that instance and go to the Tracking part.",
      "pos": [
        1154,
        1267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Herein one will be able to view all the EDIFACT tracking information and also filter it via the filters surfaced.",
      "pos": [
        1268,
        1381
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additionally one will be able to view the interchange level data, group level data and transaction set level data as one steps into the view.",
      "pos": [
        1382,
        1523
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If batches have been created as part of EDIFACT agreements in the associated Trading Partner Management API app then the Batching part will list all these batches.",
      "pos": [
        1526,
        1689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One would be able to step into a batch to see the message which constitute the active message (if any) and also the information for batches which have completed in the past.",
      "pos": [
        1690,
        1863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][2]",
      "pos": [
        1865,
        1871
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X12",
      "pos": [
        1882,
        1885
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have created an instance of a X12 API App then browse to that instance and go to the Tracking part.",
      "pos": [
        1886,
        1994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Herein one will be able to view all the X12 tracking information and also filter it via the filters surfaced.",
      "pos": [
        1995,
        2104
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additionally one will be able to view the interchange level data, group level data and transaction set level data as one steps into the view.",
      "pos": [
        2105,
        2246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If batches have been created as part of X12 agreements in the associated Trading Partner Management API app then the Batching part will list all these batches.",
      "pos": [
        2249,
        2408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One would be able to step into a batch to see the message which constitute the active message (if any) and also the information for batches which have completed in the past.",
      "pos": [
        2409,
        2582
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X12 &amp; EDIFACT have similar tracking views.",
      "pos": [
        2585,
        2627
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        2792,
        2796
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Track B2B messages\" \n   description=\"This topic covers tracking of B2B processing\" \n   services=\"app-service\\logic\" \n   documentationCenter=\".net,nodejs,java\" \n   authors=\"rajram\" \n   manager=\"dwrede\" \n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"app-service-logic\"\n   ms.devlang=\"multiple\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"integration\" \n   ms.date=\"07/01/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"rajram\"/>\n\n\n# Track B2B messages\n\n## B2B Tracking Information\nB2B communication involves message processing between trading partners. The relationships are defined as agreements between two trading partners. Once the communication is established then there needs to be a way to monitor if the communication is happening as expected. \nAs part of bringing B2B API Apps as part of Azure App Services we have enabled tracking data and the same is also surfaced via Azure Portal. \n\n## AS2\nOnce you have created an instance of an AS2 API App then browse to that instance and go to the Tracking part. Herein one will be able to view all the AS2 tracking information and also filter it via the filter blades surfaced.\n\n![][1]  \n\n## EDIFACT\nOnce you have created an instance of an EDIFACT API App then browse to that instance and go to the Tracking part. Herein one will be able to view all the EDIFACT tracking information and also filter it via the filters surfaced.\nAdditionally one will be able to view the interchange level data, group level data and transaction set level data as one steps into the view. \n\nIf batches have been created as part of EDIFACT agreements in the associated Trading Partner Management API app then the Batching part will list all these batches. One would be able to step into a batch to see the message which constitute the active message (if any) and also the information for batches which have completed in the past.\n\n![][2]      \n\n## X12\nOnce you have created an instance of a X12 API App then browse to that instance and go to the Tracking part. Herein one will be able to view all the X12 tracking information and also filter it via the filters surfaced.\nAdditionally one will be able to view the interchange level data, group level data and transaction set level data as one steps into the view. \n\nIf batches have been created as part of X12 agreements in the associated Trading Partner Management API app then the Batching part will list all these batches. One would be able to step into a batch to see the message which constitute the active message (if any) and also the information for batches which have completed in the past. \n\nX12 & EDIFACT have similar tracking views. \n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/app-service-logic-track-b2b-messages/AS2Tracking.jpg\n[2]: ./media/app-service-logic-track-b2b-messages/EDIFACTTracking.jpg \n\ntest\n"
}