{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Learning PowerShell Workflow",
      "pos": [
        27,
        55
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Runbooks in Azure Automation are based on Windows PowerShell Workflow.",
      "pos": [
        73,
        143
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article is intended as a quick lesson for authors familiar with PowerShell to understand the specific differences between PowerShell and PowerShell Workflow.",
      "pos": [
        145,
        307
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learning Windows PowerShell Workflow",
      "pos": [
        612,
        648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Runbooks in Azure Automation are implemented as Windows PowerShell Workflows.",
      "pos": [
        650,
        727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A Windows PowerShell Workflow is similar to a Windows PowerShell script but has some significant differences that can be confusing to a new user.",
      "pos": [
        729,
        874
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article is intended for users already familiar with PowerShell and briefly explains concepts that you require if you are converting a PowerShell script to a PowerShell Workflow for use in a runbook.",
      "pos": [
        876,
        1079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A workflow is a sequence of programmed, connected steps that perform long-running tasks or require the coordination of multiple steps across multiple devices or managed nodes.",
      "pos": [
        1083,
        1258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The benefits of a workflow over a normal script include the ability to simultaneously perform an action against multiple devices and the ability to automatically recover from failures.",
      "pos": [
        1259,
        1443
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A Windows PowerShell Workflow is a Windows PowerShell script that leverages Windows Workflow Foundation.",
      "pos": [
        1444,
        1548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While the workflow is written with Windows PowerShell syntax and launched by Windows PowerShell, it is processed by Windows Workflow Foundation.",
      "pos": [
        1549,
        1693
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1695,
        1854
      ],
      "content": "For complete details on the topics in this article, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Getting Started with Windows PowerShell Workflow<ept id=\"p1\">](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj134242.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Types of runbook",
      "pos": [
        1859,
        1875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two types of runbook in Azure Automation, <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>textual<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>graphical<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1877,
        1955
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You define the runbook type when you create the runbook, and you can't convert a runbook to the other type once it's been created.",
      "pos": [
        1957,
        2087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Textual runbooks are for users who prefer to work directly with the PowerShell workflow code either using the textual editor in Azure Automation or an offline editor such as PowerShell ISE.",
      "pos": [
        2089,
        2278
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should understand the information in this article if you are creating a textual runbook.",
      "pos": [
        2279,
        2371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Graphical runbooks allow you to create a runbook using the same activities and cmdlets but using a graphical interface that hides the complexities of the underlying PowerShell workflow.",
      "pos": [
        2374,
        2559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Concepts in this article such as checkpoints and parallel execution still apply to graphical runbooks, but you won't have to worry about the detailed syntax.",
      "pos": [
        2561,
        2718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Basic structure of a workflow",
      "pos": [
        2724,
        2753
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The first step to converting a PowerShell script to a PowerShell workflow is enclosing it with the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Workflow<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> keyword.",
      "pos": [
        2755,
        2875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A workflow starts with the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Workflow<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> keyword followed by the body of the script enclosed in braces.",
      "pos": [
        2877,
        2979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name of the workflow follows the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Workflow<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> keyword as shown in the following syntax.",
      "pos": [
        2980,
        3071
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name of the workflow must match the name of the Automation runbook.",
      "pos": [
        3132,
        3203
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the runbook is being imported, then the filename must match the workflow name and must end in .ps1.",
      "pos": [
        3204,
        3306
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3308,
        3399
      ],
      "content": "To add parameters to the workflow, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Param<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> keyword just as you would to a script."
    },
    {
      "content": "Code changes",
      "pos": [
        3405,
        3417
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell workflow code looks almost identical to PowerShell script code except for a few significant changes.",
      "pos": [
        3419,
        3530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following sections describe changes that you will need to make to a PowerShell script for it to run in a workflow.",
      "pos": [
        3532,
        3650
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Activities",
      "pos": [
        3656,
        3666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An activity is a specific task in a workflow.",
      "pos": [
        3668,
        3713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Just as a script is composed of one or more commands, a workflow is composed of one or more activities that are carried out in a sequence.",
      "pos": [
        3714,
        3852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows PowerShell Workflow automatically converts many of the Windows PowerShell cmdlets to activities when it runs a workflow.",
      "pos": [
        3853,
        3981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you specify one of these cmdlets in your runbook, the corresponding activity is actually run by Windows Workflow Foundation.",
      "pos": [
        3982,
        4111
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For those cmdlets without a corresponding activity, Windows PowerShell Workflow automatically runs the cmdlet within an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>InlineScript<ept id=\"p1\">](#inlinescript)</ept> activity.",
      "pos": [
        4112,
        4271
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There is a set of cmdlets that are excluded and cannot be used in a workflow unless you explicitly include them in an InlineScript block.",
      "pos": [
        4272,
        4409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For further details on these concepts, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using Activities in Script Workflows<ept id=\"p1\">](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj574194.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4410,
        4544
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Workflow activities share a set of common parameters to configure their operation.",
      "pos": [
        4546,
        4628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For details about the workflow common parameters, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>about_WorkflowCommonParameters<ept id=\"p1\">](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj129719.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4629,
        4768
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Positional parameters",
      "pos": [
        4774,
        4795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can't use positional parameters with activities and cmdlets in a workflow.",
      "pos": [
        4797,
        4875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All this means is that you must use parameter names.",
      "pos": [
        4877,
        4929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, consider the following code that gets all running services.",
      "pos": [
        4931,
        5003
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you try to run this same code in a workflow, you'll get a message like \"Parameter set cannot be resolved using the specified named parameters.\"",
      "pos": [
        5064,
        5210
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To correct this, simply provide the parameter name as in the following.",
      "pos": [
        5212,
        5283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deserialized objects",
      "pos": [
        5410,
        5430
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Objects in workflows are deserialized.",
      "pos": [
        5432,
        5470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that their properties are still available, but not their methods.",
      "pos": [
        5472,
        5548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, consider the following PowerShell code that stops a service using the Stop method of the Service object.",
      "pos": [
        5550,
        5667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you try to run this in a workflow, you'll get an error saying \"Method invocation is not supported in a Windows PowerShell Workflow\".",
      "pos": [
        5733,
        5868
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5872,
        6026
      ],
      "content": "One option is to wrap these two lines of code in an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>InlineScript<ept id=\"p1\">](#InlineScript)</ept> block in which case $Service would be a service object within the block."
    },
    {
      "content": "Another option is to use another cmdlet that performs the same functionality as the method, if one is available.",
      "pos": [
        6181,
        6293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the case of our sample, the Stop-Service cmdlet provides the same functionality as the Stop method, and you could use the following for a workflow.",
      "pos": [
        6295,
        6445
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "InlineScript",
      "pos": [
        6580,
        6592
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>InlineScript<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> activity is useful when you need to run one or more commands as traditional PowerShell script instead of PowerShell workflow.",
      "pos": [
        6594,
        6740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While commands in a workflow are sent to Windows Workflow Foundation for processing, commands in an InlineScript block are processed by Windows PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        6742,
        6897
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "InlineScript uses the syntax shown below.",
      "pos": [
        6900,
        6941
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can return output from an InlineScript by assigning the output to a variable.",
      "pos": [
        7014,
        7095
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following example stops a service and then outputs the service name.",
      "pos": [
        7096,
        7168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can pass values into an InlineScript block, but you must use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>$Using<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> scope modifier.",
      "pos": [
        7377,
        7468
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following example is identical to the previous example except that the service name is provided by a variable.",
      "pos": [
        7470,
        7584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While InlineScript activities may be critical in certain workflows, they do not support workflow constructs and should only be used when necessary for the following reasons:",
      "pos": [
        7841,
        8014
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>checkpoints<ept id=\"p1\">](#Checkpoints)</ept> inside of an InlineScript block.",
      "pos": [
        8018,
        8093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a failure occurs within the block, it must be resumed from the beginning of the block.",
      "pos": [
        8094,
        8183
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8186,
        8274
      ],
      "content": "You cannot use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>parallel execution<ept id=\"p1\">](#parallel-execution)</ept> inside of an InlineScriptBlock."
    },
    {
      "content": "InlineScript affects scalability of the workflow since it holds the Windows PowerShell session for the entire length of the InlineScript block.",
      "pos": [
        8277,
        8420
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8422,
        8650
      ],
      "content": "For further details on using InlineScript, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Running Windows PowerShell Commands in a Workflow<ept id=\"p1\">](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj574197.aspx)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>about_InlineScript<ept id=\"p2\">](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj649082.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Parallel processing",
      "pos": [
        8656,
        8675
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One advantage of Windows PowerShell Workflows is the ability to perform a set of commands in parallel instead of sequentially as with a typical script.",
      "pos": [
        8677,
        8828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Parallel<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> keyword to create a script block with multiple commands that will run concurrently.",
      "pos": [
        8831,
        8943
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This uses the syntax shown below.",
      "pos": [
        8944,
        8977
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, Activity1 and Activity2 will start at the same time.",
      "pos": [
        8978,
        9044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Activity3 will start only after both Activity1 and Activity2 have completed.",
      "pos": [
        9045,
        9121
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, consider the following PowerShell commands that copy multiple files to a network destination.",
      "pos": [
        9202,
        9308
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These commands are run sequentially so that one file must finish copying before the next is started.",
      "pos": [
        9310,
        9410
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following workflow runs these same commands in parallel so that they all start copying at the same time.",
      "pos": [
        9661,
        9769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only after they are all completely copied is the completion message displayed.",
      "pos": [
        9771,
        9849
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ForEach -Parallel<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> construct to process commands for each item in a collection concurrently.",
      "pos": [
        10214,
        10325
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The items in the collection are processed in parallel while the commands in the script block run sequentially.",
      "pos": [
        10326,
        10436
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This uses the syntax shown below.",
      "pos": [
        10437,
        10470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, Activity1 will start at the same time for all items in the collection.",
      "pos": [
        10471,
        10555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For each item, Activity2 will start after Activity1 is complete.",
      "pos": [
        10556,
        10620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Activity3 will start only after both Activity1 and Activity2 have completed for all items.",
      "pos": [
        10621,
        10711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following example is similar to the previous example copying files in parallel.",
      "pos": [
        10827,
        10910
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, a message is displayed for each file after it copies.",
      "pos": [
        10912,
        10979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only after they are all completely copied is the final completion message displayed.",
      "pos": [
        10981,
        11065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph>  We do not recommend running child runbooks in parallel since this has been shown to give unreliable results.",
      "pos": [
        11420,
        11542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The output from the child runbook sometimes will not show up, and settings in one child runbook can affect the other parallel child runbooks",
      "pos": [
        11544,
        11684
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Checkpoints",
      "pos": [
        11691,
        11702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>checkpoint<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is a snapshot of the current state of the workflow that includes the current value for variables and any output generated to that point.",
      "pos": [
        11704,
        11855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a workflow ends in error or is <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>suspended<ept id=\"p1\">](suspending-a-workflow)</ept>, then the next time it is run it will start from its last checkpoint instead of the start of the worfklow.",
      "pos": [
        11856,
        12031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can set a checkpoint in a workflow with the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Checkpoint-Workflow<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> activity.",
      "pos": [
        12033,
        12114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the following sample code, an exception occurs after Activity2 causing the workflow to end.",
      "pos": [
        12116,
        12210
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When the workflow is run again, it starts by running Activity2 since this was just after the last checkpoint set.",
      "pos": [
        12211,
        12324
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should set checkpoints in a workflow after activities that may be prone to exception and should not be repeated if the workflow is resumed.",
      "pos": [
        12415,
        12558
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, your workflow may create a virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        12559,
        12615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You could set a checkpoint both before and after the commands to create the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        12616,
        12708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the creation fails, then the commands would be repeated if the workflow is started again.",
      "pos": [
        12709,
        12801
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the the worfklow fails after the creation succeeds, then the virtual machine will not be created again when the workflow is resumed.",
      "pos": [
        12802,
        12937
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following example copies multiple files to a network location and sets a checkpoint after each file.",
      "pos": [
        12939,
        13043
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the network location is lost, then the workflow will end in error.",
      "pos": [
        13045,
        13114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When it is started again, it will resume at the last checkpoint meaning that only the files that have already been copied will be skipped.",
      "pos": [
        13116,
        13254
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13631,
        13769
      ],
      "content": "For more information about checkpoints, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Adding Checkpoints to a Script Workflow<ept id=\"p1\">](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj574114.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Related articles",
      "pos": [
        13776,
        13792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Getting Started with Windows PowerShell Workflow<ept id=\"p1\">](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj134242.aspx)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        13796,
        13898
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        13900,
        13904
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Learning PowerShell Workflow\"\n   description=\"Runbooks in Azure Automation are based on Windows PowerShell Workflow.  This article is intended as a quick lesson for authors familiar with PowerShell to understand the specific differences between PowerShell and PowerShell Workflow.\"\n   services=\"automation\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"bwren\"\n   manager=\"stevenka\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"automation\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"07/06/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"bwren\" />\n\n# Learning Windows PowerShell Workflow\n\nRunbooks in Azure Automation are implemented as Windows PowerShell Workflows.  A Windows PowerShell Workflow is similar to a Windows PowerShell script but has some significant differences that can be confusing to a new user.  This article is intended for users already familiar with PowerShell and briefly explains concepts that you require if you are converting a PowerShell script to a PowerShell Workflow for use in a runbook.  \n\nA workflow is a sequence of programmed, connected steps that perform long-running tasks or require the coordination of multiple steps across multiple devices or managed nodes. The benefits of a workflow over a normal script include the ability to simultaneously perform an action against multiple devices and the ability to automatically recover from failures. A Windows PowerShell Workflow is a Windows PowerShell script that leverages Windows Workflow Foundation. While the workflow is written with Windows PowerShell syntax and launched by Windows PowerShell, it is processed by Windows Workflow Foundation.\n\nFor complete details on the topics in this article, see [Getting Started with Windows PowerShell Workflow](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj134242.aspx).\n\n## Types of runbook\n\nThere are two types of runbook in Azure Automation, *textual* and *graphical*.  You define the runbook type when you create the runbook, and you can't convert a runbook to the other type once it's been created.\n\nTextual runbooks are for users who prefer to work directly with the PowerShell workflow code either using the textual editor in Azure Automation or an offline editor such as PowerShell ISE. You should understand the information in this article if you are creating a textual runbook. \n\nGraphical runbooks allow you to create a runbook using the same activities and cmdlets but using a graphical interface that hides the complexities of the underlying PowerShell workflow.  Concepts in this article such as checkpoints and parallel execution still apply to graphical runbooks, but you won't have to worry about the detailed syntax. \n\n## Basic structure of a workflow\n\nThe first step to converting a PowerShell script to a PowerShell workflow is enclosing it with the **Workflow** keyword.  A workflow starts with the **Workflow** keyword followed by the body of the script enclosed in braces. The name of the workflow follows the **Workflow** keyword as shown in the following syntax. \n\n    Workflow Test-Workflow\n    {\n       <Commands>\n    }\n\nThe name of the workflow must match the name of the Automation runbook. If the runbook is being imported, then the filename must match the workflow name and must end in .ps1.\n\nTo add parameters to the workflow, use the **Param** keyword just as you would to a script. \n\n## Code changes\n\nPowerShell workflow code looks almost identical to PowerShell script code except for a few significant changes.  The following sections describe changes that you will need to make to a PowerShell script for it to run in a workflow.\n\n### Activities\n\nAn activity is a specific task in a workflow. Just as a script is composed of one or more commands, a workflow is composed of one or more activities that are carried out in a sequence. Windows PowerShell Workflow automatically converts many of the Windows PowerShell cmdlets to activities when it runs a workflow. When you specify one of these cmdlets in your runbook, the corresponding activity is actually run by Windows Workflow Foundation. For those cmdlets without a corresponding activity, Windows PowerShell Workflow automatically runs the cmdlet within an [InlineScript](#inlinescript) activity. There is a set of cmdlets that are excluded and cannot be used in a workflow unless you explicitly include them in an InlineScript block. For further details on these concepts, see [Using Activities in Script Workflows](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj574194.aspx).\n\nWorkflow activities share a set of common parameters to configure their operation. For details about the workflow common parameters, see [about_WorkflowCommonParameters](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj129719.aspx).\n\n### Positional parameters\n\nYou can't use positional parameters with activities and cmdlets in a workflow.  All this means is that you must use parameter names.\n\nFor example, consider the following code that gets all running services.\n\n     Get-Service | Where-Object {$_.Status -eq \"Running\"}\n\nIf you try to run this same code in a workflow, you'll get a message like \"Parameter set cannot be resolved using the specified named parameters.\"  To correct this, simply provide the parameter name as in the following.\n\n    Workflow Get-RunningServices\n    {\n        Get-Service | Where-Object -FilterScript {$_.Status -eq \"Running\"}\n    }\n\n### Deserialized objects\n\nObjects in workflows are deserialized.  This means that their properties are still available, but not their methods.  For example, consider the following PowerShell code that stops a service using the Stop method of the Service object.\n\n    $Service = Get-Service -Name MyService\n    $Service.Stop()\n\nIf you try to run this in a workflow, you'll get an error saying \"Method invocation is not supported in a Windows PowerShell Workflow\".  \n\nOne option is to wrap these two lines of code in an [InlineScript](#InlineScript) block in which case $Service would be a service object within the block. \n\n    Workflow Stop-Service\n    {\n        InlineScript {\n            $Service = Get-Service -Name MyService\n            $Service.Stop()\n        }\n    } \n\nAnother option is to use another cmdlet that performs the same functionality as the method, if one is available.  In the case of our sample, the Stop-Service cmdlet provides the same functionality as the Stop method, and you could use the following for a workflow.\n\n    Workflow Stop-MyService\n    {\n        $Service = Get-Service -Name MyService\n        Stop-Service -Name $Service.Name\n    }\n\n\n## InlineScript\n\nThe **InlineScript** activity is useful when you need to run one or more commands as traditional PowerShell script instead of PowerShell workflow.  While commands in a workflow are sent to Windows Workflow Foundation for processing, commands in an InlineScript block are processed by Windows PowerShell. \n\nInlineScript uses the syntax shown below.\n\n    InlineScript\n    {\n      <Script Block>\n    } <Common Parameters>\n\nYou can return output from an InlineScript by assigning the output to a variable. The following example stops a service and then outputs the service name.\n\n    Workflow Stop-MyService\n    {\n        $Output = InlineScript {\n            $Service = Get-Service -Name MyService\n            $Service.Stop()\n            $Service\n        }\n\n        $Output.Name\n    }\n\n\nYou can pass values into an InlineScript block, but you must use **$Using** scope modifier.  The following example is identical to the previous example except that the service name is provided by a variable. \n\n    Workflow Stop-MyService\n    {\n        $ServiceName = \"MyService\"\n    \n        $Output = InlineScript {\n            $Service = Get-Service -Name $Using:MyService\n            $Service.Stop()\n            $Service\n        }\n\n        $Output.Name\n    }\n\n\nWhile InlineScript activities may be critical in certain workflows, they do not support workflow constructs and should only be used when necessary for the following reasons:\n\n- You cannot use [checkpoints](#Checkpoints) inside of an InlineScript block. If a failure occurs within the block, it must be resumed from the beginning of the block.\n- You cannot use [parallel execution](#parallel-execution) inside of an InlineScriptBlock.\n- InlineScript affects scalability of the workflow since it holds the Windows PowerShell session for the entire length of the InlineScript block.\n\nFor further details on using InlineScript, see [Running Windows PowerShell Commands in a Workflow](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj574197.aspx) and [about_InlineScript](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj649082.aspx).\n\n\n## Parallel processing\n\nOne advantage of Windows PowerShell Workflows is the ability to perform a set of commands in parallel instead of sequentially as with a typical script. \n\nYou can use the **Parallel** keyword to create a script block with multiple commands that will run concurrently. This uses the syntax shown below. In this case, Activity1 and Activity2 will start at the same time. Activity3 will start only after both Activity1 and Activity2 have completed.\n\n    Parallel\n    {\n      <Activity1>\n      <Activity2>\n    }\n    <Activity3>\n\n\nFor example, consider the following PowerShell commands that copy multiple files to a network destination.  These commands are run sequentially so that one file must finish copying before the next is started.     \n\n    $Copy-Item -Path C:\\LocalPath\\File1.txt -Destination \\\\NetworkPath\\File1.txt\n    $Copy-Item -Path C:\\LocalPath\\File2.txt -Destination \\\\NetworkPath\\File2.txt\n    $Copy-Item -Path C:\\LocalPath\\File3.txt -Destination \\\\NetworkPath\\File3.txt\n\nThe following workflow runs these same commands in parallel so that they all start copying at the same time.  Only after they are all completely copied is the completion message displayed.\n\n    Workflow Copy-Files\n    {\n        Parallel \n        {\n            $Copy-Item -Path \"C:\\LocalPath\\File1.txt\" -Destination \"\\\\NetworkPath\"\n            $Copy-Item -Path \"C:\\LocalPath\\File2.txt\" -Destination \"\\\\NetworkPath\"\n            $Copy-Item -Path \"C:\\LocalPath\\File3.txt\" -Destination \"\\\\NetworkPath\"\n        }\n\n        Write-Output \"Files copied.\"\n    }\n\n\nYou can use the **ForEach -Parallel** construct to process commands for each item in a collection concurrently. The items in the collection are processed in parallel while the commands in the script block run sequentially. This uses the syntax shown below. In this case, Activity1 will start at the same time for all items in the collection. For each item, Activity2 will start after Activity1 is complete. Activity3 will start only after both Activity1 and Activity2 have completed for all items.\n\n    ForEach -Parallel ($<item> in $<collection>)\n    {\n      <Activity1>\n      <Activity2>\n    }\n    <Activity3>\n\nThe following example is similar to the previous example copying files in parallel.  In this case, a message is displayed for each file after it copies.  Only after they are all completely copied is the final completion message displayed.\n\n    Workflow Copy-Files\n    {\n        $files = @(\"C:\\LocalPath\\File1.txt\",\"C:\\LocalPath\\File2.txt\",\"C:\\LocalPath\\File3.txt\")\n\n        ForEach -Parallel ($File in $Files) \n        {\n            $Copy-Item -Path $File -Destination \\\\NetworkPath\n            Write-Output \"$File copied.\"\n        }\n        \n        Write-Output \"All files copied.\"\n    }\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE]  We do not recommend running child runbooks in parallel since this has been shown to give unreliable results.  The output from the child runbook sometimes will not show up, and settings in one child runbook can affect the other parallel child runbooks \n\n\n## Checkpoints\n\nA *checkpoint* is a snapshot of the current state of the workflow that includes the current value for variables and any output generated to that point. If a workflow ends in error or is [suspended](suspending-a-workflow), then the next time it is run it will start from its last checkpoint instead of the start of the worfklow.  You can set a checkpoint in a workflow with the **Checkpoint-Workflow** activity.\n\nIn the following sample code, an exception occurs after Activity2 causing the workflow to end. When the workflow is run again, it starts by running Activity2 since this was just after the last checkpoint set.\n\n    <Activity1>\n    Checkpoint-Workflow\n    <Activity2>\n    <Exception>\n    <Activity3>\n\nYou should set checkpoints in a workflow after activities that may be prone to exception and should not be repeated if the workflow is resumed. For example, your workflow may create a virtual machine. You could set a checkpoint both before and after the commands to create the virtual machine. If the creation fails, then the commands would be repeated if the workflow is started again. If the the worfklow fails after the creation succeeds, then the virtual machine will not be created again when the workflow is resumed.\n\nThe following example copies multiple files to a network location and sets a checkpoint after each file.  If the network location is lost, then the workflow will end in error.  When it is started again, it will resume at the last checkpoint meaning that only the files that have already been copied will be skipped.\n\n    Workflow Copy-Files\n    {\n        $files = @(\"C:\\LocalPath\\File1.txt\",\"C:\\LocalPath\\File2.txt\",\"C:\\LocalPath\\File3.txt\")\n\n        ForEach ($File in $Files) \n        {\n            $Copy-Item -Path $File -Destination \\\\NetworkPath\n            Write-Output \"$File copied.\"\n            Checkpoint-Workflow\n        }\n        \n        Write-Output \"All files copied.\"\n    }\n\n\n\nFor more information about checkpoints, see [Adding Checkpoints to a Script Workflow](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj574114.aspx).\n\n\n\n## Related articles\n\n- [Getting Started with Windows PowerShell Workflow](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj134242.aspx) \ntest\n"
}