{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Migrate your solution to SQL Data Warehouse | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        87
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Migration guidance for bringing your solution to Azure SQL Data Warehouse platform.",
      "pos": [
        105,
        188
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Migrate your solution to SQL Data Warehouse",
      "pos": [
        526,
        569
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Data Warehouse is a distributed database system that elastically scales to meet your needs.",
      "pos": [
        571,
        666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To maintain both performance and scale not all features within SQL Server are implemented inside SQL Data Warehouse.",
      "pos": [
        667,
        783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following migration topics touch on some of the key factors for migrating your solution to SQL Data Warehouse.",
      "pos": [
        784,
        898
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Designing data warehouses for scale introduces different design patterns and so traditional approaches aren't always the best.",
      "pos": [
        899,
        1025
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will probably find that you will want to adapt your solution to ensure you take full advantage of the distributed platform provided by SQL Data Warehouse.",
      "pos": [
        1026,
        1184
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is also important to remember that SQL Data Warehouse is a platform based in Microsoft Azure.",
      "pos": [
        1186,
        1282
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Therefore part of your migration may well include transferring your data to the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        1283,
        1369
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data transfer is a subject in its own right and should be carefully considered; especially as volumes increase.",
      "pos": [
        1370,
        1481
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data transfer should also not be confused with data loading which is again a discrete topic.",
      "pos": [
        1482,
        1574
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Migration guidance",
      "pos": [
        1579,
        1597
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before embarking on your migration make sure you have read through these articles to ensure you understand some of the product differences and fundamental concepts.",
      "pos": [
        1598,
        1762
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Migrate your schema",
      "pos": [
        1767,
        1786
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Migrate your data",
      "pos": [
        1793,
        1810
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Migrate your code",
      "pos": [
        1817,
        1834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        1843,
        1853
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1854,
        1920
      ],
      "content": "For additional development tips, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>development overview<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1922,
        1997
      ],
      "content": "You can also view the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Transact-SQL reference<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept> for even more information."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1999,
        2130
      ],
      "content": "Finally, check out the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>loading overview<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept> that discusses various data loading options as well as providing step by step guidance."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Migrate your solution to SQL Data Warehouse | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Migration guidance for bringing your solution to Azure SQL Data Warehouse platform.\"\n   services=\"sql-data-warehouse\"\n   documentationCenter=\"NA\"\n   authors=\"jrowlandjones\"\n   manager=\"barbkess\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"sql-data-warehouse\"\n   ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"data-services\"\n   ms.date=\"06/22/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"JRJ@BigBangData.co.uk;barbkess\"/>\n\n# Migrate your solution to SQL Data Warehouse\n\nSQL Data Warehouse is a distributed database system that elastically scales to meet your needs. To maintain both performance and scale not all features within SQL Server are implemented inside SQL Data Warehouse. The following migration topics touch on some of the key factors for migrating your solution to SQL Data Warehouse. Designing data warehouses for scale introduces different design patterns and so traditional approaches aren't always the best. You will probably find that you will want to adapt your solution to ensure you take full advantage of the distributed platform provided by SQL Data Warehouse.\n\nIt is also important to remember that SQL Data Warehouse is a platform based in Microsoft Azure. Therefore part of your migration may well include transferring your data to the cloud. Data transfer is a subject in its own right and should be carefully considered; especially as volumes increase. Data transfer should also not be confused with data loading which is again a discrete topic.\n\n## Migration guidance\nBefore embarking on your migration make sure you have read through these articles to ensure you understand some of the product differences and fundamental concepts.\n\n- [Migrate your schema][]\n- [Migrate your data][]\n- [Migrate your code][]\n \n## Next steps\nFor additional development tips, see the [development overview][].\n\nYou can also view the [Transact-SQL reference][] for even more information.\n\nFinally, check out the [loading overview][] that discusses various data loading options as well as providing step by step guidance.\n\n<!--Image references-->\n\n<!--Article references-->\n[Migrate your schema]: sql-data-warehouse-migrate-schema.md\n[Migrate your data]: sql-data-warehouse-migrate-data.md\n[Migrate your code]: sql-data-warehouse-migrate-code.md\n\n[development overview]: sql-data-warehouse-overview-develop.md\n[loading overview]: sql-data-warehouse-overview-load.md\n[Transact-SQL reference]: sql-data-warehouse-overview-migrate.md\n\n<!--MSDN references-->\n\n\n<!--Other Web references-->\n\n"
}