{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "How to create a VNet in the Azure portal",
      "pos": [
        3,
        43
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a VNet based on the scenario above, follow the steps below.",
      "pos": [
        45,
        114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From a browser, navigate to http://manage.windowsazure.com and, if necessary, sign in with your Azure account.",
      "pos": [
        119,
        229
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        233,
        341
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>NEW<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>NETWORK SERVICES<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>VIRTUAL NETWORK<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>CUSTOM CREATE<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> as shown in the figure below."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create VNet in portal",
      "pos": [
        349,
        370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Network Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, type the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>NAME<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> of the VNet, select its <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>LOCATION<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and then click on the arrow on the bottom right hand corner of the page to advance to step 2.",
      "pos": [
        468,
        658
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The figure below shows the settings for our scenario.",
      "pos": [
        659,
        712
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual network details page",
      "pos": [
        720,
        748
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DNS Servers and VPN Connectivity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, specify the name and IP address for up to 9 DNS servers to use.",
      "pos": [
        846,
        959
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not specify a DNS server, your VNet will use the internal naming resolution resolution provided by Azure.",
      "pos": [
        960,
        1075
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For our scenario, we will not configure DNS servers.",
      "pos": [
        1076,
        1128
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to provide point-to-site VPN access to your VNet, enable the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure a point-to-site VPN<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> checkbox.",
      "pos": [
        1132,
        1248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not configure a point-to-site VPN, you can add it to your VNet at any time after creation.",
      "pos": [
        1249,
        1349
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For our scenario, we will not configure a point-to-site VPN.",
      "pos": [
        1350,
        1410
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to provide site-to-site VPN connectivity between your VNet and another VNet or your on-premises network, enable the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure a site-to-site VPN<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> checkbox and specify if you want to use <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ExpressRoute<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> or note, and the name of the network to connect to.",
      "pos": [
        1414,
        1683
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not configure a site-to-site VPN, you can add it to your VNet at any time after creation.",
      "pos": [
        1684,
        1783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For our scenario, we will not configure a site-to-site VPN.",
      "pos": [
        1784,
        1843
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click on the arrow on the bottom right hand corner of the page to advance to step 3.The figure below shows the settings for our scenario.",
      "pos": [
        1847,
        1984
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DNS Servers and VPN connectivity page",
      "pos": [
        1992,
        2029
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Network Address Spaces<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, under <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>STARTING IP<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, click on <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>10.0.0.0<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept> to change the VNet address space, and then type the starting address space you want to use.",
      "pos": [
        2127,
        2309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For our scenario, type <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>192.168.0.0<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2310,
        2347
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CIDR (ADDRESS COUNT)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select the number of bits for the subnet mask.",
      "pos": [
        2352,
        2429
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For our scenario, select <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>16 (65536)<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2430,
        2468
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SUBNETS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Subnet-1<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> and rename the subnet if necessary.",
      "pos": [
        2473,
        2544
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For our scenario, rename it to <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>FrontEnd<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2545,
        2587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> If you click outside the name textbox for a subnet you will not be able to edit the name if the subnet again.",
      "pos": [
        2594,
        2716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To fix that, you need to remove the subnet by clicking on the X button to its right, then add a new subnet as described in step 13 below.",
      "pos": [
        2717,
        2854
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>STARTING IP<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for the first subnet, specify the starting IP address for the subnet.",
      "pos": [
        2860,
        2951
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For our scenario, type <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>192.168.1.0<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2952,
        2989
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CIDR (ADDRESS COUNT)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select the number of bits for the subnet mask for the first subnet.",
      "pos": [
        2994,
        3092
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For our scenario, select <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>24 (256)<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3093,
        3129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>add subnet<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to add a new subnet, if necessary.",
      "pos": [
        3134,
        3189
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For our scenario, add a subnet and repeat steps 10 to 12 to configure the VNet as shown in the figure below.",
      "pos": [
        3190,
        3298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual network address spaces page",
      "pos": [
        3306,
        3341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click on the check mark button on the bottom right hand corner of the page to create the VNet.",
      "pos": [
        3440,
        3534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After a few seconds your VNet will be shown in the list of available VNets, as shown in the figure below.",
      "pos": [
        3535,
        3640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "New virtual network",
      "pos": [
        3648,
        3667
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "## How to create a VNet in the Azure portal\n\nTo create a VNet based on the scenario above, follow the steps below.\n\n1. From a browser, navigate to http://manage.windowsazure.com and, if necessary, sign in with your Azure account.\n2. Click **NEW** > **NETWORK SERVICES** > **VIRTUAL NETWORK** > **CUSTOM CREATE** as shown in the figure below.\n\n    ![Create VNet in portal](./media/virtual-networks-create-vnet-classic-portal-include/vnet-create-portal-figure1.gif)\n\n3. On the **Virtual Network Details** page, type the **NAME** of the VNet, select its **LOCATION**, and then click on the arrow on the bottom right hand corner of the page to advance to step 2. The figure below shows the settings for our scenario.\n\n    ![Virtual network details page](./media/virtual-networks-create-vnet-classic-portal-include/vnet-create-portal-figure2.png)\n\n4. On the **DNS Servers and VPN Connectivity** page, specify the name and IP address for up to 9 DNS servers to use. If you do not specify a DNS server, your VNet will use the internal naming resolution resolution provided by Azure. For our scenario, we will not configure DNS servers.\n5. If you want to provide point-to-site VPN access to your VNet, enable the **Configure a point-to-site VPN** checkbox. If you do not configure a point-to-site VPN, you can add it to your VNet at any time after creation. For our scenario, we will not configure a point-to-site VPN.\n6. If you want to provide site-to-site VPN connectivity between your VNet and another VNet or your on-premises network, enable the **Configure a site-to-site VPN** checkbox and specify if you want to use **ExpressRoute** or note, and the name of the network to connect to. If you do not configure a site-to-site VPN, you can add it to your VNet at any time after creation. For our scenario, we will not configure a site-to-site VPN.\n7. Click on the arrow on the bottom right hand corner of the page to advance to step 3.The figure below shows the settings for our scenario.\n\n    ![DNS Servers and VPN connectivity page](./media/virtual-networks-create-vnet-classic-portal-include/vnet-create-portal-figure3.png)\n\n8. On the **Virtual Network Address Spaces** page, under **STARTING IP**, click on *10.0.0.0* to change the VNet address space, and then type the starting address space you want to use. For our scenario, type *192.168.0.0*. \n9. Under **CIDR (ADDRESS COUNT)** select the number of bits for the subnet mask. For our scenario, select *16 (65536)*.\n10. Under **SUBNETS**, click *Subnet-1* and rename the subnet if necessary. For our scenario, rename it to *FrontEnd*.\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] If you click outside the name textbox for a subnet you will not be able to edit the name if the subnet again. To fix that, you need to remove the subnet by clicking on the X button to its right, then add a new subnet as described in step 13 below.\n\n11. Under **STARTING IP** for the first subnet, specify the starting IP address for the subnet. For our scenario, type *192.168.1.0*.\n12. Under **CIDR (ADDRESS COUNT)** select the number of bits for the subnet mask for the first subnet. For our scenario, select *24 (256)*.\n13. Click **add subnet** to add a new subnet, if necessary. For our scenario, add a subnet and repeat steps 10 to 12 to configure the VNet as shown in the figure below.\n\n    ![Virtual network address spaces page](./media/virtual-networks-create-vnet-classic-portal-include/vnet-create-portal-figure4.png)\n\n14. Click on the check mark button on the bottom right hand corner of the page to create the VNet. After a few seconds your VNet will be shown in the list of available VNets, as shown in the figure below.\n\n    ![New virtual network](./media/virtual-networks-create-vnet-classic-portal-include/vnet-create-portal-figure5.png)"
}