{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Enable Remote Desktop Connection for a Role in Azure Cloud Services",
      "pos": [
        24,
        91
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to configure your azure cloud service application to allow remote desktop connections",
      "pos": [
        107,
        196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enable Remote Desktop Connection for a Role in Azure Cloud Services using PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        456,
        540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[AZURE.SELECTOR]",
      "pos": [
        543,
        559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Portal",
      "pos": [
        563,
        575
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        626,
        636
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Visual Studio",
      "pos": [
        698,
        711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remote Desktop enables you to access the desktop of a role running in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        765,
        841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use a Remote Desktop connection to troubleshoot and diagnose problems with your application while it is running.",
      "pos": [
        842,
        962
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article describes how to enable remote desktop on your Cloud Service Roles using PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        965,
        1062
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to install and configure Azure PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](powershell-install-configure.md)</ept> for the prerequisites needed for this article.",
      "pos": [
        1063,
        1194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell uses the Remote Desktop Extension approach so you can enable Remote Desktop even after the application is deployed.",
      "pos": [
        1195,
        1321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure Remote Desktop from PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        1328,
        1368
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495117.aspx)</ept> cmdlet allows you to enable Remote Desktop on specified roles or all roles of your cloud service deployment.",
      "pos": [
        1370,
        1579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cmdlet lets you specify the Username and Password for the remote desktop user through the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Credential<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> parameter which accepts a PSCredential object.",
      "pos": [
        1580,
        1733
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1735,
        1913
      ],
      "content": "If you are using PowerShell interactively you can easily set the PSCredential object by calling the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get-Credentials<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh849815.aspx)</ept> cmdlet."
    },
    {
      "content": "This will display a dialog box allowing you to enter the username and password for the remote user in a secure manner.",
      "pos": [
        1969,
        2087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since PowerShell will mostly be used for automation scenarios you can also setup the PSCredential object in a way that doesn't require user interaction.",
      "pos": [
        2090,
        2242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this first you need to setup a secure password.",
      "pos": [
        2243,
        2296
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You begin with specifying a plain text password convert it to a secure string using <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ConvertTo-SecureString<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh849818.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2297,
        2459
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next you need to convert this secure string into an encrypted standard string using <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ConvertFrom-SecureString<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh849814.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2460,
        2624
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Now you can save this encrypted standard string to a file using <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set-Content<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/ee176959.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2625,
        2756
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When creating the PSCredential object you can read from this file to set the password in a secure way without having to specify the password on a prompt or storing the password as plain text.",
      "pos": [
        2757,
        2948
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following PowerShell to create a secure password file:",
      "pos": [
        2951,
        3013
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the password file (password.txt) is created you will only be using this file and will not have to specify the password in plain text.",
      "pos": [
        3152,
        3290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need to update the password then you can run the above powershell again with the new password to generate a new password.txt file.",
      "pos": [
        3291,
        3428
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3432,
        3578
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> When setting the password make sure you meet the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>complexity requirements<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/cc786468.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "To create the credential object from the secure password file you must read the file contents and convert them back to a secure string using <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ConvertTo-SecureString<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh849818.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3581,
        3800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition to credentials the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495117.aspx)</ept> cmdlet also accepts an <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Expiration<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> parameter which specifies a DateTime at which the user account will expire.",
      "pos": [
        3801,
        4040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You get set it by specifying a static date and time or you could simply choose to expire the account a few days from the current date.",
      "pos": [
        4041,
        4175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This PowerShell example shows you how to set the Remote Desktop Extension on a cloud service:",
      "pos": [
        4177,
        4270
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also optionally specify the deployment slot and roles that you want to enable remote desktop on.",
      "pos": [
        4681,
        4785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If these parameters are not specified the cmdlet will default to using the Production deployment slot and enable remote desktop on all roles in the production deployment.",
      "pos": [
        4786,
        4956
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Remote Desktop extension is associated with a deployment.",
      "pos": [
        4959,
        5020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you were to create a new deployment for the service then you will have to enable remote desktop on the new deployment again.",
      "pos": [
        5021,
        5148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to always have remote desktop enabled on your deployments then you should consider integrating the PowerShell scripts to enable remote desktop into your deployment workflow.",
      "pos": [
        5149,
        5334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remote Desktop into an role instance",
      "pos": [
        5340,
        5376
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get-AzureRemoteDesktopFile<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495261.aspx)</ept> cmdlet can be used to remote desktop into a specific role instance of your cloud service.",
      "pos": [
        5377,
        5555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>LocalPath<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> parameter on the cmdlet to download the RDP file locally or you can use the <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Launch<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> parameter to directly launch the Remote Desktop Connection dialog to access the cloud service role instance.",
      "pos": [
        5556,
        5777
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check if Remote Desktop extension is enabled on a service",
      "pos": [
        5882,
        5939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495261.aspx)</ept> cmdlet displays whether remote desktop is enabled on a service deployment.",
      "pos": [
        5941,
        6116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cmdlet will return the username for the remote desktop user and the roles that the remote desktop extension is enabled on.",
      "pos": [
        6117,
        6243
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can optionally specify a deployment slot with the default being production.",
      "pos": [
        6244,
        6323
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remove Remote Desktop extension from a service",
      "pos": [
        6406,
        6452
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have already enabled the remote desktop extension on a deployment and need to update the remote desktop settings then you must first remove the remote desktop extension and then enable it again with the new settings.",
      "pos": [
        6454,
        6677
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example if you want to set a new password for the remote user account or if the user account has expired then you need to remove the extension and then add it again with the new password or expiration.",
      "pos": [
        6678,
        6883
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is only required on existing deployments which have the remote desktop extension enabled.",
      "pos": [
        6884,
        6978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For new deployments you can call simply apply the extension directly.",
      "pos": [
        6979,
        7048
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To remove the remote desktop extension from s service deployment you can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Remove-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495280.aspx)</ept> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        7050,
        7238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also optionally specify the deployment slot and role from which you want to remove the remote desktop extension.",
      "pos": [
        7239,
        7359
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> The <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>UninstallConfiguration<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> parameter will uninstall any extension configuration that was applied to the service.",
      "pos": [
        7467,
        7594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All extension configuration is associated with the service configuration to activate the extension with a deployment the deployment must be associated with that extension configuration.",
      "pos": [
        7595,
        7780
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Calling the Remove cmdlet without <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>UninstallConfiguration<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> will disassociate the deployment from the extension configuration thus effectively removing the extension from the deployment.",
      "pos": [
        7781,
        7966
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However the extension configuration will still remain associated with the service.",
      "pos": [
        7967,
        8049
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To completely remove the extension configuration you should call the Remove cmdlet with the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>UninstallConfiguration<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> parameter.",
      "pos": [
        8050,
        8177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additional Resources",
      "pos": [
        8185,
        8205
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Configure Cloud Services<ept id=\"p1\">](cloud-services-how-to-configure.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        8207,
        8276
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        8277,
        8281
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \npageTitle=\"Enable Remote Desktop Connection for a Role in Azure Cloud Services\" \ndescription=\"How to configure your azure cloud service application to allow remote desktop connections\" \nservices=\"cloud-services\" \ndocumentationCenter=\"\" \nauthors=\"sbtron\" \nmanager=\"timlt\" \neditor=\"\"/>\n<tags \nms.service=\"cloud-services\" \nms.workload=\"tbd\" \nms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \nms.devlang=\"na\" \nms.topic=\"article\" \nms.date=\"08/31/2015\" \nms.author=\"saurabh\"/>\n\n# Enable Remote Desktop Connection for a Role in Azure Cloud Services using PowerShell\n\n>[AZURE.SELECTOR]\n- [Azure Portal](cloud-services-role-enable-remote-desktop.md)\n- [PowerShell](cloud-services-role-enable-remote-desktop-powershell.md)\n- [Visual Studio](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/gg443832.aspx)\n\n\nRemote Desktop enables you to access the desktop of a role running in Azure. You can use a Remote Desktop connection to troubleshoot and diagnose problems with your application while it is running. \n\nThis article describes how to enable remote desktop on your Cloud Service Roles using PowerShell. See [How to install and configure Azure PowerShell](powershell-install-configure.md) for the prerequisites needed for this article. PowerShell uses the Remote Desktop Extension approach so you can enable Remote Desktop even after the application is deployed. \n\n\n## Configure Remote Desktop from PowerShell\n\nThe [Set-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495117.aspx) cmdlet allows you to enable Remote Desktop on specified roles or all roles of your cloud service deployment. The cmdlet lets you specify the Username and Password for the remote desktop user through the *Credential* parameter which accepts a PSCredential object.\n\nIf you are using PowerShell interactively you can easily set the PSCredential object by calling the [Get-Credentials](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh849815.aspx) cmdlet. \n\n```\n    $remoteusercredentials = Get-Credential\n```\n\nThis will display a dialog box allowing you to enter the username and password for the remote user in a secure manner. \n\nSince PowerShell will mostly be used for automation scenarios you can also setup the PSCredential object in a way that doesn't require user interaction. To do this first you need to setup a secure password. You begin with specifying a plain text password convert it to a secure string using [ConvertTo-SecureString](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh849818.aspx). Next you need to convert this secure string into an encrypted standard string using [ConvertFrom-SecureString](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh849814.aspx). Now you can save this encrypted standard string to a file using [Set-Content](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/ee176959.aspx). When creating the PSCredential object you can read from this file to set the password in a secure way without having to specify the password on a prompt or storing the password as plain text. \n\nUse the following PowerShell to create a secure password file:  \n\n```\n    ConvertTo-SecureString -String \"Password123\" -AsPlainText -Force | ConvertFrom-SecureString | Set-Content \"password.txt\"\n``` \n\nOnce the password file (password.txt) is created you will only be using this file and will not have to specify the password in plain text. If you need to update the password then you can run the above powershell again with the new password to generate a new password.txt file. \n\n>[AZURE.IMPORTANT] When setting the password make sure you meet the [complexity requirements](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/cc786468.aspx). \n\nTo create the credential object from the secure password file you must read the file contents and convert them back to a secure string using [ConvertTo-SecureString](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh849818.aspx). In addition to credentials the [Set-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495117.aspx) cmdlet also accepts an *Expiration* parameter which specifies a DateTime at which the user account will expire. You get set it by specifying a static date and time or you could simply choose to expire the account a few days from the current date.\n\nThis PowerShell example shows you how to set the Remote Desktop Extension on a cloud service:   \n\n```\n    $servicename = \"cloudservice\"\n    $username = \"RemoteDesktopUser\"\n    $securepassword = Get-Content -Path \"password.txt\" | ConvertTo-SecureString\n    $expiry = $(Get-Date).AddDays(1)\n    $credential = New-Object System.Management.Automation.PSCredential $username,$securepassword\n    Set-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension -ServiceName $servicename -Credential $credential -Expiration $expiry \n```\nYou can also optionally specify the deployment slot and roles that you want to enable remote desktop on. If these parameters are not specified the cmdlet will default to using the Production deployment slot and enable remote desktop on all roles in the production deployment. \n\nThe Remote Desktop extension is associated with a deployment. If you were to create a new deployment for the service then you will have to enable remote desktop on the new deployment again. If you want to always have remote desktop enabled on your deployments then you should consider integrating the PowerShell scripts to enable remote desktop into your deployment workflow.\n\n\n## Remote Desktop into an role instance\nThe [Get-AzureRemoteDesktopFile](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495261.aspx) cmdlet can be used to remote desktop into a specific role instance of your cloud service. You can use the *LocalPath* parameter on the cmdlet to download the RDP file locally or you can use the *Launch* parameter to directly launch the Remote Desktop Connection dialog to access the cloud service role instance.\n\n```\n    Get-AzureRemoteDesktopFile -ServiceName $servicename -Name \"WorkerRole1_IN_0\" -Launch\n```\n\n\n## Check if Remote Desktop extension is enabled on a service \nThe [Get-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495261.aspx) cmdlet displays whether remote desktop is enabled on a service deployment. The cmdlet will return the username for the remote desktop user and the roles that the remote desktop extension is enabled on. You can optionally specify a deployment slot with the default being production.\n\n```\n    Get-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension -ServiceName $servicename\n```\n\n## Remove Remote Desktop extension from a service \nIf you have already enabled the remote desktop extension on a deployment and need to update the remote desktop settings then you must first remove the remote desktop extension and then enable it again with the new settings. For example if you want to set a new password for the remote user account or if the user account has expired then you need to remove the extension and then add it again with the new password or expiration. This is only required on existing deployments which have the remote desktop extension enabled. For new deployments you can call simply apply the extension directly.\n\nTo remove the remote desktop extension from s service deployment you can use the [Remove-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn495280.aspx) cmdlet. You can also optionally specify the deployment slot and role from which you want to remove the remote desktop extension. \n\n```\nRemove-AzureServiceRemoteDesktopExtension -ServiceName $servicename -UninstallConfiguration\n\n```  \n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] The *UninstallConfiguration* parameter will uninstall any extension configuration that was applied to the service. All extension configuration is associated with the service configuration to activate the extension with a deployment the deployment must be associated with that extension configuration. Calling the Remove cmdlet without *UninstallConfiguration* will disassociate the deployment from the extension configuration thus effectively removing the extension from the deployment. However the extension configuration will still remain associated with the service. To completely remove the extension configuration you should call the Remove cmdlet with the *UninstallConfiguration* parameter. \n\n\n\n## Additional Resources\n\n[How to Configure Cloud Services](cloud-services-how-to-configure.md)\ntest\n"
}