{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Introduction to Azure Data Factory",
      "pos": [
        28,
        62
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how you can use the Azure Data Factory service to compose data processing, data storage and data movement services to create pipelines that produce trusted information.",
      "pos": [
        82,
        256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Introduction to Azure Data Factory Service",
      "pos": [
        596,
        638
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        643,
        651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Factory is a cloud-based data integration service that orchestrates and automates the movement and transformation of data.",
      "pos": [
        652,
        779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Just like a manufacturing factory that runs equipment to take raw materials and transform them into finished goods, Data Factory orchestrates existing services that collect raw data and transform it into ready-to-use information.",
      "pos": [
        780,
        1009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Factory works across on-premises and cloud data sources and SaaS to ingest, prepare, transform, analyze, and publish your data.",
      "pos": [
        1012,
        1144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use Data Factory to compose services into managed data flow pipelines to transform your data using services like <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure HDInsight (Hadoop)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/services/hdinsight/)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure Batch<ept id=\"p2\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/services/batch/)</ept> for your big data computing needs, and with <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Azure Machine Learning<ept id=\"p3\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/services/machine-learning/)</ept> to operationalize your analytics solutions.",
      "pos": [
        1146,
        1605
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Go beyond just a tabular monitoring view, and use the rich visualizations of Data Factory to quickly display the lineage and dependencies between your data pipelines.",
      "pos": [
        1607,
        1773
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitor all of your data flow pipelines from a single unified view to easily pinpoint issues and setup monitoring alerts.",
      "pos": [
        1774,
        1895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        1899,
        1907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure1.",
      "pos": [
        1973,
        1981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Collect data from many different on-premises data sources, ingest and prepare it, organize and analyze it with a range of transformations, then publish ready-to-use data for consumption.",
      "pos": [
        1984,
        2170
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use Data Factory anytime you need to collect data of different shapes and sizes, transform it, and publish it to extract deep insights – all on a reliable schedule.",
      "pos": [
        2172,
        2344
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Factory is used to create highly available data flow pipelines for many scenarios across different industries for their analytics pipeline needs.",
      "pos": [
        2345,
        2495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Online retailers use it to generate personalized <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>product recommendations<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-product-reco-usecase.md)</ept> based on customer browsing behavior.",
      "pos": [
        2497,
        2646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Game studios use it to understand the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>effectiveness of their marketing<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-customer-profiling-usecase.md)</ept> campaigns.",
      "pos": [
        2647,
        2774
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn directly from our customers how and why they use Data Factory by reviewing <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Customer Case Studies<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-customer-case-studies.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2775,
        2919
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Key Concepts",
      "pos": [
        2925,
        2937
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Data Factory has a few key entities that work together to define the input and output data, processing events, and the schedule and resources required to execute the desired data flow.",
      "pos": [
        2939,
        3129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Key Concepts",
      "pos": [
        3133,
        3145
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure 2.",
      "pos": [
        3202,
        3211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Relationships between Dataset, Activity, Pipeline, and Linked service",
      "pos": [
        3214,
        3283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Activities",
      "pos": [
        3290,
        3300
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Activities define the actions to perform on your data.",
      "pos": [
        3301,
        3355
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each activity takes zero or more <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>datasets<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-datasets.md)</ept> as inputs and produces one or more datasets as outputs.",
      "pos": [
        3356,
        3488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An activity is a unit of orchestration in Azure Data Factory.",
      "pos": [
        3489,
        3550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, you may use a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Copy activity<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-data-movement-activities.md)</ept> to orchestrate copying data from one dataset to another.",
      "pos": [
        3551,
        3692
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Similarly you may use a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Hive activity<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-data-transformation-activities.md)</ept> which will run a Hive query on an Azure HDInsight cluster to transform or analyze your data.",
      "pos": [
        3693,
        3873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Data Factory provides a wide range of data transformation, analysis, and data movement activities.",
      "pos": [
        3874,
        3978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pipelines",
      "pos": [
        3985,
        3994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Pipelines<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-pipelines.md)</ept> are a logical grouping of Activities.",
      "pos": [
        3995,
        4078
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They are used to group activities into a unit that together perform a task.",
      "pos": [
        4079,
        4154
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, a sequence of several transformation Activities might be needed to cleanse log file data.",
      "pos": [
        4155,
        4257
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This sequence could have a complex schedule and dependencies that need to be orchestrated and automated.",
      "pos": [
        4259,
        4363
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All of these activities could be grouped into a single Pipeline named “CleanLogFiles”.",
      "pos": [
        4364,
        4450
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "“CleanLogFiles” could then be deployed, scheduled, or deleted as one single unit  instead of managing each individual activity independently.",
      "pos": [
        4452,
        4593
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Datasets",
      "pos": [
        4599,
        4607
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Datasets<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-datasets.md)</ept> are named references/pointers to the data you want to use as an input or an output of an Activity.",
      "pos": [
        4608,
        4750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Datasets identify data structures within different data stores including tables, files, folders, and documents.",
      "pos": [
        4751,
        4862
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linked service",
      "pos": [
        4868,
        4882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linked services define the information needed for Data Factory to connect to external resources.",
      "pos": [
        4883,
        4979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linked services are used for two purposes in Data Factory:",
      "pos": [
        4981,
        5039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To represent a data store  including, but not limited to, an on-premises SQL Server, Oracle DB, File share or an Azure Blob Storage account.",
      "pos": [
        5043,
        5183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As discussed above, Datasets represent the structures within the data stores connected to Data Factory through a Linked service.",
      "pos": [
        5186,
        5314
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To represent a compute resource that can host the execution of an Activity.",
      "pos": [
        5317,
        5392
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, the “HDInsightHive Activity”executes on an HDInsight Hadoop cluster.",
      "pos": [
        5394,
        5475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With the four simple concepts of datasets, activities, pipelines and linked services, you are ready to get started!",
      "pos": [
        5477,
        5592
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>build your first pipeline<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-build-your-first-pipeline.md)</ept>  from the ground up, or deploy a ready-made sample by following the instructions in our <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Data Factory Samples<ept id=\"p2\">](data-factory-samples.md)</ept> article.",
      "pos": [
        5594,
        5817
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Send Feedback",
      "pos": [
        5823,
        5836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We would really appreciate your feedback on this article.",
      "pos": [
        5837,
        5894
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please take a few minutes to submit your feedback via <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>email<ept id=\"p1\">](mailto:adfdocfeedback@microsoft.com?subject=data-factory-introduction.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5895,
        6031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        6039,
        6043
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Introduction to Azure Data Factory\" \n    description=\"Learn how you can use the Azure Data Factory service to compose data processing, data storage and data movement services to create pipelines that produce trusted information.\" \n    services=\"data-factory\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"spelluru\" \n    manager=\"jhubbard\" \n    editor=\"monicar\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"data-factory\" \n    ms.workload=\"data-services\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"get-started-article\" \n    ms.date=\"08/05/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"spelluru\"/>\n\n# Introduction to Azure Data Factory Service\n\n## Overview\nData Factory is a cloud-based data integration service that orchestrates and automates the movement and transformation of data. Just like a manufacturing factory that runs equipment to take raw materials and transform them into finished goods, Data Factory orchestrates existing services that collect raw data and transform it into ready-to-use information. \n\nData Factory works across on-premises and cloud data sources and SaaS to ingest, prepare, transform, analyze, and publish your data.  Use Data Factory to compose services into managed data flow pipelines to transform your data using services like [Azure HDInsight (Hadoop)](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/services/hdinsight/) and [Azure Batch](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/services/batch/) for your big data computing needs, and with [Azure Machine Learning](http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/services/machine-learning/) to operationalize your analytics solutions.  Go beyond just a tabular monitoring view, and use the rich visualizations of Data Factory to quickly display the lineage and dependencies between your data pipelines. Monitor all of your data flow pipelines from a single unified view to easily pinpoint issues and setup monitoring alerts.\n\n![Overview](./media/data-factory-introduction/data-factory-overview.png)\n\n**Figure1.** Collect data from many different on-premises data sources, ingest and prepare it, organize and analyze it with a range of transformations, then publish ready-to-use data for consumption.\n\nYou can use Data Factory anytime you need to collect data of different shapes and sizes, transform it, and publish it to extract deep insights – all on a reliable schedule. Data Factory is used to create highly available data flow pipelines for many scenarios across different industries for their analytics pipeline needs.  Online retailers use it to generate personalized [product recommendations](data-factory-product-reco-usecase.md) based on customer browsing behavior. Game studios use it to understand the [effectiveness of their marketing](data-factory-customer-profiling-usecase.md) campaigns. Learn directly from our customers how and why they use Data Factory by reviewing [Customer Case Studies](data-factory-customer-case-studies.md). \n\n## Key Concepts\n\nAzure Data Factory has a few key entities that work together to define the input and output data, processing events, and the schedule and resources required to execute the desired data flow.\n\n![Key Concepts](./media/data-factory-introduction/key-concepts.png)\n\n**Figure 2.** Relationships between Dataset, Activity, Pipeline, and Linked service\n\n\n### Activities\nActivities define the actions to perform on your data. Each activity takes zero or more [datasets](data-factory-create-datasets.md) as inputs and produces one or more datasets as outputs. An activity is a unit of orchestration in Azure Data Factory. For example, you may use a [Copy activity](data-factory-data-movement-activities.md) to orchestrate copying data from one dataset to another. Similarly you may use a [Hive activity](data-factory-data-transformation-activities.md) which will run a Hive query on an Azure HDInsight cluster to transform or analyze your data. Azure Data Factory provides a wide range of data transformation, analysis, and data movement activities. \n\n### Pipelines\n[Pipelines](data-factory-create-pipelines.md) are a logical grouping of Activities. They are used to group activities into a unit that together perform a task. For example, a sequence of several transformation Activities might be needed to cleanse log file data.  This sequence could have a complex schedule and dependencies that need to be orchestrated and automated. All of these activities could be grouped into a single Pipeline named “CleanLogFiles”.  “CleanLogFiles” could then be deployed, scheduled, or deleted as one single unit  instead of managing each individual activity independently.\n\n### Datasets\n[Datasets](data-factory-create-datasets.md) are named references/pointers to the data you want to use as an input or an output of an Activity. Datasets identify data structures within different data stores including tables, files, folders, and documents.\n\n### Linked service\nLinked services define the information needed for Data Factory to connect to external resources.  Linked services are used for two purposes in Data Factory:\n\n- To represent a data store  including, but not limited to, an on-premises SQL Server, Oracle DB, File share or an Azure Blob Storage account.   As discussed above, Datasets represent the structures within the data stores connected to Data Factory through a Linked service.\n- To represent a compute resource that can host the execution of an Activity.  For example, the “HDInsightHive Activity”executes on an HDInsight Hadoop cluster.\n\nWith the four simple concepts of datasets, activities, pipelines and linked services, you are ready to get started!  You can [build your first pipeline](data-factory-build-your-first-pipeline.md)  from the ground up, or deploy a ready-made sample by following the instructions in our [Data Factory Samples](data-factory-samples.md) article. \n\n## Send Feedback\nWe would really appreciate your feedback on this article. Please take a few minutes to submit your feedback via [email](mailto:adfdocfeedback@microsoft.com?subject=data-factory-introduction.md).  \n\n\n\n\n\ntest\n"
}