{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Automated Backup for SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines",
      "pos": [
        27,
        84
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Explains the Automated Backup feature for SQL Server running in Azure Virtual Machines.",
      "pos": [
        102,
        189
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automated Backup for SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines",
      "pos": [
        529,
        586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automated Backup automatically configures <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Managed Backup to Microsoft Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn449496.aspx)</ept> for all existing and new databases on an Azure VM running SQL Server 2014 Standard or Enterprise.",
      "pos": [
        588,
        813
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This enables you to configure regular database backups that utilize durable Azure blob storage.",
      "pos": [
        814,
        909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Automated Backup relies on the SQL Server IaaS Agent.",
      "pos": [
        912,
        978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To install and configure the agent, you must have the Azure VM Agent running on the target virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        979,
        1086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Newer virtual machine gallery images have this option enabled by default, but the Azure VM Agent might be missing on existing VMs.",
      "pos": [
        1087,
        1217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using your own VM image, you will also need to install the SQL Server IaaS Agent.",
      "pos": [
        1218,
        1310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>VM Agent and Extensions<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/blog/2014/04/15/vm-agent-and-extensions-part-2/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1311,
        1439
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automated Backup Settings",
      "pos": [
        1444,
        1469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following table describes the options that can be configured for Automated Backup.",
      "pos": [
        1471,
        1557
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The actual configuration steps vary depending on whether you use the Azure Portal or Azure Windows PowerShell commands.",
      "pos": [
        1558,
        1677
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Setting",
      "pos": [
        1680,
        1687
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Range (Default)",
      "pos": [
        1688,
        1703
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        1704,
        1715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automated Backup",
      "pos": [
        1734,
        1750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enable/Disable (Disabled)",
      "pos": [
        1753,
        1778
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enables or disables Automated Backup for an Azure VM running SQL Server 2014 Standard or Enterprise.",
      "pos": [
        1779,
        1879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retention Period",
      "pos": [
        1884,
        1900
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1-30 days (30 days)",
      "pos": [
        1903,
        1922
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The number of days to retain a backup.",
      "pos": [
        1923,
        1961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage Account",
      "pos": [
        1966,
        1981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure storage account (the storage account created for the specified VM)",
      "pos": [
        1984,
        2056
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Azure storage account to use for storing Automated Backup files in blob storage.",
      "pos": [
        2057,
        2140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A container is created at this location to store all backup files.",
      "pos": [
        2141,
        2207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The backup file naming convention includes the date, time, and machine name.",
      "pos": [
        2208,
        2284
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Encryption",
      "pos": [
        2289,
        2299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enable/Disable (Disabled)",
      "pos": [
        2302,
        2327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enables or disables encryption.",
      "pos": [
        2328,
        2359
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When encryption is enabled, the certificates used to restore the backup are located in the specified storage account in the same automaticbackup container using the same naming convention.",
      "pos": [
        2360,
        2548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the password changes, a new certificate is generated with that password, but the old certificate remains to restore prior backups.",
      "pos": [
        2549,
        2682
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Password",
      "pos": [
        2687,
        2695
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Password text (None)",
      "pos": [
        2698,
        2718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A password for encryption keys.",
      "pos": [
        2719,
        2750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is only required if encryption is enabled.",
      "pos": [
        2751,
        2798
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In order to restore an encrypted backup, you must have the correct password and related certificate that was used at the time the backup was taken.",
      "pos": [
        2799,
        2946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure Automated Backup in the Portal",
      "pos": [
        2952,
        2992
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Preview Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=525040&amp;clcid=0x409)</ept> to configure Automated Backup when you create a new SQL Server 2014 Virtual Machine.",
      "pos": [
        2994,
        3176
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following screenshot shows these options under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OPTIONAL CONFIGURATION<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> | <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SQL AUTOMATED BACKUP<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3177,
        3282
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Automatic Backup configuration in Azure Portal",
      "pos": [
        3286,
        3336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For existing SQL Server 2014 virtual machines, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Auto backup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> settings in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configuration<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> section of the virtual machine properties.",
      "pos": [
        3406,
        3556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Automated backup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> window, you can enable the feature, set the retention period, select the storage account, and set encryption.",
      "pos": [
        3557,
        3694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is shown in the following screenshot.",
      "pos": [
        3695,
        3737
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automated Backup Configuration in Azure Portal",
      "pos": [
        3741,
        3787
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> When you enable Automated Backup for the first time, Azure configures the SQL Server IaaS Agent in the background.",
      "pos": [
        3858,
        3985
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During this time, the portal will not show that Automated Backup is configured.",
      "pos": [
        3986,
        4065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Wait several minutes for the agent to be installed, configured.",
      "pos": [
        4066,
        4129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After that the portal will reflect the new settings.",
      "pos": [
        4130,
        4182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure Automated Backup with PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        4187,
        4229
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the following PowerShell example, Automated Backup is configured for an existing SQL Server 2014 VM.",
      "pos": [
        4231,
        4334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New-AzureVMSqlServerAutoBackupConfig<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> command configures the Automated Backup settings to store backups in the Azure storage account specified by the $storageaccount variable.",
      "pos": [
        4335,
        4517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These backups will be retained for 10 days.",
      "pos": [
        4518,
        4561
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Set-AzureVMSqlServerExtension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> command updates the specified Azure VM with these settings.",
      "pos": [
        4562,
        4659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It could take several minutes to install and configure the SQL Server IaaS Agent.",
      "pos": [
        5191,
        5272
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To enable encryption, modify the previous script to pass the EnableEncryption parameter along with a password (secure string) for the CertificatePassword parameter.",
      "pos": [
        5274,
        5438
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following script enables the Automated Backup settings in the previous example and adds encryption.",
      "pos": [
        5439,
        5542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To disable automatic backup, run the same script without the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>-Enable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter to the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>New-AzureVMSqlServerAutoBackupConfig<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6244,
        6375
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As with installation, it can take several minutes to disable Automated Backup.",
      "pos": [
        6376,
        6454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Disabling and Uninstalling the SQL Server IaaS Agent",
      "pos": [
        6459,
        6511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to disable the SQL Server IaaS Agent for Automated Backup and Patching, use the following command:",
      "pos": [
        6513,
        6623
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To uninstall the SQL Server IaaS Agent, use the following syntax:",
      "pos": [
        6744,
        6809
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6932,
        7024
      ],
      "content": "You can also uninstall the extension using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Remove-AzureVMSqlServerExtension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> command:"
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Disabling and uninstalling the SQL Server IaaS Agent does not remove the previously configured Managed Backup settings.",
      "pos": [
        7140,
        7272
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should disable Automated Backup before disabling or uninstalling the SQL Server IaaS Agent.",
      "pos": [
        7273,
        7368
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Compatibility",
      "pos": [
        7373,
        7386
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following products are compatible with the SQL Server IaaS Agent features for Automated Backup:",
      "pos": [
        7388,
        7487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2012",
      "pos": [
        7491,
        7510
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2012 R2",
      "pos": [
        7514,
        7536
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Server 2014 Standard",
      "pos": [
        7540,
        7564
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Server 2014 Enterprise",
      "pos": [
        7568,
        7594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        7599,
        7609
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automated Backup configures Managed Backup on Azure VMs.",
      "pos": [
        7611,
        7667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "So it is important to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>review the documentation for Managed Backup<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn449496.aspx)</ept> to understand the behavior and implications.",
      "pos": [
        7668,
        7830
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7832,
        8049
      ],
      "content": "You can find additional backup and restore guidance for SQL Server on Azure VMs in the following topic: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Backup and Restore for SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-machines-sql-server-backup-and-restore.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8051,
        8213
      ],
      "content": "A related feature for SQL Server VMs in Azure is <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Automated Patching for SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-machines-sql-server-automated-patching.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8215,
        8345
      ],
      "content": "Review other <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>resources for running SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-machines-sql-server-infrastructure-services.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Automated Backup for SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines\"\n   description=\"Explains the Automated Backup feature for SQL Server running in Azure Virtual Machines.\"\n   services=\"virtual-machines\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   authors=\"rothja\"\n   manager=\"jeffreyg\"\n   editor=\"monicar\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"virtual-machines\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"vm-windows-sql-server\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"08/05/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"jroth\" />\n\n# Automated Backup for SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines\n\nAutomated Backup automatically configures [Managed Backup to Microsoft Azure](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn449496.aspx) for all existing and new databases on an Azure VM running SQL Server 2014 Standard or Enterprise. This enables you to configure regular database backups that utilize durable Azure blob storage.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] Automated Backup relies on the SQL Server IaaS Agent. To install and configure the agent, you must have the Azure VM Agent running on the target virtual machine. Newer virtual machine gallery images have this option enabled by default, but the Azure VM Agent might be missing on existing VMs. If you are using your own VM image, you will also need to install the SQL Server IaaS Agent. For more information, see [VM Agent and Extensions](http://azure.microsoft.com/blog/2014/04/15/vm-agent-and-extensions-part-2/).\n\n## Automated Backup Settings\n\nThe following table describes the options that can be configured for Automated Backup. The actual configuration steps vary depending on whether you use the Azure Portal or Azure Windows PowerShell commands.\n\n|Setting|Range (Default)|Description|\n|---|---|---|\n|**Automated Backup**|Enable/Disable (Disabled)|Enables or disables Automated Backup for an Azure VM running SQL Server 2014 Standard or Enterprise.|\n|**Retention Period**|1-30 days (30 days)|The number of days to retain a backup.|\n|**Storage Account**|Azure storage account (the storage account created for the specified VM)|An Azure storage account to use for storing Automated Backup files in blob storage. A container is created at this location to store all backup files. The backup file naming convention includes the date, time, and machine name.|\n|**Encryption**|Enable/Disable (Disabled)|Enables or disables encryption. When encryption is enabled, the certificates used to restore the backup are located in the specified storage account in the same automaticbackup container using the same naming convention. If the password changes, a new certificate is generated with that password, but the old certificate remains to restore prior backups.|\n|**Password**|Password text (None)|A password for encryption keys. This is only required if encryption is enabled. In order to restore an encrypted backup, you must have the correct password and related certificate that was used at the time the backup was taken.|\n\n## Configure Automated Backup in the Portal\n\nYou can use the [Azure Preview Portal](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=525040&clcid=0x409) to configure Automated Backup when you create a new SQL Server 2014 Virtual Machine. The following screenshot shows these options under **OPTIONAL CONFIGURATION** | **SQL AUTOMATED BACKUP**.\n\n![SQL Automatic Backup configuration in Azure Portal](./media/virtual-machines-sql-server-automated-backup/IC778483.jpg)\n\nFor existing SQL Server 2014 virtual machines, select the **Auto backup** settings in the **Configuration** section of the virtual machine properties. In the **Automated backup** window, you can enable the feature, set the retention period, select the storage account, and set encryption. This is shown in the following screenshot.\n\n![Automated Backup Configuration in Azure Portal](./media/virtual-machines-sql-server-automated-backup/IC792133.jpg)\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] When you enable Automated Backup for the first time, Azure configures the SQL Server IaaS Agent in the background. During this time, the portal will not show that Automated Backup is configured. Wait several minutes for the agent to be installed, configured. After that the portal will reflect the new settings.\n\n## Configure Automated Backup with PowerShell\n\nIn the following PowerShell example, Automated Backup is configured for an existing SQL Server 2014 VM. The **New-AzureVMSqlServerAutoBackupConfig** command configures the Automated Backup settings to store backups in the Azure storage account specified by the $storageaccount variable. These backups will be retained for 10 days. The **Set-AzureVMSqlServerExtension** command updates the specified Azure VM with these settings.\n\n    $storageaccount = \"<storageaccountname>\"\n    $storageaccountkey = (Get-AzureStorageKey -StorageAccountName $storageaccount).Primary\n    $storagecontext = New-AzureStorageContext -StorageAccountName $storageaccount -StorageAccountKey $storageaccountkey\n    $autobackupconfig = New-AzureVMSqlServerAutoBackupConfig -StorageContext $storagecontext -Enable -RetentionPeriod 10\n    \n    Get-AzureVM -ServiceName <vmservicename> -Name <vmname> | Set-AzureVMSqlServerExtension -AutoBackupSettings $autobackupconfig | Update-AzureVM\n\nIt could take several minutes to install and configure the SQL Server IaaS Agent.\n\nTo enable encryption, modify the previous script to pass the EnableEncryption parameter along with a password (secure string) for the CertificatePassword parameter. The following script enables the Automated Backup settings in the previous example and adds encryption.\n\n    $storageaccount = \"<storageaccountname>\"\n    $storageaccountkey = (Get-AzureStorageKey -StorageAccountName $storageaccount).Primary\n    $storagecontext = New-AzureStorageContext -StorageAccountName $storageaccount -StorageAccountKey $storageaccountkey\n    $password = \"P@ssw0rd\"\n    $encryptionpassword = $password | ConvertTo-SecureString -AsPlainText -Force  \n    $autobackupconfig = New-AzureVMSqlServerAutoBackupConfig -StorageContext $storagecontext -Enable -RetentionPeriod 10 -EnableEncryption -CertificatePassword $encryptionpassword\n    \n    Get-AzureVM -ServiceName <vmservicename> -Name <vmname> | Set-AzureVMSqlServerExtension -AutoBackupSettings $autobackupconfig | Update-AzureVM \n\nTo disable automatic backup, run the same script without the **-Enable** parameter to the **New-AzureVMSqlServerAutoBackupConfig**. As with installation, it can take several minutes to disable Automated Backup.\n\n## Disabling and Uninstalling the SQL Server IaaS Agent\n\nIf you want to disable the SQL Server IaaS Agent for Automated Backup and Patching, use the following command:\n\n    Get-AzureVM -ServiceName <vmservicename> -Name <vmname> | Set-AzureVMSqlServerExtension -Disable | Update-AzureVM\n\nTo uninstall the SQL Server IaaS Agent, use the following syntax:\n\n    Get-AzureVM -ServiceName <vmservicename> -Name <vmname> | Set-AzureVMSqlServerExtension –Uninstall | Update-AzureVM\n\nYou can also uninstall the extension using the **Remove-AzureVMSqlServerExtension** command:\n\n    Get-AzureVM -ServiceName <vmservicename> -Name <vmname> | Remove-AzureVMSqlServerExtension | Update-AzureVM\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] Disabling and uninstalling the SQL Server IaaS Agent does not remove the previously configured Managed Backup settings. You should disable Automated Backup before disabling or uninstalling the SQL Server IaaS Agent.\n\n## Compatibility\n\nThe following products are compatible with the SQL Server IaaS Agent features for Automated Backup:\n\n- Windows Server 2012\n\n- Windows Server 2012 R2\n\n- SQL Server 2014 Standard\n\n- SQL Server 2014 Enterprise\n\n## Next Steps\n\nAutomated Backup configures Managed Backup on Azure VMs. So it is important to [review the documentation for Managed Backup](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn449496.aspx) to understand the behavior and implications.\n\nYou can find additional backup and restore guidance for SQL Server on Azure VMs in the following topic: [Backup and Restore for SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines](virtual-machines-sql-server-backup-and-restore.md).\n\nA related feature for SQL Server VMs in Azure is [Automated Patching for SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines](virtual-machines-sql-server-automated-patching.md).\n\nReview other [resources for running SQL Server in Azure Virtual Machines](virtual-machines-sql-server-infrastructure-services.md).\n"
}