{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "An Azure virtual network (VNet) is a representation of your own network in the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        0,
        85
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can control your Azure network settings and define DHCP address blocks, DNS settings, security policies, and routing.",
      "pos": [
        86,
        207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also further segment your VNet into subnets and deploy Azure IaaS virtual machines (VMs) and PaaS role instances, in the same way you can deploy physical and virtual machines to your on-premises datacenter.",
      "pos": [
        208,
        422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In essence, you can expand your network to Azure, bringing your own IP address blocks.",
      "pos": [
        423,
        509
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Read the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>virtual network overview<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-networks-overview.md)</ept> if you are not familiar with VNets.",
      "pos": [
        510,
        611
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph>Before you create a VNet, it's important to understand that Azure currently works with two deployment models: Resource Manager, and classic.",
      "pos": [
        614,
        771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure you understand <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>deployment models and tools<ept id=\"p1\">](azure-classic-rm.md)</ept> before creating VNets.",
      "pos": [
        772,
        870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can view the documentation for different tools by clicking the tabs at the top of this article.",
      "pos": [
        871,
        970
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "An Azure virtual network (VNet) is a representation of your own network in the cloud. You can control your Azure network settings and define DHCP address blocks, DNS settings, security policies, and routing. You can also further segment your VNet into subnets and deploy Azure IaaS virtual machines (VMs) and PaaS role instances, in the same way you can deploy physical and virtual machines to your on-premises datacenter. In essence, you can expand your network to Azure, bringing your own IP address blocks. Read the [virtual network overview](virtual-networks-overview.md) if you are not familiar with VNets.\n\n>[AZURE.IMPORTANT]Before you create a VNet, it's important to understand that Azure currently works with two deployment models: Resource Manager, and classic. Make sure you understand [deployment models and tools](azure-classic-rm.md) before creating VNets. You can view the documentation for different tools by clicking the tabs at the top of this article.\n\n\n"
}