{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Sign ins from possibly infected devices",
      "pos": [
        27,
        66
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A report that includes sign in attempts that have been executed from devices on which some malware (malicious software) may be running.",
      "pos": [
        85,
        220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign ins from possibly infected devices",
      "pos": [
        539,
        578
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This report attempts to identify your users' devices that that have become infected and are now part of a botnet (also known as a zombie army).",
      "pos": [
        582,
        725
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We correlate IP addresses of users' sign ins against IP addresses that we know to be in contact with botnet servers.",
      "pos": [
        726,
        842
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Recommendation: This report flags IP addresses, not user devices.",
      "pos": [
        850,
        915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend that you contact the user and scan all the user's devices to be certain.",
      "pos": [
        916,
        1001
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is also possible that a user's personal device is infected, or that someone other than the user, who was using the same IP address as the user, has an infected device.",
      "pos": [
        1002,
        1172
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about how to address malware infections, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p1\">Malware Protection Center](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=335773)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1181,
        1326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign ins from possibly infected devices",
      "pos": [
        1336,
        1375
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        1493,
        1497
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Sign ins from possibly infected devices\"\n    description=\"A report that includes sign in attempts that have been executed from devices on which some malware (malicious software) may be running.\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"SSalahAhmed\"\n    manager=\"gchander\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n    ms.workload=\"identity\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"08/17/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"saah;kenhoff\"/>\n\n# Sign ins from possibly infected devices\n<p>This report attempts to identify your users' devices that that have become infected and are now part of a botnet (also known as a zombie army). We correlate IP addresses of users' sign ins against IP addresses that we know to be in contact with botnet servers.</p>\n<p>Recommendation: This report flags IP addresses, not user devices. We recommend that you contact the user and scan all the user's devices to be certain. It is also possible that a user's personal device is infected, or that someone other than the user, who was using the same IP address as the user, has an infected device. </p>\n<p>For more information about how to address malware infections, see the [Malware Protection Center](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=335773). </p>\n\n\n![Sign ins from possibly infected devices](./media/active-directory-reporting-sign-ins-from-possibly-infected-devices/signInsFromPossiblyInfectedDevices.PNG)\n\ntest\n"
}