{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Manage and Monitor your Connectors and API Apps in Azure App Service",
      "pos": [
        28,
        96
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "View performance of your Connectors and API Apps in Azure App Service; microservices architecture",
      "pos": [
        116,
        213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Manage and Monitor your built-in API Apps and Connectors",
      "pos": [
        566,
        622
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You created a built-in API App.",
      "pos": [
        624,
        655
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Now what?",
      "pos": [
        656,
        665
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Azure, every API App is a separate web site hosted on Azure.",
      "pos": [
        668,
        731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result, you can easily see how many requests are made, and see how much data is being used by the connector.",
      "pos": [
        732,
        845
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also backup your API App, create alerts, enable Tinfoil Security, and add users and roles.",
      "pos": [
        847,
        945
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic describes some of the different options to manage your API App.",
      "pos": [
        947,
        1021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To see these built-in features, open your API App in the preview <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=525040)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1024,
        1153
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the API App is on your startboard, select it to open the properties.",
      "pos": [
        1154,
        1225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Browse<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>API Apps<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then select your API App:",
      "pos": [
        1226,
        1308
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][browse]",
      "pos": [
        1310,
        1321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the properties you entered",
      "pos": [
        1326,
        1356
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you open the API App, there are several features and tasks available:",
      "pos": [
        1358,
        1432
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][settings]",
      "pos": [
        1434,
        1447
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can:",
      "pos": [
        1449,
        1457
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> shows specific information on the API App, including your subscription details, and lists the users who have access to your API app.",
      "pos": [
        1462,
        1607
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also increase or decrease the number of instances of your API App using the Scale feature; among other features.",
      "pos": [
        1608,
        1728
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1731,
        1793
      ],
      "content": "Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Start<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Stop<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> buttons to control the API App."
    },
    {
      "content": "When product updates are made to the underlying files used by your API App, you can click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Update<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to get the latest versions.",
      "pos": [
        1796,
        1924
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if there is a fix or a security update released by Microsoft, clicking <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Update<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> automatically updates your API App to include this fix.",
      "pos": [
        1925,
        2075
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change Plan<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to upgrade or downgrade based on the data usage of the API App.",
      "pos": [
        2079,
        2165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also use this feature to see your data usage.",
      "pos": [
        2166,
        2219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create a connector that has tables, like the SQL connector, you can optionally enter a table name to connect to.",
      "pos": [
        2222,
        2343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A schema based on the table is automatically created and available when you click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download Schemas<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2344,
        2447
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can then use this downloaded schema to create a transform or a map.",
      "pos": [
        2448,
        2519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Change your connector or API configuration values you entered",
      "pos": [
        2525,
        2586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you configured or created your built-connector, you can change the values you entered.",
      "pos": [
        2588,
        2680
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you configured the SQL Connector and you want to change the SQL Server name or table name, you can do this in the API App blade for your connector.",
      "pos": [
        2681,
        2844
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Steps include:",
      "pos": [
        2847,
        2861
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open your connector or API App.",
      "pos": [
        2866,
        2897
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you do, the API App blade opens.",
      "pos": [
        2898,
        2935
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Essentials, click the hyperlink under the Host property.",
      "pos": [
        2939,
        2998
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The hyperlink is named something like <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>slackconnector<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>microsoftsqlconnector123<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>:",
      "pos": [
        2999,
        3084
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][apiapphost]",
      "pos": [
        3090,
        3105
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3110,
        3157
      ],
      "content": "In the API App Host blade, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3161,
        3216
      ],
      "content": "In the Settings blade, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Application Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3220,
        3280
      ],
      "content": "Your configuration values are listed under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>App Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:"
    },
    {
      "content": "![][hostsettings]",
      "pos": [
        3291,
        3308
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3313,
        3398
      ],
      "content": "Click the setting you want to change, enter the new value, and <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> your changes."
    },
    {
      "content": "Install the Hybrid Connection Manager - Optional",
      "pos": [
        3405,
        3453
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][hcsetup]",
      "pos": [
        3455,
        3467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Hybrid Connection Manager gives you the ability to connect to an on-premises system, like SQL Server or SAP.",
      "pos": [
        3469,
        3581
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This hybrid connectivity uses Azure Service Bus to connect and control the security between your Azure resources and your on-premises resources.",
      "pos": [
        3582,
        3726
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3728,
        3839
      ],
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using the Hybrid Connection Manager in Azure App Service<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-logic-hybrid-connection-manager.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Hybrid Connection Manager is required only if you are connecting to an on-premises resource behind your firewall.",
      "pos": [
        3844,
        3970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are not connecting to an on-premises system,  the Hybrid Connection Manager may not be listed in your connector blade.",
      "pos": [
        3971,
        4096
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitor the performance",
      "pos": [
        4101,
        4124
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Performance metrics are built-in features and included with every API App you create.",
      "pos": [
        4125,
        4210
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These metrics are specific to your API App hosted in Azure:",
      "pos": [
        4211,
        4270
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][monitoring]",
      "pos": [
        4273,
        4288
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can:",
      "pos": [
        4290,
        4298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Requests and errors<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to add different performance metrics including commonly-known HTTP error codes, like 200, 400, or 500 HTTP status codes.",
      "pos": [
        4303,
        4454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also see response times,  see how many requests are made to the API App, and see how much data comes in and how much data goes out.",
      "pos": [
        4455,
        4594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Based on the performance metrics, you can create email Alerts if a metric exceeds a threshold of your choosing.",
      "pos": [
        4595,
        4706
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Usage<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you can see how much <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>CPU<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> is used by the API App, review the current <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Usage Quota<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> in MB, and see your maximum data usage based on your cost tier.",
      "pos": [
        4710,
        4875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Estimated spend<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  can help you determine the potential costs of running your API App.",
      "pos": [
        4876,
        4964
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Processes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to open Process Explorer.",
      "pos": [
        4967,
        5013
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This shows your web instances and their properties, including thread count and memory usage.",
      "pos": [
        5014,
        5106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using these tools, you can determine if the App Service Plan should be scaled up or scaled down, based on your business needs.",
      "pos": [
        5108,
        5234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These features are built-in to the portal with no additional tools required.",
      "pos": [
        5235,
        5311
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Control the security",
      "pos": [
        5317,
        5337
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "API Apps use role-based security.",
      "pos": [
        5339,
        5372
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These roles apply to the entire Azure experience, including API Apps and other Azure resources.",
      "pos": [
        5373,
        5468
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The roles include:",
      "pos": [
        5469,
        5487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Role",
      "pos": [
        5489,
        5493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        5496,
        5507
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Owner",
      "pos": [
        5518,
        5523
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Have full access to the management experience and can give access to other users or groups.",
      "pos": [
        5526,
        5617
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Contributor",
      "pos": [
        5618,
        5629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Have full access to the management experience.",
      "pos": [
        5632,
        5678
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cannot give access to other users or groups.",
      "pos": [
        5679,
        5723
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reader",
      "pos": [
        5724,
        5730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can view all resources except secrets.",
      "pos": [
        5733,
        5771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User Access Administrator",
      "pos": [
        5772,
        5797
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can view all resources, create/manage roles, and create/manage support tickets.",
      "pos": [
        5800,
        5879
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5881,
        5983
      ],
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Role-based access control in the Microsoft Azure portal<ept id=\"p1\">](role-based-access-control-configure.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "You can easily add users and assign them specific roles to your API App.",
      "pos": [
        5985,
        6057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The portal shows you the users that have access and their assigned role:",
      "pos": [
        6058,
        6130
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][access]",
      "pos": [
        6132,
        6143
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6149,
        6214
      ],
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Users<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to add a user, assign a role, and remove a user."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6217,
        6327
      ],
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Roles<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to see all the users in a specific role, add a user to a role, and remove a user from a role."
    },
    {
      "content": "More Good Stuff",
      "pos": [
        6334,
        6349
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6352,
        6451
      ],
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>API definition<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to open the automatically-created Swagger file for your specific API app."
    },
    {
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dependencies<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to view the files required by your API App.",
      "pos": [
        6454,
        6521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you're using the SAP connector, you install some additional files on the on-premises Hybrid Connection Manager.",
      "pos": [
        6522,
        6649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These dependencies are shows in your API app blade.",
      "pos": [
        6650,
        6701
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6706,
        6855
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> When you open your API app properties and look under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Essentials<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, there are <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Host<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Gateway<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> links that open new blades:"
    },
    {
      "content": "![][host]",
      "pos": [
        6861,
        6870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These properties are specific to the website that hosts your API App.",
      "pos": [
        6876,
        6945
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using a built-in API App or connector, most of these properties don't really apply and we recommend that you  don't update these properties.",
      "pos": [
        6946,
        7091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you created your own API App in Visual Studio and deployed it to your Azure subscription, then you can use the Host and Gateway blades.",
      "pos": [
        7092,
        7230
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage API apps<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-api/app-service-api-manage-in-portal.md)</ept> provides more information on what you can do in these blades with your custom-created API app.",
      "pos": [
        7231,
        7399
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Read More",
      "pos": [
        7405,
        7414
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Monitor your Logic Apps<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-logic-monitor-your-logic-apps.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        7416,
        7487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Connectors and API Apps List in App Service<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-logic-connectors-list.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        7493,
        7576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Role-based access control in the Microsoft Azure portal<ept id=\"p1\">](role-based-access-control-configure.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        7582,
        7679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using the Hybrid Connection Manager in Azure App Service<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-logic-hybrid-connection-manager.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        7685,
        7791
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[bro",
      "pos": [
        7818,
        7822
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Manage and Monitor your Connectors and API Apps in Azure App Service\" \n    description=\"View performance of your Connectors and API Apps in Azure App Service; microservices architecture\" \n    services=\"app-service\\logic\" \n    documentationCenter=\".net,nodejs,java\"\n    authors=\"MandiOhlinger\" \n    manager=\"dwrede\" \n    editor=\"cgronlun\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"app-service-logic\" \n    ms.workload=\"integration\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"07/08/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"mandia\"/>\n\n# Manage and Monitor your built-in API Apps and Connectors\n\nYou created a built-in API App. Now what? \n\nIn Azure, every API App is a separate web site hosted on Azure. As a result, you can easily see how many requests are made, and see how much data is being used by the connector.\n\nYou can also backup your API App, create alerts, enable Tinfoil Security, and add users and roles.\n\nThis topic describes some of the different options to manage your API App. \n\nTo see these built-in features, open your API App in the preview [Azure portal](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=525040). If the API App is on your startboard, select it to open the properties. You can also select **Browse**, select **API Apps**, and then select your API App:\n\n![][browse]\n\n## See the properties you entered\n\nWhen you open the API App, there are several features and tasks available:\n\n![][settings]\n\nYou can: \n\n- **Settings** shows specific information on the API App, including your subscription details, and lists the users who have access to your API app. You can also increase or decrease the number of instances of your API App using the Scale feature; among other features.\n- Use the **Start** and **Stop** buttons to control the API App.\n- When product updates are made to the underlying files used by your API App, you can click **Update** to get the latest versions. For example, if there is a fix or a security update released by Microsoft, clicking **Update** automatically updates your API App to include this fix. \n- Select **Change Plan** to upgrade or downgrade based on the data usage of the API App. You can also use this feature to see your data usage.\n- When you create a connector that has tables, like the SQL connector, you can optionally enter a table name to connect to. A schema based on the table is automatically created and available when you click **Download Schemas**. You can then use this downloaded schema to create a transform or a map. \n\n## Change your connector or API configuration values you entered\n\nAfter you configured or created your built-connector, you can change the values you entered. For example, if you configured the SQL Connector and you want to change the SQL Server name or table name, you can do this in the API App blade for your connector. \n\nSteps include:\n\n1. Open your connector or API App. When you do, the API App blade opens.\n2. In Essentials, click the hyperlink under the Host property. The hyperlink is named something like *slackconnector* or *microsoftsqlconnector123*:\n\n    ![][apiapphost]\n\n3. In the API App Host blade, select **Settings**.\n4. In the Settings blade, select **Application Settings**.\n5. Your configuration values are listed under **App Settings**: \n    \n    ![][hostsettings]\n\n6. Click the setting you want to change, enter the new value, and **Save** your changes. \n\n\n## Install the Hybrid Connection Manager - Optional\n\n![][hcsetup]\n\nThe Hybrid Connection Manager gives you the ability to connect to an on-premises system, like SQL Server or SAP. This hybrid connectivity uses Azure Service Bus to connect and control the security between your Azure resources and your on-premises resources.\n\nSee [Using the Hybrid Connection Manager in Azure App Service](app-service-logic-hybrid-connection-manager.md). \n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Hybrid Connection Manager is required only if you are connecting to an on-premises resource behind your firewall. If you are not connecting to an on-premises system,  the Hybrid Connection Manager may not be listed in your connector blade.\n\n## Monitor the performance\nPerformance metrics are built-in features and included with every API App you create. These metrics are specific to your API App hosted in Azure: \n\n![][monitoring]\n\nYou can: \n\n- Select **Requests and errors** to add different performance metrics including commonly-known HTTP error codes, like 200, 400, or 500 HTTP status codes. You can also see response times,  see how many requests are made to the API App, and see how much data comes in and how much data goes out. Based on the performance metrics, you can create email Alerts if a metric exceeds a threshold of your choosing. \n- In **Usage**, you can see how much **CPU** is used by the API App, review the current **Usage Quota** in MB, and see your maximum data usage based on your cost tier. **Estimated spend**  can help you determine the potential costs of running your API App.\n- Select **Processes** to open Process Explorer. This shows your web instances and their properties, including thread count and memory usage.\n\nUsing these tools, you can determine if the App Service Plan should be scaled up or scaled down, based on your business needs. These features are built-in to the portal with no additional tools required. \n\n## Control the security\n\nAPI Apps use role-based security. These roles apply to the entire Azure experience, including API Apps and other Azure resources. The roles include:\n\nRole | Description\n--- | ---\nOwner | Have full access to the management experience and can give access to other users or groups.\nContributor | Have full access to the management experience. Cannot give access to other users or groups.\nReader | Can view all resources except secrets.\nUser Access Administrator | Can view all resources, create/manage roles, and create/manage support tickets.\n\nSee [Role-based access control in the Microsoft Azure portal](role-based-access-control-configure.md).\n\nYou can easily add users and assign them specific roles to your API App. The portal shows you the users that have access and their assigned role:\n\n![][access]  \n\n- Select **Users** to add a user, assign a role, and remove a user.\n- Select **Roles** to see all the users in a specific role, add a user to a role, and remove a user from a role. \n\n\n## More Good Stuff\n- Select **API definition** to open the automatically-created Swagger file for your specific API app.\n- Select **Dependencies** to view the files required by your API App. For example, if you're using the SAP connector, you install some additional files on the on-premises Hybrid Connection Manager. These dependencies are shows in your API app blade. \n\n> [AZURE.IMPORTANT] When you open your API app properties and look under **Essentials**, there are **Host** and **Gateway** links that open new blades:\n> \n> ![][host]\n> \n> These properties are specific to the website that hosts your API App. When using a built-in API App or connector, most of these properties don't really apply and we recommend that you  don't update these properties. If you created your own API App in Visual Studio and deployed it to your Azure subscription, then you can use the Host and Gateway blades. [Manage API apps](../app-service-api/app-service-api-manage-in-portal.md) provides more information on what you can do in these blades with your custom-created API app. \n\n## Read More\n\n[Monitor your Logic Apps](app-service-logic-monitor-your-logic-apps.md)<br/>\n[Connectors and API Apps List in App Service](app-service-logic-connectors-list.md)<br/>\n[Role-based access control in the Microsoft Azure portal](role-based-access-control-configure.md)<br/>\n[Using the Hybrid Connection Manager in Azure App Service](app-service-logic-hybrid-connection-manager.md)\n\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[browse]: ./media/app-service-logic-monitor-your-connectors/browse.png\n[settings]: ./media/app-service-logic-monitor-your-connectors/settings.png\n[hcsetup]: ./media/app-service-logic-monitor-your-connectors/hcsetup.png\n[monitoring]: ./media/app-service-logic-monitor-your-connectors/monitoring.png\n[access]: ./media/app-service-logic-monitor-your-connectors/access.png\n[host]: ./media/app-service-logic-monitor-your-connectors/host.png\n[hostsettings]: ./media/app-service-logic-monitor-your-connectors/hostsettings.png\n[apiapphost]: ./media/app-service-logic-monitor-your-connectors/apiapphost.png\ntest\n"
}