{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Backup FAQ | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        60
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Frequently asked questions on the Azure Backup service",
      "pos": [
        78,
        132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Backup - FAQ",
      "pos": [
        472,
        490
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following is a list of commonly asked questions about Azure Backup.",
      "pos": [
        491,
        562
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have any additional questions about Azure Backup, please go to the the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>discussion forum<ept id=\"p1\">](https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/forums/azure/home?forum=windowsazureonlinebackup)</ept> and post your questions.",
      "pos": [
        563,
        768
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Someone from our community will help you get your answers.",
      "pos": [
        769,
        827
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a question is commonly asked, we will add it to this article so that it can be found quickly and easily.",
      "pos": [
        828,
        935
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Installation &amp; Configuration",
      "pos": [
        940,
        968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q1. What is the list of supported operating systems from which I can backup to Azure using Azure Backup?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        969,
        1077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A1.",
      "pos": [
        1084,
        1087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following list of operating systems is supported by Azure Backup",
      "pos": [
        1088,
        1156
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operating System",
      "pos": [
        1161,
        1177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Platform",
      "pos": [
        1187,
        1195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SKU",
      "pos": [
        1208,
        1211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows 8 and latest SPs",
      "pos": [
        1258,
        1282
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1290,
        1296
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enterprise, Pro",
      "pos": [
        1299,
        1314
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows 7 and latest SPs",
      "pos": [
        1319,
        1343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1351,
        1357
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ultimate, Enterprise, Professional, Home Premium, Home Basic, Starter",
      "pos": [
        1360,
        1429
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows 8.1 and latest SPs",
      "pos": [
        1434,
        1460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1463,
        1469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enterprise, Pro",
      "pos": [
        1480,
        1495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows 10",
      "pos": [
        1500,
        1510
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1518,
        1524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enterprise, Pro, Home",
      "pos": [
        1527,
        1548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2012 R2 and latest SPs",
      "pos": [
        1552,
        1589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1591,
        1597
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard, Datacenter, Foundation",
      "pos": [
        1599,
        1631
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2012 and latest SPs",
      "pos": [
        1634,
        1668
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1673,
        1679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Datacenter, Foundation, Standard",
      "pos": [
        1681,
        1713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Storage Server 2012 R2 and latest SPs",
      "pos": [
        1716,
        1761
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1764,
        1770
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard, Workgroup",
      "pos": [
        1775,
        1794
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Storage Server 2012 and latest SPs",
      "pos": [
        1797,
        1839
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1841,
        1847
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard, Workgroup",
      "pos": [
        1849,
        1868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2012 R2 and latest SPs",
      "pos": [
        1870,
        1907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1910,
        1916
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Essential",
      "pos": [
        1921,
        1930
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2008 R2 SP1",
      "pos": [
        1933,
        1959
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        1961,
        1967
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard, Enterprise, Datacenter, Foundation",
      "pos": [
        1972,
        2016
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2008 SP2",
      "pos": [
        2019,
        2042
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "64 bit",
      "pos": [
        2047,
        2053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard, Enterprise, Datacenter, Foundation",
      "pos": [
        2058,
        2102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q2. Where can I download the latest Azure Backup agent?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        2105,
        2164
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A2.",
      "pos": [
        2171,
        2174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download the latest agent from <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/azurebackup_agent)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2175,
        2254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This can be installed on Windows Server, SCDPM server or Windows client",
      "pos": [
        2255,
        2326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q3. Which version of SCDPM server is supported?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        2328,
        2379
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A3.",
      "pos": [
        2386,
        2389
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend that you install the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>latest<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/azurebackup_agent)</ept> Azure Backup agent on the latest update rollup of SCDPM (UR6 as of July 2015)",
      "pos": [
        2390,
        2543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q4. When configuring the Azure Backup agent, I am prompted to enter the “vault credentials”. Is there any expiration date attached to the vault credentials?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        2545,
        2705
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A4.",
      "pos": [
        2712,
        2715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes, the vault credential expire after 48hours.",
      "pos": [
        2716,
        2763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the file expires, log in to the Azure portal and download the vault credentials files from your Backup vault.",
      "pos": [
        2764,
        2876
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q5. Is there any limit on the number of backup vaults that can be created in each Azure subscription?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        2878,
        2983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A5.",
      "pos": [
        2990,
        2993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes.",
      "pos": [
        2994,
        2998
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As of July 2015, you can create 25 vaults per subscription.",
      "pos": [
        2999,
        3058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need more vaults, then create a new subscription.",
      "pos": [
        3059,
        3115
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q6. Should I look at a vault as a billing entity?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        3117,
        3170
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A6.",
      "pos": [
        3177,
        3180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Though it is possible to get a detailed bill for each vault, we highly recommend that you consider an Azure subscription as a billing entity.",
      "pos": [
        3181,
        3322
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is consistent across all services and is easier to manage.",
      "pos": [
        3323,
        3384
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q7. Are there any limits on the number of servers/machines that can be registered against each vault?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        3386,
        3491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A7.",
      "pos": [
        3498,
        3501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes, you can register upto 50 machines per vault.",
      "pos": [
        3502,
        3551
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need to register more machines, create a new vault.",
      "pos": [
        3552,
        3610
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q8. Are there any limits on the amount of data that can be backed up from a Windows server/client or SCDPM server?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        3612,
        3730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A8.",
      "pos": [
        3737,
        3740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No.",
      "pos": [
        3741,
        3744
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q9. How do I register my server to another datacenter?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        3746,
        3804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A9.",
      "pos": [
        3810,
        3813
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In general the backup data is sent to the datacenter of the Backup Service to which it is registered.",
      "pos": [
        3814,
        3915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The easiest way to change the datacenter is to uninstall the agent and reinstall the agent and register to a new datacenter.",
      "pos": [
        3916,
        4040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q10. What happens if I rename a Windows server that is backing up data to Azure?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        4042,
        4126
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A10.",
      "pos": [
        4133,
        4137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any currently configured backups will be stopped.",
      "pos": [
        4138,
        4187
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will need to reregister the server with the backup vault and it will be considered a new server by Recovery Services, so the first backup operation that occurs after registration will be a full backup of all of the data included in the backup instead of just the changes since the last backup occurred.",
      "pos": [
        4188,
        4494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, if you need to perform a recovery operation you can recover the data that has been backed up using Recover from another server recovery option.",
      "pos": [
        4495,
        4647
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see Rename a server.",
      "pos": [
        4648,
        4690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q11. What types of drives can I backup files and folders from?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        4692,
        4758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A11.",
      "pos": [
        4765,
        4769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following set of drives/volumes can't be backup:",
      "pos": [
        4770,
        4822
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Removable Media: The drive must report as a fixed to be used a backup item source.",
      "pos": [
        4826,
        4908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Read-only Volumes: The volume must be writable for the volume shadow copy service (VSS) to function.",
      "pos": [
        4911,
        5011
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Offline Volumes: The volume must be online for VSS to function.",
      "pos": [
        5014,
        5077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network share: The volume must be local to the server to be backed up using online backup.",
      "pos": [
        5080,
        5170
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Bitlocker protected volumes: The volume must be unlocked before the backup can occur.",
      "pos": [
        5173,
        5258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "File System Identification: NTFS is the only file system supported for this version of the online backup service.",
      "pos": [
        5261,
        5374
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q12. What file and folder types can I back up from my server?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        5376,
        5441
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A12.",
      "pos": [
        5447,
        5451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following types are supported:",
      "pos": [
        5452,
        5486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Encrypted",
      "pos": [
        5490,
        5499
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Compressed",
      "pos": [
        5502,
        5512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sparse",
      "pos": [
        5515,
        5521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Compressed + Sparse",
      "pos": [
        5524,
        5543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hard Links: Not supported, skipped",
      "pos": [
        5546,
        5580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reparse Point: Not supported, skipped",
      "pos": [
        5583,
        5620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Encrypted + Compressed: Not supported, skipped",
      "pos": [
        5623,
        5669
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Encrypted + Sparse: Not supported, skipped",
      "pos": [
        5672,
        5714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Compressed Stream: Not supported, skipped",
      "pos": [
        5717,
        5758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sparse Stream: Not supported, skipped",
      "pos": [
        5761,
        5798
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q13. What's the minimum size requirement for the cache folder?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        5800,
        5866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A13.",
      "pos": [
        5873,
        5877
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The size of the cache folder is determined by the amount of data that you are backing up.",
      "pos": [
        5878,
        5967
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In general you should expect that 10-15% of the space required for data storage should be allocated for the cache folder.",
      "pos": [
        5968,
        6089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q14. How can I isolate specific server data from being recovered by other servers in my organization?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        6091,
        6196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A14.",
      "pos": [
        6202,
        6206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any servers that are registered using the same vault will be able to recover the data backed up by other servers that use the same passphrase.",
      "pos": [
        6207,
        6349
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have servers that you want to ensure recovery only occurs to specific servers in your organization, you should use a separate passphrase designated for those servers.",
      "pos": [
        6350,
        6523
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, human resources servers could use one encryption passphrase, accounting servers another, and storage servers a third.",
      "pos": [
        6524,
        6654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q15. Can I “migrate” my backup data between subscriptions?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        6656,
        6718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A15: No",
      "pos": [
        6725,
        6732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q16. Can I “migrate” my backup vault between subscriptions?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        6734,
        6797
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A16: No.",
      "pos": [
        6804,
        6812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The vault is created at a subscription level and cannot be reassigned to another subscription once it’s created.",
      "pos": [
        6813,
        6925
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q17. Does the Azure Backup Agent work on a server that uses Windows Server 2012 deduplication?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        6927,
        7025
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A17: Yes.",
      "pos": [
        7032,
        7041
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The agent service converts the deduplicated data to normal data when it prepares the backup operation.",
      "pos": [
        7042,
        7144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It then optimizes the data for backup, encrypts the data and then sends the encrypted data to the online backup service.",
      "pos": [
        7145,
        7265
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q18. Does the backup data get deleted if I cancel a backup after it has started?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        7267,
        7351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A18: No.",
      "pos": [
        7358,
        7366
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The backup vault stores the backed up data that had been transferred up to the point of the cancellation.",
      "pos": [
        7367,
        7472
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Backup uses a checkpoint mechanism so that the backup data gets check-pointed occasionally during the backup and the next backup process can validate the integrity of the files.",
      "pos": [
        7473,
        7656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The next backup triggered would be incremental over the data that had been backed up previously.",
      "pos": [
        7657,
        7753
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This provides better utilization of bandwidth, so that you do not need to transfer the same data repeatedly.",
      "pos": [
        7754,
        7862
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q19. Why am I seeing the warning \"Azure Backups have not been configured for this server\" even though I had scheduled regular backups previously?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        7864,
        8013
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A19: This can occur when the backup schedule settings stored on the local server are not the same as the settings stored in the backup vault.",
      "pos": [
        8020,
        8161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When either the server or the settings have been recovered to a known good state, the backup schedules can lose synchronization.",
      "pos": [
        8162,
        8290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this has happened, you should reconfigure the backup policy and then <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Run Back Up Now<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to resynchronize the local server with Azure.",
      "pos": [
        8291,
        8428
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q20. What firewall rules are to be configured for backup of Azure Backup?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        8430,
        8507
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A20.",
      "pos": [
        8514,
        8518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure firewall rules enable communication with URLs below for seamless backup of on-premises to Azure and workload protection on Azure:",
      "pos": [
        8519,
        8655
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "www.msftncsi.com",
      "pos": [
        8659,
        8675
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\*.Microsoft.com",
      "pos": [
        8678,
        8694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\*.WindowsAzure.com",
      "pos": [
        8697,
        8716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\*.microsoftonline.com",
      "pos": [
        8719,
        8741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\*.windows.net",
      "pos": [
        8744,
        8758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Backup &amp; Retention",
      "pos": [
        8764,
        8782
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q1. Is there a limit on the size of each data source being backed up?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        8783,
        8856
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A1.",
      "pos": [
        8863,
        8866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As of August 2015, The maximum size of data source is as mentioned below for various operating systems",
      "pos": [
        8867,
        8969
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "S.No",
      "pos": [
        8972,
        8976
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operating system",
      "pos": [
        8979,
        8995
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Maximum size of data source",
      "pos": [
        8999,
        9026
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        9073,
        9074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2012 or above",
      "pos": [
        9076,
        9104
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "54400 GB",
      "pos": [
        9106,
        9114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        9117,
        9118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 8 or above",
      "pos": [
        9120,
        9145
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "54400 GB",
      "pos": [
        9147,
        9155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3",
      "pos": [
        9158,
        9159
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server 2008, Windows Server 2008 R2",
      "pos": [
        9161,
        9204
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1700 GB",
      "pos": [
        9207,
        9214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4",
      "pos": [
        9217,
        9218
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows 7",
      "pos": [
        9220,
        9229
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1700 GB",
      "pos": [
        9232,
        9239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The datasource size is measured as mentioned below",
      "pos": [
        9243,
        9293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Datasource",
      "pos": [
        9299,
        9309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Details",
      "pos": [
        9315,
        9322
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Volume",
      "pos": [
        9361,
        9367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The amount of data being backed up from single volume of a machine.",
      "pos": [
        9369,
        9436
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is applicable for the volumes being protected on both server and client machines.",
      "pos": [
        9437,
        9523
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V virtual machine",
      "pos": [
        9526,
        9549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sum of data of all the VHDs of the virtual machine being backed up",
      "pos": [
        9550,
        9616
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft SQL Server database",
      "pos": [
        9619,
        9648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Size of single SQL database size being backed up",
      "pos": [
        9649,
        9697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft SharePoint",
      "pos": [
        9701,
        9721
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sum of the content and config databases within a SharePoint farm being backed up",
      "pos": [
        9722,
        9802
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Exchange",
      "pos": [
        9805,
        9823
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sum of all Exchange databases in an Exchange server being backed up",
      "pos": [
        9824,
        9891
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "BMR/System State",
      "pos": [
        9894,
        9910
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each individual copy of BMR or system state of the machine being backed up",
      "pos": [
        9911,
        9985
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q2. Is there are limit on the number of times backup can be scheduled per day?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        9988,
        10070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A2.",
      "pos": [
        10076,
        10079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes, Azure Backup enables 3 backup copies per day through Windows Server/Client and 2 backup copies per day through SCDPM.",
      "pos": [
        10080,
        10202
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q3. Is there a difference between DPM’s and Azure Backup’s (i.e on Windows Server without DPM) backup scheduling policy?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        10204,
        10328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A3.",
      "pos": [
        10335,
        10338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes.",
      "pos": [
        10339,
        10343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using DPM, you can specify daily, weekly, monthly, yearly scheduling while from a Windows Server (without DPM), you can specify only daily, weekly schedules.",
      "pos": [
        10344,
        10501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q4. Is there a difference between DPM’s and Azure Backup’s (i.e on Windows Server without DPM) retention policy?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        10503,
        10619
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A4.",
      "pos": [
        10625,
        10628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No, you have the same capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        10629,
        10664
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can specify daily, weekly, monthly and yearly retention policies.",
      "pos": [
        10665,
        10734
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q5. Can I configure my retention policies selectively – i.e. configure weekly and daily but not yearly and monthly?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        10736,
        10855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A5.",
      "pos": [
        10861,
        10864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You have the full set of knobs to come up with policies which best define your compliance/retention requirements.",
      "pos": [
        10865,
        10978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q6. Can I “schedule a backup” at 6pm and specify “retention policies” at a different time?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        10980,
        11074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A6.",
      "pos": [
        11080,
        11083
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No.",
      "pos": [
        11084,
        11087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retention policies can only be applied on backup points.",
      "pos": [
        11088,
        11144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the below image, the retention policy is being specified on backups taken at 12am and 6pm.",
      "pos": [
        11145,
        11238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Schedule Backup and Retention",
      "pos": [
        11248,
        11277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q7. Is an incremental copy transferred for the retention policies scheduled?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        11332,
        11412
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A7.",
      "pos": [
        11419,
        11422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No, the incremental copy is sent based on the time mentioned in the backup schedule page.",
      "pos": [
        11423,
        11512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The points that can be retained are determined based on the retention policy.",
      "pos": [
        11513,
        11590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q8. If backup is retained for a long duration, does it take a significant time to recover the data (say the oldest point)?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        11592,
        11718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A8.",
      "pos": [
        11725,
        11728
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No – the time taken to recovery the oldest or the latest point is one and the same.",
      "pos": [
        11729,
        11812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each recovery point behaves like a full point.",
      "pos": [
        11813,
        11859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q9. If each recovery point is like a full point, does it impact the total billable backup storage?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        11861,
        11963
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A9.",
      "pos": [
        11969,
        11972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typical long term retention point products store backup data as full points.",
      "pos": [
        11974,
        12050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, these are storage inefficient but are easier and faster to restore.",
      "pos": [
        12051,
        12127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Incremental copies are storage efficient but require you to restore a chain of data which impacts your recovery time.",
      "pos": [
        12128,
        12245
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Backup’s unique storage architecture gives you the best of both worlds by optimally storing data for fast restores and incurring low storage costs.",
      "pos": [
        12246,
        12399
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This approach ensures that your (ingress and egress) bandwidth is efficiently used, storage is kept to the minimum and the time taken to recover is kept to the minimum.",
      "pos": [
        12400,
        12568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q10. Is there a limit on the number of recovery points that can be created?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        12570,
        12649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A10.",
      "pos": [
        12655,
        12659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As of April 2015, you can have upto 366 recovery points.",
      "pos": [
        12660,
        12716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use any permutation to arrive at a number which is less than 366.",
      "pos": [
        12717,
        12790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Eg – the retention points in the below picture add to 354.",
      "pos": [
        12791,
        12849
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retention screen",
      "pos": [
        12859,
        12875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q11. Once Microsoft improves the limit from 366, will I need to upgrade the agent or reseed the initial backup?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        12932,
        13047
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A11.",
      "pos": [
        13054,
        13058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No.",
      "pos": [
        13059,
        13062
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once we make the change in our service, you will be notified through our social media outlets (blogs, Azure announcements, portal etc).",
      "pos": [
        13063,
        13198
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Based on your needs, you would then be required to only change the retention policy.",
      "pos": [
        13199,
        13283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q12. Why is the amount of data transferred in backup not equal to the amount of data I backed up?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        13285,
        13386
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A12.",
      "pos": [
        13392,
        13396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All the data that is backed up is compressed and encrypted before being transferred.",
      "pos": [
        13397,
        13481
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can expect 30-40% compression benefits depending on the type of data being backed up.",
      "pos": [
        13482,
        13571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Recovery",
      "pos": [
        13576,
        13584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q1. How many recoveries can I perform on the data that is backed up to Azure?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        13585,
        13666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A1.",
      "pos": [
        13672,
        13675
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There is no limit on the number of recoveries from Azure Backup.",
      "pos": [
        13676,
        13740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q2. Do I have to pay for the egress traffic from Azure data center during recoveries?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        13742,
        13831
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A2.",
      "pos": [
        13837,
        13840
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No.",
      "pos": [
        13841,
        13844
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your recoveries are free and you are not charged for the egress traffic.",
      "pos": [
        13845,
        13917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Security",
      "pos": [
        13922,
        13930
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q1. Is the data sent to Azure encrypted?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        13931,
        13975
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A1.",
      "pos": [
        13982,
        13985
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes.",
      "pos": [
        13986,
        13990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data is encrypted on the on-premises server/client/SCDPM machine using AES256 and the data is sent over a secure HTTPS link.",
      "pos": [
        13991,
        14115
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q2. Is the backup data on Azure encrypted as well?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        14117,
        14171
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A2.",
      "pos": [
        14177,
        14180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yes.",
      "pos": [
        14181,
        14185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The data which is sent to Azure remains encrypted (at rest).",
      "pos": [
        14186,
        14246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft does not decrypt the backup data at any point.",
      "pos": [
        14247,
        14303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q3. What is the minimum length of encryption key used to encrypt backup data?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        14305,
        14386
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A3.",
      "pos": [
        14393,
        14396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The encryption key should be at least 16 characters.",
      "pos": [
        14397,
        14449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Q4. What happens if I misplace the encryption key? Can I recover the data (or) can Microsoft recover the data?<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        14451,
        14565
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A4.",
      "pos": [
        14572,
        14575
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The key used to encrypt the backup data is present only on the customer premises.",
      "pos": [
        14576,
        14657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft does not maintain a copy in Azure and does not have any access to the key.",
      "pos": [
        14658,
        14742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the customer misplaces the key, Microsoft cannot recover the backup data.",
      "pos": [
        14743,
        14819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Backup cache",
      "pos": [
        14826,
        14838
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Q1.",
      "pos": [
        14842,
        14845
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How can I change the cache location specified for the Azure Backup agent?",
      "pos": [
        14846,
        14919
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stop the OBEngine by executing the below command in an elevated command prompt:",
      "pos": [
        14925,
        15004
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the cache space folder to a different drive with sufficient space.",
      "pos": [
        15043,
        15114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend you copy the files from the cache space folder instead of moving them; the original cache space can be removed after confirming that the backups are working with the new cache space.",
      "pos": [
        15115,
        15310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update following registry entries with the path to new cache space folder:",
      "pos": [
        15314,
        15388
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Start the OBEngine by executing the below command in an elevated command prompt:",
      "pos": [
        15749,
        15829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the backups happen successfully with the new cache location, you can remove the original cache folder.",
      "pos": [
        15867,
        15974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        15976,
        15980
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Azure Backup FAQ | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Frequently asked questions on the Azure Backup service\"\n   services=\"backup\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"Jim-Parker\"\n   manager=\"shreeshd\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"backup\"\n   ms.workload=\"storage-backup-recovery\"\n     ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n     ms.devlang=\"na\"\n     ms.topic=\"article\"\n     ms.date=\"08/26/2015\"\n     ms.author=\"giridham\"; \"arunak\"; \"jimpark\"; \"aashishr\"/>\n\n# Azure Backup - FAQ\nThe following is a list of commonly asked questions about Azure Backup. If you have any additional questions about Azure Backup, please go to the the [discussion forum](https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/forums/azure/home?forum=windowsazureonlinebackup) and post your questions. Someone from our community will help you get your answers. If a question is commonly asked, we will add it to this article so that it can be found quickly and easily.\n\n## Installation & Configuration\n**Q1. What is the list of supported operating systems from which I can backup to Azure using Azure Backup?** <br/>\nA1. The following list of operating systems is supported by Azure Backup\n\n\n| Operating System        | Platform           | SKU  |\n| :------------- |-------------| :-----|\n| Windows 8 and latest SPs      | 64 bit | Enterprise, Pro |\n| Windows 7 and latest SPs      | 64 bit | Ultimate, Enterprise, Professional, Home Premium, Home Basic, Starter |\n| Windows 8.1 and latest SPs | 64 bit      |    Enterprise, Pro |\n| Windows 10      | 64 bit | Enterprise, Pro, Home |\n|Windows Server 2012 R2 and latest SPs| 64 bit| Standard, Datacenter, Foundation|\n|Windows Server 2012 and latest SPs|    64 bit| Datacenter, Foundation, Standard|\n|Windows Storage Server 2012 R2 and latest SPs  |64 bit|    Standard, Workgroup|\n|Windows Storage Server 2012 and latest SPs |64 bit |Standard, Workgroup\n|Windows Server 2012 R2 and latest SPs  |64 bit|    Essential|\n|Windows Server 2008 R2 SP1 |64 bit|    Standard, Enterprise, Datacenter, Foundation|\n|Windows Server 2008 SP2    |64 bit|    Standard, Enterprise, Datacenter, Foundation|\n\n**Q2. Where can I download the latest Azure Backup agent?** <br/>\nA2. You can download the latest agent from [here](http://aka.ms/azurebackup_agent). This can be installed on Windows Server, SCDPM server or Windows client\n\n**Q3. Which version of SCDPM server is supported?** <br/>\nA3. We recommend that you install the [latest](http://aka.ms/azurebackup_agent) Azure Backup agent on the latest update rollup of SCDPM (UR6 as of July 2015)\n\n**Q4. When configuring the Azure Backup agent, I am prompted to enter the “vault credentials”. Is there any expiration date attached to the vault credentials?** <br/>\nA4. Yes, the vault credential expire after 48hours. If the file expires, log in to the Azure portal and download the vault credentials files from your Backup vault.\n\n**Q5. Is there any limit on the number of backup vaults that can be created in each Azure subscription?** <br/>\nA5. Yes. As of July 2015, you can create 25 vaults per subscription. If you need more vaults, then create a new subscription.\n\n**Q6. Should I look at a vault as a billing entity?** <br/>\nA6. Though it is possible to get a detailed bill for each vault, we highly recommend that you consider an Azure subscription as a billing entity. It is consistent across all services and is easier to manage.\n\n**Q7. Are there any limits on the number of servers/machines that can be registered against each vault?** <br/>\nA7. Yes, you can register upto 50 machines per vault. If you need to register more machines, create a new vault.\n\n**Q8. Are there any limits on the amount of data that can be backed up from a Windows server/client or SCDPM server?** <br/>\nA8. No.\n\n**Q9. How do I register my server to another datacenter?**<br/>\nA9. In general the backup data is sent to the datacenter of the Backup Service to which it is registered. The easiest way to change the datacenter is to uninstall the agent and reinstall the agent and register to a new datacenter.\n\n**Q10. What happens if I rename a Windows server that is backing up data to Azure?** <br/>\nA10. Any currently configured backups will be stopped. You will need to reregister the server with the backup vault and it will be considered a new server by Recovery Services, so the first backup operation that occurs after registration will be a full backup of all of the data included in the backup instead of just the changes since the last backup occurred. However, if you need to perform a recovery operation you can recover the data that has been backed up using Recover from another server recovery option. For more information, see Rename a server.\n\n**Q11. What types of drives can I backup files and folders from?** <br/>\nA11. The following set of drives/volumes can't be backup:\n\n- Removable Media: The drive must report as a fixed to be used a backup item source.\n- Read-only Volumes: The volume must be writable for the volume shadow copy service (VSS) to function.\n- Offline Volumes: The volume must be online for VSS to function.\n- Network share: The volume must be local to the server to be backed up using online backup.\n- Bitlocker protected volumes: The volume must be unlocked before the backup can occur.\n- File System Identification: NTFS is the only file system supported for this version of the online backup service.\n\n**Q12. What file and folder types can I back up from my server?**<br/>\nA12. The following types are supported:\n\n- Encrypted\n- Compressed\n- Sparse\n- Compressed + Sparse\n- Hard Links: Not supported, skipped\n- Reparse Point: Not supported, skipped\n- Encrypted + Compressed: Not supported, skipped\n- Encrypted + Sparse: Not supported, skipped\n- Compressed Stream: Not supported, skipped\n- Sparse Stream: Not supported, skipped\n\n**Q13. What's the minimum size requirement for the cache folder?** <br/>\nA13. The size of the cache folder is determined by the amount of data that you are backing up. In general you should expect that 10-15% of the space required for data storage should be allocated for the cache folder.\n\n**Q14. How can I isolate specific server data from being recovered by other servers in my organization?**<br/>\nA14. Any servers that are registered using the same vault will be able to recover the data backed up by other servers that use the same passphrase. If you have servers that you want to ensure recovery only occurs to specific servers in your organization, you should use a separate passphrase designated for those servers. For example, human resources servers could use one encryption passphrase, accounting servers another, and storage servers a third.\n\n**Q15. Can I “migrate” my backup data between subscriptions?** <br/>\nA15: No\n\n**Q16. Can I “migrate” my backup vault between subscriptions?** <br/>\nA16: No. The vault is created at a subscription level and cannot be reassigned to another subscription once it’s created.\n\n**Q17. Does the Azure Backup Agent work on a server that uses Windows Server 2012 deduplication?** <br/>\nA17: Yes. The agent service converts the deduplicated data to normal data when it prepares the backup operation. It then optimizes the data for backup, encrypts the data and then sends the encrypted data to the online backup service.\n\n**Q18. Does the backup data get deleted if I cancel a backup after it has started?** <br/>\nA18: No. The backup vault stores the backed up data that had been transferred up to the point of the cancellation. Azure Backup uses a checkpoint mechanism so that the backup data gets check-pointed occasionally during the backup and the next backup process can validate the integrity of the files. The next backup triggered would be incremental over the data that had been backed up previously. This provides better utilization of bandwidth, so that you do not need to transfer the same data repeatedly.\n\n**Q19. Why am I seeing the warning \"Azure Backups have not been configured for this server\" even though I had scheduled regular backups previously?** <br/>\nA19: This can occur when the backup schedule settings stored on the local server are not the same as the settings stored in the backup vault. When either the server or the settings have been recovered to a known good state, the backup schedules can lose synchronization. If this has happened, you should reconfigure the backup policy and then **Run Back Up Now** to resynchronize the local server with Azure.\n\n**Q20. What firewall rules are to be configured for backup of Azure Backup?** <br/>\nA20. Ensure firewall rules enable communication with URLs below for seamless backup of on-premises to Azure and workload protection on Azure:\n\n- www.msftncsi.com\n- \\*.Microsoft.com\n- \\*.WindowsAzure.com\n- \\*.microsoftonline.com\n- \\*.windows.net\n\n\n## Backup & Retention\n**Q1. Is there a limit on the size of each data source being backed up?** <br/>\nA1. As of August 2015, The maximum size of data source is as mentioned below for various operating systems\n\n|S.No | Operating system |  Maximum size of data source |\n| :-------------: |:-------------| :-----|\n|1| Windows Server 2012 or above| 54400 GB|\n|2| Windows Server 8 or above| 54400 GB|\n|3| Windows Server 2008, Windows Server 2008 R2 | 1700 GB|\n|4| Windows 7 | 1700 GB|\n \nThe datasource size is measured as mentioned below\n\n|   Datasource  |   Details |\n| :-------------: |:-------------|\n|Volume |The amount of data being backed up from single volume of a machine. This is applicable for the volumes being protected on both server and client machines.|\n|Hyper-V virtual machine|Sum of data of all the VHDs of the virtual machine being backed up|\n|Microsoft SQL Server database|Size of single SQL database size being backed up |\n|Microsoft SharePoint|Sum of the content and config databases within a SharePoint farm being backed up|\n|Microsoft Exchange|Sum of all Exchange databases in an Exchange server being backed up|\n|BMR/System State|Each individual copy of BMR or system state of the machine being backed up|\n\n**Q2. Is there are limit on the number of times backup can be scheduled per day?**<br/>\nA2. Yes, Azure Backup enables 3 backup copies per day through Windows Server/Client and 2 backup copies per day through SCDPM.\n\n**Q3. Is there a difference between DPM’s and Azure Backup’s (i.e on Windows Server without DPM) backup scheduling policy?** <br/>\nA3. Yes. Using DPM, you can specify daily, weekly, monthly, yearly scheduling while from a Windows Server (without DPM), you can specify only daily, weekly schedules.\n\n**Q4. Is there a difference between DPM’s and Azure Backup’s (i.e on Windows Server without DPM) retention policy?**<br/>\nA4. No, you have the same capabilities. You can specify daily, weekly, monthly and yearly retention policies.\n\n**Q5. Can I configure my retention policies selectively – i.e. configure weekly and daily but not yearly and monthly?**<br/>\nA5. You have the full set of knobs to come up with policies which best define your compliance/retention requirements.\n\n**Q6. Can I “schedule a backup” at 6pm and specify “retention policies” at a different time?**<br/>\nA6. No. Retention policies can only be applied on backup points. In the below image, the retention policy is being specified on backups taken at 12am and 6pm. <br/>\n\n![Schedule Backup and Retention](./media/backup-azure-backup-faq/Schedule.png)\n<br/>\n\n**Q7. Is an incremental copy transferred for the retention policies scheduled?** <br/>\nA7. No, the incremental copy is sent based on the time mentioned in the backup schedule page. The points that can be retained are determined based on the retention policy.\n\n**Q8. If backup is retained for a long duration, does it take a significant time to recover the data (say the oldest point)?** <br/>\nA8. No – the time taken to recovery the oldest or the latest point is one and the same. Each recovery point behaves like a full point.\n\n**Q9. If each recovery point is like a full point, does it impact the total billable backup storage?**<br/>\nA9.  Typical long term retention point products store backup data as full points. However, these are storage inefficient but are easier and faster to restore. Incremental copies are storage efficient but require you to restore a chain of data which impacts your recovery time. Azure Backup’s unique storage architecture gives you the best of both worlds by optimally storing data for fast restores and incurring low storage costs. This approach ensures that your (ingress and egress) bandwidth is efficiently used, storage is kept to the minimum and the time taken to recover is kept to the minimum.\n\n**Q10. Is there a limit on the number of recovery points that can be created?**<br/>\nA10. As of April 2015, you can have upto 366 recovery points. You can use any permutation to arrive at a number which is less than 366. Eg – the retention points in the below picture add to 354. <br/>\n\n![Retention screen](./media/backup-azure-backup-faq/RetentionScreen1.png)\n\n**Q11. Once Microsoft improves the limit from 366, will I need to upgrade the agent or reseed the initial backup?** <br/>\nA11. No. Once we make the change in our service, you will be notified through our social media outlets (blogs, Azure announcements, portal etc). Based on your needs, you would then be required to only change the retention policy.\n\n**Q12. Why is the amount of data transferred in backup not equal to the amount of data I backed up?**<br/>\nA12. All the data that is backed up is compressed and encrypted before being transferred. You can expect 30-40% compression benefits depending on the type of data being backed up.\n\n## Recovery\n**Q1. How many recoveries can I perform on the data that is backed up to Azure?**<br/>\nA1. There is no limit on the number of recoveries from Azure Backup.\n\n**Q2. Do I have to pay for the egress traffic from Azure data center during recoveries?**<br/>\nA2. No. Your recoveries are free and you are not charged for the egress traffic.\n\n## Security\n**Q1. Is the data sent to Azure encrypted?** <br/>\nA1. Yes. Data is encrypted on the on-premises server/client/SCDPM machine using AES256 and the data is sent over a secure HTTPS link.\n\n**Q2. Is the backup data on Azure encrypted as well?**<br/>\nA2. Yes. The data which is sent to Azure remains encrypted (at rest). Microsoft does not decrypt the backup data at any point.\n\n**Q3. What is the minimum length of encryption key used to encrypt backup data?** <br/>\nA3. The encryption key should be at least 16 characters.\n\n**Q4. What happens if I misplace the encryption key? Can I recover the data (or) can Microsoft recover the data?** <br/>\nA4. The key used to encrypt the backup data is present only on the customer premises. Microsoft does not maintain a copy in Azure and does not have any access to the key. If the customer misplaces the key, Microsoft cannot recover the backup data.\n \n\n## Backup cache\n\n**Q1. How can I change the cache location specified for the Azure Backup agent?**\n\n+ Stop the OBEngine by executing the below command in an elevated command prompt:\n\n  ```PS C:\\> Net stop obengine```\n\n+ Copy the cache space folder to a different drive with sufficient space. We recommend you copy the files from the cache space folder instead of moving them; the original cache space can be removed after confirming that the backups are working with the new cache space.\n\n+ Update following registry entries with the path to new cache space folder:\n\n\n    | Registry path | Registry Key | Value |\n    | ------ | ------- | ------ |\n    | HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows Azure Backup\\Config |  ScratchLocation | <i>New cache folder location</i> |\n    | HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows Azure Backup\\Config\\CloudBackupProvider | ScratchLocation | <i>New cache folder location</i> |\n\n\n+ Start the OBEngine by executing the below command in an elevated command prompt:\n\n  ```PS C:\\> Net start obengine```\n\nOnce the backups happen successfully with the new cache location, you can remove the original cache folder.\n\ntest\n"
}