{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Securely Connecting to BackEnd Resources from an App Service Environment",
      "pos": [
        28,
        100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn about how to securely connect to backend resources from an App Service Environment.",
      "pos": [
        120,
        209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Securely Connecting to Backend Resources from an App Service Environment",
      "pos": [
        526,
        598
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        605,
        613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since an App Service Environment is always created in a subnet of a regional [virtual network][virtualnetwork], outbound connections from an App Service Environment to other backend resources can flow exclusively over the virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        617,
        855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, there may be a SQL Server running on a cluster of virtual machines with port 1433 locked down.",
      "pos": [
        859,
        966
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The endpoint may be ACLd to only allow access from other resources on the same virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        968,
        1063
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As another example, sensitive endpoints may run on-premises and be connected to Azure via either [Site-to-Site][SiteToSite] or [Azure ExpressRoute][ExpressRoute] connections.",
      "pos": [
        1067,
        1241
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result, only resources in virtual networks connected to the Site-to-Site or ExpressRoute tunnels will be able to access on-premises endpoints.",
      "pos": [
        1243,
        1390
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For all of these scenarios, apps running on an App Service Environment will be able to securely connect to the various servers and resources.",
      "pos": [
        1392,
        1533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Outbound traffic from apps running in an App Service Environment to private endpoints in the same virtual network (or connected to the same virtual network), will only flow over the virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        1535,
        1733
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Outbound traffic to private endpoints will not flow over the public Internet.",
      "pos": [
        1735,
        1812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Outbound Connectivity and DNS Requirements",
      "pos": [
        1817,
        1859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that for an App Service Environment to function properly, it requires outbound access to Azure Storage as well as Sql Database in the same Azure region.",
      "pos": [
        1863,
        2020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If outbound Internet access is blocked in the virtual network, App Service Environments will not be able to access these Azure endpoints.",
      "pos": [
        2022,
        2159
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Customer may also have custom DNS servers configured in the virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        2161,
        2237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service Environments need to be able to resolve Azure endpoints under *.database.windows.net, *.file.core.windows.net and *.blob.core.windows.net.",
      "pos": [
        2239,
        2389
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is also recommended that any custom DNS servers on the virtual network be setup ahead of time prior to creating an App Service Environment.",
      "pos": [
        2393,
        2535
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a virtual network's DNS configuration is changed while an App Service Environment is being created, that will result in the App Service Environment creation process failing.",
      "pos": [
        2537,
        2713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connecting to a SQL Server",
      "pos": [
        2718,
        2744
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A common SQL Server configuration has an endpoint listening on port 1433:",
      "pos": [
        2745,
        2818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Server Endpoint",
      "pos": [
        2822,
        2841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two approaches for restricting traffic to this endpoint:",
      "pos": [
        2863,
        2929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Network Access Control Lists][NetworkAccessControlLists] (Network ACLs)",
      "pos": [
        2934,
        3006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Network Security Groups][NetworkSecurityGroups]",
      "pos": [
        3010,
        3058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restricting Access With a Network ACL",
      "pos": [
        3064,
        3101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Port 1433 can be secured using a network access control list.",
      "pos": [
        3103,
        3164
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The example below whitelists client addresses originating from inside of a virtual network, and blocks access to all other clients.",
      "pos": [
        3166,
        3297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network Access Control List Example",
      "pos": [
        3301,
        3336
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3372,
        3595
      ],
      "content": "Any applications running in App Service Environment in the same virtual network as the SQL Server will be able to connect to the SQL Server instance using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>VNet internal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> IP address for the SQL Server virtual machine."
    },
    {
      "content": "The example connection string below references the SQL Server using its private IP address.",
      "pos": [
        3599,
        3690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Although the virtual machine has a public endpoint as well, connection attempts using the public IP address will be rejected because of the network ACL.",
      "pos": [
        3805,
        3957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restricting Access With a Network Security Group",
      "pos": [
        3963,
        4011
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An alternative approach for securing access is with a network security group.",
      "pos": [
        4012,
        4089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network security groups can be applied to individual virtual machines, or to a subnet containing virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        4091,
        4205
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "First a network security group needs to be created:",
      "pos": [
        4207,
        4258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restricting access to only VNet internal traffic is very simple with a network security group.",
      "pos": [
        4418,
        4512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The default rules in a network security group only allow access from other network clients in the same virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        4514,
        4633
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result locking down access to SQL Server is as simple as applying a network security group with its default rules to either the virtual machines running SQL Server, or the subnet containing the virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        4635,
        4851
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The sample below applies a network security group to the containing subnet:",
      "pos": [
        4853,
        4928
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The end result is a set of security rules that block external access, while allowing VNet internal access:",
      "pos": [
        5086,
        5192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Default Network Security Rules",
      "pos": [
        5196,
        5226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting started",
      "pos": [
        5262,
        5277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get started with App Service Environments, see [Introduction to App Service Environment][IntroToAppServiceEnvironment]",
      "pos": [
        5279,
        5400
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For details around controlling inbound traffic to your App Service Environment, see [Controlling inbound traffic to an App Service Environment][ControlInboundASE]",
      "pos": [
        5402,
        5564
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about the Azure App Service platform, see [Azure App Service][AzureAppService].",
      "pos": [
        5566,
        5666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        7275,
        7279
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Securely Connecting to BackEnd Resources from an App Service Environment\" \n    description=\"Learn about how to securely connect to backend resources from an App Service Environment.\" \n    services=\"app-service\\web\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"ccompy\" \n    manager=\"wpickett\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"app-service-web\" \n    ms.workload=\"web\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"06/30/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"stefsh\"/>    \n\n# Securely Connecting to Backend Resources from an App Service Environment #\n\n## Overview ##\nSince an App Service Environment is always created in a subnet of a regional [virtual network][virtualnetwork], outbound connections from an App Service Environment to other backend resources can flow exclusively over the virtual network.  \n\nFor example, there may be a SQL Server running on a cluster of virtual machines with port 1433 locked down.  The endpoint may be ACLd to only allow access from other resources on the same virtual network.  \n\nAs another example, sensitive endpoints may run on-premises and be connected to Azure via either [Site-to-Site][SiteToSite] or [Azure ExpressRoute][ExpressRoute] connections.  As a result, only resources in virtual networks connected to the Site-to-Site or ExpressRoute tunnels will be able to access on-premises endpoints.\n\nFor all of these scenarios, apps running on an App Service Environment will be able to securely connect to the various servers and resources.  Outbound traffic from apps running in an App Service Environment to private endpoints in the same virtual network (or connected to the same virtual network), will only flow over the virtual network.  Outbound traffic to private endpoints will not flow over the public Internet.\n\n## Outbound Connectivity and DNS Requirements ##\nNote that for an App Service Environment to function properly, it requires outbound access to Azure Storage as well as Sql Database in the same Azure region.  If outbound Internet access is blocked in the virtual network, App Service Environments will not be able to access these Azure endpoints.\n\nCustomer may also have custom DNS servers configured in the virtual network.  App Service Environments need to be able to resolve Azure endpoints under *.database.windows.net, *.file.core.windows.net and *.blob.core.windows.net.  \n\nIt is also recommended that any custom DNS servers on the virtual network be setup ahead of time prior to creating an App Service Environment.  If a virtual network's DNS configuration is changed while an App Service Environment is being created, that will result in the App Service Environment creation process failing.\n\n## Connecting to a SQL Server\nA common SQL Server configuration has an endpoint listening on port 1433:\n\n![SQL Server Endpoint][SqlServerEndpoint]\n\nThere are two approaches for restricting traffic to this endpoint:\n\n\n- [Network Access Control Lists][NetworkAccessControlLists] (Network ACLs)\n\n- [Network Security Groups][NetworkSecurityGroups]\n\n\n## Restricting Access With a Network ACL\n\nPort 1433 can be secured using a network access control list.  The example below whitelists client addresses originating from inside of a virtual network, and blocks access to all other clients.\n\n![Network Access Control List Example][NetworkAccessControlListExample]\n\nAny applications running in App Service Environment in the same virtual network as the SQL Server will be able to connect to the SQL Server instance using the **VNet internal** IP address for the SQL Server virtual machine.  \n\nThe example connection string below references the SQL Server using its private IP address.\n\n    Server=tcp:10.0.1.6;Database=MyDatabase;User ID=MyUser;Password=PasswordHere;provider=System.Data.SqlClient\n\nAlthough the virtual machine has a public endpoint as well, connection attempts using the public IP address will be rejected because of the network ACL. \n\n## Restricting Access With a Network Security Group\nAn alternative approach for securing access is with a network security group.  Network security groups can be applied to individual virtual machines, or to a subnet containing virtual machines.\n\nFirst a network security group needs to be created:\n\n    New-AzureNetworkSecurityGroup -Name \"testNSGexample\" -Location \"South Central US\" -Label \"Example network security group for an app service environment\"\n\nRestricting access to only VNet internal traffic is very simple with a network security group.  The default rules in a network security group only allow access from other network clients in the same virtual network.\n\nAs a result locking down access to SQL Server is as simple as applying a network security group with its default rules to either the virtual machines running SQL Server, or the subnet containing the virtual machines.\n\nThe sample below applies a network security group to the containing subnet:\n\n    Get-AzureNetworkSecurityGroup -Name \"testNSGExample\" | Set-AzureNetworkSecurityGroupToSubnet -VirtualNetworkName 'testVNet' -SubnetName 'Subnet-1'\n    \nThe end result is a set of security rules that block external access, while allowing VNet internal access:\n\n![Default Network Security Rules][DefaultNetworkSecurityRules]\n\n\n## Getting started\n\nTo get started with App Service Environments, see [Introduction to App Service Environment][IntroToAppServiceEnvironment]\n\nFor details around controlling inbound traffic to your App Service Environment, see [Controlling inbound traffic to an App Service Environment][ControlInboundASE]\n\nFor more information about the Azure App Service platform, see [Azure App Service][AzureAppService].\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [app-service-web-whats-changed](../../includes/app-service-web-whats-changed.md)]\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [app-service-web-try-app-service](../../includes/app-service-web-try-app-service.md)]\n \n\n<!-- LINKS -->\n[virtualnetwork]: https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/virtual-networks-faq/\n[ControlInboundTraffic]:  http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/app-service-app-service-environment-control-inbound-traffic/\n[SiteToSite]: https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/vpn-gateway-site-to-site-create/\n[ExpressRoute]: http://azure.microsoft.com/services/expressroute/\n[NetworkAccessControlLists]: https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/virtual-networks-acl/\n[NetworkSecurityGroups]: https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/virtual-networks-nsg/\n[IntroToAppServiceEnvironment]:  http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/app-service-app-service-environment-intro/\n[AzureAppService]: http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/app-service-value-prop-what-is/ \n[ControlInboundASE]:  http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/app-service-app-service-environment-control-inbound-traffic/ \n\n<!-- IMAGES -->\n[SqlServerEndpoint]: ./media/app-service-app-service-environment-securely-connecting-to-backend-resources/SqlServerEndpoint01.png\n[NetworkAccessControlListExample]: ./media/app-service-app-service-environment-securely-connecting-to-backend-resources/NetworkAcl01.png\n[DefaultNetworkSecurityRules]: ./media/app-service-app-service-environment-securely-connecting-to-backend-resources/DefaultNetworkSecurityRules01.png \n\ntest\n"
}