{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "By default, all requests to mobile service resources are restricted to clients that present the application key, which does not strictly secure access to resources.",
      "pos": [
        2,
        166
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To secure your resources, you must restrict access to only authenticated clients.",
      "pos": [
        167,
        248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Visual Studio, open your mobile service project, expand the Controllers folder, and open <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>TodoItemController.cs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        253,
        371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>TodoItemController<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> class implements data access for the TodoItem table.",
      "pos": [
        372,
        451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add the following <ph id=\"ph1\">`using`</ph> statement:",
      "pos": [
        452,
        488
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        556,
        639
      ],
      "content": "Apply the following <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>AuthorizeLevel<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> attribute to the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>TodoItemController<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> class."
    },
    {
      "content": "This makes sure that all operations against the <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>TodoItem<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> table require an authenticated user.",
      "pos": [
        697,
        792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also apply the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>AuthorizeLevel<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> attribute at the method level.",
      "pos": [
        793,
        863
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        868,
        1035
      ],
      "content": "(Optional) If you wish to debug authentication locally, expand the <ph id=\"ph1\">`App_Start`</ph> folder, open <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WebApiConfig.cs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and add the following code to the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Register<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> method."
    },
    {
      "content": "This tells the local mobile service project to run as if it is being hosted in Azure, including honoring the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>AuthorizeLevel<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> settings.",
      "pos": [
        1078,
        1213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Without this setting, all HTTP requests to localhost are permitted without authentication despite the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>AuthorizeLevel<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> setting.",
      "pos": [
        1214,
        1341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you enable self-hosted mode, you also need to set a value for the local application key.",
      "pos": [
        1342,
        1435
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1440,
        1542
      ],
      "content": "(Optional) In the web.config project file, set a string value for the <ph id=\"ph1\">`MS_ApplicationKey`</ph> app setting."
    },
    {
      "content": "This is the password that you use (with no username) to test the API help pages when you run the service locally.",
      "pos": [
        1549,
        1662
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This string value is not used by the live site in Azure, and you do not need to use the actual application key; any valid string value will work.",
      "pos": [
        1664,
        1809
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Republish your project.",
      "pos": [
        1815,
        1838
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "\n\nBy default, all requests to mobile service resources are restricted to clients that present the application key, which does not strictly secure access to resources. To secure your resources, you must restrict access to only authenticated clients.\n\n1. In Visual Studio, open your mobile service project, expand the Controllers folder, and open **TodoItemController.cs**. The **TodoItemController** class implements data access for the TodoItem table. Add the following `using` statement:\n\n        using Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Mobile.Service.Security;\n\n2. Apply the following _AuthorizeLevel_ attribute to the **TodoItemController** class. \n\n        [AuthorizeLevel(AuthorizationLevel.User)]\n\n    This makes sure that all operations against the _TodoItem_ table require an authenticated user. You can also apply the *AuthorizeLevel* attribute at the method level.\n\n3. (Optional) If you wish to debug authentication locally, expand the `App_Start` folder, open **WebApiConfig.cs**, and add the following code to the **Register** method.  \n\n        config.SetIsHosted(true);\n\n    This tells the local mobile service project to run as if it is being hosted in Azure, including honoring the *AuthorizeLevel* settings. Without this setting, all HTTP requests to localhost are permitted without authentication despite the *AuthorizeLevel* setting. When you enable self-hosted mode, you also need to set a value for the local application key.\n\n4. (Optional) In the web.config project file, set a string value for the `MS_ApplicationKey` app setting. \n\n    This is the password that you use (with no username) to test the API help pages when you run the service locally.  This string value is not used by the live site in Azure, and you do not need to use the actual application key; any valid string value will work.\n \n4. Republish your project.\n"
}