{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement Troubleshooting Guide - APIs",
      "pos": [
        27,
        79
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Troubleshooting Guides for Azure Mobile Engagement - APIs",
      "pos": [
        98,
        155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Troubleshooting guide for API issues",
      "pos": [
        472,
        508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following are possible issues you may encounter with how administrators interact with Azure Mobile Engagement via the APIs.",
      "pos": [
        510,
        637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Syntax issues",
      "pos": [
        642,
        655
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Issue",
      "pos": [
        661,
        666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Syntax Errors using the API (or unexpected behavior).",
      "pos": [
        669,
        722
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Causes",
      "pos": [
        728,
        734
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Syntax issues:",
      "pos": [
        738,
        752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure to check the Syntax of the specific API you are using to confirm that the option is available.",
      "pos": [
        759,
        863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A common issue with API usage is to confuse the Reach API and the Push API (most tasks should be performed with the Reach API instead of the Push API).",
      "pos": [
        870,
        1021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Another common issue with SDK integration and API usage is to confuse the SDK Key and the API Key.",
      "pos": [
        1029,
        1127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scripts that connect to the APIs need to send data at least every 10 minutes or the connection will time out (especially common in Monitor API scripts listening for data).",
      "pos": [
        1134,
        1305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To prevent timeouts, have your script send an XMPP ping every 10 minutes to keep the session alive with the server.",
      "pos": [
        1306,
        1421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See also",
      "pos": [
        1427,
        1435
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[API Documentation][Link 4]",
      "pos": [
        1440,
        1467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "XMPP Protocol Info",
      "pos": [
        1471,
        1489
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Unable to use the API to perform the same action available in the Azure Mobile Engagement UI",
      "pos": [
        1539,
        1631
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Issue",
      "pos": [
        1637,
        1642
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An action that works from the Azure Mobile Engagement UI doesn't work from the related Azure Mobile Engagement API.",
      "pos": [
        1645,
        1760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Causes",
      "pos": [
        1766,
        1772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Confirming that you can perform the same action from the Azure Mobile Engagement UI shows that you have correctly integrated this feature of Azure Mobile Engagement with the SDK.",
      "pos": [
        1776,
        1954
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See also",
      "pos": [
        1960,
        1968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[UI Documentation][Link 1]",
      "pos": [
        1973,
        1999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Error Messages",
      "pos": [
        2005,
        2019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Issue",
      "pos": [
        2025,
        2030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Error codes using the API displayed at runtime or in logs.",
      "pos": [
        2033,
        2091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Causes",
      "pos": [
        2097,
        2103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is a composite list of common API status codes numbers for reference and preliminary troubleshooting:",
      "pos": [
        2107,
        2213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See also",
      "pos": [
        4974,
        4982
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[API Documentation - for detailed errors on each specific API][Link 4]",
      "pos": [
        4986,
        5056
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Silent failures",
      "pos": [
        5062,
        5077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Issue",
      "pos": [
        5083,
        5088
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "API action fails with no error message displayed at runtime or in logs.",
      "pos": [
        5091,
        5162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Causes",
      "pos": [
        5168,
        5174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Many items will be disabled in the Azure Mobile Engagement UI if they aren't integrated correctly, but will fail silently from the API, so remember to test the same functionality from the UI to see if it works.",
      "pos": [
        5178,
        5388
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement, and many advanced features of Azure Mobile Engagement you are attempting to use, need to be individually integrated into your app with the SDK as separate steps before you can use them.",
      "pos": [
        5391,
        5601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See also",
      "pos": [
        5607,
        5615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Troubleshooting Guide - SDK][Link 25]",
      "pos": [
        5619,
        5657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        7440,
        7444
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Azure Mobile Engagement Troubleshooting Guide - APIs\" \n   description=\"Troubleshooting Guides for Azure Mobile Engagement - APIs\" \n   services=\"mobile-engagement\" \n   documentationCenter=\"\" \n   authors=\"piyushjo\" \n   manager=\"dwrede\" \n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"mobile-engagement\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"mobile-multiple\"\n   ms.workload=\"mobile\" \n   ms.date=\"06/18/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"piyushjo\"/>\n\n# Troubleshooting guide for API issues\n\nThe following are possible issues you may encounter with how administrators interact with Azure Mobile Engagement via the APIs.\n\n## Syntax issues\n\n### Issue\n- Syntax Errors using the API (or unexpected behavior).\n\n### Causes\n\n- Syntax issues:\n    - Make sure to check the Syntax of the specific API you are using to confirm that the option is available.\n    - A common issue with API usage is to confuse the Reach API and the Push API (most tasks should be performed with the Reach API instead of the Push API). \n    - Another common issue with SDK integration and API usage is to confuse the SDK Key and the API Key.\n    - Scripts that connect to the APIs need to send data at least every 10 minutes or the connection will time out (especially common in Monitor API scripts listening for data). To prevent timeouts, have your script send an XMPP ping every 10 minutes to keep the session alive with the server.\n\n### See also\n \n- [API Documentation][Link 4]\n- [XMPP Protocol Info]( http://xmpp.org/extensions/xep-0199.html)\n \n## Unable to use the API to perform the same action available in the Azure Mobile Engagement UI\n\n### Issue\n- An action that works from the Azure Mobile Engagement UI doesn't work from the related Azure Mobile Engagement API.\n\n### Causes\n\n- Confirming that you can perform the same action from the Azure Mobile Engagement UI shows that you have correctly integrated this feature of Azure Mobile Engagement with the SDK.\n\n### See also\n \n- [UI Documentation][Link 1]\n \n## Error Messages\n\n### Issue\n- Error codes using the API displayed at runtime or in logs.\n\n### Causes\n\n- Here is a composite list of common API status codes numbers for reference and preliminary troubleshooting:\n\n        200        Success.\n        200        Account updated: device registered, associated, updated, or removed from the current account.\n        200        Returns a list of projects as a JSON object or an authentication token generated and returned in the response’s body.\n        201        Account created.\n        400        Invalid parameter or validation exception (check payload for details). The parameters provided to the API or service are invalid. In this case, the HTTP response will embed more details. Make sure to test for the MIME type of the response as the payload can either be plain text or a JSON object.\n        401        Authentication error. No user is currently authenticated or connected (check the AppID and SDK key).\n        402        Billing lock. The application is either off its quotas or is currently in a bad billing state.\n        403        The application is not enabled or the specific API is disabled for this application.\n        403        Unauthorized access to the project or application, invalid access key (the key must match the one provided when created).\n        403        Campaign specific errors: campaign must be finished (or has already been activated), the suspend action can only be performed on an scheduled campaign, cannot finish a campaign that is not currently “in progress”, campaign must be “in progress” and the campaign’s property named, manual Push must be set to true.\n        403        The email address is already associated to another account (a super user for instance). No authentication token will be generated.\n        404        Application, device, campaign, or project identifier not found.\n        404        Query parameter is invalid JSON or has a field with an unexpected value.\n        404        The email address is not associated with an account. Please create or update the account first.\n        405        Invalid HTTP method (GET, POST, etc.) or trying to edit a read only segment (i.e. add or update or delete a criterion). A segment becomes read only after it has been computed for the first time.\n        409        Name already associated to a different device ID or campaign.\n        413        Too many device identifiers (current limit is 1,000), POST URL encoded entity is over 2MB, or the period is too large to be displayed (the server didn’t retrieve the analytics because the user request is for a period that is too large).\n        503        Analytics not available yet (the requested information is not computed yet for an application).\n        504        The server was not able to handle your request in a reasonable time (if you make multiple calls to an API very quickly, try to make one call at a time and spread the calls out over time).\n\n### See also\n\n- [API Documentation - for detailed errors on each specific API][Link 4]\n \n## Silent failures\n\n### Issue\n- API action fails with no error message displayed at runtime or in logs.\n\n### Causes\n\n- Many items will be disabled in the Azure Mobile Engagement UI if they aren't integrated correctly, but will fail silently from the API, so remember to test the same functionality from the UI to see if it works.\n- Azure Mobile Engagement, and many advanced features of Azure Mobile Engagement you are attempting to use, need to be individually integrated into your app with the SDK as separate steps before you can use them.\n\n### See also\n\n- [Troubleshooting Guide - SDK][Link 25]\n \n<!--Link references-->\n[Link 1]: mobile-engagement-user-interface.md\n[Link 2]: mobile-engagement-troubleshooting-guide.md\n[Link 3]: mobile-engagement-how-tos.md\n[Link 4]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=525553\n[Link 5]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=525554\n[Link 6]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=525555\n[Link 7]: https://account.windowsazure.com/PreviewFeatures\n[Link 8]: https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/azure/en-US/home?forum=azuremobileengagement\n[Link 9]: http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/mobile-engagement/\n[Link 10]: http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/services/mobile-engagement/\n[Link 11]: http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/pricing/details/mobile-engagement/\n[Link 12]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-navigation.md\n[Link 13]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-home.md\n[Link 14]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-my-account.md\n[Link 15]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-analytics.md\n[Link 16]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-monitor.md\n[Link 17]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-reach.md\n[Link 18]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-segments.md\n[Link 19]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-dashboard.md\n[Link 20]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-settings.md\n[Link 21]: mobile-engagement-troubleshooting-guide-analytics.md\n[Link 22]: mobile-engagement-troubleshooting-guide-apis.md\n[Link 23]: mobile-engagement-troubleshooting-guide-push-reach.md\n[Link 24]: mobile-engagement-troubleshooting-guide-service.md\n[Link 25]: mobile-engagement-troubleshooting-guide-sdk.md\n[Link 26]: mobile-engagement-troubleshooting-guide-sr-info.md\n[Link 27]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-reach-campaign.md\n[Link 28]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-reach-criterion.md\n[Link 29]: mobile-engagement-user-interface-reach-content.md\n \ntest\n"
}