{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC Overview",
      "pos": [
        27,
        56
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Overview of Azure Automation Desired State Configuration (DSC), its terms, and known issues",
      "pos": [
        75,
        169
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC Overview",
      "pos": [
        491,
        520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Automation DSC is currently in limited preview<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and is not supported for production workloads.",
      "pos": [
        525,
        647
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is mostly cmdlet-based for now, and has a minimal graphical user interface.",
      "pos": [
        648,
        726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By signing up for Azure Automation DSC’s preview, you acknowledge that this feature is in Preview and subject to reduced or different service terms, as set forth in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>service agreement<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=389530&amp;clcid=0x409)</ept>, and that you agree to the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>preview supplemental terms<ept id=\"p2\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=247638&amp;clcid=0x409)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        727,
        1096
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While the service is currently free to use, pricing will be introduced in the future.",
      "pos": [
        1097,
        1182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is PowerShell DSC?",
      "pos": [
        1187,
        1210
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Desired State Configuration (DSC) is a new management platform in Windows PowerShell that enables management of configuration for physical hosts and virtual machines using a declarative PowerShell syntax.",
      "pos": [
        1214,
        1418
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DSC provides a set of Windows PowerShell language extensions, new Windows PowerShell cmdlets, and resources that you can use to declaratively specify how you want your software environment to be configured.",
      "pos": [
        1420,
        1626
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It also provides a means to maintain and manage existing configurations.",
      "pos": [
        1627,
        1699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Practical applications",
      "pos": [
        1705,
        1727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Following are some example scenarios where you can use built-in DSC resources to configure and manage a set of computers (also known as target nodes) in an automated way:",
      "pos": [
        1732,
        1902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enabling or disabling server roles and features",
      "pos": [
        1906,
        1953
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Managing registry settings",
      "pos": [
        1956,
        1982
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Managing files and directories",
      "pos": [
        1985,
        2015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting, stopping, and managing processes and services",
      "pos": [
        2018,
        2073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Managing groups and user accounts",
      "pos": [
        2076,
        2109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploying new software",
      "pos": [
        2112,
        2134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Managing environment variables",
      "pos": [
        2137,
        2167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Running Windows PowerShell scripts",
      "pos": [
        2170,
        2204
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Fixing a configuration that has drifted away from the desired state",
      "pos": [
        2207,
        2274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Discovering the actual configuration state on a given node",
      "pos": [
        2277,
        2335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition, you can create custom resources to configure the state of any application or system setting.",
      "pos": [
        2337,
        2442
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2445,
        2707
      ],
      "content": "For more details on PowerShell DSC, see: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configuration in a DevOps world - Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration<ept id=\"p1\">](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/powershell/archive/2013/11/01/configuration-in-a-devops-world-windows-powershell-desired-state-configuration.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Azure Automation DSC?",
      "pos": [
        2711,
        2740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC builds on top of the fundamentals introduced in PowerShell DSC to provide an even easier configuration management experience.",
      "pos": [
        2743,
        2889
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC brings the same management layer to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>PowerShell Desired State Configuration<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249912.aspx)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        2890,
        3040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "as Azure Automation offers for PowerShell scripting today.",
      "pos": [
        3048,
        3106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC allows you to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>author and manage PowerShell Desired State Configurations<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249918.aspx)</ept>, import <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>DSC Resources<ept id=\"p2\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn282125.aspx)</ept>, and generate DSC Node Configurations (MOF documents), all in the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        3108,
        3405
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These DSC items will be placed on the Azure Automation <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>DSC pull server<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249913.aspx)</ept> so that target nodes (such as physical and virtual machines) in the cloud or on-premises can pick them up, automatically conform to the desired state they specify, and report back on their compliance with the desired state to Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        3406,
        3775
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC Terms",
      "pos": [
        3891,
        3917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration",
      "pos": [
        3925,
        3938
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell DSC introduced a new concept called configurations.",
      "pos": [
        3943,
        4005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configurations allow you to define, via PowerShell syntax, the desired state of your environment.",
      "pos": [
        4006,
        4103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use DSC to configure your environment, first define a Windows PowerShell script block using the configuration keyword, then follow it with an identifier, then with braces ({}) to delimit the block.",
      "pos": [
        4104,
        4304
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "alt text",
      "pos": [
        4308,
        4316
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inside the configuration block you can define node configuration blocks that specify the desired configuration for a set of nodes (computers) in your environment that should be configured exactly the same.",
      "pos": [
        4364,
        4569
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this way, a node configuration represents a “role” for one or more nodes to assume.",
      "pos": [
        4570,
        4656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A node configuration block starts with the node keyword.",
      "pos": [
        4657,
        4713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Follow this keyword with the name of the role, which can be a variable or expression.",
      "pos": [
        4714,
        4799
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the role name, use braces {} to delimit the node configuration block.",
      "pos": [
        4800,
        4875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "alt text",
      "pos": [
        4879,
        4887
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inside the node configuration block, you can define resource blocks to configure specific DSC resources.",
      "pos": [
        4936,
        5040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A resource block starts with the name of the resource, followed by the identifier you want to specify for that block, then braces {} to delimit the block.",
      "pos": [
        5041,
        5195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "alt text",
      "pos": [
        5199,
        5207
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5255,
        5587
      ],
      "content": "For more detailed information about the configuration keyword, see: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Understanding Configuration Keyword in Desired State Configuration<ept id=\"p1\">]</ept><bpt id=\"p2\">(http://blogs.msdn.com/b/powershell/archive/2013/11/05/understanding-configuration-keyword-in-desired-state-configuration.aspx \"</bpt>Understanding Configuration Keyword in Desired State Configuration<ept id=\"p2\">\")</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Running (compiling) a DSC configuration will produce one or more DSC node configurations (MOF documents), which are what DSC nodes apply to comply with desired state.",
      "pos": [
        5589,
        5755
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC allows you to import, author, and compile DSC configurations in Azure Automation, similar to how runbooks can be imported, authored, and started in Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        5757,
        5943
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5945,
        6144
      ],
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx)</ept> for management of DSC configurations:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6231,
        6375
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> A configuration should contain only one configuration block, with the same name as the configuration, in Azure Automation DSC."
    },
    {
      "content": "Node Configuration",
      "pos": [
        6381,
        6399
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a DSC Configuration is compiled, one or more node configurations are produced depending on the Node blocks in the configuration.",
      "pos": [
        6404,
        6537
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A node configuration is the same as a “MOF,” or “configuration document” (if you are familiar with those PS DSC terms) and represents a “role,” such as webserver or worker, which desired state one or more nodes should assume.",
      "pos": [
        6538,
        6763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PS DSC nodes become aware of node configurations they should enact via either DSC push, or pull methods.",
      "pos": [
        6765,
        6869
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC relies on the DSC pull method, where nodes request node configurations they should apply from Azure Automation DSC pull server.",
      "pos": [
        6870,
        7018
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because the nodes make the request to Azure Automation DSC, nodes can be behind firewalls, have all inbound ports closed, etc. They only need outbound access to the Internet.",
      "pos": [
        7019,
        7193
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7195,
        7441
      ],
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx)</ept> for management of DSC node configurations: <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureAutomationDscNodeConfiguration`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Node",
      "pos": [
        7447,
        7451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A DSC node is any machine that has its configuration managed by DSC.",
      "pos": [
        7456,
        7524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This could be an Azure VM or an on-premises VM / physical host.",
      "pos": [
        7525,
        7588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Nodes enact node configurations to become and maintain compliance with the desired state they define, and also can report back to a reporting server on their configuration status and compliance.",
      "pos": [
        7589,
        7783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC makes onboarding of nodes for management by Azure Automation DSC easy, and allows changing of the node configuration assigned to each node server-side, so next time a node checks the server for instructions it will assume a different role and change how it is configured to match.",
      "pos": [
        7785,
        8086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Nodes also report their status and configuration compliance to Azure Automation DSC.",
      "pos": [
        8087,
        8171
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8173,
        8363
      ],
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx)</ept> for management of DSC nodes:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8404,
        8477
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">`Register-AzureAutomationDscNode`</ph> (used to onboard Azure v2 VMs as nodes)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8482,
        8550
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureAutomationDscOnboardingMetaconfig`</ph> (used to onboard Nodes)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8555,
        8641
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">`Set-AzureAutomationDscNode`</ph>  (used to set/update Node to Node Configuration mappings)"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8771,
        9024
      ],
      "content": "The <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureAutomationRegistrationInfo`</ph> cmdlet can be used to get the registration URL and key needed to onboard Azure classic VMs to an Azure Automation account, either via the Azure Automation DSC VM extension in the Azure portal, or via PowerShell."
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC VM extension:",
      "pos": [
        9027,
        9061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "alt text",
      "pos": [
        9065,
        9073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell:",
      "pos": [
        9122,
        9133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource",
      "pos": [
        11002,
        11010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DSC resources are building blocks that you can use to define a Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration (DSC) configuration.",
      "pos": [
        11014,
        11144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DSC comes with a set of built-in functionality for configuring resources such as files and folders, server features and roles, registry settings, environment variables, and services and processes.",
      "pos": [
        11145,
        11341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To learn about the full list of built-in DSC resources and how to use them, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Built-In Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration Resources<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249921.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11342,
        11543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DSC resources can also be imported as part of PowerShell Modules to extend the set of built-in DSC resources.",
      "pos": [
        11545,
        11654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Non-default resources will be pulled down by DSC nodes from the DSC pull server, if a node configuration the node is meant to enact contains references to those resources.",
      "pos": [
        11655,
        11826
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To learn how to create custom resources, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Build Custom Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration Resources<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249927.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11827,
        11997
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC ships with all the same built-in DSC resources as does PS DSC.",
      "pos": [
        11999,
        12082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additional resources can be added to Azure Automation DSC by importing PowerShell modules containing the resources into Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        12083,
        12220
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12222,
        12421
      ],
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx)</ept> for management of PowerShell modules:"
    },
    {
      "content": "Compilation Job",
      "pos": [
        12550,
        12565
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A compilation job in Azure Automation DSC is an instance of compilation of a configuration, to create one or more node configurations.",
      "pos": [
        12569,
        12703
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They are similar to Azure Automation runbook jobs, except that they do not actually perform any task except to create node configurations.",
      "pos": [
        12704,
        12842
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any node configurations created by a compilation job are automatically placed on the Azure Automation DSC pull server, and overwrite previous versions of node Configurations, if they existed for this Configuration.",
      "pos": [
        12843,
        13057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name of a node configuration produced by a compilation job takes the form of “&lt;Configuration-name&gt;.",
      "pos": [
        13058,
        13161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "”.",
      "pos": [
        13192,
        13194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, compiling the below configuration would produce a single node configuration called “MyConfiguration.webserver”",
      "pos": [
        13195,
        13318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "alt text",
      "pos": [
        13323,
        13331
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Just like runbooks, configurations can be published.",
      "pos": [
        13381,
        13446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is not related to putting DSC items onto the Azure Automation DSC pull server.",
      "pos": [
        13447,
        13530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Compilation jobs cause DSC items to be placed on the Azure Automation DSC pull server.",
      "pos": [
        13531,
        13617
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information on “publishing” in Azure Automation, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Publishing a Runbook<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn903765.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        13618,
        13753
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13756,
        13953
      ],
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx)</ept> for management of compilation jobs:"
    },
    {
      "content": "Gotchas / Known Issues:",
      "pos": [
        14095,
        14118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since Azure Automation DSC is in preview, the first time you use this feature you will need to sign up for it using the Azure PowerShell cmdlets or Azure preview portal.",
      "pos": [
        14124,
        14293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can sign up by calling the following two cmdlets:",
      "pos": [
        14294,
        14347
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        14513,
        14645
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Azure Automation DSC registration may take up to one hour to complete before the feature will become available for use."
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation DSC does not support partial or composite DSC configurations at this time.",
      "pos": [
        14649,
        14740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The latest version of WMF 5 must be installed for the PowerShell DSC agent for Windows to be able to communicate with Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        14744,
        14879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The PowerShell DSC agent for Linux does not support communicating with Azure Automation at this time.",
      "pos": [
        14880,
        14981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This should be updated soon.",
      "pos": [
        14982,
        15010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation does not support side by side use of PowerShell modules.",
      "pos": [
        15014,
        15087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means all configurations within an Automation account must work with the last version of a PowerShell module imported into that Automation account, and with any PowerShell DSC resources that module contains that the configuration uses.",
      "pos": [
        15088,
        15328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The traditional PowerShell DSC pull server expects module zips to be placed on the pull server in the format <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ModuleName_Version.zip”<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        15332,
        15469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation expects PowerShell modules to be imported with names in the form of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ModuleName.zip<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        15470,
        15574
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>this blog post<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/blog/2014/12/15/authoring-integration-modules-for-azure-automation/)</ept> for more info on the Integration Module format needed to import the module into Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        15575,
        15789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell modules that specify DSC resources side by side within the module, using the “version per folder” format, will not work in Azure Automation right now.",
      "pos": [
        15794,
        15955
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When importing a PowerShell modules into Azure Automation using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`New-AzureAutomationModule`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`Set-AzureAutomationModule`</ph> cmdlets, the module import is asynchronous.",
      "pos": [
        15959,
        16129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Even if the cmdlet returns successfully, that does not mean module import has succeeded.",
      "pos": [
        16130,
        16218
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To check if import has succeeded, use <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureAutomationModule –Name &lt;ModuleName&gt;`</ph> (make sure to get just this module, not all modules) and check that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ProvisioningState<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field of the module says succeeded.",
      "pos": [
        16219,
        16433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell modules imported into Azure Automation cannot contain .doc or .docx files.",
      "pos": [
        16437,
        16522
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some PowerShell modules containing DSC resources contain these files, for help purposes.",
      "pos": [
        16523,
        16611
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These files should be removed from modules, prior to import into Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        16612,
        16694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configurations in Azure Automation currently only support strings for parameter values.",
      "pos": [
        16698,
        16785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to pass something other than a string for the value of a parameter, pass the parameter value as a JSON string, and within the configuration use ConvertFrom-Json to convert the JSON string back to a non-string value.",
      "pos": [
        16786,
        17013
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a node is first registered with an Azure Automation account, or the node is changed to be mapped to a different node configuration server-side, it’s status will be compliant, even if the node’s status is not actually compliant with the node configuration it is now mapped to.",
      "pos": [
        17017,
        17297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the node sends its first report after registration or a node configuration mapping change, the node status can be trusted.",
      "pos": [
        17298,
        17426
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When onboarding an Azure VM for management with Azure Automation DSC using <ph id=\"ph1\">`Register-AzureAutomationDscNode`</ph>, <ph id=\"ph2\">`Set-AzureVMExtension`</ph>, or the Azure Automation DSC VM extension in the Azure preview portal, if registration fails with <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>The computer name was not specified and the configuration directory does not have any configuration files<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, this is a false alarm and the VM registration actually succeeded.",
      "pos": [
        17430,
        17837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Successful registration can be verified using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureAutomationDscNode`</ph> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        17838,
        17924
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When onboarding an Azure VM for management with Azure Automation DSC using <ph id=\"ph1\">`Register-AzureAutomationDscNode`</ph>, <ph id=\"ph2\">`Set-AzureVMExtension`</ph>, or the Azure Automation DSC VM extension in the Azure preview portal, it could take up to an hour for the VM to show up as a DSC node in Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        17928,
        18216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is due to the installation of Windows Management Framework 5.0 on the VM by the Azure VM DSC extension, which is required to onboard the VM to Azure Automation DSC.",
      "pos": [
        18217,
        18386
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DSC nodes onboarded to Azure Automation DSC will initially show a 'Compliant' status, even if they are not actually compliant with the DSC node configuration they are mapped to.",
      "pos": [
        18390,
        18567
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After a node performs its first pull and sends its first DSC report to Azure Automation DSC, the status of the node should be correct.",
      "pos": [
        18568,
        18702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        18704,
        18708
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Azure Automation DSC Overview\" \n   description=\"An Overview of Azure Automation Desired State Configuration (DSC), its terms, and known issues\" \n   services=\"automation\" \n   documentationCenter=\"dev-center-name\" \n   authors=\"coreyp-at-msft\" \n   manager=\"stevenka\" \n   editor=\"tysonn\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"automation\"\n   ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"powershell\"\n   ms.workload=\"TBD\" \n   ms.date=\"08/18/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"coreyp\"/>\n\n# Azure Automation DSC Overview #\n\n>[AZURE.IMPORTANT] **Azure Automation DSC is currently in limited preview**, and is not supported for production workloads. It is mostly cmdlet-based for now, and has a minimal graphical user interface. By signing up for Azure Automation DSC’s preview, you acknowledge that this feature is in Preview and subject to reduced or different service terms, as set forth in the [service agreement](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=389530&clcid=0x409), and that you agree to the [preview supplemental terms](https://go.microsoft.com/fwLink/p/?LinkID=247638&clcid=0x409). While the service is currently free to use, pricing will be introduced in the future.\n\n## What is PowerShell DSC? ##\nDesired State Configuration (DSC) is a new management platform in Windows PowerShell that enables management of configuration for physical hosts and virtual machines using a declarative PowerShell syntax.\n\nDSC provides a set of Windows PowerShell language extensions, new Windows PowerShell cmdlets, and resources that you can use to declaratively specify how you want your software environment to be configured. It also provides a means to maintain and manage existing configurations.\n\n### Practical applications ###\nFollowing are some example scenarios where you can use built-in DSC resources to configure and manage a set of computers (also known as target nodes) in an automated way:\n\n- Enabling or disabling server roles and features\n- Managing registry settings\n- Managing files and directories\n- Starting, stopping, and managing processes and services\n- Managing groups and user accounts\n- Deploying new software\n- Managing environment variables\n- Running Windows PowerShell scripts\n- Fixing a configuration that has drifted away from the desired state\n- Discovering the actual configuration state on a given node\n\nIn addition, you can create custom resources to configure the state of any application or system setting.\n\n\nFor more details on PowerShell DSC, see: [Configuration in a DevOps world - Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/powershell/archive/2013/11/01/configuration-in-a-devops-world-windows-powershell-desired-state-configuration.aspx)\n\n##What is Azure Automation DSC?##\nAzure Automation DSC builds on top of the fundamentals introduced in PowerShell DSC to provide an even easier configuration management experience. Azure Automation DSC brings the same management layer to [PowerShell Desired State Configuration](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249912.aspx) <link> as Azure Automation offers for PowerShell scripting today.\n\nAzure Automation DSC allows you to [author and manage PowerShell Desired State Configurations](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249918.aspx), import [DSC Resources](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn282125.aspx), and generate DSC Node Configurations (MOF documents), all in the cloud. These DSC items will be placed on the Azure Automation [DSC pull server](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249913.aspx) so that target nodes (such as physical and virtual machines) in the cloud or on-premises can pick them up, automatically conform to the desired state they specify, and report back on their compliance with the desired state to Azure Automation.\n\n> [AZURE.VIDEO microsoft-ignite-2015-heterogeneous-configuration-management-using-microsoft-azure-automation]\n\n## Azure Automation DSC Terms ##\n### Configuration ###\nPowerShell DSC introduced a new concept called configurations. Configurations allow you to define, via PowerShell syntax, the desired state of your environment. To use DSC to configure your environment, first define a Windows PowerShell script block using the configuration keyword, then follow it with an identifier, then with braces ({}) to delimit the block.\n\n![alt text](./media/automation-dsc-overview/AADSC_1.png)\n\nInside the configuration block you can define node configuration blocks that specify the desired configuration for a set of nodes (computers) in your environment that should be configured exactly the same. In this way, a node configuration represents a “role” for one or more nodes to assume. A node configuration block starts with the node keyword. Follow this keyword with the name of the role, which can be a variable or expression. After the role name, use braces {} to delimit the node configuration block.\n\n![alt text](./media/automation-dsc-overview/AADSC_2.png)\n \nInside the node configuration block, you can define resource blocks to configure specific DSC resources. A resource block starts with the name of the resource, followed by the identifier you want to specify for that block, then braces {} to delimit the block.\n\n![alt text](./media/automation-dsc-overview/AADSC_3.png)\n\nFor more detailed information about the configuration keyword, see: [Understanding Configuration Keyword in Desired State Configuration](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/powershell/archive/2013/11/05/understanding-configuration-keyword-in-desired-state-configuration.aspx \"Understanding Configuration Keyword in Desired State Configuration\")\n\nRunning (compiling) a DSC configuration will produce one or more DSC node configurations (MOF documents), which are what DSC nodes apply to comply with desired state.\n\nAzure Automation DSC allows you to import, author, and compile DSC configurations in Azure Automation, similar to how runbooks can be imported, authored, and started in Azure Automation.\n\nAzure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the [Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx) for management of DSC configurations:\n\n- `Get-AzureAutomationDscConfiguration`\n- `Import-AzureAutomationDscConfiguration`\n\n>[AZURE.IMPORTANT] A configuration should contain only one configuration block, with the same name as the configuration, in Azure Automation DSC. \n\n###Node Configuration###\n\nWhen a DSC Configuration is compiled, one or more node configurations are produced depending on the Node blocks in the configuration. A node configuration is the same as a “MOF,” or “configuration document” (if you are familiar with those PS DSC terms) and represents a “role,” such as webserver or worker, which desired state one or more nodes should assume.\n\nPS DSC nodes become aware of node configurations they should enact via either DSC push, or pull methods. Azure Automation DSC relies on the DSC pull method, where nodes request node configurations they should apply from Azure Automation DSC pull server. Because the nodes make the request to Azure Automation DSC, nodes can be behind firewalls, have all inbound ports closed, etc. They only need outbound access to the Internet.\n\nAzure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the [Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx) for management of DSC node configurations: `Get-AzureAutomationDscNodeConfiguration`\n\n\n###Node###\n\nA DSC node is any machine that has its configuration managed by DSC. This could be an Azure VM or an on-premises VM / physical host. Nodes enact node configurations to become and maintain compliance with the desired state they define, and also can report back to a reporting server on their configuration status and compliance.\n\nAzure Automation DSC makes onboarding of nodes for management by Azure Automation DSC easy, and allows changing of the node configuration assigned to each node server-side, so next time a node checks the server for instructions it will assume a different role and change how it is configured to match. Nodes also report their status and configuration compliance to Azure Automation DSC.\n\nAzure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the [Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx) for management of DSC nodes:\n\n-   `Get-AzureAutomationDscNode`  \n-   `Register-AzureAutomationDscNode` (used to onboard Azure v2 VMs as nodes)\n-   `Get-AzureAutomationDscOnboardingMetaconfig` (used to onboard Nodes)\n-   `Set-AzureAutomationDscNode`  (used to set/update Node to Node Configuration mappings)\n-   `Unregister-AzureAutomationDscNode`\n-   `Get-AzureAutomationDscNodeReport`\n-   `Export-AzureAutomationDscNodeReportContent`\n\nThe `Get-AzureAutomationRegistrationInfo` cmdlet can be used to get the registration URL and key needed to onboard Azure classic VMs to an Azure Automation account, either via the Azure Automation DSC VM extension in the Azure portal, or via PowerShell.\n\n\nAzure Automation DSC VM extension:\n\n![alt text](./media/automation-dsc-overview/AADSC_4.png)\n\n\nPowerShell:\n\n    # fill in correct values for your VM / Automation Account here\n    $VMName = \"\"\n    $ServiceName = \"\"\n    $AutomationAccountName = \"\"\n    $AutomationAccountResourceGroup = \"\"\n\n\n    # get Azure Automation DSC registration info\n    Switch-AzureMode AzureResourceManager\n\n    $Account = Get-AzureAutomationAccount -ResourceGroupName $AutomationAccountResourceGroup -Name $AutomationAccountName\n\n    $RegistrationInfo = $Account | Get-AzureAutomationRegistrationInfo\n\n\n    # use the DSC extension to onboard the VM for management with Azure Automation DSC\n    Switch-AzureMode AzureServiceManagement\n\n    $VM = Get-AzureVM -Name $VMName -ServiceName $ServiceName\n\n    $PublicConfiguration = ConvertTo-Json -Depth 8 @{\n        SasToken = \"\"\n        ModulesUrl = \"https://eus2oaasibizamarketprod1.blob.core.windows.net/automationdscpreview/RegistrationMetaConfig.zip\"\n        ConfigurationFunction = \"RegistrationMetaConfig.ps1\\RegistrationMetaConfig\"\n\n        # update these DSC agent configurations if these defaults are not what you want. \n        # See https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249922.aspx?f=255&MSPPError=-2147217396 for more details\n        Properties = @{\n            RegistrationKey = $RegistrationInfo.PrimaryKey\n            RegistrationUrl = $RegistrationInfo.Endpoint\n            NodeConfigurationName = \"configname.webserver\"\n            ConfigurationMode = \"ApplyAndMonitor\"\n            ConfigurationModeFrequencyMins = 15\n            RefreshFrequencyMins = 30\n           RebootNodeIfNeeded = $False\n           ActionAfterReboot = \"ContinueConfiguration\"\n           AllowModuleOverwrite = $False\n        }\n    } \n\n    $VM = Set-AzureVMExtension `\n        -VM $vm `\n        -Publisher Microsoft.Powershell `\n        -ExtensionName DSC `\n        -Version 1.9 `\n        -PublicConfiguration $PublicConfiguration\n\n    $VM | Update-AzureVM\n \n\n###Resource###\nDSC resources are building blocks that you can use to define a Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration (DSC) configuration. DSC comes with a set of built-in functionality for configuring resources such as files and folders, server features and roles, registry settings, environment variables, and services and processes. To learn about the full list of built-in DSC resources and how to use them, see [Built-In Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration Resources](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249921.aspx).\n\nDSC resources can also be imported as part of PowerShell Modules to extend the set of built-in DSC resources. Non-default resources will be pulled down by DSC nodes from the DSC pull server, if a node configuration the node is meant to enact contains references to those resources. To learn how to create custom resources, see [Build Custom Windows PowerShell Desired State Configuration Resources](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn249927.aspx).\n\nAzure Automation DSC ships with all the same built-in DSC resources as does PS DSC. Additional resources can be added to Azure Automation DSC by importing PowerShell modules containing the resources into Azure Automation.\n\nAzure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the [Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx) for management of PowerShell modules:\n\n- `New-AzureAutomationModule`\n- `Remove-AzureAutomationModule`\n- `Set-AzureAutomationModule`\n- `Get-AzureAutomationModule`\n\n###Compilation Job###\nA compilation job in Azure Automation DSC is an instance of compilation of a configuration, to create one or more node configurations. They are similar to Azure Automation runbook jobs, except that they do not actually perform any task except to create node configurations. Any node configurations created by a compilation job are automatically placed on the Azure Automation DSC pull server, and overwrite previous versions of node Configurations, if they existed for this Configuration. The name of a node configuration produced by a compilation job takes the form of “<Configuration-name>.<Node configuration-block-name>”. For example, compiling the below configuration would produce a single node configuration called “MyConfiguration.webserver”\n\n\n![alt text](./media/automation-dsc-overview/AADSC_5.png)\n\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] Just like runbooks, configurations can be published. This is not related to putting DSC items onto the Azure Automation DSC pull server. Compilation jobs cause DSC items to be placed on the Azure Automation DSC pull server. For more information on “publishing” in Azure Automation, see [Publishing a Runbook](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn903765.aspx).\n\n\nAzure Automation DSC currently provides the following cmdlets in the [Azure Resource Manager PowerShell module](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/mt244122.aspx) for management of compilation jobs:\n\n-   `Get-AzureAutomationDscCompilationJob`\n-   `Get-AzureAutomationDscCompilationJobOutput`\n-   `Start-AzureAutomationDscCompilationJob`\n\n##Gotchas / Known Issues:##\n\n- Since Azure Automation DSC is in preview, the first time you use this feature you will need to sign up for it using the Azure PowerShell cmdlets or Azure preview portal. You can sign up by calling the following two cmdlets:\n\n - `Register-AzureProvider –ProviderNamespace Microsoft.Automation`\n - `Register-AzureProviderFeature -FeatureName dsc -ProviderNamespace Microsoft.Automation` \n \n>[AZURE.NOTE] Azure Automation DSC registration may take up to one hour to complete before the feature will become available for use.\n\n- Azure Automation DSC does not support partial or composite DSC configurations at this time.\n\n- The latest version of WMF 5 must be installed for the PowerShell DSC agent for Windows to be able to communicate with Azure Automation. The PowerShell DSC agent for Linux does not support communicating with Azure Automation at this time. This should be updated soon.\n\n- Azure Automation does not support side by side use of PowerShell modules. This means all configurations within an Automation account must work with the last version of a PowerShell module imported into that Automation account, and with any PowerShell DSC resources that module contains that the configuration uses.\n\n- The traditional PowerShell DSC pull server expects module zips to be placed on the pull server in the format **ModuleName_Version.zip”**. Azure Automation expects PowerShell modules to be imported with names in the form of **ModuleName.zip**. See [this blog post](http://azure.microsoft.com/blog/2014/12/15/authoring-integration-modules-for-azure-automation/) for more info on the Integration Module format needed to import the module into Azure Automation. \n\n- PowerShell modules that specify DSC resources side by side within the module, using the “version per folder” format, will not work in Azure Automation right now.\n\n- When importing a PowerShell modules into Azure Automation using the `New-AzureAutomationModule` or `Set-AzureAutomationModule` cmdlets, the module import is asynchronous. Even if the cmdlet returns successfully, that does not mean module import has succeeded. To check if import has succeeded, use `Get-AzureAutomationModule –Name <ModuleName>` (make sure to get just this module, not all modules) and check that the **ProvisioningState** field of the module says succeeded.\n\n- PowerShell modules imported into Azure Automation cannot contain .doc or .docx files. Some PowerShell modules containing DSC resources contain these files, for help purposes. These files should be removed from modules, prior to import into Azure Automation.\n\n- Configurations in Azure Automation currently only support strings for parameter values. If you want to pass something other than a string for the value of a parameter, pass the parameter value as a JSON string, and within the configuration use ConvertFrom-Json to convert the JSON string back to a non-string value.\n\n- When a node is first registered with an Azure Automation account, or the node is changed to be mapped to a different node configuration server-side, it’s status will be compliant, even if the node’s status is not actually compliant with the node configuration it is now mapped to. After the node sends its first report after registration or a node configuration mapping change, the node status can be trusted.\n\n- When onboarding an Azure VM for management with Azure Automation DSC using `Register-AzureAutomationDscNode`, `Set-AzureVMExtension`, or the Azure Automation DSC VM extension in the Azure preview portal, if registration fails with **The computer name was not specified and the configuration directory does not have any configuration files**, this is a false alarm and the VM registration actually succeeded. Successful registration can be verified using the `Get-AzureAutomationDscNode` cmdlet.\n\n- When onboarding an Azure VM for management with Azure Automation DSC using `Register-AzureAutomationDscNode`, `Set-AzureVMExtension`, or the Azure Automation DSC VM extension in the Azure preview portal, it could take up to an hour for the VM to show up as a DSC node in Azure Automation. This is due to the installation of Windows Management Framework 5.0 on the VM by the Azure VM DSC extension, which is required to onboard the VM to Azure Automation DSC.\n\n- DSC nodes onboarded to Azure Automation DSC will initially show a 'Compliant' status, even if they are not actually compliant with the DSC node configuration they are mapped to. After a node performs its first pull and sends its first DSC report to Azure Automation DSC, the status of the node should be correct.\n\ntest\n"
}