{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "What are API Apps?",
      "pos": [
        28,
        46
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn why Azure App Service is the best platform for developing, publishing, and hosting RESTful APIs.",
      "pos": [
        66,
        168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What are API Apps?",
      "pos": [
        494,
        512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "API Apps provides a rich platform and ecosystem for building, hosting, consuming, and distributing APIs in the cloud and on-premises.",
      "pos": [
        514,
        647
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy your API as an API app and benefit from enterprise grade security, simple access control, hybrid and SaaS connectivity.",
      "pos": [
        648,
        774
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "automatic SDK generation, and seamless integration with <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Logic Apps<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        775,
        907
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        909,
        1058
      ],
      "content": "API Apps is part of <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure App Service<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service/app-service-value-prop-what-is.md)</ept>, which also includes Web Apps, Mobile Apps, and Logic Apps."
    },
    {
      "content": "Why API Apps?",
      "pos": [
        1137,
        1150
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "API Apps provides capabilities for developing, deploying, publishing, consuming and managing RESTful web APIs.",
      "pos": [
        1152,
        1262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service provides the following features available today in public preview:",
      "pos": [
        1263,
        1341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Easy consumption<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Integrated <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Swagger<ept id=\"p2\">](http://swagger.io/)</ept> support makes your APIs easily consumable by a variety of clients.",
      "pos": [
        1345,
        1475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The API Apps SDK can generate client code for your APIs in a variety of languages including C#, Java, and Javascript.",
      "pos": [
        1477,
        1594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Simple access control<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Built-in authentication services support Azure Active Directory or third-party services such as Facebook and Twitter.",
      "pos": [
        1598,
        1743
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can protect an API app fgrom unauthenticated access with no changes to your code.",
      "pos": [
        1744,
        1829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're familiar with the authentication services provided by <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Mobile Services<ept id=\"p1\">](../mobile-services-windows-dotnet-how-to-use-client-library.md#authentication)</ept>, API Apps builds on that framework and extends it to APIs hosted by API Apps.",
      "pos": [
        1830,
        2074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The App Service SDK also enables you to use a simplified syntax for authorization code.",
      "pos": [
        2076,
        2163
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Authentication for API apps and mobile apps in Azure App Service<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service/app-service-authentication-overview.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2164,
        2312
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2316,
        2635
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Easy connection to SaaS platforms<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Connector API apps<ept id=\"p2\">](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-biztalk-api-apps.md)</ept> in the Azure Marketplace are provided by Microsoft and third parties to simplify the code you write for interacting with SalesForce, Office 365, Twitter, Facebook, Dropbox, and many others."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2639,
        2805
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Integration with Logic Apps<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - API apps that you create can be consumed by <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>App Service Logic Apps<ept id=\"p2\">](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2813,
        3080
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Visual Studio integration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Dedicated tools in Visual Studio streamline the work of <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>creating<ept id=\"p2\">](app-service-dotnet-create-api-app.md)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>deploying<ept id=\"p3\">](app-service-dotnet-deploy-api-app.md)</ept>, <bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>debugging<ept id=\"p4\">](app-service-dotnet-remotely-debug-api-app)</ept>, and managing API apps."
    },
    {
      "content": "You can bring your existing API as-is: you don't have to change any of the code in your existing APIs to take advantage of API App features, just deploy your code to an API app.",
      "pos": [
        3082,
        3259
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use ASP.NET, Java, PHP, Node.js or Python for your APIs.",
      "pos": [
        3260,
        3324
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3326,
        3440
      ],
      "content": "API Apps additionally includes <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>features of App Service Web Apps<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-web/app-service-web-overview.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure API Management<ept id=\"p1\">](/services/api-management/)</ept> is a separate service that offers features such as endpoint consolidation and throttling.",
      "pos": [
        3443,
        3595
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use API Management with API Apps.",
      "pos": [
        3596,
        3637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "API Apps is currently in public preview.",
      "pos": [
        3641,
        3681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>App Service Web Apps<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-web/app-service-web-overview.md)</ept> is a Generally Available (GA) service designed for building and hosting secure mission-critical applications at global scale.",
      "pos": [
        3682,
        3878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are looking for a GA service for building your API today, Web Apps is a great option.",
      "pos": [
        3879,
        3971
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When API Apps goes GA, we'll provide a path for taking existing web apps and leveraging the additional features of API Apps.",
      "pos": [
        3972,
        4096
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "API Apps features available in the future",
      "pos": [
        4102,
        4143
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the near future, the API Apps platform will also create a rich ecosystem of APIs by making it easy to share your code:",
      "pos": [
        4145,
        4266
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Public and private marketplaces<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - The <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure Marketplace<ept id=\"p2\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/)</ept> will make it easy to find and deploy to your Azure subscription pre-packaged API apps developed by Microsoft and third parties.",
      "pos": [
        4272,
        4502
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "And you'll be able to package and publish your own API apps that you develop, so other developers can deploy them to their Azure subscriptions.",
      "pos": [
        4503,
        4646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you publish your APIs to the Azure Marketplace, you'll be able to make them visible only to other members of your organization.",
      "pos": [
        4647,
        4779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Automatic dependency deployment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Whenever you deploy an API app from the Marketplace to your Azure subscription, Azure will automatically deploy dependent API apps and create required resources.",
      "pos": [
        4784,
        4983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An API app package will specify the API apps that it depends on and the Azure resources that it requires.",
      "pos": [
        4984,
        5089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Automatic updates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - When you update the code for one of your API app packages that you've shared, you'll be able to push the update out to everyone who has installed and is running your API app.",
      "pos": [
        5093,
        5291
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will work for non-breaking changes and users who have opted-in to receiving updates.",
      "pos": [
        5292,
        5381
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Many of these features, such the public marketplace and automatic updates, are already available for API apps provided by Microsoft.",
      "pos": [
        5383,
        5515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "API Apps concepts",
      "pos": [
        5520,
        5537
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5544,
        5666
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Gateway<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - A web app that handles API administration functions and authentication for all API apps in a resource group."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Swagger<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - A framework for interactive documentation and discovery of a RESTful API, used by default in API apps.",
      "pos": [
        5670,
        5786
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>http://swagger.io/<ept id=\"p1\">](http://swagger.io/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5787,
        5854
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Connector<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - A type of API app that makes it easy to connect to SaaS platforms such as Salesforce and Office 365.",
      "pos": [
        5857,
        5973
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>What are connectors and BizTalk API apps<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-biztalk-api-apps.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5974,
        6112
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Trigger<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - A REST API that <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>logic apps<ept id=\"p2\">](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps.md)</ept> can call to initiate a workflow process when a certain condition is met.",
      "pos": [
        6115,
        6293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, an API app could provide a method that the logic app calls periodically to look for a certain phrase in a Twitter feed.",
      "pos": [
        6294,
        6426
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>API app triggers<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-api-dotnet-triggers.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6427,
        6508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Action<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - A REST API that <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>logic apps<ept id=\"p2\">](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps.md)</ept> can call to process data after a workflow has been started by a trigger.",
      "pos": [
        6511,
        6688
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, an API app could provide a method that the logic app calls to respond to a tweet found by the Twitter trigger.",
      "pos": [
        6689,
        6812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actions are API methods that are exposed by a Swagger API definition.",
      "pos": [
        6813,
        6882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting started",
      "pos": [
        6887,
        6902
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6904,
        7012
      ],
      "content": "To get started with API apps, follow the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create an API app tutorial<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-dotnet-create-api-app.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7014,
        7223
      ],
      "content": "To see a list of known issues with API apps, please refer to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>this MSDN forum post<ept id=\"p1\">](https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/en-US/7f8b42f2-ac0d-48b8-a35e-3b4934e1c25e/api-app-known-issues?forum=AzureAPIApps)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7225,
        7358
      ],
      "content": "For more information about the Azure App Service platform, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure App Service<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service/app-service-value-prop-what-is.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        7363,
        7367
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"What are API Apps?\" \n    description=\"Learn why Azure App Service is the best platform for developing, publishing, and hosting RESTful APIs.\" \n    services=\"app-service\\api\" \n    documentationCenter=\".net\" \n    authors=\"tdykstra\" \n    manager=\"wpickett\" \n    editor=\"jimbe\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"app-service-api\" \n    ms.workload=\"web\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"07/30/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"tdykstra\"/>\n\n# What are API Apps?\n\nAPI Apps provides a rich platform and ecosystem for building, hosting, consuming, and distributing APIs in the cloud and on-premises. Deploy your API as an API app and benefit from enterprise grade security, simple access control, hybrid and SaaS connectivity. automatic SDK generation, and seamless integration with [Logic Apps](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps.md).\n\nAPI Apps is part of [Azure App Service](../app-service/app-service-value-prop-what-is.md), which also includes Web Apps, Mobile Apps, and Logic Apps. \n\n![](./media/app-service-api-apps-why-best-platform/appservicesuite.png)\n\n## Why API Apps?\n\nAPI Apps provides capabilities for developing, deploying, publishing, consuming and managing RESTful web APIs. App Service provides the following features available today in public preview:\n\n- **Easy consumption** - Integrated [Swagger](http://swagger.io/) support makes your APIs easily consumable by a variety of clients.  The API Apps SDK can generate client code for your APIs in a variety of languages including C#, Java, and Javascript.\n\n- **Simple access control** - Built-in authentication services support Azure Active Directory or third-party services such as Facebook and Twitter. You can protect an API app fgrom unauthenticated access with no changes to your code. If you're familiar with the authentication services provided by [Azure Mobile Services](../mobile-services-windows-dotnet-how-to-use-client-library.md#authentication), API Apps builds on that framework and extends it to APIs hosted by API Apps.  The App Service SDK also enables you to use a simplified syntax for authorization code. For more information, see [Authentication for API apps and mobile apps in Azure App Service](../app-service/app-service-authentication-overview.md).\n\n- **Easy connection to SaaS platforms** - [Connector API apps](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-biztalk-api-apps.md) in the Azure Marketplace are provided by Microsoft and third parties to simplify the code you write for interacting with SalesForce, Office 365, Twitter, Facebook, Dropbox, and many others.\n\n- **Integration with Logic Apps** - API apps that you create can be consumed by [App Service Logic Apps](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps.md).    \n\n- **Visual Studio integration** - Dedicated tools in Visual Studio streamline the work of [creating](app-service-dotnet-create-api-app.md), [deploying](app-service-dotnet-deploy-api-app.md), [debugging](app-service-dotnet-remotely-debug-api-app), and managing API apps.\n\nYou can bring your existing API as-is: you don't have to change any of the code in your existing APIs to take advantage of API App features, just deploy your code to an API app. You can use ASP.NET, Java, PHP, Node.js or Python for your APIs.\n\nAPI Apps additionally includes [features of App Service Web Apps](../app-service-web/app-service-web-overview.md).\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] [Azure API Management](/services/api-management/) is a separate service that offers features such as endpoint consolidation and throttling. You can use API Management with API Apps.\n>\n>API Apps is currently in public preview. [App Service Web Apps](../app-service-web/app-service-web-overview.md) is a Generally Available (GA) service designed for building and hosting secure mission-critical applications at global scale. If you are looking for a GA service for building your API today, Web Apps is a great option. When API Apps goes GA, we'll provide a path for taking existing web apps and leveraging the additional features of API Apps.\n\n### API Apps features available in the future\n\nIn the near future, the API Apps platform will also create a rich ecosystem of APIs by making it easy to share your code:  \n\n- **Public and private marketplaces** - The [Azure Marketplace](http://azure.microsoft.com/marketplace/) will make it easy to find and deploy to your Azure subscription pre-packaged API apps developed by Microsoft and third parties. And you'll be able to package and publish your own API apps that you develop, so other developers can deploy them to their Azure subscriptions. When you publish your APIs to the Azure Marketplace, you'll be able to make them visible only to other members of your organization. \n\n- **Automatic dependency deployment** - Whenever you deploy an API app from the Marketplace to your Azure subscription, Azure will automatically deploy dependent API apps and create required resources. An API app package will specify the API apps that it depends on and the Azure resources that it requires.\n\n- **Automatic updates** - When you update the code for one of your API app packages that you've shared, you'll be able to push the update out to everyone who has installed and is running your API app. This will work for non-breaking changes and users who have opted-in to receiving updates.\n\nMany of these features, such the public marketplace and automatic updates, are already available for API apps provided by Microsoft.\n\n## API Apps concepts ##\n\n- **Gateway** - A web app that handles API administration functions and authentication for all API apps in a resource group. \n- **Swagger** - A framework for interactive documentation and discovery of a RESTful API, used by default in API apps. For more information, see [http://swagger.io/](http://swagger.io/).\n- **Connector** - A type of API app that makes it easy to connect to SaaS platforms such as Salesforce and Office 365. For more information, see [What are connectors and BizTalk API apps](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-biztalk-api-apps.md).\n- **Trigger** - A REST API that [logic apps](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps.md) can call to initiate a workflow process when a certain condition is met. For example, an API app could provide a method that the logic app calls periodically to look for a certain phrase in a Twitter feed. For more information, see [API app triggers](app-service-api-dotnet-triggers.md).\n- **Action** - A REST API that [logic apps](../app-service-logic/app-service-logic-what-are-logic-apps.md) can call to process data after a workflow has been started by a trigger. For example, an API app could provide a method that the logic app calls to respond to a tweet found by the Twitter trigger. Actions are API methods that are exposed by a Swagger API definition.\n\n## Getting started\n\nTo get started with API apps, follow the [Create an API app tutorial](app-service-dotnet-create-api-app.md).\n\nTo see a list of known issues with API apps, please refer to [this MSDN forum post](https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/en-US/7f8b42f2-ac0d-48b8-a35e-3b4934e1c25e/api-app-known-issues?forum=AzureAPIApps).\n\nFor more information about the Azure App Service platform, see [Azure App Service](../app-service/app-service-value-prop-what-is.md).\n\n \n\ntest\n"
}