{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Government Overview",
      "pos": [
        27,
        52
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article provides an overview of the Azure Government Cloud capabilities and the trustworthy design and security used to support compliance applicable to federal, state, and local government organizations and their partners.",
      "pos": [
        71,
        299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Azure Government Overview",
      "pos": [
        624,
        659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Azure Government is a physically and network isolated instance of Microsoft Azure.",
      "pos": [
        666,
        758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This overview will provide an introduction to the environment and services as well as links to additional information.",
      "pos": [
        760,
        878
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        884,
        915
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"Overview\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Overview"
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Government is a government-community cloud (GCC) designed to support strategic government scenarios that require speed, scale, security, compliance and economics for U.S.",
      "pos": [
        917,
        1093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "government organizations.",
      "pos": [
        1094,
        1119
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It was developed based on Microsoft’s extensive experience delivering software, security, compliance, and controls in other Microsoft cloud offerings such as Azure public, Office 365, O365 GCC, Microsoft CRM Online etc.",
      "pos": [
        1122,
        1341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition, Azure Government is designed to meet the higher level security and compliance needs for sensitive, dedicated, U.S.",
      "pos": [
        1344,
        1471
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Public Sector workloads found in regulations such as United States Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP), Department of Defense Enterprise Cloud Service Broker (ECSB), Criminal Justice Information Services (CJIS) Security Policy and Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).",
      "pos": [
        1472,
        1787
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Below is a summary view of the Azure Government Cloud infrastructure, fabric, services and frameworks that are available to help government organizations build hybrid cloud solutions to meet their goals.",
      "pos": [
        1794,
        1997
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As some services below are only available in preview, please see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>regions page<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/regions/#services)</ept> as the most up to date services that are generally available are listed.",
      "pos": [
        1999,
        2201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][2]",
      "pos": [
        2203,
        2209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Government includes the core components of Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) and Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS).",
      "pos": [
        2211,
        2328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This includes infrastructure, network, storage, data management, identity management and many other services.",
      "pos": [
        2330,
        2439
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Government supports the same great features that public Azure customers have leveraged like Geo-Synchronous data replication and auto scaling.",
      "pos": [
        2441,
        2589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft has been identified as the leader in both <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"https://www.gartner.com/doc/2575715/magic-quadrant-cloud-infrastructure-service\" target=\"_new\"&gt;</ph>IaaS<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;a href=\"https://www.gartner.com/doc/2645317/magic-quadrant-enterprise-application-platform\" target=\"_new\"&gt;</ph>PaaS<ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;a/&gt;</ph> by leading industry analysts.",
      "pos": [
        2590,
        2904
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition to providing the robust services and features of public Azure, Azure Government provides a number of features to assure US government entities that their data is secure by providing:",
      "pos": [
        2906,
        3100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Physical and network-isolated instance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The Azure Government environment is a completely separate instance from Microsoft Azure public and only used by qualified U.S.",
      "pos": [
        3104,
        3275
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "government organizations and solution providers.",
      "pos": [
        3276,
        3324
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3328,
        3565
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Security, Privacy &amp; Compliance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Microsoft has implemented its robust security, privacy, and compliance controls framework plus additional stringent controls to meet the higher level requirements found in ECSB Impact Levels and CJIS."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data Storage<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The Azure Government environment maintains 2 datacenters over 500 miles apart.",
      "pos": [
        3570,
        3667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All customer managed data is stored within the Continental United States (CONUS) datacenters",
      "pos": [
        3668,
        3760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>U.S. Personnel<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – All Azure Government operators and administrators are screened U.S.",
      "pos": [
        3764,
        3852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "citizens.",
      "pos": [
        3853,
        3862
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3866,
        4001
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Identity Management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Identity Management within the Azure Government environment is a separate instance of Azure Active Directory."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Compliance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Microsoft is continuously investing to meet and maintain rigorous and changing federal, state, and local compliance requirements such as FedRAMP, CJIS, ECSB, and HIPAA for U.S.",
      "pos": [
        4005,
        4198
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "government cloud solutions.",
      "pos": [
        4199,
        4226
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4231,
        4440
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud Integration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Azure Government provides an integrated environment with O365 Government allowing for a single sign-on across cloud services and enhanced services such as 1TB of OneDrive storage space."
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Government also enables organizations to maintain their existing technology investments and realize the benefits of cloud services.",
      "pos": [
        4442,
        4579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since Azure Government is an interoperable cloud platform, with products and technologies organizations can build applications that are more open from the ground up.",
      "pos": [
        4581,
        4746
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Agencies can choose the tools, services, operating system, architecture, and frameworks including Windows, Linux, Oracle, SharePoint, .NET, Java, PHP and Node.js, for their cloud solutions.",
      "pos": [
        4748,
        4937
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The flexibility of the Azure Government platform allows for new forms of cross-agency collaboration, application development, and integration.",
      "pos": [
        4938,
        5080
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "U.S.",
      "pos": [
        5084,
        5088
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "government organizations interested in cloud services can be confident that Azure Government provides enormous scale and rigorous security practices to meet their evolving needs.",
      "pos": [
        5089,
        5267
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5279,
        5361
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"Features\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> Features currently available in Microsoft Azure Government"
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Government currently has the following services available in both US GOV IOWA and US GOV VIRGINIA regions:",
      "pos": [
        5362,
        5474
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual Machines",
      "pos": [
        5478,
        5494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cloud Services",
      "pos": [
        5497,
        5511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage",
      "pos": [
        5514,
        5521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        5524,
        5540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduler",
      "pos": [
        5543,
        5552
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual Networking",
      "pos": [
        5555,
        5573
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Database",
      "pos": [
        5576,
        5588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Files",
      "pos": [
        5591,
        5602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Media Services",
      "pos": [
        5605,
        5619
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traffic Manager",
      "pos": [
        5622,
        5637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Bus",
      "pos": [
        5640,
        5651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StorSimple",
      "pos": [
        5654,
        5664
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Other services are available, and more services will be added on a continuous basis.",
      "pos": [
        5666,
        5750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the most current list of services, please see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>regions page<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/regions/#services)</ept> which will highlight each available region and their services.",
      "pos": [
        5752,
        5929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Currently, US GOV Iowa and US GOV Virginia are the data centers supporting Azure Government.",
      "pos": [
        5933,
        6025
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please refer to the regions page above for current data centers and services available.",
      "pos": [
        6027,
        6114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">\n\n## &lt;a name=\"next\"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Next steps\n\nIf you are interested in learning more and about Azure Government please leverage some of the links below.",
      "pos": [
        6232,
        6374
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "- **<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;A href=\"http://azure.com/gov\"&gt;</ph>Acquiring and accessing Azure Government<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>**\n\n- **<ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;A href=\"/azure-government-developer-guide\"&gt;</ph>Azure Government Developer Guide<ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>**",
      "pos": [
        6376,
        6545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        7135,
        7139
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Azure Government Overview\" \n   description=\"This article provides an overview of the Azure Government Cloud capabilities and the trustworthy design and security used to support compliance applicable to federal, state, and local government organizations and their partners. \" \n   services=\"Azure-Government\" \n   documentationCenter=\"\" \n   authors=\"joharve2\" \n   manager=\"chrisnie\" \n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"multiple\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"azure-government\" \n   ms.date=\"07/22/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"john.harvey@microsoft.com\"/>\n\n#  Microsoft Azure Government Overview \n\n<p> Microsoft Azure Government is a physically and network isolated instance of Microsoft Azure.  This overview will provide an introduction to the environment and services as well as links to additional information.\n\n\n## <a name=\"Overview\"></a>Overview\n\nAzure Government is a government-community cloud (GCC) designed to support strategic government scenarios that require speed, scale, security, compliance and economics for U.S. government organizations.   It was developed based on Microsoft’s extensive experience delivering software, security, compliance, and controls in other Microsoft cloud offerings such as Azure public, Office 365, O365 GCC, Microsoft CRM Online etc. \n\nIn addition, Azure Government is designed to meet the higher level security and compliance needs for sensitive, dedicated, U.S. Public Sector workloads found in regulations such as United States Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP), Department of Defense Enterprise Cloud Service Broker (ECSB), Criminal Justice Information Services (CJIS) Security Policy and Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).     \n\nBelow is a summary view of the Azure Government Cloud infrastructure, fabric, services and frameworks that are available to help government organizations build hybrid cloud solutions to meet their goals.  As some services below are only available in preview, please see the [regions page](http://azure.microsoft.com/regions/#services) as the most up to date services that are generally available are listed.\n\n![][2]\n\nAzure Government includes the core components of Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) and Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS).  This includes infrastructure, network, storage, data management, identity management and many other services.  Azure Government supports the same great features that public Azure customers have leveraged like Geo-Synchronous data replication and auto scaling. Microsoft has been identified as the leader in both <a href=\"https://www.gartner.com/doc/2575715/magic-quadrant-cloud-infrastructure-service\" target=\"_new\">IaaS</a> and <a href=\"https://www.gartner.com/doc/2645317/magic-quadrant-enterprise-application-platform\" target=\"_new\">PaaS<a/> by leading industry analysts.\n\nIn addition to providing the robust services and features of public Azure, Azure Government provides a number of features to assure US government entities that their data is secure by providing:\n\n- **Physical and network-isolated instance** – The Azure Government environment is a completely separate instance from Microsoft Azure public and only used by qualified U.S. government organizations and solution providers.\n\n- **Security, Privacy & Compliance** - Microsoft has implemented its robust security, privacy, and compliance controls framework plus additional stringent controls to meet the higher level requirements found in ECSB Impact Levels and CJIS. \n\n- **Data Storage** – The Azure Government environment maintains 2 datacenters over 500 miles apart. All customer managed data is stored within the Continental United States (CONUS) datacenters\n\n- **U.S. Personnel** – All Azure Government operators and administrators are screened U.S. citizens.\n\n- **Identity Management** – Identity Management within the Azure Government environment is a separate instance of Azure Active Directory.\n\n- **Compliance** – Microsoft is continuously investing to meet and maintain rigorous and changing federal, state, and local compliance requirements such as FedRAMP, CJIS, ECSB, and HIPAA for U.S. government cloud solutions. \n\n- **Cloud Integration** – Azure Government provides an integrated environment with O365 Government allowing for a single sign-on across cloud services and enhanced services such as 1TB of OneDrive storage space.\n\nAzure Government also enables organizations to maintain their existing technology investments and realize the benefits of cloud services.  Since Azure Government is an interoperable cloud platform, with products and technologies organizations can build applications that are more open from the ground up.  Agencies can choose the tools, services, operating system, architecture, and frameworks including Windows, Linux, Oracle, SharePoint, .NET, Java, PHP and Node.js, for their cloud solutions. The flexibility of the Azure Government platform allows for new forms of cross-agency collaboration, application development, and integration.  \n\nU.S. government organizations interested in cloud services can be confident that Azure Government provides enormous scale and rigorous security practices to meet their evolving needs. \n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n## <a name=\"Features\"></a> Features currently available in Microsoft Azure Government\nAzure Government currently has the following services available in both US GOV IOWA and US GOV VIRGINIA regions:\n\n- Virtual Machines\n- Cloud Services\n- Storage\n- Active Directory\n- Scheduler\n- Virtual Networking\n- SQL Database\n- Azure Files\n- Media Services\n- Traffic Manager\n- Service Bus\n- StorSimple\n\nOther services are available, and more services will be added on a continuous basis.  For the most current list of services, please see the [regions page](http://azure.microsoft.com/regions/#services) which will highlight each available region and their services.  \n\nCurrently, US GOV Iowa and US GOV Virginia are the data centers supporting Azure Government.  Please refer to the regions page above for current data centers and services available.\n\n<!--Every topic should have next steps and links to the next logical set of content to keep the customer engaged -->\n\n## <a name=\"next\"></a>Next steps\n\nIf you are interested in learning more and about Azure Government please leverage some of the links below.\n\n- **<A href=\"http://azure.com/gov\">Acquiring and accessing Azure Government</a>**\n\n- **<A href=\"/azure-government-developer-guide\">Azure Government Developer Guide</a>**\n\n<!--- **<A href=\"/azure-government-service-description\">Azure Government Service Descriptions</a>**-->\n\n\n\n\n<!-- Images. -->\n\n[1]: ./media/azure-government-developer-guide/publisherguide.png\n[2]: ./media/azure-government-overview/azure-gov-overview.jpg\n\n<!--Link references-->\n[Link 1 to another azure.microsoft.com documentation topic]: virtual-machines/virtual-machines-windows-tutorial.md\n[Link 2 to another azure.microsoft.com documentation topic]: app-service-web/web-sites-custom-domain-name.md\n[Link 3 to another azure.microsoft.com documentation topic]: storage-whatis-account.md\n\ntest\n"
}