{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Finalize your recovered Azure SQL Database",
      "pos": [
        26,
        68
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Point in Time Restore, Microsoft Azure SQL Database, restore database, recover database, Azure Management Portal, Azure portal",
      "pos": [
        86,
        212
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Finalize your recovered Azure SQL Database",
      "pos": [
        517,
        559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        564,
        572
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article provides a checklist of tasks that you need to go through before putting a newly recovered Azure SQL Database back into production.",
      "pos": [
        574,
        718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This checklist applies to databases recovered from Geo-Replication failover, Deleted Database Restore, Point-in-Time Restore, or Geo-Restore.",
      "pos": [
        719,
        860
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update Connection Strings",
      "pos": [
        865,
        890
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify connection strings of your application are pointing to the newly recovered database.",
      "pos": [
        892,
        983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update your connection strings if one of the below situations applies:",
      "pos": [
        984,
        1054
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The recovered database uses a different name from the source database name",
      "pos": [
        1060,
        1134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The recovered database is on a different server from the source server",
      "pos": [
        1139,
        1209
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1211,
        1509
      ],
      "content": "For more information about changing connection strings, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Guidelines for Connecting to Azure SQL Database Programmatically<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee336282.aspx)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Connections to Azure SQL Database: Central Recommendations <ept id=\"p2\">](sql-database-connect-central-recommendations.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Modify Firewall Rules",
      "pos": [
        1515,
        1536
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify the firewall rules at server-level and database-level, and make sure connections from your client computers or Azure to the server and the newly recovered database are enabled.",
      "pos": [
        1537,
        1720
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure SQL Database Firewall<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee621782.aspx)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>How to: Configure Firewall Settings (Azure SQL Database)<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj553530.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1721,
        1952
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify Server Logins and Database Users",
      "pos": [
        1957,
        1996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify if all the logins used by your application exist on the server which is hosting your recovered database.",
      "pos": [
        1998,
        2109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Re-create the missing logins and grant them appropriate permissions on the recovered database.",
      "pos": [
        2110,
        2204
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Managing Databases and Logins in Azure SQL Database<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee336235.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2205,
        2341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify if each database users in the recovered database is associated with a valid server login.",
      "pos": [
        2343,
        2439
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use ALTER USER statement to map user to valid server login.",
      "pos": [
        2440,
        2499
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ALTER USER<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=397486)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2500,
        2586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Setup Telemetry Alerts",
      "pos": [
        2593,
        2615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify if your existing alert rule settings are map to your recovered database.",
      "pos": [
        2617,
        2696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Update the setting if one of below situations applies:",
      "pos": [
        2697,
        2751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The recovered database uses a different name from the source database name",
      "pos": [
        2757,
        2831
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The recovered database is on a different server from the source server",
      "pos": [
        2836,
        2906
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2908,
        3087
      ],
      "content": "For more information about database alert rules, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Receive Alert Notifications and Manage Alert Rules in Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn306638.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Enable Auditing",
      "pos": [
        3093,
        3108
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If auditing is required to access your database, you need to enable Auditing after the database recovery.",
      "pos": [
        3110,
        3215
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A good indicator of auditing is required is that client applications use secure connection strings in a pattern of *.database.secure.windows.net.",
      "pos": [
        3216,
        3361
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get started with SQL database auditing<ept id=\"p1\">](sql-database-auditing-get-started.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3362,
        3467
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Finalize your recovered Azure SQL Database\"\n   description=\"Point in Time Restore, Microsoft Azure SQL Database, restore database, recover database, Azure Management Portal, Azure portal\"\n   services=\"sql-database\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"elfisher\"\n   manager=\"jeffreyg\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"sql-database\"\n   ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"storage-backup-recovery\"\n   ms.date=\"07/30/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"elfish\"/>\n\n# Finalize your recovered Azure SQL Database\n\n## Overview\n\nThis article provides a checklist of tasks that you need to go through before putting a newly recovered Azure SQL Database back into production. This checklist applies to databases recovered from Geo-Replication failover, Deleted Database Restore, Point-in-Time Restore, or Geo-Restore.\n\n## Update Connection Strings\n\nVerify connection strings of your application are pointing to the newly recovered database. Update your connection strings if one of the below situations applies:\n\n  + The recovered database uses a different name from the source database name\n  + The recovered database is on a different server from the source server\n\nFor more information about changing connection strings, see [Guidelines for Connecting to Azure SQL Database Programmatically](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee336282.aspx) and [Connections to Azure SQL Database: Central Recommendations ](sql-database-connect-central-recommendations.md).\n \n## Modify Firewall Rules\nVerify the firewall rules at server-level and database-level, and make sure connections from your client computers or Azure to the server and the newly recovered database are enabled. For more information, see [Azure SQL Database Firewall](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee621782.aspx) and [How to: Configure Firewall Settings (Azure SQL Database)](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj553530.aspx).\n\n## Verify Server Logins and Database Users\n\nVerify if all the logins used by your application exist on the server which is hosting your recovered database. Re-create the missing logins and grant them appropriate permissions on the recovered database. For more information, see [Managing Databases and Logins in Azure SQL Database](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee336235.aspx).\n\nVerify if each database users in the recovered database is associated with a valid server login. Use ALTER USER statement to map user to valid server login. For more information, see [ALTER USER](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=397486). \n\n\n## Setup Telemetry Alerts\n\nVerify if your existing alert rule settings are map to your recovered database. Update the setting if one of below situations applies:\n\n  + The recovered database uses a different name from the source database name\n  + The recovered database is on a different server from the source server\n\nFor more information about database alert rules, see [How to: Receive Alert Notifications and Manage Alert Rules in Azure](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn306638.aspx).\n\n\n## Enable Auditing\n\nIf auditing is required to access your database, you need to enable Auditing after the database recovery. A good indicator of auditing is required is that client applications use secure connection strings in a pattern of *.database.secure.windows.net. For more information, see [Get started with SQL database auditing](sql-database-auditing-get-started.md). \n \n"
}