{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Application Scenarios and Design with Service Fabric",
      "pos": [
        27,
        79
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Categories of applications.",
      "pos": [
        98,
        125
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application design using stateful and stateless services",
      "pos": [
        126,
        182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric Application Scenarios",
      "pos": [
        484,
        520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Azure Service Fabric offers a reliable and flexible platform that enables you to write and run many types of business applications and services.",
      "pos": [
        522,
        676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These applications and microservices can be stateless or stateful, and they are resource balanced across the virtual machines to maximize efficiency.",
      "pos": [
        677,
        826
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The unique architecture of Service Fabric enables you to perform near real-time data analysis, in-memory computation, parallel transactions, and event processing in your applications.",
      "pos": [
        827,
        1010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can easily scale your applications up or down (really in or out), depending on your changing resource requirements.",
      "pos": [
        1011,
        1130
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Service Fabric platform in Azure is ideal for the following categories of applications and services:",
      "pos": [
        1133,
        1237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Highly available services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Service Fabric services provide extremely fast failover.",
      "pos": [
        1241,
        1328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric allows you to create multiple secondary service replicas.",
      "pos": [
        1329,
        1401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a node, process, or individual service goes down due to hardware or other failure, one of the secondary replicas is immediately promoted to a primary replica with negligible loss of service to customers.",
      "pos": [
        1402,
        1608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Scalable services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Individual Services can be partitioned allowing for state to be scaled out across the cluster.",
      "pos": [
        1613,
        1730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition, individual services can be created and removed on the fly.",
      "pos": [
        1731,
        1802
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Services can be quickly and easily scaled out from a few instances on a few nodes to thousands of instances on many nodes, and then immediately scaled down again, depending on your resource needs.",
      "pos": [
        1803,
        1999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use Service Fabric to build these service and manage their complete lifecycle.",
      "pos": [
        2000,
        2086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Computation on non-static data<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Service Fabric enables you to build data, I/O, and compute intensive stateful applications.",
      "pos": [
        2091,
        2218
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric allows the colocation of the processing (computation) and data in applications.",
      "pos": [
        2219,
        2313
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Normally today when your application requires access to data there is network latency that is associated with an external data cache or storage tier.",
      "pos": [
        2314,
        2463
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With stateful Service Fabric services that latency is eliminated, enabling more performant reads and writes.",
      "pos": [
        2464,
        2572
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, say you had an application that performs near real-time recommendation selection for customers with a round-trip time requirement of less than 100ms.",
      "pos": [
        2573,
        2735
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The latency and performance characteristics of Service Fabric services (where the computation of recommendation selection is colocated with the data and rules) provides a responsive experience to the user compared to the standard implementation model of having to fetch the necessary data from remote storage.",
      "pos": [
        2736,
        3045
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Session based interactive applications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Service Fabric is useful if your applications, such as online gaming or instant messaging, require low latency reads and writes.",
      "pos": [
        3052,
        3224
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric enables you to build these interactive, stateful applications without having to create a separate store or cache required for stateless apps (increasing latency and potentially introducing consistency issues).",
      "pos": [
        3225,
        3449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Distributed graph processing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The growth of social networks has greatly increased the need to analyze large-scale graphs in parallel.",
      "pos": [
        3454,
        3591
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Fast scaling and parallel load processing make Service Fabric a natural platform for processing large-scale graphs.",
      "pos": [
        3592,
        3707
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric enables you to build highly scalable services for groups such as social networking, business intelligence, and scientific research.",
      "pos": [
        3708,
        3854
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data analytics and workflows<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: The fast read/writes of Service Fabric enables applications that must reliably process events or streams of data.",
      "pos": [
        3859,
        4006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric also enables applications that describe a processing pipeline, where results must be reliable and then passed on without loss to the next processing stage, including transactional and financial systems, where data consistency and computation guarantees are essential.",
      "pos": [
        4007,
        4289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Designing applications composed of stateless and stateful microservices",
      "pos": [
        4295,
        4366
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Building applications with Azure Cloud Service worker roles are an example of stateless services.",
      "pos": [
        4370,
        4467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By contrast stateful microservices maintain the authoritative state beyond the request and its response, providing high availability and consistency of that state through simple APIs that provide transactional guarantees backed by replication.",
      "pos": [
        4468,
        4711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric's Stateful services democratize high availability (HA), bringing it to all types of applications, not just databases and other data stores.",
      "pos": [
        4712,
        4866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is a natural progression: applications have already moved from using purely relational databases for HA, to NoSQL databases; now the applications themselves can have their \"hot\" state and data managed within them for additional performance gains without sacrificing reliability, consistency, or availability.",
      "pos": [
        4867,
        5180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When building applications consisting of microservices you typically have a combination of stateless web apps (ASP.NET, node.js, etc.) calling onto stateless and stateful business middle-tier services, all deployed into the same Service Fabric cluster using the Service Fabric deployment commands.",
      "pos": [
        5182,
        5479
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each of these services is independence with regards to scale, reliability, and resource usage, greatly improving agility in development and lifecycle management.",
      "pos": [
        5480,
        5641
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stateful microservices simplify application designs as they remove the need for additional queues and caches that have traditionally been required to address the availability and latency requirements of a purely stateless application.",
      "pos": [
        5645,
        5879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since stateful service are naturally highly-available and low-latency this means fewer moving parts to manage in your application as a whole.",
      "pos": [
        5880,
        6021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The diagrams below illustrate the differences between designing an application that is stateless verses one that is stateful.",
      "pos": [
        6022,
        6147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By taking advantage of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Reliable Services<ept id=\"p1\">](../Service-Fabric/service-fabric-reliable-services-introduction.md)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Reliable Actors<ept id=\"p2\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-introduction.md)</ept> programming models, stateful services reduce application complexity, whilst achieving high throughput and low latency.",
      "pos": [
        6148,
        6451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An application built using stateless services",
      "pos": [
        6456,
        6501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![Application using Stateless Service][Image1]",
      "pos": [
        6504,
        6550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An application built using stateful services",
      "pos": [
        6555,
        6599
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![Application using Stateless Service][Image2]",
      "pos": [
        6602,
        6648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">\n##</ph> Next steps\n\n\nGet started building stateless and stateful services with the Service Fabric",
      "pos": [
        6765,
        6858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p1\">Reliable Services](service-fabric-reliable-services-quick-start.md)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p2\">Reliable Actors](service-fabric-reliable-actors-get-started.md)</ept> programming models.",
      "pos": [
        6860,
        7017
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Also see the following topics:\n\n<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ept id=\"p1\">Defining and Managing Service State](service-fabric-concepts-state.md)</ept><bpt id=\"p2\">\n\n[</bpt><ept id=\"p2\">Availability of services](../service-fabric-concepts-availability-services.md)</ept><bpt id=\"p3\">\n\n[</bpt><ept id=\"p3\">Scalability of Service Fabric services](service-fabric-concepts-scalability.md)</ept><bpt id=\"p4\">\n\n[</bpt><ept id=\"p4\">Partitioning Service Fabric services](service-fabric-concepts-partitioning.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">\n\n[Image1]: media/service-fabric-application-scenarios/AppwithStatelessServices.jpg\n[Image2]: media/service-fabric-application-scenarios/AppwithStatefulServices.jpg</ph>",
      "pos": [
        7019,
        7530
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Application Scenarios and Design with Service Fabric\" \n   description=\"Categories of applications. Application design using stateful and stateless services\" \n   services=\"service-fabric\" \n   documentationCenter=\".net\" \n   authors=\"msfussell\" \n   manager=\"timlt\" \n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"service-fabric\"\n   ms.devlang=\"dotnet\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"NA\" \n   ms.date=\"08/21/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"mfussell\"/>\n\n# Service Fabric Application Scenarios\n\nMicrosoft Azure Service Fabric offers a reliable and flexible platform that enables you to write and run many types of business applications and services. These applications and microservices can be stateless or stateful, and they are resource balanced across the virtual machines to maximize efficiency. The unique architecture of Service Fabric enables you to perform near real-time data analysis, in-memory computation, parallel transactions, and event processing in your applications. You can easily scale your applications up or down (really in or out), depending on your changing resource requirements. \n\nThe Service Fabric platform in Azure is ideal for the following categories of applications and services:\n\n- **Highly available services**: Service Fabric services provide extremely fast failover. Service Fabric allows you to create multiple secondary service replicas. If a node, process, or individual service goes down due to hardware or other failure, one of the secondary replicas is immediately promoted to a primary replica with negligible loss of service to customers. \n\n- **Scalable services**: Individual Services can be partitioned allowing for state to be scaled out across the cluster. In addition, individual services can be created and removed on the fly. Services can be quickly and easily scaled out from a few instances on a few nodes to thousands of instances on many nodes, and then immediately scaled down again, depending on your resource needs. You can use Service Fabric to build these service and manage their complete lifecycle.\n \n- **Computation on non-static data**: Service Fabric enables you to build data, I/O, and compute intensive stateful applications. Service Fabric allows the colocation of the processing (computation) and data in applications. Normally today when your application requires access to data there is network latency that is associated with an external data cache or storage tier. With stateful Service Fabric services that latency is eliminated, enabling more performant reads and writes. For example, say you had an application that performs near real-time recommendation selection for customers with a round-trip time requirement of less than 100ms. The latency and performance characteristics of Service Fabric services (where the computation of recommendation selection is colocated with the data and rules) provides a responsive experience to the user compared to the standard implementation model of having to fetch the necessary data from remote storage.  \n \n- **Session based interactive applications**: Service Fabric is useful if your applications, such as online gaming or instant messaging, require low latency reads and writes. Service Fabric enables you to build these interactive, stateful applications without having to create a separate store or cache required for stateless apps (increasing latency and potentially introducing consistency issues).\n \n- **Distributed graph processing**: The growth of social networks has greatly increased the need to analyze large-scale graphs in parallel. Fast scaling and parallel load processing make Service Fabric a natural platform for processing large-scale graphs. Service Fabric enables you to build highly scalable services for groups such as social networking, business intelligence, and scientific research.\n \n- **Data analytics and workflows**: The fast read/writes of Service Fabric enables applications that must reliably process events or streams of data. Service Fabric also enables applications that describe a processing pipeline, where results must be reliable and then passed on without loss to the next processing stage, including transactional and financial systems, where data consistency and computation guarantees are essential. \n\n## Designing applications composed of stateless and stateful microservices ##\nBuilding applications with Azure Cloud Service worker roles are an example of stateless services. By contrast stateful microservices maintain the authoritative state beyond the request and its response, providing high availability and consistency of that state through simple APIs that provide transactional guarantees backed by replication. Service Fabric's Stateful services democratize high availability (HA), bringing it to all types of applications, not just databases and other data stores. This is a natural progression: applications have already moved from using purely relational databases for HA, to NoSQL databases; now the applications themselves can have their \"hot\" state and data managed within them for additional performance gains without sacrificing reliability, consistency, or availability.\n\nWhen building applications consisting of microservices you typically have a combination of stateless web apps (ASP.NET, node.js, etc.) calling onto stateless and stateful business middle-tier services, all deployed into the same Service Fabric cluster using the Service Fabric deployment commands. Each of these services is independence with regards to scale, reliability, and resource usage, greatly improving agility in development and lifecycle management.\n  \nStateful microservices simplify application designs as they remove the need for additional queues and caches that have traditionally been required to address the availability and latency requirements of a purely stateless application. Since stateful service are naturally highly-available and low-latency this means fewer moving parts to manage in your application as a whole. The diagrams below illustrate the differences between designing an application that is stateless verses one that is stateful. By taking advantage of the [Reliable Services](../Service-Fabric/service-fabric-reliable-services-introduction.md) and [Reliable Actors](service-fabric-reliable-actors-introduction.md) programming models, stateful services reduce application complexity, whilst achieving high throughput and low latency.\n\n## An application built using stateless services##\n![Application using Stateless Service][Image1]\n\n## An application built using stateful services##\n![Application using Stateless Service][Image2]\n\n<!--Every topic should have next steps and links to the next logical set of content to keep the customer engaged-->\n## Next steps\n\n\nGet started building stateless and stateful services with the Service Fabric \n[Reliable Services](service-fabric-reliable-services-quick-start.md) and [Reliable Actors](service-fabric-reliable-actors-get-started.md) programming models.\n\nAlso see the following topics:\n\n[Defining and Managing Service State](service-fabric-concepts-state.md)\n\n[Availability of services](../service-fabric-concepts-availability-services.md)\n\n[Scalability of Service Fabric services](service-fabric-concepts-scalability.md)\n\n[Partitioning Service Fabric services](service-fabric-concepts-partitioning.md)\n\n[Image1]: media/service-fabric-application-scenarios/AppwithStatelessServices.jpg\n[Image2]: media/service-fabric-application-scenarios/AppwithStatefulServices.jpg\n \n \n"
}