{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric Reliable Actors Overview",
      "pos": [
        26,
        65
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Introduction to the Service Fabric Reliable Actors programming model",
      "pos": [
        83,
        151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Introduction to Service Fabric Reliable Actors",
      "pos": [
        449,
        495
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        496,
        713
      ],
      "content": "The Reliable Actors API is one of two high-level frameworks provided by <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Service Fabric<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-technical-overview.md)</ept>, along with the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Reliable Services API<ept id=\"p2\">](service-fabric-reliable-services-introduction.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Based on the Actor pattern, the Reliable Actors API provides an asynchronous, single-threaded programming model that simplifies your code while still taking advantage of the scalability and reliability guarantees provided by Service Fabric.",
      "pos": [
        715,
        955
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actors",
      "pos": [
        960,
        966
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actors are isolated, single-threaded components that encapsulate both state and behavior.",
      "pos": [
        967,
        1056
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They are similar to .NET objects and hence provide a natural programming model.",
      "pos": [
        1057,
        1136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Every actor is an instance of an actor type, similar to the way a .NET object is an instance of a .NET type.",
      "pos": [
        1137,
        1245
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, there may be an actor type that implements the functionality of a calculator and there could be many actors of that type that are distributed on various nodes across a cluster.",
      "pos": [
        1246,
        1435
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each such actor is uniquely identified by an actor ID.",
      "pos": [
        1436,
        1490
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Defining and implementing Actor interfaces",
      "pos": [
        1495,
        1537
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actors interact with rest of the system, including other actors, by passing asynchronous messages using a request-response pattern.",
      "pos": [
        1539,
        1670
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These interactions are defined in an interface as asynchronous methods.",
      "pos": [
        1671,
        1742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, the interface for an actor type that implements the functionality of a calculator might be defined as follows:",
      "pos": [
        1743,
        1866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An actor type could implement the above interface as follows:",
      "pos": [
        2057,
        2118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because method invocations and their responses ultimately result in network requests across the cluster, the arguments and the result type of the Task that it returns must be serializable by the platform.",
      "pos": [
        2464,
        2668
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In particular, they must be <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>data contract serializable<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-notes-on-actor-type-serialization.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2669,
        2795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.TIP]</ph> The Fabric Actors runtime emits some <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>events and performance counters related to actor methods<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-diagnostics.md#actor-method-events-and-performance-counters)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2799,
        2999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They are useful in diagnostics and performance monitoring.",
      "pos": [
        3000,
        3058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following rules pertaining to actor interface methods are worth mentioning:",
      "pos": [
        3060,
        3139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor interface methods cannot be overloaded.",
      "pos": [
        3142,
        3187
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor interface methods must not have out, ref or optional parameters.",
      "pos": [
        3190,
        3260
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor Communication",
      "pos": [
        3265,
        3284
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Actor Proxy",
      "pos": [
        3289,
        3304
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Actors client API provides communication between an actor instance and an actor client.",
      "pos": [
        3305,
        3396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To communicate with an actor, a client creates an actor proxy object that implements the actor interface.",
      "pos": [
        3397,
        3502
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The client interacts with the actor by invoking methods on the proxy object.",
      "pos": [
        3503,
        3579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The actor proxy can be used for client-to-actor as well as actor-to-actor communication.",
      "pos": [
        3580,
        3668
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Continuing our calculator example, the client code for a calculator actor could be written as shown below:",
      "pos": [
        3669,
        3775
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note the two pieces of information used to create the actor proxy object - the actor ID and the application name.",
      "pos": [
        4035,
        4148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The actor ID is an identifier that uniquely identifies the actor, while the application name identifies the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Service Fabric application<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-platform.md#service-fabric-application-model-concepts-for-actors)</ept> that the actor is deployed in.",
      "pos": [
        4149,
        4413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor Lifetime",
      "pos": [
        4419,
        4433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric actors are virtual, meaning that their lifetime is not tied to their in-memory representation.",
      "pos": [
        4435,
        4544
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result, they do not need to be explicitly created or destroyed.",
      "pos": [
        4545,
        4613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Actors runtime automatically activates an actor the first time it receives a request for that actor.",
      "pos": [
        4614,
        4718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If an actor is not used for certain time, the Actors runtime will garbage collect the in-memory object while maintaining knowledge of the actor's existence should it need to be reactivated later.",
      "pos": [
        4719,
        4914
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Actor lifecycle and Garbage Collection<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-lifecycle.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4915,
        5023
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Location Transparency and Automatic Failover",
      "pos": [
        5029,
        5073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To provide high scalability and reliability, Service Fabric distributes actors throughout the cluster and automatically migrates them from failed nodes to healthy ones as required.",
      "pos": [
        5075,
        5255
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <ph id=\"ph1\">`ActorProxy`</ph> class on the client side performs the necessary resolution to locate the actor by ID <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>partition<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-platform.md#service-fabric-partition-concepts-for-actors)</ept> and open a communication channel with it.",
      "pos": [
        5256,
        5500
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <ph id=\"ph1\">`ActorProxy`</ph> also retries in the case of communication failures and failovers.",
      "pos": [
        5501,
        5583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This ensures that messages will be reliably delivered despite the presence of faults but it also means that it is possible for an Actor implementation to get duplicate messages from the same client.",
      "pos": [
        5584,
        5782
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Concurrency",
      "pos": [
        5787,
        5798
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Turn-based concurrency",
      "pos": [
        5803,
        5825
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Actors runtime provides a simple turn-based concurrency for actor methods.",
      "pos": [
        5827,
        5905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that no more than one thread can be active inside the actor code at any time.",
      "pos": [
        5906,
        5994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A turn consists of the complete execution of an actor method in response to the request from other actors or clients, or the complete execution of a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>timer/reminder<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-timers-reminders.md)</ept> callback.",
      "pos": [
        5996,
        6223
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Even though these methods and callbacks are asynchronous, the Actors runtime does not interleave them - a turn must be fully completed before a new turn is allowed.",
      "pos": [
        6224,
        6388
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In other words, an actor method or timer/reminder callback that is currently executing must be completed fully before a new call to a method or a callback is allowed.",
      "pos": [
        6389,
        6555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A method or callback is considered completed if execution has returned from the method or callback, and the Task returned by the method or callback has completed.",
      "pos": [
        6556,
        6718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is worth emphasizing that turn-based concurrency is respected even across different methods, timers and callbacks.",
      "pos": [
        6719,
        6836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Actors runtime enforces turn-based concurrency by acquiring a per-actor lock at the beginning of a turn and releasing the lock at the end of the turn.",
      "pos": [
        6838,
        6992
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Thus, turn-based concurrency is enforced on a per-actor basis and not across actors.",
      "pos": [
        6993,
        7077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor methods and timer/reminder callbacks can execute simultaneously on behalf of different actors.",
      "pos": [
        7078,
        7178
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following example illustrates the above concepts.",
      "pos": [
        7180,
        7233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Consider an actor type that implements two asynchronous methods (say <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Method1<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Method2<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>), a timer and a reminder.",
      "pos": [
        7234,
        7352
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The diagram below shows an example of a timeline for the execution of these methods and callbacks on behalf of two actors - <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>ActorId1<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>ActorId2<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> - that belong to this actor type.",
      "pos": [
        7353,
        7536
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][1]",
      "pos": [
        7538,
        7544
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The conventions followed by the above diagram are:",
      "pos": [
        7546,
        7596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each vertical line shows the logical flow of execution of a method or a callback on behalf of a particular actor.",
      "pos": [
        7600,
        7713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The events marked on each vertical line occur in chronological order with newer events occurring below the older ones.",
      "pos": [
        7716,
        7834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Different colors are used for timelines corresponding to different actors.",
      "pos": [
        7837,
        7911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Highlighting is used to indicate the duration for which the per-actor lock is held on behalf of a method or callback.",
      "pos": [
        7914,
        8031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following points about the above diagram are worth mentioning:",
      "pos": [
        8033,
        8099
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Method1<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is executing on behalf of <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>ActorId2<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> in response to client request <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>xyz789<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept>, another client request <bpt id=\"p4\">*</bpt>abc123<ept id=\"p4\">*</ept> arrives that also requires <bpt id=\"p5\">*</bpt>Method1<ept id=\"p5\">*</ept> to be executed by <bpt id=\"p6\">*</bpt>ActorId2<ept id=\"p6\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8103,
        8293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, the latter execution of <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Method1<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> does not begin until the former execution has completed.",
      "pos": [
        8294,
        8393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Similarly, a reminder registered by <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>ActorId2<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> fires while <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Method1<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> is being executed in response to client request <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>xyz789<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8394,
        8520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The reminder callback is executed only after both executions of <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Method1<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> are complete.",
      "pos": [
        8521,
        8608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All of this is due to turn-based concurrency being enforced for <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>ActorId2<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8609,
        8684
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8687,
        8888
      ],
      "content": "Similarly, turn-based concurrency is also enforced for <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>ActorId1<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>, as demonstrated by the execution of <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Method1<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>Method2<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept> and the timer callback on behalf of <bpt id=\"p4\">*</bpt>ActorId1<ept id=\"p4\">*</ept> happening in a serial fashion."
    },
    {
      "content": "Execution of <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Method1<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> on behalf of <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>ActorId1<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> overlaps with its execution on behalf of <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>ActorId2<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8891,
        8990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is because turn-based concurrency is only enforced within an actor and not across actors.",
      "pos": [
        8991,
        9085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In some of the method/callback executions, the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Task`</ph> returned by the method/callback completes after the method returns.",
      "pos": [
        9088,
        9209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In some others, the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Task`</ph> is already complete by the time the method/callback returns.",
      "pos": [
        9210,
        9297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In either case, the per-actor lock is released only after the both of these happen, i.e. after the method/callback returns and the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Task`</ph> completes.",
      "pos": [
        9298,
        9446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reentrancy",
      "pos": [
        9452,
        9462
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Actors runtime allows reentrancy by default.",
      "pos": [
        9464,
        9512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that if an actor method of Actor A calls method on Actor B which in turn calls another method on actor A, that method is allowed to run as it is part of the same logical call chain context.",
      "pos": [
        9513,
        9713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All timer and reminder calls start with the new logical call context.",
      "pos": [
        9714,
        9783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Reentrancy<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-reentrancy.md)</ept> section for more details.",
      "pos": [
        9784,
        9872
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scope of concurrency guarantees",
      "pos": [
        9878,
        9909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Actors runtime provides these concurrency guarantees in situations where it controls the invocation of these methods.",
      "pos": [
        9911,
        10032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, it provides these guarantees for the method invocations that are done in response to receiving a client request and for timer and reminder callbacks.",
      "pos": [
        10033,
        10195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, if the actor code directly invokes these methods outside of the mechanisms provided by the Actors runtime, then the runtime cannot provide any concurrency guarantees.",
      "pos": [
        10196,
        10371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if the method is invoked in the context of some Task that is not associated with the Task returned by the actor methods, or if it is invoked from a thread that the actor creates on its own, then the runtime cannot provide concurrency guarantees.",
      "pos": [
        10372,
        10630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Therefore, to perform background operations, actors should use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Actor Timers or Actor Reminders<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-timers-reminders.md)</ept> that respect the turn-based concurrency.",
      "pos": [
        10631,
        10820
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.TIP]</ph> The Fabric Actors runtime emits some <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>events and performance counters related to concurrency<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-diagnostics.md#concurrency-events-and-performance-counters)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        10824,
        11021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They are useful in diagnostics and performance monitoring.",
      "pos": [
        11022,
        11080
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor State Management",
      "pos": [
        11085,
        11107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Fabric Actors allows you to create the actors that are either stateless or stateful.",
      "pos": [
        11108,
        11192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stateless Actors",
      "pos": [
        11198,
        11214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stateless actors, which are derived from the <ph id=\"ph1\">``Actor``</ph> base class, do not have any state that is managed by the Actors runtime.",
      "pos": [
        11215,
        11342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Their member variables are preserved throughout their in-memory lifetime just like any other .NET type.",
      "pos": [
        11343,
        11446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, when they are garbage collected after a period of inactivity, their state is lost.",
      "pos": [
        11447,
        11538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Similarly, state can be lost due to failovers, which occur during upgrades, resource-balancing operations or as the result of failures in the actor process or its hosting node.",
      "pos": [
        11539,
        11715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following is an example of a stateless actor.",
      "pos": [
        11717,
        11766
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stateful Actors",
      "pos": [
        11972,
        11987
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stateful  actors have a state that needs to be preserved across garbage collections and failovers.",
      "pos": [
        11988,
        12086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They derive from the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Actor&lt;TState&gt;`</ph> base class, where <ph id=\"ph2\">`TState`</ph> is the type of the state that needs to be preserved.",
      "pos": [
        12087,
        12203
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The state can be accessed in the actor methods via <ph id=\"ph1\">`State`</ph> property on the base class.",
      "pos": [
        12204,
        12290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following is an example of a stateful actor accessing the state.",
      "pos": [
        12294,
        12362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor state is preserved across garbage collections and failovers by persisting it on disk and replicating it across multiple nodes in the cluster.",
      "pos": [
        12572,
        12719
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that, like method arguments and return values, the actor state's type must be  <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>data contract serializable<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-notes-on-actor-type-serialization.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        12720,
        12908
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12912,
        13138
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Please refer to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Reliable Actors notes on serialization<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-notes-on-actor-type-serialization.md)</ept> article for mode details on how interfaces and Actor State types should be defined."
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor state providers",
      "pos": [
        13147,
        13168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The storage and retrieval of the state is provided by an actor state provider.",
      "pos": [
        13169,
        13247
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "State providers can be configured per actor or for all actors within an assembly by the state provider specific attribute.",
      "pos": [
        13248,
        13370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When an actor is activated its state is loaded in memory.",
      "pos": [
        13371,
        13428
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When an actor method completes, the modified state is automatically saved by the Actors runtime by calling a method on the state provider.",
      "pos": [
        13429,
        13567
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If failure occurs during the save operation, the Actors runtime creates a new actor instance and loads the last consistent state from the state provider.",
      "pos": [
        13568,
        13721
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default, stateful actors use the key-value store actor state provider, which is built on the distributed key-value store provided by the Service Fabric platform.",
      "pos": [
        13723,
        13887
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, please see the topic on <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>state provider choices<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-platform.md#actor-state-provider-choices)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        13888,
        14032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.TIP]</ph> The Actors runtime emits some <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>events and performance counters related to actor state management<ept id=\"p1\">](service-fabric-reliable-actors-diagnostics.md#actor-state-management-events-and-performance-counters)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        14036,
        14248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They are useful in diagnostics and performance monitoring.",
      "pos": [
        14249,
        14307
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Readonly Methods",
      "pos": [
        14314,
        14330
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default the Actors runtime saves Actor state upon the completion of an actor method call, timer callback or reminder callback.",
      "pos": [
        14331,
        14460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No other actor call is allowed until the save state is complete.",
      "pos": [
        14461,
        14525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There may be actor methods that do not modify the state and in that case the additional time spent on saving the state can affect the overall throughput of the system.",
      "pos": [
        14529,
        14696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To avoid that you can mark the methods and timer callbacks that do not modify the state as read-only.",
      "pos": [
        14697,
        14798
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        14800,
        14892
      ],
      "content": "The example below shows how to mark an actor method as read-only using <ph id=\"ph1\">`Readonly`</ph> attribute."
    },
    {
      "content": "Timer callbacks can be marked with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Readonly`</ph> attribute in a similar way.",
      "pos": [
        15019,
        15096
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For reminders, the read-only flag is passed in as an argument to the <ph id=\"ph1\">`RegisterReminder`</ph> method that is invoked to register the reminder.",
      "pos": [
        15097,
        15233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        15238,
        15248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Concepts",
      "pos": [
        15253,
        15261
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor Lifecycle and Garbage Collection",
      "pos": [
        15263,
        15301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor Timers &amp; Reminders",
      "pos": [
        15350,
        15374
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor Events",
      "pos": [
        15430,
        15442
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor Reentrancy",
      "pos": [
        15488,
        15504
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How Fabric Actors use the Service Fabric platform",
      "pos": [
        15554,
        15603
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuring KVSActorStateProvider Actor",
      "pos": [
        15651,
        15690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Actor Diagnostics and Performance Monitoring",
      "pos": [
        15765,
        15809
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Service Fabric Reliable Actors Overview\"\n   description=\"Introduction to the Service Fabric Reliable Actors programming model\"\n   services=\"service-fabric\"\n   documentationCenter=\".net\"\n   authors=\"jessebenson\"\n   manager=\"timlt\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"service-fabric\"\n   ms.devlang=\"dotnet\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"NA\"\n   ms.date=\"08/05/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"claudioc\"/>\n\n# Introduction to Service Fabric Reliable Actors\nThe Reliable Actors API is one of two high-level frameworks provided by [Service Fabric](service-fabric-technical-overview.md), along with the [Reliable Services API](service-fabric-reliable-services-introduction.md).\n\nBased on the Actor pattern, the Reliable Actors API provides an asynchronous, single-threaded programming model that simplifies your code while still taking advantage of the scalability and reliability guarantees provided by Service Fabric.\n\n## Actors\nActors are isolated, single-threaded components that encapsulate both state and behavior. They are similar to .NET objects and hence provide a natural programming model. Every actor is an instance of an actor type, similar to the way a .NET object is an instance of a .NET type. For example, there may be an actor type that implements the functionality of a calculator and there could be many actors of that type that are distributed on various nodes across a cluster. Each such actor is uniquely identified by an actor ID.\n\n## Defining and implementing Actor interfaces\n\nActors interact with rest of the system, including other actors, by passing asynchronous messages using a request-response pattern. These interactions are defined in an interface as asynchronous methods. For example, the interface for an actor type that implements the functionality of a calculator might be defined as follows:\n\n```csharp\npublic interface ICalculatorActor : IActor\n{\n    Task<double> AddAsync(double valueOne, double valueTwo);\n    Task<double> SubtractAsync(double valueOne, double valueTwo);\n}\n```\n\nAn actor type could implement the above interface as follows:\n\n```csharp\npublic class CalculatorActor : Actor, ICalculatorActor\n{\n    public Task<double> AddAsync(double valueOne, double valueTwo)\n    {\n        return Task.FromResult(valueOne + valueTwo);\n    }\n\n    public Task<double> SubtractAsync(double valueOne, double valueTwo)\n    {\n        return Task.FromResult(valueOne - valueTwo);\n    }\n}\n```\n\nBecause method invocations and their responses ultimately result in network requests across the cluster, the arguments and the result type of the Task that it returns must be serializable by the platform. In particular, they must be [data contract serializable](service-fabric-reliable-actors-notes-on-actor-type-serialization.md).\n\n> [AZURE.TIP] The Fabric Actors runtime emits some [events and performance counters related to actor methods](service-fabric-reliable-actors-diagnostics.md#actor-method-events-and-performance-counters). They are useful in diagnostics and performance monitoring.\n\nThe following rules pertaining to actor interface methods are worth mentioning:\n- Actor interface methods cannot be overloaded.\n- Actor interface methods must not have out, ref or optional parameters.\n\n## Actor Communication\n### The Actor Proxy\nThe Actors client API provides communication between an actor instance and an actor client. To communicate with an actor, a client creates an actor proxy object that implements the actor interface. The client interacts with the actor by invoking methods on the proxy object. The actor proxy can be used for client-to-actor as well as actor-to-actor communication. Continuing our calculator example, the client code for a calculator actor could be written as shown below:\n\n```csharp\nActorId actorId = ActorId.NewId();\nstring applicationName = \"fabric:/CalculatorActorApp\";\nICalculatorActor calculatorActor = ActorProxy.Create<ICalculatorActor>(actorId, applicationName);\ndouble result = calculatorActor.AddAsync(2, 3).Result;\n```\n\nNote the two pieces of information used to create the actor proxy object - the actor ID and the application name. The actor ID is an identifier that uniquely identifies the actor, while the application name identifies the [Service Fabric application](service-fabric-reliable-actors-platform.md#service-fabric-application-model-concepts-for-actors) that the actor is deployed in.\n\n### Actor Lifetime\n\nService Fabric actors are virtual, meaning that their lifetime is not tied to their in-memory representation. As a result, they do not need to be explicitly created or destroyed. The Actors runtime automatically activates an actor the first time it receives a request for that actor. If an actor is not used for certain time, the Actors runtime will garbage collect the in-memory object while maintaining knowledge of the actor's existence should it need to be reactivated later. For more details, see [Actor lifecycle and Garbage Collection](service-fabric-reliable-actors-lifecycle.md).\n\n### Location Transparency and Automatic Failover\n\nTo provide high scalability and reliability, Service Fabric distributes actors throughout the cluster and automatically migrates them from failed nodes to healthy ones as required. The `ActorProxy` class on the client side performs the necessary resolution to locate the actor by ID [partition](service-fabric-reliable-actors-platform.md#service-fabric-partition-concepts-for-actors) and open a communication channel with it. The `ActorProxy` also retries in the case of communication failures and failovers. This ensures that messages will be reliably delivered despite the presence of faults but it also means that it is possible for an Actor implementation to get duplicate messages from the same client.\n\n## Concurrency\n### Turn-based concurrency\n\nThe Actors runtime provides a simple turn-based concurrency for actor methods. This means that no more than one thread can be active inside the actor code at any time.\n\nA turn consists of the complete execution of an actor method in response to the request from other actors or clients, or the complete execution of a [timer/reminder](service-fabric-reliable-actors-timers-reminders.md) callback. Even though these methods and callbacks are asynchronous, the Actors runtime does not interleave them - a turn must be fully completed before a new turn is allowed. In other words, an actor method or timer/reminder callback that is currently executing must be completed fully before a new call to a method or a callback is allowed. A method or callback is considered completed if execution has returned from the method or callback, and the Task returned by the method or callback has completed. It is worth emphasizing that turn-based concurrency is respected even across different methods, timers and callbacks.\n\nThe Actors runtime enforces turn-based concurrency by acquiring a per-actor lock at the beginning of a turn and releasing the lock at the end of the turn. Thus, turn-based concurrency is enforced on a per-actor basis and not across actors. Actor methods and timer/reminder callbacks can execute simultaneously on behalf of different actors.\n\nThe following example illustrates the above concepts. Consider an actor type that implements two asynchronous methods (say *Method1* and *Method2*), a timer and a reminder. The diagram below shows an example of a timeline for the execution of these methods and callbacks on behalf of two actors - *ActorId1* and *ActorId2* - that belong to this actor type.\n\n![][1]\n\nThe conventions followed by the above diagram are:\n\n- Each vertical line shows the logical flow of execution of a method or a callback on behalf of a particular actor.\n- The events marked on each vertical line occur in chronological order with newer events occurring below the older ones.\n- Different colors are used for timelines corresponding to different actors.\n- Highlighting is used to indicate the duration for which the per-actor lock is held on behalf of a method or callback.\n\nThe following points about the above diagram are worth mentioning:\n\n- When *Method1* is executing on behalf of *ActorId2* in response to client request *xyz789*, another client request *abc123* arrives that also requires *Method1* to be executed by *ActorId2*. However, the latter execution of *Method1* does not begin until the former execution has completed. Similarly, a reminder registered by *ActorId2* fires while *Method1* is being executed in response to client request *xyz789*. The reminder callback is executed only after both executions of *Method1* are complete. All of this is due to turn-based concurrency being enforced for *ActorId2*.\n- Similarly, turn-based concurrency is also enforced for *ActorId1*, as demonstrated by the execution of *Method1*, *Method2* and the timer callback on behalf of *ActorId1* happening in a serial fashion.\n- Execution of *Method1* on behalf of *ActorId1* overlaps with its execution on behalf of *ActorId2*. This is because turn-based concurrency is only enforced within an actor and not across actors.\n- In some of the method/callback executions, the `Task` returned by the method/callback completes after the method returns. In some others, the `Task` is already complete by the time the method/callback returns. In either case, the per-actor lock is released only after the both of these happen, i.e. after the method/callback returns and the `Task` completes.\n\n### Reentrancy\n\nThe Actors runtime allows reentrancy by default. This means that if an actor method of Actor A calls method on Actor B which in turn calls another method on actor A, that method is allowed to run as it is part of the same logical call chain context. All timer and reminder calls start with the new logical call context. See [Reentrancy](service-fabric-reliable-actors-reentrancy.md) section for more details.\n\n### Scope of concurrency guarantees\n\nThe Actors runtime provides these concurrency guarantees in situations where it controls the invocation of these methods. For example, it provides these guarantees for the method invocations that are done in response to receiving a client request and for timer and reminder callbacks. However, if the actor code directly invokes these methods outside of the mechanisms provided by the Actors runtime, then the runtime cannot provide any concurrency guarantees. For example, if the method is invoked in the context of some Task that is not associated with the Task returned by the actor methods, or if it is invoked from a thread that the actor creates on its own, then the runtime cannot provide concurrency guarantees. Therefore, to perform background operations, actors should use [Actor Timers or Actor Reminders](service-fabric-reliable-actors-timers-reminders.md) that respect the turn-based concurrency.\n\n> [AZURE.TIP] The Fabric Actors runtime emits some [events and performance counters related to concurrency](service-fabric-reliable-actors-diagnostics.md#concurrency-events-and-performance-counters). They are useful in diagnostics and performance monitoring.\n\n## Actor State Management\nFabric Actors allows you to create the actors that are either stateless or stateful.\n\n### Stateless Actors\nStateless actors, which are derived from the ``Actor`` base class, do not have any state that is managed by the Actors runtime. Their member variables are preserved throughout their in-memory lifetime just like any other .NET type. However, when they are garbage collected after a period of inactivity, their state is lost. Similarly, state can be lost due to failovers, which occur during upgrades, resource-balancing operations or as the result of failures in the actor process or its hosting node.\n\nThe following is an example of a stateless actor.\n\n```csharp\nclass HelloActor : Actor, IHello\n{\n    public Task<string> SayHello(string greeting)\n    {\n        return Task.FromResult(\"You said: '\" + greeting + \"', I say: Hello Actors!\");\n    }\n}\n```\n\n### Stateful Actors\nStateful  actors have a state that needs to be preserved across garbage collections and failovers. They derive from the `Actor<TState>` base class, where `TState` is the type of the state that needs to be preserved. The state can be accessed in the actor methods via `State` property on the base class.  \n\nThe following is an example of a stateful actor accessing the state.\n\n```csharp\nclass VoicemailBoxActor : Actor<VoicemailBox>, IVoicemailBoxActor\n{\n    public Task<List<Voicemail>> GetMessagesAsync()\n    {\n        return Task.FromResult(State.MessageList);\n    }\n    ...\n}\n```\n\nActor state is preserved across garbage collections and failovers by persisting it on disk and replicating it across multiple nodes in the cluster. This means that, like method arguments and return values, the actor state's type must be  [data contract serializable](service-fabric-reliable-actors-notes-on-actor-type-serialization.md).\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Please refer to the [Reliable Actors notes on serialization](service-fabric-reliable-actors-notes-on-actor-type-serialization.md) article for mode details on how interfaces and Actor State types should be defined.  \n\n#### Actor state providers\nThe storage and retrieval of the state is provided by an actor state provider. State providers can be configured per actor or for all actors within an assembly by the state provider specific attribute. When an actor is activated its state is loaded in memory. When an actor method completes, the modified state is automatically saved by the Actors runtime by calling a method on the state provider. If failure occurs during the save operation, the Actors runtime creates a new actor instance and loads the last consistent state from the state provider.\n\nBy default, stateful actors use the key-value store actor state provider, which is built on the distributed key-value store provided by the Service Fabric platform. For more information, please see the topic on [state provider choices](service-fabric-reliable-actors-platform.md#actor-state-provider-choices).\n\n> [AZURE.TIP] The Actors runtime emits some [events and performance counters related to actor state management](service-fabric-reliable-actors-diagnostics.md#actor-state-management-events-and-performance-counters). They are useful in diagnostics and performance monitoring.\n\n#### Readonly Methods\nBy default the Actors runtime saves Actor state upon the completion of an actor method call, timer callback or reminder callback. No other actor call is allowed until the save state is complete.  \n\nThere may be actor methods that do not modify the state and in that case the additional time spent on saving the state can affect the overall throughput of the system. To avoid that you can mark the methods and timer callbacks that do not modify the state as read-only.\n\nThe example below shows how to mark an actor method as read-only using `Readonly` attribute.\n\n```csharp\npublic interface IVoicemailBoxActor : IActor\n{\n    [Readonly]\n    Task<List<Voicemail>> GetMessagesAsync();\n}\n```\n\nTimer callbacks can be marked with the `Readonly` attribute in a similar way. For reminders, the read-only flag is passed in as an argument to the `RegisterReminder` method that is invoked to register the reminder.\n\n## Next steps\n### Concepts\n[Actor Lifecycle and Garbage Collection](service-fabric-reliable-actors-lifecycle.md)\n\n[Actor Timers & Reminders](service-fabric-reliable-actors-timers-reminders.md)\n\n[Actor Events](service-fabric-reliable-actors-events.md)\n\n[Actor Reentrancy](service-fabric-reliable-actors-reentrancy.md)\n\n[How Fabric Actors use the Service Fabric platform](service-fabric-reliable-actors-platform.md)\n\n[Configuring KVSActorStateProvider Actor](service-fabric-reliable-actors-KVSActorstateprovider-configuration.md)\n\n[Actor Diagnostics and Performance Monitoring](service-fabric-reliable-actors-diagnostics.md)\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/service-fabric-reliable-actors-introduction/concurrency.png\n"
}