{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Create an Azure Search index in the portal | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        87
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add an index to Azure Search service by filling in field definitions in the Azure portal",
      "pos": [
        106,
        194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create an Azure Search index in the Azure portal",
      "pos": [
        526,
        574
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can quickly prototype an index in Azure Search by creating one in the Azure portal.",
      "pos": [
        576,
        663
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using the portal is great for proof-of-concept testing, but you can also use it to view schema definitions and resource usage for any index deployed to your service.",
      "pos": [
        664,
        829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To complete this task, make sure you have an Azure Search service that's ready to go.",
      "pos": [
        831,
        916
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create an Azure Search service in the portal<ept id=\"p1\">](search-create-service-portal.md)</ept> if you need help setting it up.",
      "pos": [
        917,
        1032
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1037,
        1093
      ],
      "content": "Sign in to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://portal.azure.com)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Open the service dashboard of your Azure Search service.",
      "pos": [
        1098,
        1154
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here are a few ways to find the dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        1155,
        1197
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the Jumpbar, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Home<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1204,
        1235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The home page has tiles for every service in your subscription.",
      "pos": [
        1236,
        1299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the tile to open the service dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        1300,
        1345
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1352,
        1467
      ],
      "content": "In the Jumpbar, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Browse All<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Filter by<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Search services<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> to find your Search service in the list."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1472,
        1569
      ],
      "content": "In the service dashboard, you will see a command bar at the top, including one for <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add Index<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Check the pricing tier.",
      "pos": [
        1575,
        1598
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have the free version, you can have up to 3 indexes.",
      "pos": [
        1599,
        1658
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You might need to delete one to free up space.",
      "pos": [
        1659,
        1705
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][1]",
      "pos": [
        1712,
        1718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To delete an index, click one to slide open a blade.",
      "pos": [
        1723,
        1775
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Delete<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1776,
        1793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][2]",
      "pos": [
        1800,
        1806
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1811,
        1905
      ],
      "content": "To create a new index in the portal, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add Index<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and give it a name, such as <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>hotels<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "It can take a minute to create the index, but when it's ready for you to work with, it will appear in the Indexes list.",
      "pos": [
        1911,
        2030
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2035,
        2087
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>hotels<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to open the index definition blade."
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create an index in the portal, a required field (id) is created for you.",
      "pos": [
        2093,
        2174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is the key field, used to uniquely identify each document.",
      "pos": [
        2175,
        2238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There is only one field per key (no composite keys), and it is always a string.",
      "pos": [
        2239,
        2318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to rename the key field, it's important to do this step now, during index creation.",
      "pos": [
        2324,
        2419
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You won't be able to rename the field after the index is created.",
      "pos": [
        2420,
        2485
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][3]",
      "pos": [
        2491,
        2497
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To edit the field name, click the right arrow in the fields list.",
      "pos": [
        2502,
        2567
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2572,
        2604
      ],
      "content": "Replace <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>id<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> with <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>hotelId<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2609,
        2675
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on each blade (fields and index) to create the index."
    },
    {
      "content": "Add fields",
      "pos": [
        2680,
        2690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Azure Search, index attributes such as searchable, facetable, and filterable are enabled by default.",
      "pos": [
        2692,
        2795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, when you set these attributes, it's usually to turn off search behaviors that don't make sense (for example, sorting or faceting on a description).",
      "pos": [
        2796,
        2954
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The portal is different.",
      "pos": [
        2956,
        2980
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the portal, search behaviors are off by default so that you can select all of the behaviors that apply, on a field by field basis.",
      "pos": [
        2981,
        3114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add/Edit fields<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to add more fields.",
      "pos": [
        3119,
        3164
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this exercise, we'll recreate the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>hotels<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> index described in the article <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>How to use Fiddler with Azure Search<ept id=\"p2\">](search-fiddler.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3165,
        3300
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][4]",
      "pos": [
        3306,
        3312
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add and configure fields to complete the schema.",
      "pos": [
        3317,
        3365
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][5]",
      "pos": [
        3371,
        3377
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3383,
        3595
      ],
      "content": "Review <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Naming rules<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn857353.aspx)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Supported data types<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn798938.aspx)</ept> for reference information on field names and types."
    },
    {
      "content": "Index attributes consist of the following items:",
      "pos": [
        3601,
        3649
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3657,
        3734
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retrievable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> specifies whether a field can be returned in a search result."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3741,
        3807
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Filterable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> allows the field to be used in <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>$filter<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> queries."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3814,
        3872
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sortable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> allows the field to be used as a sort option."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Facetable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> allows a field to be used in a faceted navigation structure for self-directed filtering.",
      "pos": [
        3879,
        3981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically fields containing repetitive values that you can use to group multiple documents together (for example, multiple documents that fall under a single product or service category) work best as facets.",
      "pos": [
        3982,
        4189
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Key<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is the unique ID of each document, used for document look up.",
      "pos": [
        4196,
        4265
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Every index must have one key.",
      "pos": [
        4266,
        4296
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only one field can be the key, and it must be set to Edm.String.",
      "pos": [
        4297,
        4361
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4368,
        4423
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Searchable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> marks the field as full-text searchable."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4428,
        4499
      ],
      "content": "To remove any fields you don't want, right-click and select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Delete<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4504,
        4616
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to save the index you just defined, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> on the Add index page to build the index."
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        4622,
        4632
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Although the index is defined, it won't be ready to use until you load documents.",
      "pos": [
        4634,
        4715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Assuming that you're recreating the Hotels index, used for testing purposes, you can easily load the small number of documents for that index in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Fiddler<ept id=\"p1\">](search-fiddler.md)</ept>, using the instructions in the Load Documents section of <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>How to use Fiddler with Azure Search<ept id=\"p2\">](search-fiddler.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4716,
        5005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can then follow the remaining steps in that article to run some queries.",
      "pos": [
        5006,
        5082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you are comfortable with the basic index, consider adding a language analyzer or suggester to add multilanguage support or type-ahead suggestions.",
      "pos": [
        5084,
        5235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both features are specified in the index schema.",
      "pos": [
        5236,
        5284
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Language Support<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/elibrary/azure/dn879793.aspx)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Create Index<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn798941.aspx)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        5285,
        5461
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Create an Azure Search index in the portal | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Add an index to Azure Search service by filling in field definitions in the Azure portal\"\n    services=\"search\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"HeidiSteen\"\n    manager=\"mblythe\"\n    editor=\"\"\n    tags=\"azure-portal\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"search\"\n    ms.devlang=\"rest-api\"\n    ms.workload=\"search\"\n    ms.topic=\"get-started-article\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.date=\"07/08/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"heidist\"/>\n\n# Create an Azure Search index in the Azure portal\n\nYou can quickly prototype an index in Azure Search by creating one in the Azure portal. Using the portal is great for proof-of-concept testing, but you can also use it to view schema definitions and resource usage for any index deployed to your service.\n\nTo complete this task, make sure you have an Azure Search service that's ready to go. See [Create an Azure Search service in the portal](search-create-service-portal.md) if you need help setting it up.\n\n1. Sign in to the [Azure portal](https://portal.azure.com).\n\n2. Open the service dashboard of your Azure Search service. Here are a few ways to find the dashboard.\n    - In the Jumpbar, click **Home**. The home page has tiles for every service in your subscription. Click the tile to open the service dashboard.\n    - In the Jumpbar, click **Browse All** > **Filter by** > **Search services** to find your Search service in the list.\n\n3. In the service dashboard, you will see a command bar at the top, including one for **Add Index**.\n\n    Check the pricing tier. If you have the free version, you can have up to 3 indexes. You might need to delete one to free up space.\n\n     ![][1]\n\n4. To delete an index, click one to slide open a blade. Click **Delete**.\n\n     ![][2]\n\n5. To create a new index in the portal, click **Add Index** and give it a name, such as *hotels*.\n\n    It can take a minute to create the index, but when it's ready for you to work with, it will appear in the Indexes list.\n\n6. Click **hotels** to open the index definition blade.\n\n    When you create an index in the portal, a required field (id) is created for you. This is the key field, used to uniquely identify each document. There is only one field per key (no composite keys), and it is always a string.\n\n    If you want to rename the key field, it's important to do this step now, during index creation. You won't be able to rename the field after the index is created.\n\n    ![][3]\n\n7. To edit the field name, click the right arrow in the fields list.\n\n8. Replace **id** with **hotelId**.\n\n9. Click **OK** on each blade (fields and index) to create the index.\n\n## Add fields\n\nIn Azure Search, index attributes such as searchable, facetable, and filterable are enabled by default. Typically, when you set these attributes, it's usually to turn off search behaviors that don't make sense (for example, sorting or faceting on a description).\n\nThe portal is different. In the portal, search behaviors are off by default so that you can select all of the behaviors that apply, on a field by field basis.\n\n1. Click **Add/Edit fields** to add more fields. In this exercise, we'll recreate the *hotels* index described in the article [How to use Fiddler with Azure Search](search-fiddler.md).\n\n    ![][4]\n\n2. Add and configure fields to complete the schema.\n\n    ![][5]\n\n    Review [Naming rules](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn857353.aspx) and [Supported data types](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn798938.aspx) for reference information on field names and types.\n\n    Index attributes consist of the following items:\n\n    - **Retrievable** specifies whether a field can be returned in a search result.\n    - **Filterable** allows the field to be used in **$filter** queries.\n    - **Sortable** allows the field to be used as a sort option.\n    - **Facetable** allows a field to be used in a faceted navigation structure for self-directed filtering. Typically fields containing repetitive values that you can use to group multiple documents together (for example, multiple documents that fall under a single product or service category) work best as facets.\n    - **Key** is the unique ID of each document, used for document look up. Every index must have one key. Only one field can be the key, and it must be set to Edm.String.\n    - **Searchable** marks the field as full-text searchable.\n\n3. To remove any fields you don't want, right-click and select **Delete**.\n\n4. Click **OK** to save the index you just defined, and then click **OK** on the Add index page to build the index.\n\n\n## Next steps\n\nAlthough the index is defined, it won't be ready to use until you load documents. Assuming that you're recreating the Hotels index, used for testing purposes, you can easily load the small number of documents for that index in [Fiddler](search-fiddler.md), using the instructions in the Load Documents section of [How to use Fiddler with Azure Search](search-fiddler.md). You can then follow the remaining steps in that article to run some queries.\n\nOnce you are comfortable with the basic index, consider adding a language analyzer or suggester to add multilanguage support or type-ahead suggestions. Both features are specified in the index schema. See [Language Support](https://msdn.microsoft.com/elibrary/azure/dn879793.aspx) and [Create Index](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn798941.aspx) for more information.\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/search-create-index-portal/AzureSearch-PortalIndex-1.PNG\n[2]: ./media/search-create-index-portal/AzureSearch-PortalIndex-2.PNG\n[3]: ./media/search-create-index-portal/AzureSearch-PortalIndex-3.PNG\n[4]: ./media/search-create-index-portal/AzureSearch-PortalIndex-4.PNG\n[5]: ./media/search-create-index-portal/AzureSearch-PortalIndex-5.PNG\n"
}