{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Create a virtual network with a site-to-site VPN connection using Azure Resource Manager and PowerShell | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a site-to-site VPN connection from your virtual network to your on-premises location by using Azure Resource Manager and PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        165,
        303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a virtual network with a site-to-site VPN connection using Azure Resource Manager and PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        641,
        744
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[AZURE.SELECTOR]",
      "pos": [
        748,
        764
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Portal",
      "pos": [
        768,
        780
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell - Resource Manager",
      "pos": [
        821,
        850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic will walk you through creating an Azure Resource Manager virtual network and a site-to-site VPN connection to your on-premises network.",
      "pos": [
        904,
        1050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure currently has two deployment models: the classic deployment model, and the Azure Resource Manager deployment model.",
      "pos": [
        1053,
        1174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The site-to-site setup is different, depending on the model that was used to deploy your virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        1175,
        1280
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These instructions apply to Resource Manager.",
      "pos": [
        1281,
        1326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to create a site-to-site VPN gateway connection using the classic deployment model, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a site-to-site VPN connection in the Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-site-to-site-create.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1327,
        1527
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you begin",
      "pos": [
        1533,
        1549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you begin, verify that you have the following:",
      "pos": [
        1551,
        1604
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A compatible VPN device (and someone who is able to configure it).",
      "pos": [
        1608,
        1674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About VPN Devices<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-vpn-devices.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1675,
        1727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An externally-facing public IP address for your VPN device.",
      "pos": [
        1730,
        1789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This IP address cannot be located behind a NAT.",
      "pos": [
        1790,
        1837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The latest version of Azure PowerShell cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        1840,
        1887
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download and install the latest version from the Windows PowerShell section of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Download page<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/downloads/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1888,
        2034
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Azure subscription.",
      "pos": [
        2038,
        2060
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don't already have an Azure subscription, you can activate your <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>MSDN subscriber benefits<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/member-offers/msdn-benefits-details/)</ept> or sign up for a <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>free trial<ept id=\"p2\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2061,
        2310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connect to your subscription",
      "pos": [
        2320,
        2348
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open your PowerShell console and switch to the Azure Resource Manager mode.",
      "pos": [
        2352,
        2427
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following sample to help you connect:",
      "pos": [
        2428,
        2473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the Select-AzureSubscription to connect to the subscription that you want to use.",
      "pos": [
        2501,
        2586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, switch to the ARM mode.",
      "pos": [
        2641,
        2670
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will switch the mode to allow you to use the ARM cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        2671,
        2733
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a virtual network and a gateway subnet",
      "pos": [
        2792,
        2837
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2841,
        2971
      ],
      "content": "If you already have a virtual network with a gateway subnet, you can go jump ahead to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Add your local site<ept id=\"p1\">](#add-your-local-site)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2975,
        3109
      ],
      "content": "If you have a virtual network and you want to add a gateway subnet to your VNet, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Add a gateway subnet to a VNet<ept id=\"p1\">](#gatewaysubnet)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a virtual network and a gateway subnet",
      "pos": [
        3115,
        3163
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the sample below to create a virtual network and a gateway subnet.",
      "pos": [
        3165,
        3235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Substitute the values for your own.",
      "pos": [
        3236,
        3271
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "First, create a Resource Group:",
      "pos": [
        3274,
        3305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, create your virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        3377,
        3411
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The sample below creates a virtual network named <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>testvnet<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> and two subnets, one called <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>GatewaySubnet<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> and the other called <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>Subnet1<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3412,
        3547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's important to create one subnet named specifically <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>GatewaySubnet<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3548,
        3619
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you name it something else, your connection configuration will fail.",
      "pos": [
        3620,
        3691
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4050,
        4111
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"gatewaysubnet\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>To add a gateway subnet to a VNet"
    },
    {
      "content": "If you already have an existing virtual network and you want to add a gateway subnet to it, you can create your gateway subnet by using the sample below.",
      "pos": [
        4113,
        4266
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Be sure to name the gateway subnet 'GatewaySubnet'.",
      "pos": [
        4267,
        4318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you name it something else, your VPN configuration will not work as expected.",
      "pos": [
        4319,
        4399
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add your local site",
      "pos": [
        4661,
        4680
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In a virtual network, the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>local site<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> typically refers to your on-premises location.",
      "pos": [
        4682,
        4767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll give that site a name by which Azure can refer to it.",
      "pos": [
        4768,
        4828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll also specify the address space prefix for the local site.",
      "pos": [
        4831,
        4895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure will use the IP address prefix you specify to identify which traffic to send to the local site.",
      "pos": [
        4896,
        4997
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that you'll have to specify each address prefix that you want to be associated with the local site.",
      "pos": [
        4998,
        5108
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can easily update these prefixes if your on-premises network changes.",
      "pos": [
        5109,
        5182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the PowerShell samples below to specify your local site.",
      "pos": [
        5183,
        5243
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>GatewayIPAddress<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is the IP address of your on-premises VPN device.",
      "pos": [
        5253,
        5325
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your VPN device cannot be located behind a NAT.",
      "pos": [
        5326,
        5373
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5377,
        5431
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>AddressPrefix<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is your on-premises address space."
    },
    {
      "content": "Use this example to add a local site with a single address prefix.",
      "pos": [
        5433,
        5499
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to add a local site with multiple address prefixes, use this example.",
      "pos": [
        5665,
        5746
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To add additional address prefixes to a local site that you already created, use the example below.",
      "pos": [
        5929,
        6028
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To remove an address prefix from a local site, use the example below.",
      "pos": [
        6245,
        6314
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Leave out the prefixes that you no longer need.",
      "pos": [
        6315,
        6362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example, we no longer need prefix 20.0.0.0/24 (from the previous example), so we will update the local site and exclude that prefix.",
      "pos": [
        6363,
        6503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Request a public IP address for the VNet gateway",
      "pos": [
        6708,
        6756
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, you'll request a public IP address to be allocated to your Azure VNet VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        6758,
        6846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is not the same IP address that is assigned to your VPN device, rather it's assigned to the Azure VPN gateway itself.",
      "pos": [
        6847,
        6969
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot specify the IP address that you want to use; it is dynamically allocated to your gateway.",
      "pos": [
        6970,
        7070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll use this IP address when configuring your on-premises VPN device to connect to the gateway.",
      "pos": [
        7071,
        7169
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the PowerShell sample below.",
      "pos": [
        7171,
        7203
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Allocation Method for this address must be Dynamic.",
      "pos": [
        7204,
        7259
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create the gateway IP addressing configuration",
      "pos": [
        7391,
        7437
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The gateway configuration defines the subnet and the public IP address to use.",
      "pos": [
        7439,
        7517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the sample below to create your gateway configuration.",
      "pos": [
        7518,
        7576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create the gateway",
      "pos": [
        7894,
        7912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this step, you'll create the virtual network gateway.",
      "pos": [
        7914,
        7970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following values:",
      "pos": [
        7971,
        7996
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8000,
        8026
      ],
      "content": "The Gateway Type is <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Vpn<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "The VpnType can be RouteBased* (referred to as a Dynamic Gateway in some documentation), or <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Policy Based<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> (referred to as a Static Gateway in some documentation).",
      "pos": [
        8029,
        8192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about VPN gateway types, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About VPN Gateways<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-about-vpngateways.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8193,
        8298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure your VPN device",
      "pos": [
        8476,
        8501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At this point, you'll need the public IP address of the virtual network gateway for configuring your on-premises VPN device.",
      "pos": [
        8503,
        8627
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Work with your device manufacturer for specific configuration information.",
      "pos": [
        8628,
        8702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additionally, refer to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>VPN Devices<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=615099)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        8703,
        8814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To find the public IP address of your virtual network gateway, use the following sample:",
      "pos": [
        8816,
        8904
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create the VPN connection",
      "pos": [
        8977,
        9002
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, you'll create the site-to-site VPN connection between your virtual network gateway and your VPN device.",
      "pos": [
        9004,
        9113
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Be sure to replace the values for your own.",
      "pos": [
        9114,
        9157
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The shared key must match the value you used for your VPN device configuration.",
      "pos": [
        9158,
        9237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After a few minutes, the connection should be established.",
      "pos": [
        9655,
        9713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At this time, the site-to-site VPN connections created with Resource Manager are not visible in the Portal.",
      "pos": [
        9714,
        9821
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        9827,
        9837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add a virtual machine to your virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        9839,
        9885
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a Virtual Machine<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-machines/virtual-machines-windows-tutorial.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9886,
        9971
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Create a virtual network with a site-to-site VPN connection using Azure Resource Manager and PowerShell | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Create a site-to-site VPN connection from your virtual network to your on-premises location by using Azure Resource Manager and PowerShell\"\n   services=\"vpn-gateway\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   authors=\"cherylmc\"\n   manager=\"carolz\"\n   editor=\"\"\n   tags=\"azure-resource-manager\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"vpn-gateway\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"08/21/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"cherylmc\"/>\n\n# Create a virtual network with a site-to-site VPN connection using Azure Resource Manager and PowerShell\n\n> [AZURE.SELECTOR]\n- [Azure Portal](vpn-gateway-site-to-site-create.md)\n- [PowerShell - Resource Manager](vpn-gateway-create-site-to-site-rm-powershell.md)\n\n\nThis topic will walk you through creating an Azure Resource Manager virtual network and a site-to-site VPN connection to your on-premises network. \n\nAzure currently has two deployment models: the classic deployment model, and the Azure Resource Manager deployment model. The site-to-site setup is different, depending on the model that was used to deploy your virtual network.\nThese instructions apply to Resource Manager. If you want to create a site-to-site VPN gateway connection using the classic deployment model, see [Create a site-to-site VPN connection in the Management Portal](vpn-gateway-site-to-site-create.md).\n\n\n## Before you begin\n\nBefore you begin, verify that you have the following:\n\n- A compatible VPN device (and someone who is able to configure it). See [About VPN Devices](vpn-gateway-vpn-devices.md).\n- An externally-facing public IP address for your VPN device. This IP address cannot be located behind a NAT.\n- The latest version of Azure PowerShell cmdlets. You can download and install the latest version from the Windows PowerShell section of the [Download page](http://azure.microsoft.com/downloads/). \n- An Azure subscription. If you don't already have an Azure subscription, you can activate your [MSDN subscriber benefits](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/member-offers/msdn-benefits-details/) or sign up for a [free trial](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/).\n    \n\n## Connect to your subscription \n\n\nOpen your PowerShell console and switch to the Azure Resource Manager mode. Use the following sample to help you connect:\n\n        Add-AzureAccount\n\nUse the Select-AzureSubscription to connect to the subscription that you want to use.\n\n        Select-AzureSubscription \"yoursubscription\"\n\nNext, switch to the ARM mode. This will switch the mode to allow you to use the ARM cmdlets.\n\n        Switch-AzureMode -Name AzureResourceManager\n\n\n## Create a virtual network and a gateway subnet\n\n- If you already have a virtual network with a gateway subnet, you can go jump ahead to [Add your local site](#add-your-local-site). \n- If you have a virtual network and you want to add a gateway subnet to your VNet, see [Add a gateway subnet to a VNet](#gatewaysubnet).\n\n### To create a virtual network and a gateway subnet\n\nUse the sample below to create a virtual network and a gateway subnet. Substitute the values for your own. \n\nFirst, create a Resource Group:\n\n    \n        New-AzureResourceGroup -Name testrg -Location 'West US'\n\nNext, create your virtual network. The sample below creates a virtual network named *testvnet* and two subnets, one called *GatewaySubnet* and the other called *Subnet1*. It's important to create one subnet named specifically *GatewaySubnet*. If you name it something else, your connection configuration will fail.\n\n        $subnet1 = New-AzureVirtualNetworkSubnetConfig -Name 'GatewaySubnet' -AddressPrefix 10.0.0.0/28\n        $subnet2 = New-AzureVirtualNetworkSubnetConfig -Name 'Subnet1' -AddressPrefix '10.0.1.0/28'\n        New-AzurevirtualNetwork -Name testvnet -ResourceGroupName testrg -Location 'West US' -AddressPrefix 10.0.0.0/16 -Subnet $subnet1, $subnet2\n\n\n### <a name=\"gatewaysubnet\"></a>To add a gateway subnet to a VNet\n\nIf you already have an existing virtual network and you want to add a gateway subnet to it, you can create your gateway subnet by using the sample below. Be sure to name the gateway subnet 'GatewaySubnet'. If you name it something else, your VPN configuration will not work as expected.\n\n\n    \n        $vnet = Get-AzureVirtualNetwork -ResourceGroupName testrg -Name testvnet\n        Add-AzureVirtualNetworkSubnetConfig -Name 'GatewaySubnet' -AddressPrefix 10.0.3.0/28 -VirtualNetwork $vnet\n        Set-AzureVirtualNetwork -VirtualNetwork $vnet\n\n## Add your local site\n\nIn a virtual network, the *local site* typically refers to your on-premises location. You'll give that site a name by which Azure can refer to it. \n\nYou'll also specify the address space prefix for the local site. Azure will use the IP address prefix you specify to identify which traffic to send to the local site. This means that you'll have to specify each address prefix that you want to be associated with the local site. You can easily update these prefixes if your on-premises network changes. Use the PowerShell samples below to specify your local site. \n\n    \n- The *GatewayIPAddress* is the IP address of your on-premises VPN device. Your VPN device cannot be located behind a NAT. \n- The *AddressPrefix* is your on-premises address space.\n\nUse this example to add a local site with a single address prefix.\n\n        New-AzureLocalNetworkGateway -Name LocalSite -ResourceGroupName testrg -Location 'West US' -GatewayIpAddress '23.99.221.164' -AddressPrefix '10.5.51.0/24'\n\nIf you want to add a local site with multiple address prefixes, use this example.\n\n        New-AzureLocalNetworkGateway -Name LocalSite -ResourceGroupName testrg -Location 'West US' -GatewayIpAddress '23.99.221.164' -AddressPrefix @('10.0.0.0/24','20.0.0.0/24')\n\n\nTo add additional address prefixes to a local site that you already created, use the example below.\n\n        $local = Get-AzureLocalNetworkGateway -Name LocalSite -ResourceGroupName testrg\n        Set-AzureLocalNetworkGateway -LocalNetworkGateway $local -AddressPrefix @('10.0.0.0/24','20.0.0.0/24','30.0.0.0/24')\n\n\nTo remove an address prefix from a local site, use the example below. Leave out the prefixes that you no longer need. In this example, we no longer need prefix 20.0.0.0/24 (from the previous example), so we will update the local site and exclude that prefix.\n\n        local = Get-AzureLocalNetworkGateway -Name LocalSite -ResourceGroupName testrg\n        Set-AzureLocalNetworkGateway -LocalNetworkGateway $local -AddressPrefix @('10.0.0.0/24','30.0.0.0/24')\n\n\n## Request a public IP address for the VNet gateway\n\nNext, you'll request a public IP address to be allocated to your Azure VNet VPN gateway. This is not the same IP address that is assigned to your VPN device, rather it's assigned to the Azure VPN gateway itself. You cannot specify the IP address that you want to use; it is dynamically allocated to your gateway. You'll use this IP address when configuring your on-premises VPN device to connect to the gateway.\n\nUse the PowerShell sample below. The Allocation Method for this address must be Dynamic. \n\n        $gwpip= New-AzurePublicIpAddress -Name gwpip -ResourceGroupName testrg -Location 'West US' -AllocationMethod Dynamic\n\n## Create the gateway IP addressing configuration\n\nThe gateway configuration defines the subnet and the public IP address to use. Use the sample below to create your gateway configuration. \n\n\n        $vnet = Get-AzureVirtualNetwork -Name testvnet -ResourceGroupName testrg\n        $subnet = Get-AzureVirtualNetworkSubnetConfig -Name 'GatewaySubnet' -VirtualNetwork $vnet\n        $gwipconfig = New-AzureVirtualNetworkGatewayIpConfig -Name gwipconfig1 -SubnetId $subnet.Id -PublicIpAddressId $gwpip.Id \n\n\n## Create the gateway\n\nIn this step, you'll create the virtual network gateway. Use the following values:\n\n- The Gateway Type is *Vpn*.\n- The VpnType can be RouteBased* (referred to as a Dynamic Gateway in some documentation), or *Policy Based* (referred to as a Static Gateway in some documentation). For more information about VPN gateway types, see [About VPN Gateways](vpn-gateway-about-vpngateways.md).     \n\n        New-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway -Name vnetgw1 -ResourceGroupName testrg -Location 'West US' -IpConfigurations $gwipconfig -GatewayType Vpn -VpnType RouteBased\n\n\n## Configure your VPN device\n\nAt this point, you'll need the public IP address of the virtual network gateway for configuring your on-premises VPN device. Work with your device manufacturer for specific configuration information. Additionally, refer to the [VPN Devices](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=615099) for more information.\n\nTo find the public IP address of your virtual network gateway, use the following sample:\n\n    Get-AzurePublicIpAddress -Name gwpip -ResourceGroupName testrg\n\n## Create the VPN connection\n\nNext, you'll create the site-to-site VPN connection between your virtual network gateway and your VPN device. Be sure to replace the values for your own. The shared key must match the value you used for your VPN device configuration.\n\n        $gateway1 = Get-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway -Name vnetgw1 -ResourceGroupName testrg\n        $local = Get-AzureLocalNetworkGateway -Name LocalSite -ResourceGroupName testrg\n\n        New-AzureVirtualNetworkGatewayConnection -Name localtovon -ResourceGroupName testrg -Location 'West US' -VirtualNetworkGateway1 $gateway1 -LocalNetworkGateway2 $local -ConnectionType IPsec -RoutingWeight 10 -SharedKey 'abc123'\n\nAfter a few minutes, the connection should be established. At this time, the site-to-site VPN connections created with Resource Manager are not visible in the Portal.\n\n\n## Next Steps\n\nAdd a virtual machine to your virtual network. [Create a Virtual Machine](../virtual-machines/virtual-machines-windows-tutorial.md)."
}