{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Create an Azure Search service in the portal",
      "pos": [
        27,
        71
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add a free or standard Azure Search service to an existing subscription using the management portal",
      "pos": [
        90,
        189
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create an Azure Search service in the portal",
      "pos": [
        522,
        566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Azure Search is a new service that allows you to embed search functionality into custom applications.",
      "pos": [
        568,
        679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It provides a search engine and storage of your search data, which you access and manage using the portal, a .NET SDK, or a REST API.",
      "pos": [
        680,
        813
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Key features include auto-complete queries, fuzzy matching, hit-highlighting, faceted navigation, and multi-language support.",
      "pos": [
        814,
        939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about what Search does, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Introducing Azure Search<ept id=\"p1\">](fundamentals-azure-search-chappell/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        940,
        1053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add Search to your subscription",
      "pos": [
        1057,
        1088
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As an administrator, you can add Search to an existing subscription at no cost when choosing the shared service, or at the standard rate when opting in for dedicated resources.",
      "pos": [
        1092,
        1268
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1273,
        1325
      ],
      "content": "Sign in to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://portal.azure.com)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1330,
        1394
      ],
      "content": "In the Jumpbar, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> | <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Data + storage<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> | <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Search<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "![][1]",
      "pos": [
        1401,
        1407
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure the service name, pricing tier, resource group, subscription and location.",
      "pos": [
        1412,
        1496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These settings are required and cannot be changed once the service is provisioned.",
      "pos": [
        1497,
        1579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][2]",
      "pos": [
        1586,
        1592
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Service name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> must be unique, lower-case, under 15 characters, with no spaces.",
      "pos": [
        1600,
        1681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This name becomes part of the endpoint of your Azure Search service.",
      "pos": [
        1682,
        1750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Naming Rules<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn857353.aspx)</ept> for more information about naming conventions.",
      "pos": [
        1751,
        1872
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pricing Tier<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> determines capacity and billing.",
      "pos": [
        1880,
        1929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both tiers provide the same features, but at different resource levels.",
      "pos": [
        1930,
        2001
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Free<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>  runs on clusters that are shared with other subscribers.",
      "pos": [
        2013,
        2079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It offers enough capacity to try out tutorials and write proof-of-concept code, but is not intended for production applications.",
      "pos": [
        2080,
        2208
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploying a free service typically only takes a few minutes.",
      "pos": [
        2209,
        2269
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> runs on dedicated resources and is highly scalable.",
      "pos": [
        2280,
        2344
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Initially, a standard service is provisioned with one replica and one partition, but you can adjust capacity once the service is created.",
      "pos": [
        2345,
        2482
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploying a standard service takes longer, usually about fifteen minutes.",
      "pos": [
        2483,
        2556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Resource Groups<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> are containers for services and resources used for a common purpose.",
      "pos": [
        2564,
        2652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you're building a custom search application based on Azure Search, Azure Websites, Azure BLOB storage, you could create a resource group that keeps these services together in the portal management pages.",
      "pos": [
        2653,
        2872
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2880,
        2987
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Subscription<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> allows you to choose among multiple subscriptions, if you have more than one subscription."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Location<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is the data center region.",
      "pos": [
        2995,
        3034
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Currently, all resources must run in the same data center.",
      "pos": [
        3035,
        3093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Distributing resources across multiple data centers is not supported.",
      "pos": [
        3094,
        3163
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3168,
        3210
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to provision the service."
    },
    {
      "content": "Watch for notifications in the Jumpbar.",
      "pos": [
        3212,
        3251
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A notice will appear when the service is ready to use.",
      "pos": [
        3252,
        3306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Find the service name and api-keys of your Azure Search service",
      "pos": [
        3329,
        3392
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the service is created, you can return to the portal to get the URL or <ph id=\"ph1\">`api-key`</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        3394,
        3481
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connections to your Search service requires that you have both the URL and an <ph id=\"ph1\">`api-key`</ph> to authenticate the call.",
      "pos": [
        3482,
        3595
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3600,
        3695
      ],
      "content": "In the Jumpbar, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Home<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and then click the Search service to open the service dashboard."
    },
    {
      "content": "On the service dashboard, you'll see tiles for essential information, as well as the key icon for accessing the admin keys.",
      "pos": [
        3700,
        3823
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][3]",
      "pos": [
        3829,
        3835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the service URL and an admin key.",
      "pos": [
        3840,
        3878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will need them for your next task, <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Test service operations<ept id=\"p1\">](#sub-4)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3879,
        3952
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Upgrade to standard tier",
      "pos": [
        3975,
        3999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Many customers start with the free service, and then upgrade to the standard tier when query performance or storage becomes inadequate for the workloads you need to run.",
      "pos": [
        4001,
        4170
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The standard tier gives you dedicated resources in an Azure data center that can be used only by you.",
      "pos": [
        4171,
        4272
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Search operations require both storage and service replicas.",
      "pos": [
        4273,
        4333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you sign up for standard search, you can optimize service configuration to use more of whichever resource is the most important to your scenario.",
      "pos": [
        4334,
        4484
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use the standard tier, repeat the previous steps in this article to create a new Search service, choosing the Standard pricing tier.",
      "pos": [
        4486,
        4621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that setting up dedicated resources can take a while, up to 15 minutes or longer.",
      "pos": [
        4622,
        4708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There is no in-place upgrade of the free version.",
      "pos": [
        4710,
        4759
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Switching to standard, with its potential for scale, requires a new service.",
      "pos": [
        4760,
        4836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will need to reload the indexes and documents used by your search application.",
      "pos": [
        4837,
        4919
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A Search service at the standard tier is created with one replica and partition each, but can be easily re-scaled at higher resource levels.",
      "pos": [
        4921,
        5061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Return to the service dashboard after the service is created.",
      "pos": [
        5067,
        5128
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5134,
        5159
      ],
      "content": "Click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Scale<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tile."
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the sliders to add replicas, partitions, or both.",
      "pos": [
        5165,
        5218
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additional replicas and partitions are billed in terms of search units.",
      "pos": [
        5220,
        5291
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The total search units required to support any particular resource configuration is shown on the page, as you add resources.",
      "pos": [
        5292,
        5416
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can check <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Pricing Details<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=509792)</ept> to get the per-unit billing information.",
      "pos": [
        5418,
        5539
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Limits and constraints<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn798934.aspx)</ept> for help in deciding how to configure partition and replica combinations.",
      "pos": [
        5540,
        5697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test service operations",
      "pos": [
        5720,
        5743
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Confirming that your service is operational and accessible from a client application is the final step in configuring Search.",
      "pos": [
        5745,
        5870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use either of the links below for a code-free approach to verifying service availability.",
      "pos": [
        5871,
        5968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to use Chrome Postman with Azure Search",
      "pos": [
        5973,
        6016
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to use Telerik Fiddler with Azure Search",
      "pos": [
        6047,
        6091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">\n&lt;a id=\"next-steps\"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</ph>\n##Next steps\n\nThe following additional material shows you how to build and manage search applications that use Azure Search.",
      "pos": [
        6141,
        6290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">- [</bpt><ept id=\"p1\">How to use Azure Search in .NET](search-howto-dotnet-sdk.md)</ept><bpt id=\"p2\">\n\n- [</bpt><ept id=\"p2\">Manage your search solution in Microsoft Azure](search-manage.md)</ept><bpt id=\"p3\">\n\n- [</bpt><ept id=\"p3\">Azure Search on MSDN](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn798933.aspx)</ept><bpt id=\"p4\">\n\n- [</bpt><ept id=\"p4\">Channel 9 video: Introduction to Azure Search](http://channel9.msdn.com/Shows/Data-Exposed/Introduction-To-Azure-Search)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">\n\n\n</ph>",
      "pos": [
        6292,
        6628
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Create an Azure Search service in the portal\"\n    description=\"Add a free or standard Azure Search service to an existing subscription using the management portal\"\n    services=\"search\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"HeidiSteen\"\n    manager=\"mblythe\"\n    editor=\"\"\n    tags=\"azure-portal\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"search\"\n    ms.devlang=\"rest-api\"\n    ms.workload=\"search\"\n    ms.topic=\"get-started-article\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.date=\"07/08/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"heidist\"/>\n\n# Create an Azure Search service in the portal\n\nMicrosoft Azure Search is a new service that allows you to embed search functionality into custom applications. It provides a search engine and storage of your search data, which you access and manage using the portal, a .NET SDK, or a REST API. Key features include auto-complete queries, fuzzy matching, hit-highlighting, faceted navigation, and multi-language support. For more information about what Search does, see [Introducing Azure Search](fundamentals-azure-search-chappell/).\n\n##Add Search to your subscription  \n\nAs an administrator, you can add Search to an existing subscription at no cost when choosing the shared service, or at the standard rate when opting in for dedicated resources.\n\n1. Sign in to [Azure portal](https://portal.azure.com).\n\n2. In the Jumpbar, click **New** | **Data + storage** | **Search**.\n\n     ![][1]\n\n3. Configure the service name, pricing tier, resource group, subscription and location. These settings are required and cannot be changed once the service is provisioned.\n\n     ![][2]\n\n    - **Service name** must be unique, lower-case, under 15 characters, with no spaces. This name becomes part of the endpoint of your Azure Search service. See [Naming Rules](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn857353.aspx) for more information about naming conventions.\n\n    - **Pricing Tier** determines capacity and billing. Both tiers provide the same features, but at different resource levels.\n\n        - **Free**  runs on clusters that are shared with other subscribers. It offers enough capacity to try out tutorials and write proof-of-concept code, but is not intended for production applications. Deploying a free service typically only takes a few minutes.\n        - **Standard** runs on dedicated resources and is highly scalable. Initially, a standard service is provisioned with one replica and one partition, but you can adjust capacity once the service is created. Deploying a standard service takes longer, usually about fifteen minutes.\n\n    - **Resource Groups** are containers for services and resources used for a common purpose. For example, if you're building a custom search application based on Azure Search, Azure Websites, Azure BLOB storage, you could create a resource group that keeps these services together in the portal management pages.\n\n    - **Subscription** allows you to choose among multiple subscriptions, if you have more than one subscription.\n\n    - **Location** is the data center region. Currently, all resources must run in the same data center. Distributing resources across multiple data centers is not supported.\n\n4. Click **Create** to provision the service.\n\nWatch for notifications in the Jumpbar. A notice will appear when the service is ready to use.\n\n<a id=\"sub-2\"></a>\n##Find the service name and api-keys of your Azure Search service\n\nAfter the service is created, you can return to the portal to get the URL or `api-key`. Connections to your Search service requires that you have both the URL and an `api-key` to authenticate the call.\n\n1. In the Jumpbar, click **Home** and then click the Search service to open the service dashboard.\n\n2. On the service dashboard, you'll see tiles for essential information, as well as the key icon for accessing the admin keys.\n\n    ![][3]\n\n3. Copy the service URL and an admin key. You will need them for your next task, [Test service operations](#sub-4).\n\n<a id=\"sub-3\"></a>\n##Upgrade to standard tier\n\nMany customers start with the free service, and then upgrade to the standard tier when query performance or storage becomes inadequate for the workloads you need to run. The standard tier gives you dedicated resources in an Azure data center that can be used only by you. Search operations require both storage and service replicas. When you sign up for standard search, you can optimize service configuration to use more of whichever resource is the most important to your scenario.\n\nTo use the standard tier, repeat the previous steps in this article to create a new Search service, choosing the Standard pricing tier. Note that setting up dedicated resources can take a while, up to 15 minutes or longer.\n\nThere is no in-place upgrade of the free version. Switching to standard, with its potential for scale, requires a new service. You will need to reload the indexes and documents used by your search application.\n\nA Search service at the standard tier is created with one replica and partition each, but can be easily re-scaled at higher resource levels.\n\n1.  Return to the service dashboard after the service is created.\n\n2.  Click the **Scale** tile.\n\n3.  Use the sliders to add replicas, partitions, or both.\n\nAdditional replicas and partitions are billed in terms of search units. The total search units required to support any particular resource configuration is shown on the page, as you add resources.\n\nYou can check [Pricing Details](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=509792) to get the per-unit billing information. See [Limits and constraints](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn798934.aspx) for help in deciding how to configure partition and replica combinations.\n\n<a id=\"sub-4\"></a>\n##Test service operations\n\nConfirming that your service is operational and accessible from a client application is the final step in configuring Search. You can use either of the links below for a code-free approach to verifying service availability.\n\n- [How to use Chrome Postman with Azure Search](search-chrome-postman.md)\n- [How to use Telerik Fiddler with Azure Search](search-fiddler.md)\n\n<!--Next steps and links -->\n<a id=\"next-steps\"></a>\n##Next steps\n\nThe following additional material shows you how to build and manage search applications that use Azure Search.\n\n- [How to use Azure Search in .NET](search-howto-dotnet-sdk.md)\n\n- [Manage your search solution in Microsoft Azure](search-manage.md)\n\n- [Azure Search on MSDN](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn798933.aspx)\n\n- [Channel 9 video: Introduction to Azure Search](http://channel9.msdn.com/Shows/Data-Exposed/Introduction-To-Azure-Search)\n\n\n<!--Anchors-->\n[Find the service name and api-keys of your Azure Search service]: #sub-2\n[Upgrade to standard tier]: #sub-3\n[Test service operations]: #sub-4\n[Next steps]: #next-steps\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/search-create-service-portal/create-search-portal-1.PNG\n[2]: ./media/search-create-service-portal/create-search-portal-2.PNG\n[3]: ./media/search-create-service-portal/create-search-portal-3.PNG\n"
}