{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Multi-Geo Help documentation | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        72
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to create a workspace and publish a web service in an Azure region different from the South Central United States (SCUS) Azure region.",
      "pos": [
        90,
        234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Multi-Geo Help documentation",
      "pos": [
        551,
        579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Currently, all Azure Machine Learning assets are hosted in the South Central United States (SCUS) Azure region.",
      "pos": [
        581,
        692
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article describes how you can create a workspace and publish a web service in other Azure regions.",
      "pos": [
        693,
        796
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a workspace",
      "pos": [
        801,
        819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign in to the Azure Management Portal.",
      "pos": [
        824,
        863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>+NEW<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DATA SERVICES<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>MACHINE LEARNING<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>QUICK CREATE<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        869,
        946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>LOCATION<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select another region, such as <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Southeast Asia<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        948,
        1017
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![Multi-Geo Help image 1][1]",
      "pos": [
        1018,
        1046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the workspace, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sign-in to ML Studio<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1050,
        1112
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![Multi-Geo Help image 2][2]",
      "pos": [
        1113,
        1141
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You now have a workspace in another region that you may use just like any other workspace.",
      "pos": [
        1146,
        1236
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To switch among your workspaces, look to the upper right of your screen.",
      "pos": [
        1237,
        1309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the dropdown, select the region, and then select the workspace.",
      "pos": [
        1310,
        1379
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Everything is local to the workspace region; for example, all of your web services created from a workspace will be in the same region the workspace is located in.",
      "pos": [
        1380,
        1543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![Multi-Geo Help image 3][3]",
      "pos": [
        1544,
        1572
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open an experiment from Gallery",
      "pos": [
        1577,
        1608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you open an experiment from Gallery, you can also select which region you want to copy the experiment to.",
      "pos": [
        1610,
        1718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![Multi-Geo Help image 4][4a]",
      "pos": [
        1720,
        1749
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Web service management",
      "pos": [
        1754,
        1776
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1778,
        1924
      ],
      "content": "To programmatically manage web services, such as for retraining, use the region-specific address: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>https://asiasoutheast.management.azureml.net<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Things to note",
      "pos": [
        1930,
        1944
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can only copy experiments between workspaces that belong to the same region.",
      "pos": [
        1950,
        2030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the future, we will enable copying experiments between workspaces across multiple regions.",
      "pos": [
        2031,
        2124
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The region selector will only show workspaces for one region at a time.",
      "pos": [
        2129,
        2200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the future, you will be able to see a full list of workspaces you have access to across all regions at the same time.",
      "pos": [
        2201,
        2321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A free workspace or Guest Access (anonymous) workspace will be created and hosted in South Central U.S.",
      "pos": [
        2328,
        2431
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the future, you will be able to create Free/Guest Access workspaces in the region that you choose.",
      "pos": [
        2432,
        2533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Web services deployed from a workspace in Southeast Asia will also be hosted in Southeast Asia.",
      "pos": [
        2540,
        2635
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the future, you will be able to have the flexibility of creating experiments in one region, and deploying generated web service endpoints into different regions.",
      "pos": [
        2636,
        2800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "More information",
      "pos": [
        2807,
        2823
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2825,
        2953
      ],
      "content": "Ask a question on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Machine Learning forum<ept id=\"p1\">](https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/azure/home?forum=MachineLearning)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "[1]:",
      "pos": [
        2979,
        2983
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Multi-Geo Help documentation | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Learn how to create a workspace and publish a web service in an Azure region different from the South Central United States (SCUS) Azure region.\"\n   services=\"machine-learning\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"tedway\"\n   manager=\"paulettm\"\n   editor=\"rmca14\"\n   tags=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"machine-learning\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"na\"\n   ms.date=\"08/17/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"tedway; neerajkh\"/>\n\n# Multi-Geo Help documentation\n\nCurrently, all Azure Machine Learning assets are hosted in the South Central United States (SCUS) Azure region. This article describes how you can create a workspace and publish a web service in other Azure regions.\n\n## Create a workspace\n\n1. Sign in to the Azure Management Portal.\n\n2.  Click **+NEW** > **DATA SERVICES** > **MACHINE LEARNING** > **QUICK CREATE**.  Under **LOCATION** select another region, such as **Southeast Asia**.\n![Multi-Geo Help image 1][1]\n3. Select the workspace, and then click **Sign-in to ML Studio**.\n![Multi-Geo Help image 2][2]\n\n4. You now have a workspace in another region that you may use just like any other workspace. To switch among your workspaces, look to the upper right of your screen. Click the dropdown, select the region, and then select the workspace. Everything is local to the workspace region; for example, all of your web services created from a workspace will be in the same region the workspace is located in.\n![Multi-Geo Help image 3][3]\n\n## Open an experiment from Gallery\n\nIf you open an experiment from Gallery, you can also select which region you want to copy the experiment to.\n\n![Multi-Geo Help image 4][4a]\n\n## Web service management\n\nTo programmatically manage web services, such as for retraining, use the region-specific address: **https://asiasoutheast.management.azureml.net**\n\n### Things to note\n\n1.  You can only copy experiments between workspaces that belong to the same region. In the future, we will enable copying experiments between workspaces across multiple regions.\n2.  The region selector will only show workspaces for one region at a time. In the future, you will be able to see a full list of workspaces you have access to across all regions at the same time.  \n3.  A free workspace or Guest Access (anonymous) workspace will be created and hosted in South Central U.S. In the future, you will be able to create Free/Guest Access workspaces in the region that you choose.  \n4.  Web services deployed from a workspace in Southeast Asia will also be hosted in Southeast Asia. In the future, you will be able to have the flexibility of creating experiments in one region, and deploying generated web service endpoints into different regions.  \n\n## More information\n\nAsk a question on the [Azure Machine Learning forum](https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/azure/home?forum=MachineLearning).\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/machine-learning-multi-geo/multi-geo_1.png\n[2]: ./media/machine-learning-multi-geo/multi-geo_2.png\n[3]: ./media/machine-learning-multi-geo/multi-geo_3.png\n[4a]: ./media/machine-learning-multi-geo/multi-geo_4a.png\ntest\n"
}