{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Cloud Services - All you want to know about certificates",
      "pos": [
        28,
        90
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to create and use certificates with Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        110,
        171
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Certificates Overview for Azure Cloud Services",
      "pos": [
        482,
        528
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Certificates are used in Azure for cloud services (<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>service certificates<ept id=\"p1\">](#what-are-service-certificates)</ept>) and for authenticating with the management API (<bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>management certificates<ept id=\"p2\">](#what-are-management-certificates)</ept>).",
      "pos": [
        529,
        746
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic gives a general overview of both certificate types, how to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>create<ept id=\"p1\">](#create)</ept> them, and how to <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>deploy<ept id=\"p2\">](#deploy)</ept> them to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        747,
        884
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Certificates used in Azure are x.509 v3 certificates and can be signed by another trusted certificate or they can be self-signed.",
      "pos": [
        886,
        1015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A self-signed certificate is signed by its own creator, and because of this, are not trusted by default.",
      "pos": [
        1016,
        1120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Most browsers can ignore this.",
      "pos": [
        1121,
        1151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Self-signed certificates should only be used by yourself when developing and testing your cloud services.",
      "pos": [
        1152,
        1257
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Certificates used by Azure can contain a private or a public key.",
      "pos": [
        1260,
        1325
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Certificates have a thumbprint that provides a means to identify them in an unambiguous way.",
      "pos": [
        1326,
        1418
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This thumbprint is used in the Azure <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>configuration file<ept id=\"p1\">](cloud-services-configure-ssl-certificate.md)</ept> to identify which certificate a cloud service should use.",
      "pos": [
        1419,
        1579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What are service certificates?",
      "pos": [
        1585,
        1615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service certificates are attached to cloud services and enable secure communication to and from the service.",
      "pos": [
        1616,
        1724
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you deployed a web role, you would want to supply a certificate that can authenticate an exposed HTTPS endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        1725,
        1853
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service certificates, defined in your service definition, are automatically deployed to the virtual machine that is running an instance of your role.",
      "pos": [
        1854,
        2003
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can upload service certificates to Management Portal either using the Management Portal or by using the Service Management API.",
      "pos": [
        2006,
        2137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service certificates are associated with a specific cloud service and assigned to a deployment in the service definition file.",
      "pos": [
        2138,
        2264
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service certificates can be managed separately from your services, and may be managed by different individuals.",
      "pos": [
        2266,
        2377
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, a developer may upload a service package that refers to a certificate that an IT manager has previously uploaded to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        2378,
        2513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An IT manager can manage and renew that certificate changing the configuration of the service without needing to upload a new service package.",
      "pos": [
        2514,
        2656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is possible because the logical name for the certificate and its store name and location are specified in the service definition file, while the certificate thumbprint is specified in the service configuration file.",
      "pos": [
        2657,
        2877
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To update the certificate, it's only necessary to upload a new certificate and change the thumbprint value in the service configuration file.",
      "pos": [
        2878,
        3019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What are management certificates?",
      "pos": [
        3024,
        3057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Management certificates allow you to authenticate with the Service Management API provided by Azure.",
      "pos": [
        3058,
        3158
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Many programs and tools (such as Visual Studio or the Azure SDK) will use these certificates to automate configuration and deployment of various Azure services.",
      "pos": [
        3159,
        3319
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These are not really related to cloud services.",
      "pos": [
        3320,
        3367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.WARNING]</ph> Be careful!",
      "pos": [
        3371,
        3398
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These types of certificates allow anyone who authenticates with them to manage the subscription they are associated with.",
      "pos": [
        3399,
        3520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Limitations",
      "pos": [
        3527,
        3538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There is a limit of 100 management certificates per subscription.",
      "pos": [
        3539,
        3604
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There is also a limit of 100 management certificates for all subscriptions under a specific service administrator’s user ID.",
      "pos": [
        3605,
        3729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the user ID for the account administrator has already been used to add 100 management certificates and there is a need for more certificates, you can add a co-administrator to add the additional certificates.",
      "pos": [
        3730,
        3941
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before adding more than 100 certificates, see if you can reuse an existing certificate.",
      "pos": [
        3944,
        4031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using co-administrators adds potentially unneeded complexity to your certificate management process.",
      "pos": [
        4032,
        4132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a new self-signed certificate",
      "pos": [
        4160,
        4196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use any tool available to create a self-signed certificate as long as they adhere to these settings:",
      "pos": [
        4197,
        4305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An X.509 certificate.",
      "pos": [
        4309,
        4330
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Contains a private key.",
      "pos": [
        4333,
        4356
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Created for key exchange (.pfx file).",
      "pos": [
        4359,
        4396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Subject name must match the domain used to access the cloud service.",
      "pos": [
        4399,
        4467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot acquire an SSL certificate for the cloudapp.net (or for any Azure related) domain; the certificate's subject name must match the custom domain name used to access your application.",
      "pos": [
        4475,
        4666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>contoso.net<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, not <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>contoso.cloudapp.net<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4667,
        4726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Minimum of 2048-bit encryption.",
      "pos": [
        4729,
        4760
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4763,
        4865
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Service Certificate Only<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Client-side certificate must reside in the <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Personal<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> certificate store."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4867,
        4967
      ],
      "content": "There are two easy ways to create a certificate on Windows, with the <ph id=\"ph1\">`makecert.exe`</ph> utility, or IIS."
    },
    {
      "content": "Makecert.exe",
      "pos": [
        4973,
        4985
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This utility is installed with Visual Studio 2013/2015.",
      "pos": [
        4987,
        5042
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is a console utility that allows you to create and install certificates.",
      "pos": [
        5043,
        5118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you launch the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Developer Command Prompt for VS2015<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> shortcut that is created when you install Visual Studio, a command prompt will appear that has this tool in path.",
      "pos": [
        5119,
        5290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Internet Information Services (IIS)",
      "pos": [
        5431,
        5466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are many pages on the internet that cover how to do this with IIS.",
      "pos": [
        5468,
        5540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Here<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.sslshopper.com/article-how-to-create-a-self-signed-certificate-in-iis-7.html)</ept> is a great one I found that I think explains it well.",
      "pos": [
        5541,
        5691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Java",
      "pos": [
        5698,
        5702
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5703,
        5831
      ],
      "content": "You can use Java to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>create a certificate<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service-web/java-create-azure-website-using-java-sdk.md#create-a-certificate)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        5836,
        5846
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5848,
        6097
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Upload your service certificate to the Azure Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](cloud-services-configure-ssl-certificate.md)</ept> (or the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Preview Portal<ept id=\"p2\">](cloud-services-configure-ssl-certificate-portal.md)</ept>) and <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>configure them<ept id=\"p3\">](cloud-services-xml-certs.md)</ept> for the cloud service."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6099,
        6191
      ],
      "content": "Upload a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>management API certificate<ept id=\"p1\">](../azure-api-management-certs.md)</ept> to the Azure Portal."
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> The Azure Preview Portal does not use management certificates to access the API but instead uses user accounts.",
      "pos": [
        6194,
        6318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        6319,
        6323
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Azure Cloud Services - All you want to know about certificates\" \n    description=\"Learn how to create and use certificates with Microsoft Azure\" \n    services=\"cloud-services\" \n    documentationCenter=\".net\" \n    authors=\"Thraka\" \n    manager=\"timlt\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"cloud-services\" \n    ms.workload=\"tbd\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"07/16/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"adegeo\"/>\n\n# Certificates Overview for Azure Cloud Services\nCertificates are used in Azure for cloud services ([service certificates](#what-are-service-certificates)) and for authenticating with the management API ([management certificates](#what-are-management-certificates)). This topic gives a general overview of both certificate types, how to [create](#create) them, and how to [deploy](#deploy) them to Azure.\n\nCertificates used in Azure are x.509 v3 certificates and can be signed by another trusted certificate or they can be self-signed. A self-signed certificate is signed by its own creator, and because of this, are not trusted by default. Most browsers can ignore this. Self-signed certificates should only be used by yourself when developing and testing your cloud services. \n\nCertificates used by Azure can contain a private or a public key. Certificates have a thumbprint that provides a means to identify them in an unambiguous way. This thumbprint is used in the Azure [configuration file](cloud-services-configure-ssl-certificate.md) to identify which certificate a cloud service should use. \n\n## What are service certificates?\nService certificates are attached to cloud services and enable secure communication to and from the service. For example, if you deployed a web role, you would want to supply a certificate that can authenticate an exposed HTTPS endpoint. Service certificates, defined in your service definition, are automatically deployed to the virtual machine that is running an instance of your role. \n\nYou can upload service certificates to Management Portal either using the Management Portal or by using the Service Management API. Service certificates are associated with a specific cloud service and assigned to a deployment in the service definition file.\n\nService certificates can be managed separately from your services, and may be managed by different individuals. For example, a developer may upload a service package that refers to a certificate that an IT manager has previously uploaded to Azure. An IT manager can manage and renew that certificate changing the configuration of the service without needing to upload a new service package. This is possible because the logical name for the certificate and its store name and location are specified in the service definition file, while the certificate thumbprint is specified in the service configuration file. To update the certificate, it's only necessary to upload a new certificate and change the thumbprint value in the service configuration file.\n\n## What are management certificates?\nManagement certificates allow you to authenticate with the Service Management API provided by Azure. Many programs and tools (such as Visual Studio or the Azure SDK) will use these certificates to automate configuration and deployment of various Azure services. These are not really related to cloud services. \n\n>[AZURE.WARNING] Be careful! These types of certificates allow anyone who authenticates with them to manage the subscription they are associated with. \n\n### Limitations\nThere is a limit of 100 management certificates per subscription. There is also a limit of 100 management certificates for all subscriptions under a specific service administrator’s user ID. If the user ID for the account administrator has already been used to add 100 management certificates and there is a need for more certificates, you can add a co-administrator to add the additional certificates. \n\nBefore adding more than 100 certificates, see if you can reuse an existing certificate. Using co-administrators adds potentially unneeded complexity to your certificate management process.\n\n\n<a name=\"create\"></a>\n## Create a new self-signed certificate\nYou can use any tool available to create a self-signed certificate as long as they adhere to these settings:\n\n* An X.509 certificate.\n* Contains a private key.\n* Created for key exchange (.pfx file).\n* Subject name must match the domain used to access the cloud service. \n    > You cannot acquire an SSL certificate for the cloudapp.net (or for any Azure related) domain; the certificate's subject name must match the custom domain name used to access your application. For example, **contoso.net**, not **contoso.cloudapp.net**.\n* Minimum of 2048-bit encryption.\n* **Service Certificate Only**: Client-side certificate must reside in the *Personal* certificate store.\n\nThere are two easy ways to create a certificate on Windows, with the `makecert.exe` utility, or IIS.\n\n### Makecert.exe\n\nThis utility is installed with Visual Studio 2013/2015. It is a console utility that allows you to create and install certificates. If you launch the **Developer Command Prompt for VS2015** shortcut that is created when you install Visual Studio, a command prompt will appear that has this tool in path.\n\n    makecert -sky exchange -r -n \"CN=[CertificateName]\" -pe -a sha1 -len 2048 -ss My -sv [CertificateName].pvk [CertificateName].cer\n\n\n### Internet Information Services (IIS)\n\nThere are many pages on the internet that cover how to do this with IIS. [Here](https://www.sslshopper.com/article-how-to-create-a-self-signed-certificate-in-iis-7.html) is a great one I found that I think explains it well. \n\n### Java\nYou can use Java to [create a certificate](../app-service-web/java-create-azure-website-using-java-sdk.md#create-a-certificate).\n\n## Next steps\n\n[Upload your service certificate to the Azure Portal](cloud-services-configure-ssl-certificate.md) (or the [Preview Portal](cloud-services-configure-ssl-certificate-portal.md)) and [configure them](cloud-services-xml-certs.md) for the cloud service.\n\nUpload a [management API certificate](../azure-api-management-certs.md) to the Azure Portal.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] The Azure Preview Portal does not use management certificates to access the API but instead uses user accounts.\ntest\n"
}