{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure RemoteApp image requirements",
      "pos": [
        29,
        63
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn about the requirements for creating images to be used with Azure RemoteApp",
      "pos": [
        82,
        162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Requirements for Azure RemoteApp images",
      "pos": [
        456,
        495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure RemoteApp uses a Windows Server 2012 R2 image to host all the programs that you want to share with your users.",
      "pos": [
        496,
        612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a custom image, you can start with an existing image or <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>create a new one<ept id=\"p1\">](remoteapp-create-custom-image.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        613,
        732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.TIP]</ph> Did you know that your Azure RemoteApp subscription gives you access to a Windows Server 2012 R2 image in the Azure VM gallery that you can use to create your own template image?",
      "pos": [
        737,
        927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Check it out<ept id=\"p1\">](remoteapp-image-on-azurevm.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        928,
        974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The requirements for the image that can be uploaded for use with Azure RemoteApp are:",
      "pos": [
        979,
        1064
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Custom applications don’t store data locally on the image.",
      "pos": [
        1069,
        1127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These images are stateless and should only contain applications.",
      "pos": [
        1128,
        1192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The image does not contain data that can be lost.",
      "pos": [
        1195,
        1244
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The image size should be a multiple of MBs.",
      "pos": [
        1247,
        1290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you try to upload an image that is not an exact multiple, the upload will fail.",
      "pos": [
        1291,
        1373
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The image size must be 127 GB or smaller.",
      "pos": [
        1376,
        1417
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It must be on a VHD file (VHDX files are not currently supported).",
      "pos": [
        1421,
        1487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VHD must not be a generation 2 virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        1490,
        1541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VHD can be either fixed-size or dynamically expanding.",
      "pos": [
        1544,
        1602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A dynamically expanding VHD is recommended because it takes less time to upload to Azure than a fixed-size VHD file.",
      "pos": [
        1603,
        1719
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The disk must be initialized using the Master Boot Record (MBR) partitioning style.",
      "pos": [
        1722,
        1805
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The GUID partition table (GPT) partition style is not supported.",
      "pos": [
        1806,
        1870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VHD must contain a single installation of Windows Server 2012 R2.",
      "pos": [
        1874,
        1943
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It can contain multiple volumes, but only one that contains an installation of Windows.",
      "pos": [
        1944,
        2031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Remote Desktop Session Host (RDSH) role and the Desktop Experience feature must be installed.",
      "pos": [
        2035,
        2132
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2135,
        2201
      ],
      "content": "The Remote Desktop Connection Broker role must <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>not<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> be installed."
    },
    {
      "content": "The Encrypting File System (EFS) must be disabled.",
      "pos": [
        2204,
        2254
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2257,
        2378
      ],
      "content": "The image must be SYSPREPed using the parameters <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>/oobe /generalize /shutdown<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (DO NOT use the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>/mode:vm<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> parameter)."
    },
    {
      "content": "Uploading your VHD from a snapshot chain is not supported.",
      "pos": [
        2381,
        2439
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2442,
        2570
      ],
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create an Azure RemoteApp image<ept id=\"p1\">](remoteapp-imageoptions.md)</ept> for more information about creating images for Azure RemoteApp."
    }
  ],
  "content": "\n<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Azure RemoteApp image requirements\"\n    description=\"Learn about the requirements for creating images to be used with Azure RemoteApp\" \n    services=\"remoteapp\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"lizap\" \n    manager=\"mbaldwin\" />\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"remoteapp\" \n    ms.workload=\"compute\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"08/12/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"elizapo\" />\n\n\n\n# Requirements for Azure RemoteApp images\nAzure RemoteApp uses a Windows Server 2012 R2 image to host all the programs that you want to share with your users. To create a custom image, you can start with an existing image or [create a new one](remoteapp-create-custom-image.md). \n\n> [AZURE.TIP] Did you know that your Azure RemoteApp subscription gives you access to a Windows Server 2012 R2 image in the Azure VM gallery that you can use to create your own template image? [Check it out](remoteapp-image-on-azurevm.md).  \n\n\nThe requirements for the image that can be uploaded for use with Azure RemoteApp are:\n\n\n- Custom applications don’t store data locally on the image. These images are stateless and should only contain applications.\n- The image does not contain data that can be lost.\n- The image size should be a multiple of MBs. If you try to upload an image that is not an exact multiple, the upload will fail.\n- The image size must be 127 GB or smaller. \n- It must be on a VHD file (VHDX files are not currently supported).\n- The VHD must not be a generation 2 virtual machine.\n- The VHD can be either fixed-size or dynamically expanding. A dynamically expanding VHD is recommended because it takes less time to upload to Azure than a fixed-size VHD file.\n- The disk must be initialized using the Master Boot Record (MBR) partitioning style. The GUID partition table (GPT) partition style is not supported. \n- The VHD must contain a single installation of Windows Server 2012 R2. It can contain multiple volumes, but only one that contains an installation of Windows. \n- The Remote Desktop Session Host (RDSH) role and the Desktop Experience feature must be installed.\n- The Remote Desktop Connection Broker role must *not* be installed.\n- The Encrypting File System (EFS) must be disabled.\n- The image must be SYSPREPed using the parameters **/oobe /generalize /shutdown** (DO NOT use the **/mode:vm** parameter).\n- Uploading your VHD from a snapshot chain is not supported.\n \nSee [Create an Azure RemoteApp image](remoteapp-imageoptions.md) for more information about creating images for Azure RemoteApp."
}