{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Use Notification Hubs to send breaking news (Windows Universal)",
      "pos": [
        27,
        90
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use Azure Notification Hubs with tags in the registration to send breaking news to a universal Windows app.",
      "pos": [
        109,
        216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use Notification Hubs to send breaking news",
      "pos": [
        548,
        591
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        717,
        725
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic shows you how to use Azure Notification Hubs to broadcast breaking news notifications to a Windows Store or Windows Phone 8.1 (non-Silverlight) app.",
      "pos": [
        727,
        886
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are targeting Windows Phone 8.1 Silverlight, please refer to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows Phone<ept id=\"p1\">](notification-hubs-ios-send-breaking-news.md)</ept> version.",
      "pos": [
        887,
        1028
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When complete, you will be able to register for breaking news categories you are interested in, and receive only push notifications for those categories.",
      "pos": [
        1029,
        1182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This scenario is a common pattern for many apps where notifications have to be sent to groups of users that have previously declared interest in them, e.g. RSS reader, apps for music fans, and so on.",
      "pos": [
        1183,
        1382
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Broadcast scenarios are enabled by including one or more <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>tags<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> when creating a registration in the notification hub.",
      "pos": [
        1385,
        1502
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When notifications are sent to a tag, all devices that have registered for the tag will receive the notification.",
      "pos": [
        1503,
        1616
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because tags are simply strings, they do not have to be provisioned in advance.",
      "pos": [
        1617,
        1696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about tags, refer to [Notification Hubs Guidance].",
      "pos": [
        1697,
        1768
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        1772,
        1785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic builds on the app you created in [Get started with Notification Hubs][get-started].",
      "pos": [
        1787,
        1881
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before starting this tutorial, you must have already completed [Get started with Notification Hubs][get-started].",
      "pos": [
        1882,
        1995
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add category selection to the app",
      "pos": [
        1999,
        2032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The first step is to add the UI elements to your existing main page that enable the user to select categories to register.",
      "pos": [
        2034,
        2156
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The categories selected by a user are stored on the device.",
      "pos": [
        2157,
        2216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When the app starts, a device registration is created in your notification hub with the selected categories as tags.",
      "pos": [
        2217,
        2333
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2338,
        2428
      ],
      "content": "Open the MainPage.xaml project file, then copy the following code in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Grid<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> element:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3951,
        4149
      ],
      "content": "Right click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Shared<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> project and add a new class named <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Notifications<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, add the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>public<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> modifier to the class definition, then add the following <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>using<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> statements to the new code file:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4324,
        4385
      ],
      "content": "Copy the following code into the new <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Notifications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> class:"
    },
    {
      "content": "This class uses the local storage to store the categories of news that this device has to receive.",
      "pos": [
        5542,
        5640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It also contains methods to register for these categories.",
      "pos": [
        5641,
        5699
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5705,
        5786
      ],
      "content": "In the App.xaml.cs project file, add the following property to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>App<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> class:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5913,
        5985
      ],
      "content": "This property is used to create and access a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Notifications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> instance."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5991,
        6218
      ],
      "content": "In the above code, replace the <ph id=\"ph1\">`&lt;hub name&gt;`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`&lt;connection string with listen access&gt;`</ph> placeholders with your notification hub name and the connection string for <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>DefaultListenSharedAccessSignature<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> that you obtained earlier."
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Because credentials that are distributed with a client app are not generally secure, you should only distribute the key for listen access with your client app.",
      "pos": [
        6226,
        6398
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Listen access enables your app to register for notifications, but existing registrations cannot be modified and notifications cannot be sent.",
      "pos": [
        6399,
        6540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The full access key is used in a secured backend service for sending notifications and changing existing registrations.",
      "pos": [
        6541,
        6660
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In your MainPage.xaml.cs, add the following line:",
      "pos": [
        6665,
        6714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the MainPage.xaml.cs project file, add the following method:",
      "pos": [
        6753,
        6816
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This method creates a list of categories and uses the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Notifications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> class to store the list in the local storage and register the corresponding tags with your notification hub.",
      "pos": [
        7648,
        7828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When categories are changed, the registration is recreated with the new categories.",
      "pos": [
        7829,
        7912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your app is now able to store a set of categories in local storage on the device and register with the notification hub whenever the user changes the selection of categories.",
      "pos": [
        7914,
        8088
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Register for notifications",
      "pos": [
        8092,
        8118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These steps register with the notification hub on startup using the categories that have been stored in local storage.",
      "pos": [
        8120,
        8238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Because the channel URI assigned by the Windows Notification Service (WNS) can change at any time, you should register for notifications frequently to avoid notification failures.",
      "pos": [
        8242,
        8434
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This example registers for notification every time that the app starts.",
      "pos": [
        8435,
        8506
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For apps that are run frequently, more than once a day, you can probably skip registration to preserve bandwidth if less than a day has passed since the previous registration.",
      "pos": [
        8507,
        8682
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8687,
        8769
      ],
      "content": "Open the App.xaml.cs file and add the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>async<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> modifier to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OnLaunched<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> method."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8774,
        8914
      ],
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OnLaunched<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method, locate and replace the existing call to the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>InitNotificationsAsync<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> method with the following line of code:"
    },
    {
      "content": "This makes sure that every time the app starts it retrieves the categories from local storage and requests a registeration for these categories.",
      "pos": [
        8974,
        9118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>InitNotificationsAsync<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method was created as part of the [Get started with Notification Hubs] tutorial, but it is not needed in this topic.",
      "pos": [
        9119,
        9266
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9271,
        9362
      ],
      "content": "In the MainPage.xaml.cs project file, add the following code to the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>OnNavigatedTo<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> method:"
    },
    {
      "content": "This updates the main page based on the status of previously saved categories.",
      "pos": [
        9888,
        9966
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The app is now complete and can store a set of categories in the device local storage used to register with the notification hub whenever the user changes the selection of categories.",
      "pos": [
        9968,
        10151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, we will define a backend that can send category notifications to this app.",
      "pos": [
        10152,
        10232
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Send notifications from your back-end",
      "pos": [
        10236,
        10273
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run the app and generate notifications",
      "pos": [
        10369,
        10407
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Visual Studio, press F5 to compile and start the app.",
      "pos": [
        10412,
        10468
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the app UI provides a set of toggles that lets you choose the categories to subscribe to.",
      "pos": [
        10486,
        10585
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10590,
        10654
      ],
      "content": "Enable one or more categories toggles, then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Subscribe<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "The app converts the selected categories into tags and requests a new device registration for the selected tags from the notification hub.",
      "pos": [
        10660,
        10798
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The registered categories are returned and displayed in a dialog.",
      "pos": [
        10799,
        10864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Send a new notification from the backend in one of the following ways:",
      "pos": [
        10882,
        10952
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10960,
        10999
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Console app:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> start the console app."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11007,
        11041
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Java/PHP:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> run your app/script."
    },
    {
      "content": "Notifications for the selected categories appear as toast notifications.",
      "pos": [
        11047,
        11119
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        11136,
        11146
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this tutorial we learned how to broadcast breaking news by category.",
      "pos": [
        11148,
        11219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Consider completing one of the following tutorials that highlight other advanced Notification Hubs scenarios:",
      "pos": [
        11220,
        11329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Use Notification Hubs to broadcast localized breaking news]",
      "pos": [
        11333,
        11393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to expand the breaking news app to enable sending localized notifications.",
      "pos": [
        11399,
        11483
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Notify users with Notification Hubs]",
      "pos": [
        11487,
        11524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to push notifications to specific authenticated users.",
      "pos": [
        11530,
        11594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is a good solution for sending notifications only to specific users.",
      "pos": [
        11595,
        11668
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Use Notification Hubs to send breaking news (Windows Universal)\"\n    description=\"Use Azure Notification Hubs with tags in the registration to send breaking news to a universal Windows app.\"\n    services=\"notification-hubs\"\n    documentationCenter=\"windows\"\n    authors=\"wesmc7777\"\n    manager=\"dwrede\"\n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"notification-hubs\"\n    ms.workload=\"mobile\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"mobile-windows\"\n    ms.devlang=\"dotnet\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"06/16/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"wesmc\"/>\n\n# Use Notification Hubs to send breaking news\n\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [notification-hubs-selector-breaking-news](../../includes/notification-hubs-selector-breaking-news.md)]\n\n\n##Overview\n\nThis topic shows you how to use Azure Notification Hubs to broadcast breaking news notifications to a Windows Store or Windows Phone 8.1 (non-Silverlight) app. If you are targeting Windows Phone 8.1 Silverlight, please refer to the [Windows Phone](notification-hubs-ios-send-breaking-news.md) version. When complete, you will be able to register for breaking news categories you are interested in, and receive only push notifications for those categories. This scenario is a common pattern for many apps where notifications have to be sent to groups of users that have previously declared interest in them, e.g. RSS reader, apps for music fans, and so on. \n\nBroadcast scenarios are enabled by including one or more _tags_ when creating a registration in the notification hub. When notifications are sent to a tag, all devices that have registered for the tag will receive the notification. Because tags are simply strings, they do not have to be provisioned in advance. For more information about tags, refer to [Notification Hubs Guidance].\n\n##Prerequisites\n\nThis topic builds on the app you created in [Get started with Notification Hubs][get-started]. Before starting this tutorial, you must have already completed [Get started with Notification Hubs][get-started].\n\n##Add category selection to the app\n\nThe first step is to add the UI elements to your existing main page that enable the user to select categories to register. The categories selected by a user are stored on the device. When the app starts, a device registration is created in your notification hub with the selected categories as tags.\n\n1. Open the MainPage.xaml project file, then copy the following code in the **Grid** element:\n\n        <Grid>\n            <Grid.RowDefinitions>\n                <RowDefinition/>\n                <RowDefinition/>\n                <RowDefinition/>\n                <RowDefinition/>\n                <RowDefinition/>\n            </Grid.RowDefinitions>\n            <Grid.ColumnDefinitions>\n                <ColumnDefinition/>\n                <ColumnDefinition/>\n            </Grid.ColumnDefinitions>\n            <TextBlock Grid.Row=\"0\" Grid.Column=\"0\" Grid.ColumnSpan=\"2\"  TextWrapping=\"Wrap\" Text=\"Breaking News\" FontSize=\"42\" VerticalAlignment=\"Top\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Center\"/>\n            <ToggleSwitch Header=\"World\" Name=\"WorldToggle\" Grid.Row=\"1\" Grid.Column=\"0\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Center\"/>\n            <ToggleSwitch Header=\"Politics\" Name=\"PoliticsToggle\" Grid.Row=\"2\" Grid.Column=\"0\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Center\"/>\n            <ToggleSwitch Header=\"Business\" Name=\"BusinessToggle\" Grid.Row=\"3\" Grid.Column=\"0\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Center\"/>\n            <ToggleSwitch Header=\"Technology\" Name=\"TechnologyToggle\" Grid.Row=\"1\" Grid.Column=\"1\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Center\"/>\n            <ToggleSwitch Header=\"Science\" Name=\"ScienceToggle\" Grid.Row=\"2\" Grid.Column=\"1\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Center\"/>\n            <ToggleSwitch Header=\"Sports\" Name=\"SportsToggle\" Grid.Row=\"3\" Grid.Column=\"1\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Center\"/>\n            <Button Name=\"SubscribeButton\" Content=\"Subscribe\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Center\" Grid.Row=\"4\" Grid.Column=\"0\" Grid.ColumnSpan=\"2\" Click=\"SubscribeButton_Click\"/>\n        </Grid>\n\n\n2. Right click the **Shared** project and add a new class named **Notifications**, add the **public** modifier to the class definition, then add the following **using** statements to the new code file:\n\n        using Windows.Networking.PushNotifications;\n        using Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Messaging;\n        using Windows.Storage;\n        using System.Threading.Tasks;\n\n3. Copy the following code into the new **Notifications** class:\n\n        private NotificationHub hub;\n\n        public Notifications(string hubName, string listenConnectionString)\n        {\n            hub = new NotificationHub(hubName, listenConnectionString);\n        }\n\n        public async Task StoreCategoriesAndSubscribe(IEnumerable<string> categories)\n        {\n            ApplicationData.Current.LocalSettings.Values[\"categories\"] = string.Join(\",\", categories);\n            await SubscribeToCategories(categories);\n        }\n\n        public IEnumerable<string> RetrieveCategories()\n        {\n            var categories = (string) ApplicationData.Current.LocalSettings.Values[\"categories\"];\n            return categories != null ? categories.Split(','): new string[0];\n        }\n\n        public async Task SubscribeToCategories(IEnumerable<string> categories = null)\n        {\n            var channel = await PushNotificationChannelManager.CreatePushNotificationChannelForApplicationAsync();\n\n            if (categories == null)\n            {\n                IEnumerable<string> categories = RetrieveCategories();\n            }\n\n            await hub.RegisterNativeAsync(channel.Uri, categories);\n        }\n\n    This class uses the local storage to store the categories of news that this device has to receive. It also contains methods to register for these categories.\n\n\n4. In the App.xaml.cs project file, add the following property to the **App** class:\n\n        public Notifications notifications = new Notifications(\"<hub name>\", \"<connection string with listen access>\");\n\n    This property is used to create and access a **Notifications** instance.\n\n    In the above code, replace the `<hub name>` and `<connection string with listen access>` placeholders with your notification hub name and the connection string for *DefaultListenSharedAccessSignature* that you obtained earlier.\n\n    > [AZURE.NOTE] Because credentials that are distributed with a client app are not generally secure, you should only distribute the key for listen access with your client app. Listen access enables your app to register for notifications, but existing registrations cannot be modified and notifications cannot be sent. The full access key is used in a secured backend service for sending notifications and changing existing registrations.\n\n5. In your MainPage.xaml.cs, add the following line:\n\n        using Windows.UI.Popups;\n\n6. In the MainPage.xaml.cs project file, add the following method:\n\n        private async void SubscribeButton_Click(object sender, RoutedEventArgs e)\n        {\n            var categories = new HashSet<string>();\n            if (WorldToggle.IsOn) categories.Add(\"World\");\n            if (PoliticsToggle.IsOn) categories.Add(\"Politics\");\n            if (BusinessToggle.IsOn) categories.Add(\"Business\");\n            if (TechnologyToggle.IsOn) categories.Add(\"Technology\");\n            if (ScienceToggle.IsOn) categories.Add(\"Science\");\n            if (SportsToggle.IsOn) categories.Add(\"Sports\");\n\n            await ((App)Application.Current).notifications.StoreCategoriesAndSubscribe(categories);\n\n            var dialog = new MessageDialog(\"Subscribed to: \" + string.Join(\",\", categories));\n            dialog.Commands.Add(new UICommand(\"OK\"));\n            await dialog.ShowAsync();\n        }\n\n    This method creates a list of categories and uses the **Notifications** class to store the list in the local storage and register the corresponding tags with your notification hub. When categories are changed, the registration is recreated with the new categories.\n\nYour app is now able to store a set of categories in local storage on the device and register with the notification hub whenever the user changes the selection of categories.\n\n##Register for notifications\n\nThese steps register with the notification hub on startup using the categories that have been stored in local storage.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Because the channel URI assigned by the Windows Notification Service (WNS) can change at any time, you should register for notifications frequently to avoid notification failures. This example registers for notification every time that the app starts. For apps that are run frequently, more than once a day, you can probably skip registration to preserve bandwidth if less than a day has passed since the previous registration.\n\n1. Open the App.xaml.cs file and add the **async** modifier to **OnLaunched** method.\n\n2. In the **OnLaunched** method, locate and replace the existing call to the **InitNotificationsAsync** method with the following line of code:\n\n        await notifications.SubscribeToCategories();\n\n    This makes sure that every time the app starts it retrieves the categories from local storage and requests a registeration for these categories. The **InitNotificationsAsync** method was created as part of the [Get started with Notification Hubs] tutorial, but it is not needed in this topic.\n\n3. In the MainPage.xaml.cs project file, add the following code to the *OnNavigatedTo* method:\n\n        var categories = ((App)Application.Current).notifications.RetrieveCategories();\n\n        if (categories.Contains(\"World\")) WorldToggle.IsOn = true;\n        if (categories.Contains(\"Politics\")) PoliticsToggle.IsOn = true;\n        if (categories.Contains(\"Business\")) BusinessToggle.IsOn = true;\n        if (categories.Contains(\"Technology\")) TechnologyToggle.IsOn = true;\n        if (categories.Contains(\"Science\")) ScienceToggle.IsOn = true;\n        if (categories.Contains(\"Sports\")) SportsToggle.IsOn = true;\n\n    This updates the main page based on the status of previously saved categories.\n\nThe app is now complete and can store a set of categories in the device local storage used to register with the notification hub whenever the user changes the selection of categories. Next, we will define a backend that can send category notifications to this app.\n\n##Send notifications from your back-end\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [notification-hubs-back-end](../../includes/notification-hubs-back-end.md)]\n\n##Run the app and generate notifications\n\n1. In Visual Studio, press F5 to compile and start the app.\n\n    ![][1]\n\n    Note that the app UI provides a set of toggles that lets you choose the categories to subscribe to.\n\n2. Enable one or more categories toggles, then click **Subscribe**.\n\n    The app converts the selected categories into tags and requests a new device registration for the selected tags from the notification hub. The registered categories are returned and displayed in a dialog.\n\n    ![][19]\n\n4. Send a new notification from the backend in one of the following ways:\n\n    + **Console app:** start the console app.\n\n    + **Java/PHP:** run your app/script.\n\n    Notifications for the selected categories appear as toast notifications.\n\n    ![][14]\n\n##Next steps\n\nIn this tutorial we learned how to broadcast breaking news by category. Consider completing one of the following tutorials that highlight other advanced Notification Hubs scenarios:\n\n+ [Use Notification Hubs to broadcast localized breaking news]\n\n    Learn how to expand the breaking news app to enable sending localized notifications.\n\n+ [Notify users with Notification Hubs]\n\n    Learn how to push notifications to specific authenticated users. This is a good solution for sending notifications only to specific users.\n\n\n<!-- Anchors. -->\n[Add category selection to the app]: #adding-categories\n[Register for notifications]: #register\n[Send notifications from your back-end]: #send\n[Run the app and generate notifications]: #test-app\n[Next Steps]: #next-steps\n\n<!-- Images. -->\n[1]: ./media/notification-hubs-windows-store-dotnet-send-breaking-news/notification-hub-breakingnews-win1.png\n\n[14]: ./media/notification-hubs-windows-store-dotnet-send-breaking-news/notification-hub-windows-toast-2.png\n\n\n[19]: ./media/notification-hubs-windows-store-dotnet-send-breaking-news/notification-hub-windows-reg-2.png\n\n<!-- URLs.-->\n[get-started]: /manage/services/notification-hubs/getting-started-windows-dotnet/\n[Use Notification Hubs to broadcast localized breaking news]: /manage/services/notification-hubs/breaking-news-localized-dotnet/\n[Notify users with Notification Hubs]: /manage/services/notification-hubs/notify-users\n[Mobile Service]: /develop/mobile/tutorials/get-started/\n[Notification Hubs Guidance]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/jj927170.aspx\n[Notification Hubs How-To for Windows Store]: http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/jj927172.aspx\n[Submit an app page]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkID=266582\n[My Applications]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=262039\n[Live SDK for Windows]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=262253\n\n[Azure Management Portal]: https://manage.windowsazure.com/\n[wns object]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=260591\n"
}