{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "How to install and configure Trend Micro Deep Security as a Service on an Azure VM | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article describes how to install and configure Trend Micro security on a VM in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        146,
        236
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to install and configure Trend Micro Deep Security as a Service on an Azure VM",
      "pos": [
        604,
        686
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article shows you how to install and configure Trend Micro Deep Security as a Service on a new or existing virtual machine (VM) running Windows Server.",
      "pos": [
        688,
        844
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deep Security as a Service includes anti-malware protection, a firewall, an intrusion prevention system, and integrity monitoring.",
      "pos": [
        845,
        975
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that this article refers to the virtual machines created using the classic deployment model.",
      "pos": [
        976,
        1073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The client is installed as a security extension via the VM Agent.",
      "pos": [
        1075,
        1140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On a new virtual machine, you'll install the VM Agent along with the Deep Security Agent.",
      "pos": [
        1141,
        1230
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On an existing virtual machine that doesn't have the VM Agent, you'll need to download and install it first.",
      "pos": [
        1231,
        1339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article covers both situations.",
      "pos": [
        1340,
        1376
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have existing subscription from Trend Micro for an on-premises solution, you can use it to help protect your Azure virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        1378,
        1517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're not a customer yet, you can sign up for a trial subscription.",
      "pos": [
        1518,
        1589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about this solution, see the Trend Micro blog post <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Azure VM Agent Extension For Deep Security<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=403945)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1590,
        1766
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install the Deep Security Agent on a new virtual machine",
      "pos": [
        1771,
        1827
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://manage.windowsazure.com)</ept> lets you install the VM Agent and the Trend Micro security extension when you use the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>From Gallery<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> option to create the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        1829,
        2020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using this approach is an easy way to add protection from Trend Micro if you're creating a single virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        2021,
        2135
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>From Gallery<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option opens a wizard that helps you set up the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        2137,
        2223
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You use the last page of the wizard to install the VM Agent and Trend Micro security extension.",
      "pos": [
        2224,
        2319
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For general instructions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a virtual machine running Windows in the Azure portal<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-machines-windows-tutorial-classic-portal.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2320,
        2466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you get to the last page of the wizard, do the following:",
      "pos": [
        2467,
        2529
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2535,
        2582
      ],
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>VM Agent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, check <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Install VM Agent<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2588,
        2661
      ],
      "content": "Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Security Extensions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, check <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Trend Micro Deep Security Agent<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Install the VM Agent and the Deep Security Agent",
      "pos": [
        2669,
        2717
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the check mark to create the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        2791,
        2842
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install the Deep Security Agent on an existing virtual machine",
      "pos": [
        2847,
        2909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, you'll need the following:",
      "pos": [
        2911,
        2949
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure PowerShell module, version 0.8.2 or newer, installed on your local computer.",
      "pos": [
        2953,
        3039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can check the version of Azure PowerShell that you have installed by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-Module azure | format-table version<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> command.",
      "pos": [
        3040,
        3175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For instructions and a link to the latest version, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to install and configure Azure PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](../install-configure-powershell.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3176,
        3315
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VM Agent installed on the target virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        3319,
        3372
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "First, verify that the VM Agent is already installed.",
      "pos": [
        3374,
        3427
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Fill in the cloud service name and virtual machine name, and then run the following commands at an administrator-level Azure PowerShell command prompt.",
      "pos": [
        3428,
        3579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replace everything within the quotes, including the &lt; and &gt; characters.",
      "pos": [
        3580,
        3651
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3829,
        3997
      ],
      "content": "If you don't know the cloud service and virtual machine name, run <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-AzureVM<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to display that information for all the virtual machines in your current subscription."
    },
    {
      "content": "If the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>write-host<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> command returns <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>True<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, the VM Agent is installed.",
      "pos": [
        3999,
        4073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If it returns <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>False<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, see the instructions and a link to the download in the Azure blog post <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>VM Agent and Extensions - Part 2<ept id=\"p2\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=403947)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4074,
        4254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the VM Agent is installed, run these commands.",
      "pos": [
        4256,
        4305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        4546,
        4556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It takes a few minutes for the agent to start running when it is installed.",
      "pos": [
        4558,
        4633
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After that, you'll need to activate Deep Security on the virtual machine so it can be managed by a Deep Security Manager.",
      "pos": [
        4634,
        4755
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the following for additional instructions:",
      "pos": [
        4756,
        4802
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4806,
        4937
      ],
      "content": "Trend's article about this solution, <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Instant-On Cloud Security for Microsoft Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=404101)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4940,
        5056
      ],
      "content": "A <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>sample Windows PowerShell script<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=404100)</ept> to configure the virtual machine"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5059,
        5136
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Instructions<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=404099)</ept>  for the sample"
    },
    {
      "content": "Additional resources",
      "pos": [
        5141,
        5161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[How to log on to a virtual machine running Windows Server]",
      "pos": [
        5163,
        5222
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Azure VM Extensions and features]",
      "pos": [
        5224,
        5258
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"How to install and configure Trend Micro Deep Security as a Service on an Azure VM | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"This article describes how to install and configure Trend Micro security on a VM in Azure.\"\n    services=\"virtual-machines\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"dsk-2015\"\n    manager=\"timlt\"\n    editor=\"\"\n    tags=\"azure-service-management\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"virtual-machines\"\n    ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"vm-multiple\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"07/15/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"dkshir\"/>\n\n\n# How to install and configure Trend Micro Deep Security as a Service on an Azure VM\n\nThis article shows you how to install and configure Trend Micro Deep Security as a Service on a new or existing virtual machine (VM) running Windows Server. Deep Security as a Service includes anti-malware protection, a firewall, an intrusion prevention system, and integrity monitoring. Note that this article refers to the virtual machines created using the classic deployment model.\n\nThe client is installed as a security extension via the VM Agent. On a new virtual machine, you'll install the VM Agent along with the Deep Security Agent. On an existing virtual machine that doesn't have the VM Agent, you'll need to download and install it first. This article covers both situations.\n\nIf you have existing subscription from Trend Micro for an on-premises solution, you can use it to help protect your Azure virtual machines. If you're not a customer yet, you can sign up for a trial subscription. For more information about this solution, see the Trend Micro blog post [Microsoft Azure VM Agent Extension For Deep Security](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=403945).\n\n## Install the Deep Security Agent on a new virtual machine\n\nThe [Azure portal](http://manage.windowsazure.com) lets you install the VM Agent and the Trend Micro security extension when you use the **From Gallery** option to create the virtual machine. Using this approach is an easy way to add protection from Trend Micro if you're creating a single virtual machine.\n\nThis **From Gallery** option opens a wizard that helps you set up the virtual machine. You use the last page of the wizard to install the VM Agent and Trend Micro security extension. For general instructions, see [Create a virtual machine running Windows in the Azure portal](virtual-machines-windows-tutorial-classic-portal.md). When you get to the last page of the wizard, do the following:\n\n1.  Under **VM Agent**, check **Install VM Agent**.\n\n2.  Under **Security Extensions**, check **Trend Micro Deep Security Agent**.\n\n    ![Install the VM Agent and the Deep Security Agent](./media/virtual-machines-install-trend/InstallVMAgentandTrend.png)\n\n3.  Click the check mark to create the virtual machine.\n\n## Install the Deep Security Agent on an existing virtual machine\n\nTo do this, you'll need the following:\n\n- The Azure PowerShell module, version 0.8.2 or newer, installed on your local computer. You can check the version of Azure PowerShell that you have installed by using the **Get-Module azure | format-table version** command. For instructions and a link to the latest version, see [How to install and configure Azure PowerShell](../install-configure-powershell.md).\n\n- The VM Agent installed on the target virtual machine.\n\nFirst, verify that the VM Agent is already installed. Fill in the cloud service name and virtual machine name, and then run the following commands at an administrator-level Azure PowerShell command prompt. Replace everything within the quotes, including the < and > characters.\n\n    $CSName = \"<cloud service name>\"\n    $VMName = \"<virtual machine name>\"\n    $vm = Get-AzureVM -ServiceName $CSName -Name $VMName\n    write-host $vm.VM.ProvisionGuestAgent\n\nIf you don't know the cloud service and virtual machine name, run **Get-AzureVM** to display that information for all the virtual machines in your current subscription.\n\nIf the **write-host** command returns **True**, the VM Agent is installed. If it returns **False**, see the instructions and a link to the download in the Azure blog post [VM Agent and Extensions - Part 2](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=403947).\n\nIf the VM Agent is installed, run these commands.\n\n    $Agent = Get-AzureVMAvailableExtension TrendMicro.DeepSecurity -ExtensionName TrendMicroDSA\n\n    Set-AzureVMExtension -Publisher TrendMicro.DeepSecurity –Version $Agent.Version -ExtensionName TrendMicroDSA -VM $vm | Update-AzureVM\n\n## Next steps\n\nIt takes a few minutes for the agent to start running when it is installed. After that, you'll need to activate Deep Security on the virtual machine so it can be managed by a Deep Security Manager. See the following for additional instructions:\n\n- Trend's article about this solution, [Instant-On Cloud Security for Microsoft Azure](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=404101)\n- A [sample Windows PowerShell script](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=404100) to configure the virtual machine\n- [Instructions](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=404099)  for the sample\n\n## Additional resources\n\n[How to log on to a virtual machine running Windows Server]\n\n[Azure VM Extensions and features]\n\n\n<!--Link references-->\n[How to log on to a virtual machine running Windows Server]: virtual-machines-log-on-windows-server.md\n[Azure VM Extensions and features]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=390493&clcid=0x409\n"
}