{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Set up protection between on-premises VMM sites with SAN",
      "pos": [
        28,
        84
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Site Recovery coordinates the replication, failover and recovery of Hyper-V virtual machines between on-premises sites using SAN replication.",
      "pos": [
        104,
        251
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up protection between on-premises VMM sites with SAN",
      "pos": [
        583,
        639
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Site Recovery contributes to your business continuity and disaster recovery (BCDR) strategy by orchestrating replication, failover and recovery of virtual machines and physical servers.",
      "pos": [
        641,
        832
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Read about possible deployment scenarios in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Site Recovery overview<ept id=\"p1\">](site-recovery-overview.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        833,
        939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This walkthrough describes how to deploy Site Recovery to orchestrate and automate protection for virtual machine workloads running on an on-premises Hyper-V server that's managed by System Center VMM to another VMM on-premises site, using storage array-based (SAN) replication.",
      "pos": [
        941,
        1219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Business advantages include:",
      "pos": [
        1221,
        1249
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Provide an enterprise scalable replication solution automated by Site Recovery.",
      "pos": [
        1253,
        1332
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Takes advantage of SAN replication capabilities provided by enterprise storage partners across both fibre channel and iSCSI storage.",
      "pos": [
        1335,
        1467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See our <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SAN storage partners<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518669)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1468,
        1546
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Leverage your existing SAN infrastructure to protect mission-critical applications deployed in Hyper-V clusters.",
      "pos": [
        1549,
        1661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Provide support for guest clusters.",
      "pos": [
        1665,
        1700
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure replication consistency across different tiers of an application with synchronized replication for low RTO and RPO, and asynchronized replication for high flexibility, depending on storage array capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        1703,
        1918
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Integration with VMM provides SAN management within the VMM console and SMI-S in VMM discovers existing storage.",
      "pos": [
        1923,
        2035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "About this article",
      "pos": [
        2043,
        2061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The article includes an overview and deployment prerequisites.",
      "pos": [
        2063,
        2125
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It walks you through configuring and enable replication in VMM and the Site Recovery vault.",
      "pos": [
        2126,
        2217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll discover and classify SAN storage in VMM, provision LUNs, and allocate storage to Hyper-V clusters.",
      "pos": [
        2218,
        2324
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It finishes up by testing failover to make sure everything's working as expected.",
      "pos": [
        2325,
        2406
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2408,
        2539
      ],
      "content": "If you run into problems post your questions on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Recovery Services Forum<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=313628)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        2544,
        2552
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This scenario protects your workloads by backing up Hyper-V virtual machines from one on-premises VMM site to another using SAN replication.",
      "pos": [
        2553,
        2693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SAN architecture",
      "pos": [
        2697,
        2713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scenario components",
      "pos": [
        2767,
        2786
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2790,
        2940
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>On-premises virtual machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Your on-premises Hyper-V servers that are managed in VMM private clouds contain virtual machines you want to protect."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2943,
        3078
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>On-premises VMM servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—You can one or more VMM servers running on the primary site you want to protect, and on the secondary site."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3081,
        3158
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SAN storage<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—A SAN array on the primary site and one in the secondary site"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3162,
        3299
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Site Recovery vault<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—The vault coordinates and orchestrates data replica, failover, and recovery between your on-premises sites."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3302,
        3376
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Site Recovery Provider<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—Provider is installed on each VMM server."
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you start",
      "pos": [
        3381,
        3397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        3403,
        3422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/)</ept> account.",
      "pos": [
        3426,
        3495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can start with a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>free trial<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/try-azure)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3496,
        3555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get pricing information at <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Site Recovery Manager Pricing Details<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=378268)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3556,
        3676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VMM prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        3682,
        3699
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3703,
        3952
      ],
      "content": "You'll need at least one VMM server in each on-premises site, deployed as a physical or virtual standalone server, or as a virtual cluster, running on System Center 2012 R2 with <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>VMM update rollup 5.0<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=517707)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "You should have at least one cloud on the primary VMM server you want to protect, and one on the secondary VMM server.",
      "pos": [
        3955,
        4073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The primary cloud you want to protect must contain the following:",
      "pos": [
        4074,
        4139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One or more VMM host groups",
      "pos": [
        4146,
        4173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One or more Hyper-V clusters in each host group.",
      "pos": [
        4180,
        4228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One or more virtual machines located on the source Hyper-V server in the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        4235,
        4314
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V requirements",
      "pos": [
        4328,
        4348
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need a Hyper-V host cluster deployed in the primary and secondary sites, running at least Windows Server 2012 with the latest updates.",
      "pos": [
        4352,
        4493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SAN prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        4499,
        4516
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using SAN replication you can replicate guest-clustered virtual machines with iSCSI or fibre channel storage, or using shared virtual hard disks (vhdx).",
      "pos": [
        4520,
        4672
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SAN prerequisites are as follows:",
      "pos": [
        4673,
        4706
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You’ll need two SAN arrays set up, one in the primary site and one in the secondary.",
      "pos": [
        4713,
        4797
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network infrastructure should be set up between the arrays.",
      "pos": [
        4804,
        4863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Peering and replication should be configured.",
      "pos": [
        4864,
        4909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replication licenses should be set up in accordance with the storage array requirements.",
      "pos": [
        4910,
        4998
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Networking should be set up between the Hyper-V host servers and the storage array so that hosts can communicate with storage LUNs using ISCSI or Fibre Channel.",
      "pos": [
        5005,
        5165
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5172,
        5260
      ],
      "content": "See a list of <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>supported storage arrays<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518669)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "SMI-S Providers, provided by the storage array manufacturers should be installed and the SAN arrays should be managed by the Provider.",
      "pos": [
        5267,
        5401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up the Provider in accordance with their documentation.",
      "pos": [
        5402,
        5461
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure that the SMI-S provider for the array is on a server that the VMM server can access over the network by IP address or FQDN.",
      "pos": [
        5468,
        5598
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each SAN array should have one or more storage pools available to use in this deployment.The VMM server at the primary site will need to manage the primary array and the secondary VMM server will manage the secondary array.",
      "pos": [
        5605,
        5828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VMM server at the primary site should manage the primary array and the secondary VMM server should manage the secondary array.",
      "pos": [
        5835,
        5965
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        5971,
        5992
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can optionally configure network mapping to ensure that replica virtual machines are optimally placed on Hyper-V host servers after failover, and that they can connect to appropriate VM networks.",
      "pos": [
        5994,
        6193
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that:",
      "pos": [
        6194,
        6204
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When network mapping is enabled, a virtual machine at the primary location will be connected to a network and its replica at the target location will be connected to its mapped network.",
      "pos": [
        6208,
        6393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don’t configure network mapping virtual machines won’t be connected to VM networks after failover.",
      "pos": [
        6396,
        6501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM networks must be set up in VMM.",
      "pos": [
        6504,
        6538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For details read Configuring VM Networks and Gateways in VMM",
      "pos": [
        6539,
        6599
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual machines on the source VMM server should be connected to a VM network.",
      "pos": [
        6602,
        6680
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The source VM network should be linked to a logical network that is associated with the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        6681,
        6775
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 1: Prepare the VMM infrastructure",
      "pos": [
        6781,
        6819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To prepare your VMM infrastructure you need to:",
      "pos": [
        6821,
        6868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure VMM clouds are set up",
      "pos": [
        6873,
        6901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Integrate and classify SAN storage in VMM",
      "pos": [
        6905,
        6946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create LUNs and allocate storage",
      "pos": [
        6950,
        6982
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create replication groups",
      "pos": [
        6986,
        7011
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up VM networks",
      "pos": [
        7015,
        7033
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure VMM clouds are set up",
      "pos": [
        7039,
        7067
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Site Recovery orchestrates protection for virtual machines located on Hyper-V host servers in VMM clouds.",
      "pos": [
        7069,
        7174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll need to ensure that those clouds are set up properly before you begin Site Recovery deployment.",
      "pos": [
        7175,
        7277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A couple of good sources include:",
      "pos": [
        7278,
        7311
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What’s New in Private Cloud",
      "pos": [
        7316,
        7343
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7394,
        7494
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>VMM 2012 and the clouds<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=324956)</ept> on Gunter Danzeisen's blog."
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuring the VMM cloud fabric",
      "pos": [
        7498,
        7530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating a private cloud in VMM",
      "pos": [
        7603,
        7634
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7685,
        7793
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Walkthrough: Creating private clouds<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=324954)</ept> in Keith Mayer's blog."
    },
    {
      "content": "Integrate and classify SAN storage in VMM",
      "pos": [
        7799,
        7840
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add an classify SANs in the VMM console:",
      "pos": [
        7843,
        7883
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Fabric<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> workspace click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Storage<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        7888,
        7934
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Home<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add Resources<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Storage Devices<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> to start the Add Storage Devices Wizard.",
      "pos": [
        7935,
        8032
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8036,
        8155
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select a storage provider type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SAN and NAS devices discovered and managed by an SMI-S provider<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Provider type",
      "pos": [
        8163,
        8176
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8236,
        8391
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify Protocol and Address of the Storage SMI-S Provider<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SMI-S CIMXML<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and specify the settings for connecting to the provider."
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Provider IP address or FQDN<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>TCP/IP port<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, specify the settings for connecting to the provider.",
      "pos": [
        8395,
        8503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use an SSL connection for SMI-S CIMXML only.",
      "pos": [
        8504,
        8556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Provider connect",
      "pos": [
        8564,
        8580
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8643,
        8748
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Run as account<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> specify a VMM Run As account that can access the provider, or create a new account."
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Gather Information<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, VMM automatically tries to discover and import the storage device information.",
      "pos": [
        8752,
        8866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To retry discovery, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Scan Provider<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8867,
        8911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the discovery process succeeds, the discovered storage arrays, storage pools, manufacturer, model, and capacity are listed on the page.",
      "pos": [
        8912,
        9050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Discover storage",
      "pos": [
        9058,
        9074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select storage pools to place under management and assign a classification<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select the storage pools that VMM will manage and assign them a classification.",
      "pos": [
        9130,
        9292
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "LUN information will be imported from the storage pools.",
      "pos": [
        9293,
        9349
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create LUNs based on the applications you need to protect, their capacity requirements and your requirement for what needs to replicate together.",
      "pos": [
        9350,
        9495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Classify storage",
      "pos": [
        9503,
        9519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create LUNs and allocate storage",
      "pos": [
        9576,
        9608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After SAN storage is integrated into VMM you create (provision) logical units (LUNs):",
      "pos": [
        9613,
        9698
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to select a method for creating logical units in VMM",
      "pos": [
        9703,
        9759
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to provision storage logical units in VMM",
      "pos": [
        9811,
        9856
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then allocate storage capacity to the Hyper-V host cluster so that VMM can deploy virtual machine data to the provisioned storage:",
      "pos": [
        9909,
        10039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before allocating storage to the cluster you'll need to allocate it to the VMM host group on which the cluster resides.",
      "pos": [
        10048,
        10167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to allocate storage logical units to a host group<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518493)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>How to allocate storage pools to a host group<ept id=\"p2\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518492)</ept>.<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        10168,
        10379
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10386,
        10560
      ],
      "content": "Then allocate storage capacity to the cluster as described in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to configure storage on a Hyper-V host cluster in VMM<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=513017)</ept>.<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create replication groups",
      "pos": [
        10566,
        10591
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a replication group which includes all the LUNs that will need to replicate together.",
      "pos": [
        10593,
        10685
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10690,
        10796
      ],
      "content": "In the VMM console open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Replication Groups<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab of the storage array properties, and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Then create the replication group.",
      "pos": [
        10800,
        10834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SAN replication group",
      "pos": [
        10842,
        10863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up networks",
      "pos": [
        10920,
        10935
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to configure network mapping do the following:",
      "pos": [
        10937,
        10995
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11000,
        11085
      ],
      "content": "Read about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Network mapping<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn801052.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Prepare VM networks in VMM:",
      "pos": [
        11089,
        11116
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11125,
        11290
      ],
      "content": "Learn about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>setting up logical networks<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=386307)</ept>.Set up logical networks—Read Configuring Logical Networking in VMM Overview."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11297,
        11365
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up VM networks<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=386308)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 2: Create a vault",
      "pos": [
        11370,
        11392
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11398,
        11459
      ],
      "content": "Sign in to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://portal.azure.com)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11465,
        11548
      ],
      "content": "Expand <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Site Recovery Vault<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11554,
        11594
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Quick Create<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11603,
        11660
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, enter a friendly name to identify the vault."
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Region<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select the geographic region for the vault.",
      "pos": [
        11665,
        11723
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To check supported regions see Geographic Availability in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Site Recovery Pricing Details<ept id=\"p1\">](href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=389880)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        11724,
        11872
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11877,
        11900
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create vault<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "New Vault",
      "pos": [
        11909,
        11918
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check the status bar to confirm that the vault was successfully created.",
      "pos": [
        11970,
        12042
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The vault will be listed as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Active<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on the main <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Recovery Services<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.",
      "pos": [
        12043,
        12121
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Register the VMM servers",
      "pos": [
        12128,
        12152
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Recovery Services<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph> page, click the vault to open the Quick Start page.",
      "pos": [
        12157,
        12240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Quick Start can also be opened at any time using the icon.",
      "pos": [
        12241,
        12299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Quick Start Icon",
      "pos": [
        12307,
        12323
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12385,
        12475
      ],
      "content": "In the dropdown list, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Between Hyper-V on-premises site using array replication<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Registration key",
      "pos": [
        12483,
        12499
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Prepare VMM servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Generate registration key<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> file.",
      "pos": [
        12563,
        12632
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The key is valid for 5 days after it's generated.",
      "pos": [
        12633,
        12682
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're not running the console on the VMM server you want to protect, download the file to a safe location that the VMM servers can access.",
      "pos": [
        12683,
        12825
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example to a share.",
      "pos": [
        12826,
        12849
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that:",
      "pos": [
        12850,
        12860
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you’re installing the Provider for the first time, install it on an active node in the cluster and finish the installation to register the VMM server in the Azure Site Recovery vault.",
      "pos": [
        12864,
        13050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then install the Provider on other nodes in the cluster.",
      "pos": [
        13051,
        13107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you’re upgrading the Provider version, run the Provider installation on all nodes in the cluster.",
      "pos": [
        13110,
        13210
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13215,
        13368
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download Microsoft Azure Site Recovery Provider for installation on VMM servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to obtain the latest version of the Provider installation file."
    },
    {
      "content": "Run this file on the source and target VMM servers to open the Azure Site Recovery Provider Setup wizard.",
      "pos": [
        13372,
        13477
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pre-requirements Check<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page select to stop the VMM service to begin Provider setup.",
      "pos": [
        13481,
        13575
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The service stops and will restart automatically when setup finishes.",
      "pos": [
        13576,
        13645
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you’re installing on a VMM cluster you’ll need to stop the Cluster role.",
      "pos": [
        13646,
        13721
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        13729,
        13742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Update<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> you can opt in for updates.",
      "pos": [
        13804,
        13855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With this setting enabled Provider updates will be installed according to your Microsoft Update policy.",
      "pos": [
        13856,
        13959
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the Provider is installed continue setup to register the server in the vault.",
      "pos": [
        13961,
        14044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the Internet Connection page specify how the Provider running on the VMM server connects to the Internet.",
      "pos": [
        14049,
        14157
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can select not to use a proxy, to use the default proxy configured on the VMM server, or to use a custom proxy server.",
      "pos": [
        14158,
        14280
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that:",
      "pos": [
        14281,
        14291
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to use a custom proxy server set it up before you install the Provider.",
      "pos": [
        14299,
        14382
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Following urls should be accessible from the VMM Server",
      "pos": [
        14389,
        14444
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.hypervrecoverymanager.windowsazure.com",
      "pos": [
        14455,
        14495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.accesscontrol.windows.net",
      "pos": [
        14506,
        14533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.backup.windowsazure.com",
      "pos": [
        14544,
        14569
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.blob.core.windows.net",
      "pos": [
        14580,
        14603
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "*.store.core.windows.net",
      "pos": [
        14615,
        14639
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Allow the IP addresses described in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Datacenter IP Ranges<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=511094)</ept> and HTTPS (443) protocol.",
      "pos": [
        14647,
        14784
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You would have to white-list IP ranges of the Azure region that you plan to use and that of West US.",
      "pos": [
        14785,
        14885
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you choose to use a custom proxy a VMM RunAs account (DRAProxyAccount) will be created automatically using the specified proxy credentials.",
      "pos": [
        14898,
        15040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure the proxy server so that this account can authenticate successfully.",
      "pos": [
        15041,
        15119
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VMM RunAs account settings can be modified in the VMM console.",
      "pos": [
        15126,
        15192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, open the Settings workspace, expand Security, click Run As Accounts, and then modify the password for DRAProxyAccount.",
      "pos": [
        15193,
        15323
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You’ll need to restart the VMM service so that this setting takes effect.",
      "pos": [
        15324,
        15397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A test will run to verify the Internet connection.",
      "pos": [
        15404,
        15454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any proxy errors are displayed in the VMM console.",
      "pos": [
        15455,
        15505
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Internet Settings",
      "pos": [
        15513,
        15530
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        15591,
        15697
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Registration Key<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select that you downloaded from Azure Site Recovery and copied to the VMM server."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        15701,
        15785
      ],
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Server name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, specify a friendly name to identify the VMM server in the vault."
    },
    {
      "content": "Server registration",
      "pos": [
        15793,
        15812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Initial cloud metadata<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> sync select whether you want to synchronize metadata for all clouds on the VMM server with the vault.",
      "pos": [
        15884,
        16015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This action only needs to happen once on each server.",
      "pos": [
        16016,
        16069
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don't want to synchronize all clouds, you can leave this setting unchecked and synchronize each cloud individually in the cloud properties in the VMM console.",
      "pos": [
        16070,
        16235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data Encryption<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option isn’t relevant in this scenario.",
      "pos": [
        16236,
        16299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server registration",
      "pos": [
        16308,
        16327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the next page click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to complete the process.",
      "pos": [
        16395,
        16455
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After registration metadata from the VMM server is retrieved by Azure Site Recovery.",
      "pos": [
        16456,
        16540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The server is displayed on the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Resources<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph> tab on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Servers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in the vault.",
      "pos": [
        16541,
        16630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After installation you modify Provider settings in the VMM console.",
      "pos": [
        16631,
        16698
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 4: Map storage arrays and pools",
      "pos": [
        16705,
        16741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Map arrays to specify which secondary storage pool receives replication data from the primary pool.",
      "pos": [
        16743,
        16842
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should map storage before you configure cloud protection because the mapping information is used when you enable protection for replication groups.",
      "pos": [
        16843,
        16994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you start check that clouds appear in the vault.",
      "pos": [
        16996,
        17051
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Clouds are detected either by selecting to synchronize all clouds when you install the Provider, or by selecting to synchronize a specific cloud on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab of the cloud properties in the VMM console.",
      "pos": [
        17052,
        17263
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then map storage arrays as follows:",
      "pos": [
        17264,
        17299
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        17304,
        17459
      ],
      "content": "Click **Resources** > **Server Storage** > **Map Source and Target Arrays**.\n ![Server registration](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_StorageMap.png)",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "   "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Resources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Server Storage<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> &gt; <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Map Source and Target Arrays<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            76
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\"> ![</ph>Server registration<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_StorageMap.png)</ph>",
          "pos": [
            77,
            152
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the storage arrays on the primary site and map them to storage arrays on the secondary site.",
      "pos": [
        17463,
        17562
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Map source and target storage pools within the arrays.",
      "pos": [
        17567,
        17621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Storage Pools<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> select a source and target storage pool to map.",
      "pos": [
        17622,
        17702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server registration",
      "pos": [
        17710,
        17729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 5: Configure cloud protection settings",
      "pos": [
        17791,
        17834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After VMM servers are registered, you can configure cloud protection settings.",
      "pos": [
        17836,
        17914
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You enabled the option <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Synchronize cloud data with the vault<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> when you installed the Provider so all clouds on the VMM server will appear in the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Protected Items<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph> tab in the vault.",
      "pos": [
        17915,
        18103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Published Cloud",
      "pos": [
        18107,
        18122
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        18180,
        18248
      ],
      "content": "On the Quick Start page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Set up protection for VMM clouds<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protected Items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, select the cloud that you want to configure and go to the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configuration<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab.",
      "pos": [
        18252,
        18364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that:",
      "pos": [
        18365,
        18375
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        18379,
        18415
      ],
      "content": "In <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Target<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>, select <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>VMM<ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        18419,
        18528
      ],
      "content": "In <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Target location<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>, select the on-site VMM server that manages the cloud you want to use for recovery."
    },
    {
      "content": "In <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Target cloud<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>, select the target cloud you want to use for failover of virtual machines in the source cloud.",
      "pos": [
        18532,
        18649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that:",
      "pos": [
        18650,
        18660
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend that you select a target cloud that meets recovery requirements for the virtual machines you'll protect.",
      "pos": [
        18667,
        18784
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A cloud can only belong to a single cloud pair — either as a primary or a target cloud.",
      "pos": [
        18791,
        18878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Site Recovery verifies that clouds have access to SAN replication capable storage, and that the storage arrays are peered.",
      "pos": [
        18882,
        19010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Participating array peers are displayed.",
      "pos": [
        19011,
        19051
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        19055,
        19126
      ],
      "content": "If verification is successful, in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Replication type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SAN<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "After you save the settings a job will be created and can be monitored on the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Jobs<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph> tab.",
      "pos": [
        19131,
        19225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cloud settings can be modified on the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Configure<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph> tab.",
      "pos": [
        19226,
        19285
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to modify the target location or target cloud you must remove the cloud configuration, and then reconfigure the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        19286,
        19416
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 6: Enable network mapping",
      "pos": [
        19425,
        19455
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        19460,
        19508
      ],
      "content": "On the Quick Start page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Map networks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the source VMM server from which you want to map networks, and then the target VMM server to which the networks will be mapped.",
      "pos": [
        19512,
        19646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The list of source networks and their associated target networks are displayed.",
      "pos": [
        19647,
        19726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A blank value is shown for networks that are not currently mapped.",
      "pos": [
        19727,
        19793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the information icon next to the source and target network names to view the subnets for each network.",
      "pos": [
        19794,
        19902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select a network in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Network on source<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Map<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        19906,
        19972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The service detects the VM networks on the target server and displays them.",
      "pos": [
        19973,
        20048
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SAN architecture",
      "pos": [
        20056,
        20072
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the dialog box that is displayed, select one of the VM networks from the target VMM server.",
      "pos": [
        20132,
        20226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SAN architecture",
      "pos": [
        20235,
        20251
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you select a target network, the protected clouds that use the source network are displayed.",
      "pos": [
        20311,
        20408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Available target networks that are associated with the clouds used for protection are also displayed.",
      "pos": [
        20409,
        20510
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We recommend that you select a target network that is available to all the clouds you are using for protection.",
      "pos": [
        20511,
        20622
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the check mark to complete the mapping process.",
      "pos": [
        20627,
        20680
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A job starts to track the mapping progress.",
      "pos": [
        20681,
        20724
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can view it on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Jobs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.",
      "pos": [
        20725,
        20761
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 7: Enable replication for replication groups",
      "pos": [
        20767,
        20816
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you can enable protection for virtual machines you’ll need to enable replication for storage replication groups.",
      "pos": [
        20823,
        20942
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the Azure Site Recovery portal, in the properties page of the primary cloud open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.",
      "pos": [
        20948,
        21061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add Replication Group<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        21062,
        21094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select one or more VMM replication groups that are associated with the cloud, verify the source and target arrays, and specify the replication frequency.",
      "pos": [
        21098,
        21251
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When this operation is complete, Azure Site Recovery, together with VMM and the SMI-S providers provision the target site storage LUNs and enable storage replication.",
      "pos": [
        21253,
        21419
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the replication group is already replicated, Azure Site Recovery reuses the existing replication relationship and updates the information in Azure Site Recovery.",
      "pos": [
        21420,
        21584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enable protection for virtual machines",
      "pos": [
        21589,
        21627
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After a storage group is replicating, enable protection for virtual machines in the VMM console using either of the following methods:",
      "pos": [
        21629,
        21763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New virtual machine<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—In the VMM console when you create a new virtual machine you enable Azure Site Recovery protection and associate the virtual machine with the replication group.",
      "pos": [
        21767,
        21951
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With this option VMM uses intelligent placement to optimally place the virtual machine storage on the LUNs of the replication group.",
      "pos": [
        21952,
        22084
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Site Recovery orchestrates the creation of a shadow virtual machine on the secondary site, and allocates capacity so that replica virtual machines can be started after failover.",
      "pos": [
        22085,
        22268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Existing virtual machine<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>—If a virtual machine is already deployed in VMM, you can enable Azure Site Recovery protection, and do a storage migration to a replication group.",
      "pos": [
        22271,
        22446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After completion, VMM and Azure Site Recovery detect the new virtual machine and start managing it in Azure Site Recovery for protection.",
      "pos": [
        22447,
        22584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A shadow virtual machine is created on the secondary site, and allocated capacity so that the replica virtual machine can be started after failover.",
      "pos": [
        22585,
        22733
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After virtual machines are enabled for protection they appear in the Azure Site Recovery console.",
      "pos": [
        22828,
        22925
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can view virtual machine properties, track status, and fail over replication groups that contain multiple virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        22926,
        23053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that in SAN replication all virtual machines associated with a replication group must fail over together.",
      "pos": [
        23054,
        23164
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is because failover occurs at the storage layer first.",
      "pos": [
        23165,
        23224
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It’s important to group your replication groups properly and place only associated virtual machines together.",
      "pos": [
        23225,
        23334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Track progress of the Enable Protection action in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Jobs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, including the initial replication.",
      "pos": [
        23340,
        23442
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the Finalize Protection job runs the virtual machine is ready for failover.",
      "pos": [
        23443,
        23524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">    ![</ph>Virtual machine protection job<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_JobPropertiesTab.png)</ph>",
      "pos": [
        23526,
        23621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 8: Test the deployment",
      "pos": [
        23626,
        23653
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test your deployment to make sure virtual machines and data fail over as expected.",
      "pos": [
        23660,
        23742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this you'll create a recovery plan by selecting replication groups.Then run a test failover on the plan.",
      "pos": [
        23743,
        23853
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        23858,
        23920
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery Plans<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Create Recovery Plan<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify a name for the recovery plan, and source and target VMM servers.",
      "pos": [
        23924,
        23996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The source server must have virtual machines that are enabled for failover and recovery.",
      "pos": [
        23997,
        24085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SAN<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to view only clouds that are configured for SAN replication.",
      "pos": [
        24086,
        24161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create recovery plan",
      "pos": [
        24171,
        24191
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select Virtual Machine<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select replication groups.",
      "pos": [
        24244,
        24301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All virtual machines associated with the replication group will be selected and added to the recovery plan.",
      "pos": [
        24302,
        24409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These virtual machines are added to the recovery plan default group—Group 1.",
      "pos": [
        24410,
        24486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "you can add more groups if required.",
      "pos": [
        24487,
        24523
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that after replication virtual machines will start up in accordance with the order of the recovery plan groups.",
      "pos": [
        24524,
        24640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add virtual machines",
      "pos": [
        24648,
        24668
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        24726,
        24819
      ],
      "content": "After a recovery plan has been created, it appears in the list on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery Plans<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        24824,
        24899
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recovery Plans<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, select the plan and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Test Failover<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirm Test Failover<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>None<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        24903,
        24958
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that with this option enabled the failed over replica virtual machines won't be connected to any network.",
      "pos": [
        24959,
        25069
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will test that the virtual machine fails over as expected but does not test your replication network environment.",
      "pos": [
        25070,
        25188
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to run a more comprehensive test failover see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=522291\"&gt;</ph>Test an on-premises deployment on MSDN<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        25189,
        25346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select test network",
      "pos": [
        25354,
        25373
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The test virtual machine will be created on the same host as the host on which the replica virtual machine exists.",
      "pos": [
        25435,
        25549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It isn’t added to the cloud in which the replica virtual machine is located.",
      "pos": [
        25550,
        25626
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After replication the replica virtual machine will have an IP address that isn’t the same as the IP address of the primary virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        25630,
        25769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're issuing addresses from DHCP then will be updated automatically.",
      "pos": [
        25770,
        25843
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're  not using DHCP and you want to make sure the addresses are the same you'll need to run a couple of scripts.",
      "pos": [
        25844,
        25962
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run this sample script to retrieve the IP address.",
      "pos": [
        25967,
        26017
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run this sample script to update DNS, specifying the IP address you retrieved using the previous sample script.",
      "pos": [
        26199,
        26310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitor activity",
      "pos": [
        26659,
        26675
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        26677,
        26992
      ],
      "content": "You can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Jobs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to view and monitor the main jobs performed by the Azure Site Recovery vault, including configuring protection for a cloud, enabling and disabling protection for a virtual machine, running a failover (planned, unplanned, or test), and committing an unplanned failover."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        26994,
        27180
      ],
      "content": "From the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Jobs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab you view jobs, drill down into job details and errors, run job queries to retrieve jobs that match specific criteria, export jobs to Excel, and restart failed jobs."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        27182,
        27489
      ],
      "content": "From the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> you can download the latest versions of Provider and Agent installation files, get configuration information for the vault, see the number of virtual machines that have protection managed by the vault, see recent jobs, manage the vault certificate, and resynchronize virtual machines."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        27491,
        27638
      ],
      "content": "For more information about interacting with jobs and the dashboard, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Operations and monitoring<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=398534)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Set up protection between on-premises VMM sites with SAN\" \n    description=\"Azure Site Recovery coordinates the replication, failover and recovery of Hyper-V virtual machines between on-premises sites using SAN replication.\" \n    services=\"site-recovery\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"rayne-wiselman\" \n    manager=\"jwhit\" \n    editor=\"tysonn\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"site-recovery\" \n    ms.workload=\"backup-recovery\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"08/05/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"raynew\"/>\n\n# Set up protection between on-premises VMM sites with SAN\n\nAzure Site Recovery contributes to your business continuity and disaster recovery (BCDR) strategy by orchestrating replication, failover and recovery of virtual machines and physical servers. Read about possible deployment scenarios in the [Azure Site Recovery overview](site-recovery-overview.md).\n\nThis walkthrough describes how to deploy Site Recovery to orchestrate and automate protection for virtual machine workloads running on an on-premises Hyper-V server that's managed by System Center VMM to another VMM on-premises site, using storage array-based (SAN) replication.\n\nBusiness advantages include:\n\n- Provide an enterprise scalable replication solution automated by Site Recovery.\n- Takes advantage of SAN replication capabilities provided by enterprise storage partners across both fibre channel and iSCSI storage. See our [SAN storage partners](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518669).\n- Leverage your existing SAN infrastructure to protect mission-critical applications deployed in Hyper-V clusters. \n- Provide support for guest clusters.\n- Ensure replication consistency across different tiers of an application with synchronized replication for low RTO and RPO, and asynchronized replication for high flexibility, depending on storage array capabilities.  \n- Integration with VMM provides SAN management within the VMM console and SMI-S in VMM discovers existing storage.  \n\n\n## About this article\n\nThe article includes an overview and deployment prerequisites. It walks you through configuring and enable replication in VMM and the Site Recovery vault. You'll discover and classify SAN storage in VMM, provision LUNs, and allocate storage to Hyper-V clusters. It finishes up by testing failover to make sure everything's working as expected.\n\nIf you run into problems post your questions on the [Azure Recovery Services Forum](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=313628).\n\n## Overview\nThis scenario protects your workloads by backing up Hyper-V virtual machines from one on-premises VMM site to another using SAN replication.\n\n![SAN architecture](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/ASRSAN_Arch.png)\n\n### Scenario components\n\n- **On-premises virtual machines**—Your on-premises Hyper-V servers that are managed in VMM private clouds contain virtual machines you want to protect.\n- **On-premises VMM servers**—You can one or more VMM servers running on the primary site you want to protect, and on the secondary site.\n- **SAN storage**—A SAN array on the primary site and one in the secondary site\n-  **Azure Site Recovery vault**—The vault coordinates and orchestrates data replica, failover, and recovery between your on-premises sites.\n- **Azure Site Recovery Provider**—Provider is installed on each VMM server.\n\n## Before you start\n\n### Azure prerequisites\n\n- You'll need a [Microsoft Azure](http://azure.microsoft.com/) account. You can start with a [free trial](http://aka.ms/try-azure). Get pricing information at [Azure Site Recovery Manager Pricing Details](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=378268).\n\n### VMM prerequisites\n\n- You'll need at least one VMM server in each on-premises site, deployed as a physical or virtual standalone server, or as a virtual cluster, running on System Center 2012 R2 with [VMM update rollup 5.0](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=517707).\n- You should have at least one cloud on the primary VMM server you want to protect, and one on the secondary VMM server. The primary cloud you want to protect must contain the following:\n    - One or more VMM host groups\n    - One or more Hyper-V clusters in each host group.\n    - One or more virtual machines located on the source Hyper-V server in the cloud.\n        \n### Hyper-V requirements\n\n- You'll need a Hyper-V host cluster deployed in the primary and secondary sites, running at least Windows Server 2012 with the latest updates.\n\n### SAN prerequisites\n\n- Using SAN replication you can replicate guest-clustered virtual machines with iSCSI or fibre channel storage, or using shared virtual hard disks (vhdx). SAN prerequisites are as follows:\n    - You’ll need two SAN arrays set up, one in the primary site and one in the secondary.\n    - Network infrastructure should be set up between the arrays. Peering and replication should be configured. Replication licenses should be set up in accordance with the storage array requirements.\n    - Networking should be set up between the Hyper-V host servers and the storage array so that hosts can communicate with storage LUNs using ISCSI or Fibre Channel.\n    - See a list of [supported storage arrays](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518669).\n    - SMI-S Providers, provided by the storage array manufacturers should be installed and the SAN arrays should be managed by the Provider. Set up the Provider in accordance with their documentation.\n    - Ensure that the SMI-S provider for the array is on a server that the VMM server can access over the network by IP address or FQDN.\n    - Each SAN array should have one or more storage pools available to use in this deployment.The VMM server at the primary site will need to manage the primary array and the secondary VMM server will manage the secondary array.\n    - The VMM server at the primary site should manage the primary array and the secondary VMM server should manage the secondary array.\n\n### Network prerequisites\n\nYou can optionally configure network mapping to ensure that replica virtual machines are optimally placed on Hyper-V host servers after failover, and that they can connect to appropriate VM networks. Note that:\n\n- When network mapping is enabled, a virtual machine at the primary location will be connected to a network and its replica at the target location will be connected to its mapped network.\n- If you don’t configure network mapping virtual machines won’t be connected to VM networks after failover.\n- VM networks must be set up in VMM. For details read Configuring VM Networks and Gateways in VMM\n- Virtual machines on the source VMM server should be connected to a VM network. The source VM network should be linked to a logical network that is associated with the cloud.\n\n\n## Step 1: Prepare the VMM infrastructure\n\nTo prepare your VMM infrastructure you need to:\n\n1. Ensure VMM clouds are set up\n2. Integrate and classify SAN storage in VMM\n3. Create LUNs and allocate storage\n4. Create replication groups\n5. Set up VM networks\n\n### Ensure VMM clouds are set up\n\nSite Recovery orchestrates protection for virtual machines located on Hyper-V host servers in VMM clouds. You'll need to ensure that those clouds are set up properly before you begin Site Recovery deployment. A couple of good sources include:\n\n- [What’s New in Private Cloud](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=324952)\n- [VMM 2012 and the clouds](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=324956) on Gunter Danzeisen's blog.\n- [Configuring the VMM cloud fabric](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn883636.aspx#BKMK_Fabric)\n- [Creating a private cloud in VMM](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=324953)\n- [Walkthrough: Creating private clouds](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=324954) in Keith Mayer's blog.\n\n### Integrate and classify SAN storage in VMM\n\n\nAdd an classify SANs in the VMM console:\n\n1. In the **Fabric** workspace click **Storage**. Click **Home** > **Add Resources** > **Storage Devices** to start the Add Storage Devices Wizard.\n2. In **Select a storage provider type** page, select **SAN and NAS devices discovered and managed by an SMI-S provider**.\n\n    ![Provider type](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_Providertype.png)\n\n3. On the **Specify Protocol and Address of the Storage SMI-S Provider** page select **SMI-S CIMXML** and specify the settings for connecting to the provider.\n4. In **Provider IP address or FQDN** and **TCP/IP port**, specify the settings for connecting to the provider. You can use an SSL connection for SMI-S CIMXML only.\n\n    ![Provider connect](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_ConnectSettings.png)\n\n5. In **Run as account** specify a VMM Run As account that can access the provider, or create a new account.\n6. On the **Gather Information** page, VMM automatically tries to discover and import the storage device information. To retry discovery, click **Scan Provider**. If the discovery process succeeds, the discovered storage arrays, storage pools, manufacturer, model, and capacity are listed on the page.\n\n    ![Discover storage](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_Discover.png)\n\n7. In **Select storage pools to place under management and assign a classification**, select the storage pools that VMM will manage and assign them a classification. LUN information will be imported from the storage pools. Create LUNs based on the applications you need to protect, their capacity requirements and your requirement for what needs to replicate together.\n\n    ![Classify storage](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_Classify.png)\n\n### Create LUNs and allocate storage\n\n1. After SAN storage is integrated into VMM you create (provision) logical units (LUNs):\n\n- [How to select a method for creating logical units in VMM](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518490)\n- [How to provision storage logical units in VMM](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518491)\n\n2. Then allocate storage capacity to the Hyper-V host cluster so that VMM can deploy virtual machine data to the provisioned storage: \n\n    - Before allocating storage to the cluster you'll need to allocate it to the VMM host group on which the cluster resides. See [How to allocate storage logical units to a host group](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518493) and [How to allocate storage pools to a host group](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=518492).</a>.\n    - Then allocate storage capacity to the cluster as described in [How to configure storage on a Hyper-V host cluster in VMM](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=513017).</a>.\n\n### Create replication groups\n\nCreate a replication group which includes all the LUNs that will need to replicate together.\n\n1. In the VMM console open the **Replication Groups** tab of the storage array properties, and click **New**.\n2. Then create the replication group.\n\n    ![SAN replication group](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_RepGroup.png)\n\n### Set up networks\n\nIf you want to configure network mapping do the following:\n\n1. Read about [Network mapping](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn801052.aspx).\n2. Prepare VM networks in VMM:\n \n    - Learn about [setting up logical networks](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=386307).Set up logical networks—Read Configuring Logical Networking in VMM Overview.\n    - [Set up VM networks](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=386308).\n\n## Step 2: Create a vault\n\n\n1. Sign in to the [Management Portal](https://portal.azure.com).\n\n\n2. Expand **Data Services** > **Recovery Services** and click **Site Recovery Vault**.\n\n\n3. Click **Create New** > **Quick Create**.\n    \n4. In **Name**, enter a friendly name to identify the vault.\n\n5. In **Region**, select the geographic region for the vault. To check supported regions see Geographic Availability in [Azure Site Recovery Pricing Details](href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=389880)\n\n6. Click **Create vault**. \n\n    ![New Vault](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_HvVault.png)\n\nCheck the status bar to confirm that the vault was successfully created. The vault will be listed as **Active** on the main **Recovery Services** page.\n\n\n### Register the VMM servers\n\n1. In the <b>Recovery Services</b> page, click the vault to open the Quick Start page. Quick Start can also be opened at any time using the icon.\n\n    ![Quick Start Icon](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_QuickStartIcon.png)\n\n2. In the dropdown list, select **Between Hyper-V on-premises site using array replication**.\n\n    ![Registration key](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_QuickStartRegKey.png)\n\n3. In **Prepare VMM servers**, click **Generate registration key** file. The key is valid for 5 days after it's generated. If you're not running the console on the VMM server you want to protect, download the file to a safe location that the VMM servers can access. For example to a share. Note that:\n\n- If you’re installing the Provider for the first time, install it on an active node in the cluster and finish the installation to register the VMM server in the Azure Site Recovery vault. Then install the Provider on other nodes in the cluster.\n- If you’re upgrading the Provider version, run the Provider installation on all nodes in the cluster.\n\n4. Click **Download Microsoft Azure Site Recovery Provider for installation on VMM servers** to obtain the latest version of the Provider installation file.\n5. Run this file on the source and target VMM servers to open the Azure Site Recovery Provider Setup wizard.\n6. On the **Pre-requirements Check** page select to stop the VMM service to begin Provider setup. The service stops and will restart automatically when setup finishes. If you’re installing on a VMM cluster you’ll need to stop the Cluster role.\n\n    ![Prerequisites](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_ProviderPrereq.png)\n\n5. In **Microsoft Update** you can opt in for updates. With this setting enabled Provider updates will be installed according to your Microsoft Update policy.\n\nAfter the Provider is installed continue setup to register the server in the vault.\n\n6. On the Internet Connection page specify how the Provider running on the VMM server connects to the Internet. You can select not to use a proxy, to use the default proxy configured on the VMM server, or to use a custom proxy server. Note that:\n\n    - If you want to use a custom proxy server set it up before you install the Provider.\n    - Following urls should be accessible from the VMM Server\n        - *.hypervrecoverymanager.windowsazure.com\n        - *.accesscontrol.windows.net\n        - *.backup.windowsazure.com\n        - *.blob.core.windows.net \n        - *.store.core.windows.net \n    - Allow the IP addresses described in [Azure Datacenter IP Ranges](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=511094) and HTTPS (443) protocol. You would have to white-list IP ranges of the Azure region that you plan to use and that of West US. \n    \n    - If you choose to use a custom proxy a VMM RunAs account (DRAProxyAccount) will be created automatically using the specified proxy credentials. Configure the proxy server so that this account can authenticate successfully.\n    - The VMM RunAs account settings can be modified in the VMM console. To do this, open the Settings workspace, expand Security, click Run As Accounts, and then modify the password for DRAProxyAccount. You’ll need to restart the VMM service so that this setting takes effect.\n    - A test will run to verify the Internet connection. Any proxy errors are displayed in the VMM console.\n\n    ![Internet Settings](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_ProviderProxy.png)\n\n7. In **Registration Key**, select that you downloaded from Azure Site Recovery and copied to the VMM server.\n8. In **Server name**, specify a friendly name to identify the VMM server in the vault.\n\n    ![Server registration](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_ProviderRegKeyServerName.png)\n\n9. In **Initial cloud metadata** sync select whether you want to synchronize metadata for all clouds on the VMM server with the vault. This action only needs to happen once on each server. If you don't want to synchronize all clouds, you can leave this setting unchecked and synchronize each cloud individually in the cloud properties in the VMM console. The **Data Encryption** option isn’t relevant in this scenario. \n\n    ![Server registration](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_ProviderSyncEncrypt.png)\n\n11. On the next page click **Register** to complete the process. After registration metadata from the VMM server is retrieved by Azure Site Recovery. The server is displayed on the <b>Resources</b> tab on the **Servers** page in the vault. After installation you modify Provider settings in the VMM console. \n\n\n## Step 4: Map storage arrays and pools\n\nMap arrays to specify which secondary storage pool receives replication data from the primary pool. You should map storage before you configure cloud protection because the mapping information is used when you enable protection for replication groups.\n\nBefore you start check that clouds appear in the vault. Clouds are detected either by selecting to synchronize all clouds when you install the Provider, or by selecting to synchronize a specific cloud on the **General** tab of the cloud properties in the VMM console. Then map storage arrays as follows:\n\n1. Click **Resources** > **Server Storage** > **Map Source and Target Arrays**.\n    ![Server registration](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_StorageMap.png)\n2. Select the storage arrays on the primary site and map them to storage arrays on the secondary site.\n3.  Map source and target storage pools within the arrays. To do this, in **Storage Pools** select a source and target storage pool to map.\n\n    ![Server registration](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_StorageMapPool.png)\n\n## Step 5: Configure cloud protection settings\n\nAfter VMM servers are registered, you can configure cloud protection settings. You enabled the option **Synchronize cloud data with the vault** when you installed the Provider so all clouds on the VMM server will appear in the <b>Protected Items</b> tab in the vault.\n\n![Published Cloud](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_CloudsList.png)\n\n1. On the Quick Start page, click **Set up protection for VMM clouds**.\n2. On the **Protected Items** tab, select the cloud that you want to configure and go to the **Configuration** tab. Note that:\n3. In <b>Target</b>, select <b>VMM</b>.\n4. In <b>Target location</b>, select the on-site VMM server that manages the cloud you want to use for recovery.\n5. In <b>Target cloud</b>, select the target cloud you want to use for failover of virtual machines in the source cloud. Note that:\n    - We recommend that you select a target cloud that meets recovery requirements for the virtual machines you'll protect.\n    - A cloud can only belong to a single cloud pair — either as a primary or a target cloud.\n6. Azure Site Recovery verifies that clouds have access to SAN replication capable storage, and that the storage arrays are peered. Participating array peers are displayed.\n7. If verification is successful, in **Replication type**, select **SAN**.\n\n<p>After you save the settings a job will be created and can be monitored on the <b>Jobs</b> tab. Cloud settings can be modified on the <b>Configure</b> tab. If you want to modify the target location or target cloud you must remove the cloud configuration, and then reconfigure the cloud.</p>\n\n## Step 6: Enable network mapping\n\n1. On the Quick Start page, click **Map networks**.\n2. Select the source VMM server from which you want to map networks, and then the target VMM server to which the networks will be mapped. The list of source networks and their associated target networks are displayed. A blank value is shown for networks that are not currently mapped. Click the information icon next to the source and target network names to view the subnets for each network.\n3. Select a network in **Network on source**, and then click **Map**. The service detects the VM networks on the target server and displays them.\n\n    ![SAN architecture](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/ASRSAN_NetworkMap1.png)\n\n4. In the dialog box that is displayed, select one of the VM networks from the target VMM server. \n\n    ![SAN architecture](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/ASRSAN_NetworkMap2.png)\n\n5. When you select a target network, the protected clouds that use the source network are displayed. Available target networks that are associated with the clouds used for protection are also displayed. We recommend that you select a target network that is available to all the clouds you are using for protection.\n6.  Click the check mark to complete the mapping process. A job starts to track the mapping progress. You can view it on the **Jobs** tab.\n\n\n## Step 7: Enable replication for replication groups</h3>\n\nBefore you can enable protection for virtual machines you’ll need to enable replication for storage replication groups. \n\n1. In the Azure Site Recovery portal, in the properties page of the primary cloud open the **Virtual Machines** tab. Click **Add Replication Group**.\n2. Select one or more VMM replication groups that are associated with the cloud, verify the source and target arrays, and specify the replication frequency.\n\nWhen this operation is complete, Azure Site Recovery, together with VMM and the SMI-S providers provision the target site storage LUNs and enable storage replication. If the replication group is already replicated, Azure Site Recovery reuses the existing replication relationship and updates the information in Azure Site Recovery.\n\n## Enable protection for virtual machines\n\nAfter a storage group is replicating, enable protection for virtual machines in the VMM console using either of the following methods:\n\n- **New virtual machine**—In the VMM console when you create a new virtual machine you enable Azure Site Recovery protection and associate the virtual machine with the replication group.\nWith this option VMM uses intelligent placement to optimally place the virtual machine storage on the LUNs of the replication group. Azure Site Recovery orchestrates the creation of a shadow virtual machine on the secondary site, and allocates capacity so that replica virtual machines can be started after failover.\n- **Existing virtual machine**—If a virtual machine is already deployed in VMM, you can enable Azure Site Recovery protection, and do a storage migration to a replication group. After completion, VMM and Azure Site Recovery detect the new virtual machine and start managing it in Azure Site Recovery for protection. A shadow virtual machine is created on the secondary site, and allocated capacity so that the replica virtual machine can be started after failover.\n\n\n    ![Enable protection](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_EnableProtection.png)\n    \n\n<P>After virtual machines are enabled for protection they appear in the Azure Site Recovery console. You can view virtual machine properties, track status, and fail over replication groups that contain multiple virtual machines. Note that in SAN replication all virtual machines associated with a replication group must fail over together. This is because failover occurs at the storage layer first. It’s important to group your replication groups properly and place only associated virtual machines together.</P>\n\nTrack progress of the Enable Protection action in the **Jobs** tab, including the initial replication. After the Finalize Protection job runs the virtual machine is ready for failover. \n    ![Virtual machine protection job](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_JobPropertiesTab.png)\n\n## Step 8: Test the deployment</h3>\n\nTest your deployment to make sure virtual machines and data fail over as expected. To do this you'll create a recovery plan by selecting replication groups.Then run a test failover on the plan.\n\n1. On the **Recovery Plans** tab, click **Create Recovery Plan**.\n2. Specify a name for the recovery plan, and source and target VMM servers. The source server must have virtual machines that are enabled for failover and recovery. Select **SAN** to view only clouds that are configured for SAN replication.\n3.\n    ![Create recovery plan](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_RPlan.png)\n\n4. In **Select Virtual Machine**, select replication groups. All virtual machines associated with the replication group will be selected and added to the recovery plan. These virtual machines are added to the recovery plan default group—Group 1. you can add more groups if required. Note that after replication virtual machines will start up in accordance with the order of the recovery plan groups.\n\n    ![Add virtual machines](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_RPlanVM.png)    \n5. After a recovery plan has been created, it appears in the list on the **Recovery Plans** tab. \n6. On the **Recovery Plans** tab, select the plan and click **Test Failover**.\n7. On the **Confirm Test Failover** page, select **None**. Note that with this option enabled the failed over replica virtual machines won't be connected to any network. This will test that the virtual machine fails over as expected but does not test your replication network environment. If you want to run a more comprehensive test failover see <a href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=522291\">Test an on-premises deployment on MSDN</a>.\n\n    ![Select test network](./media/site-recovery-vmm-san/SRSAN_TestFailover1.png)\n\n\n8. The test virtual machine will be created on the same host as the host on which the replica virtual machine exists. It isn’t added to the cloud in which the replica virtual machine is located.\n9. After replication the replica virtual machine will have an IP address that isn’t the same as the IP address of the primary virtual machine. If you're issuing addresses from DHCP then will be updated automatically. If you're  not using DHCP and you want to make sure the addresses are the same you'll need to run a couple of scripts.\n10. Run this sample script to retrieve the IP address.\n\n        $vm = Get-SCVirtualMachine -Name <VM_NAME>\n        $na = $vm[0].VirtualNetworkAdapters>\n        $ip = Get-SCIPAddress -GrantToObjectID $na[0].id\n        $ip.address  \n\n11. Run this sample script to update DNS, specifying the IP address you retrieved using the previous sample script.\n\n        [string]$Zone,\n        [string]$name,\n        [string]$IP\n        )\n        $Record = Get-DnsServerResourceRecord -ZoneName $zone -Name $name\n        $newrecord = $record.clone()\n        $newrecord.RecordData[0].IPv4Address  =  $IP\n        Set-DnsServerResourceRecord -zonename $zone -OldInputObject $record -NewInputObject $Newrecord\n\n## Monitor activity\n\nYou can use the **Jobs** tab and **Dashboard** to view and monitor the main jobs performed by the Azure Site Recovery vault, including configuring protection for a cloud, enabling and disabling protection for a virtual machine, running a failover (planned, unplanned, or test), and committing an unplanned failover.\n\nFrom the **Jobs** tab you view jobs, drill down into job details and errors, run job queries to retrieve jobs that match specific criteria, export jobs to Excel, and restart failed jobs.\n\nFrom the **Dashboard** you can download the latest versions of Provider and Agent installation files, get configuration information for the vault, see the number of virtual machines that have protection managed by the vault, see recent jobs, manage the vault certificate, and resynchronize virtual machines.\n\nFor more information about interacting with jobs and the dashboard, see [Operations and monitoring](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=398534).\n    \n "
}