{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Create links in markdown articles",
      "pos": [
        26,
        59
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Explains how to code crosslinks in markdown.",
      "pos": [
        74,
        118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linking guidance for Azure technical content",
      "pos": [
        393,
        437
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Guidelines for technical articles on azure.microsoft.com",
      "pos": [
        441,
        497
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Link scenario",
      "pos": [
        501,
        514
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Guidance",
      "pos": [
        517,
        525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linking from an ACOM article to another ACOM article",
      "pos": [
        560,
        612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use relative links.",
      "pos": [
        613,
        632
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Do not include the en-us language locale in your relative links.",
      "pos": [
        633,
        697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linking to an MSDN library topic, a TechNet library topic, or KB article",
      "pos": [
        700,
        772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "​Use the actual link to the article or topic, but remove the en-us language locale from the link.",
      "pos": [
        773,
        870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Linking from an ACOM article to any other web page",
      "pos": [
        873,
        923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the direct link",
      "pos": [
        924,
        943
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Markdown syntax for ACOM relative links",
      "pos": [
        950,
        989
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create an inline link from an ACOM technical article to another ACOM technical article, use this link format.",
      "pos": [
        991,
        1103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you create any new links to or from articles in the directories, you’ll need to follow the new linking syntax.",
      "pos": [
        1106,
        1219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Old link syntax to link from one ACOM tech doc to another:",
      "pos": [
        1221,
        1279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "New link syntax",
      "pos": [
        1313,
        1328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Article links from a subdirectory to an article in the root directory:",
      "pos": [
        1333,
        1403
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Article in the root directory links to an article in a service subdirectory:",
      "pos": [
        1442,
        1518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Article in a service subdirectory links to an article that is in another service subdirectory:",
      "pos": [
        1573,
        1667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Article in a directory links to another article in the same directory:",
      "pos": [
        1725,
        1795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You do not have to create anchors anymore - they are automatically generated at publishing time for all H2 headings.",
      "pos": [
        1832,
        1948
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The only thing you have to do is create links to the H2 sections:",
      "pos": [
        1949,
        2014
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To link to an anchor in another article in the same subdirectory:",
      "pos": [
        2112,
        2177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To link to an anchor in another service subdirectory:",
      "pos": [
        2311,
        2364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Custom markdown link syntax",
      "pos": [
        2538,
        2565
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since includes files are located in another directory, you will need to use relative paths as below.",
      "pos": [
        2567,
        2667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a link to a single article from an includes file, use this format:",
      "pos": [
        2668,
        2738
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2805,
        2937
      ],
      "content": "Learn more about how to use an includes file in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Custom markdown extensions guidelines<ept id=\"p1\">](custom-markdown-extensions.md#includes)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have selectors embedded in an include, you would use this sort of linking:",
      "pos": [
        2939,
        3020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To link to a page on ACOM (such as a pricing page, SLA page or anything else that is not a documentation article), use an absolute URL, but omit the locale.",
      "pos": [
        3369,
        3525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The goal here is that links work in GitHub and on the rendered site:",
      "pos": [
        3526,
        3594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To test your links, push your page to your fork and view it in the rendered view and publish to Sandbox.",
      "pos": [
        3675,
        3779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cross links on the GitHub version of the page should work as long as the targets of the URLs are present in your fork.",
      "pos": [
        3780,
        3902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Our [markdown template for technical articles](../markdown templates/markdown-template-for-new-articles.md/) shows an alternate way to create crosslinks in markdown so all the crosslinks are coded together at the end of the article, even while they display inline.",
      "pos": [
        3904,
        4168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reference-style links",
      "pos": [
        4173,
        4194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use reference style links to make your source content easier to read.",
      "pos": [
        4196,
        4273
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The reference style links replace the inline link syntax with simplified syntax that allows you to move the long URLs to the end of the article.",
      "pos": [
        4274,
        4418
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here's Daring Fireball's example:",
      "pos": [
        4419,
        4452
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inline text:",
      "pos": [
        4454,
        4466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Link references at the end of the article:",
      "pos": [
        4552,
        4594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remember the Azure library chrome!",
      "pos": [
        4734,
        4768
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to link to an Azure library topic that lives under <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>this node<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure)</ept>, remember to specify the Azure chrome in the link (/azure/).",
      "pos": [
        4769,
        4946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure chrome shares the ACOM navigation options and displays only the Azure content of the MSDN library.",
      "pos": [
        4947,
        5055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A properly scoped link looks like this:",
      "pos": [
        5056,
        5095
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Otherwise, the page will be rendered in the standard MSDN view, with the entire MSDN tree displayed.",
      "pos": [
        5156,
        5256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "FWLinks",
      "pos": [
        5261,
        5268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Avoid FWLinks (our redirection system) in azure.microsoft.com content.",
      "pos": [
        5270,
        5340
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They should be used only as a last resort when you need to create a link for a page whose URL you don't yet know.",
      "pos": [
        5341,
        5454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They are almost never actually needed.",
      "pos": [
        5455,
        5493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For ACOM, you define the file name, so you can know what it will be ahead of time.",
      "pos": [
        5494,
        5576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a library topic that is not yet published, you can create a link that uses the topic GUID so that you don't have to use an FWLink.",
      "pos": [
        5577,
        5711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you must use an FWLink on a web page, include the P parameter to make it a permanent redirect:",
      "pos": [
        5713,
        5810
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you paste the target URL into the FWLink tool, remember to remove the locale if your target link is ACOM, or the MSDN or TechNet library.",
      "pos": [
        5865,
        6007
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Contributors' Guide Links",
      "pos": [
        6013,
        6038
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview article",
      "pos": [
        6043,
        6059
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Index of guidance articles",
      "pos": [
        6080,
        6106
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Create links in markdown articles\" description=\"Explains how to code crosslinks in markdown.\" metaKeywords=\"\" services=\"\" solutions=\"\" documentationCenter=\"\" authors=\"tysonn\" videoId=\"\" scriptId=\"\" manager=\"carolz\" />\n\n<tags ms.service=\"contributor-guide\" ms.devlang=\"\" ms.topic=\"article\" ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"\" ms.workload=\"\" ms.date=\"02/03/2015\" ms.author=\"tysonn\" />\n\n# Linking guidance for Azure technical content\n## Guidelines for technical articles on azure.microsoft.com\n\n| Link scenario | Guidance  |\n|---------------|-----------|\n|Linking from an ACOM article to another ACOM article|Use relative links. Do not include the en-us language locale in your relative links.|\n|Linking to an MSDN library topic, a TechNet library topic, or KB article|​Use the actual link to the article or topic, but remove the en-us language locale from the link.|\n|Linking from an ACOM article to any other web page|Use the direct link|\n\n### Markdown syntax for ACOM relative links\n\nTo create an inline link from an ACOM technical article to another ACOM technical article, use this link format.   If you create any new links to or from articles in the directories, you’ll need to follow the new linking syntax.\n\nOld link syntax to link from one ACOM tech doc to another:\n\n    [link text](filename.md)\n\n**New link syntax** \n\nArticle links from a subdirectory to an article in the root directory:\n\n    [link text](../article-name.md)\n\nArticle in the root directory links to an article in a service subdirectory: \n\n    [link text](service-directory/article-name.md)\n\nArticle in a service subdirectory links to an article that is in another service subdirectory:\n\n    [link text](../service-directory/article-name.md)\n \nArticle in a directory links to another article in the same directory:\n\n    [link text](article-name.md)\n\n\nYou do not have to create anchors anymore - they are automatically generated at publishing time for all H2 headings. The only thing you have to do is create links to the H2 sections:\n\n    [link](#the-text-of-the-H2-section-separated-by-hyphens)\n    [Create cache](#create-cache)\n\nTo link to an anchor in another article in the same subdirectory:\n\n    [link text](article-name.md#anchor-name)\n    [Configure your profile](media-services-create-account.md#configure-your-profile)\n\nTo link to an anchor in another service subdirectory:\n\n    [link text](service-directory/article-name.md#anchor-name)\n    [Configure your profile](service-directory/media-services-create-account.md#configure-your-profile)\n\n\n## Custom markdown link syntax\n\nSince includes files are located in another directory, you will need to use relative paths as below. For a link to a single article from an includes file, use this format:\n\n    [link text](../articles/service-folder/article-name.md)\n    \nLearn more about how to use an includes file in the [Custom markdown extensions guidelines](custom-markdown-extensions.md#includes).\n\nIf you have selectors embedded in an include, you would use this sort of linking: \n\n    > [AZURE.SELECTOR-LIST (Dropdown1 | Dropdown2 )]\n    - [(Text1 | Example1 )](../articles/service-folder/article-name1.md)\n    - [(Text1 | Example2 )](../articles/service-folder/article-name2.md)\n    - [(Text2 | Example3 )](../articles/service-folder/article-name3.md)\n    - [(Text2 | Example4 )](../articles/service-folder/article-name4.md)\n\nTo link to a page on ACOM (such as a pricing page, SLA page or anything else that is not a documentation article), use an absolute URL, but omit the locale. The goal here is that links work in GitHub and on the rendered site:\n\n    [link text](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/details/virtual-machines/)\n\nTo test your links, push your page to your fork and view it in the rendered view and publish to Sandbox. The cross links on the GitHub version of the page should work as long as the targets of the URLs are present in your fork.\n\nOur [markdown template for technical articles](../markdown templates/markdown-template-for-new-articles.md/) shows an alternate way to create crosslinks in markdown so all the crosslinks are coded together at the end of the article, even while they display inline.\n\n## Reference-style links\n\nYou can use reference style links to make your source content easier to read. The reference style links replace the inline link syntax with simplified syntax that allows you to move the long URLs to the end of the article. Here's Daring Fireball's example:\n\nInline text:\n\n    I get 10 times more traffic from [Google][1] than from [Yahoo][2] or [MSN][3].\n\nLink references at the end of the article:\n\n    <!--Reference links in article-->\n    [1]: http://google.com/\n    [2]: http://search.yahoo.com/  \n    [3]: http://search.msn.com/\n\n## Remember the Azure library chrome!\nIf you want to link to an Azure library topic that lives under [this node](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure), remember to specify the Azure chrome in the link (/azure/). The Azure chrome shares the ACOM navigation options and displays only the Azure content of the MSDN library. A properly scoped link looks like this:\n\n    http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd163896.aspx\n\nOtherwise, the page will be rendered in the standard MSDN view, with the entire MSDN tree displayed.\n\n## FWLinks\n\nAvoid FWLinks (our redirection system) in azure.microsoft.com content. They should be used only as a last resort when you need to create a link for a page whose URL you don't yet know. They are almost never actually needed. For ACOM, you define the file name, so you can know what it will be ahead of time. For a library topic that is not yet published, you can create a link that uses the topic GUID so that you don't have to use an FWLink.\n\nIf you must use an FWLink on a web page, include the P parameter to make it a permanent redirect:\n\n    http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=389595\n\nWhen you paste the target URL into the FWLink tool, remember to remove the locale if your target link is ACOM, or the MSDN or TechNet library.\n\n### Contributors' Guide Links\n\n- [Overview article](./../README.md)\n- [Index of guidance articles](./contributor-guide-index.md)\n\n<!--image references-->\n[1]: ./media/create-tables-markdown/table-markdown.png\n[2]: ./media/create-tables-markdown/break-tables.png\n"
}