{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Using tags to organize your Azure resources",
      "pos": [
        28,
        71
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Shows how to apply tags to organize resources for billing and managing.",
      "pos": [
        91,
        162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using tags to organize your Azure resources",
      "pos": [
        506,
        549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource Manager enables you to logically organize resources by applying tags.",
      "pos": [
        551,
        629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The tags consist of key/value pairs that identify resources with properties that you define.",
      "pos": [
        630,
        722
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To mark resources as belonging to the same category, apply the same tag to those resources.",
      "pos": [
        723,
        814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you view resources with a particular tag, you see resources from all of your resource groups.",
      "pos": [
        817,
        915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You are not limited to only resources in the same resource group which enables you to organize your resources in a way that is independent of the deployment relationships.",
      "pos": [
        916,
        1087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tags can be particularly helpful when you need to organize resources for billing or management.",
      "pos": [
        1088,
        1183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each tag you add to a resource or resource group is automatically added to the subscription-wide taxonomy.",
      "pos": [
        1186,
        1292
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also prepopulate the taxonomy for your subscription with tag names and values you'd like to use as resources are tagged in the future.",
      "pos": [
        1293,
        1435
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> You can only apply tags to resources that support Resource Manager operations.",
      "pos": [
        1439,
        1530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you created a Virtual Machine, Virtual Network, or Storage through the classic deployment model (such as through the Azure portal or <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Service Management API<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn948465.aspx)</ept>), you cannot apply a tag to that resource.",
      "pos": [
        1531,
        1790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must re-deploy these resources through Resource Manager to support tagging.",
      "pos": [
        1791,
        1870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All other resources support tagging.",
      "pos": [
        1871,
        1907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tags in the preview portal",
      "pos": [
        1913,
        1939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tagging resources and resource groups in the preview portal is easy.",
      "pos": [
        1941,
        2009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the Browse hub to navigate to the resource or resource group you’d like to tag and click the Tags part in the Overview section at the top of the blade.",
      "pos": [
        2010,
        2165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tags part on resource and resource group blades",
      "pos": [
        2170,
        2217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will open a blade with the list of tags that have already been applied.",
      "pos": [
        2268,
        2344
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this is your first tag, the list will be empty.",
      "pos": [
        2345,
        2395
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To add a tag, simply specify a name and value and press Enter.",
      "pos": [
        2396,
        2458
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you've added a few tags, you'll notice autocomplete options based on pre-existing tag names and values to better ensure a consistent taxonomy across your resources and to avoid common mistakes, like misspellings.",
      "pos": [
        2459,
        2677
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tag resources with name/value pairs",
      "pos": [
        2681,
        2716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To view your taxonomy of tags in the portal, use the Browse hub to view Everything and then select Tags.",
      "pos": [
        2772,
        2876
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Find tags via the Browse hub",
      "pos": [
        2880,
        2908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pin the most important tags to your Startboard for quick access and you're ready to go.",
      "pos": [
        2962,
        3049
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Have fun!",
      "pos": [
        3050,
        3059
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pin tags to the Startboard",
      "pos": [
        3063,
        3089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tagging with PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        3143,
        3166
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have not previously used Azure PowerShell with Resource Manager, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](../powershell-azure-resource-manager.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3168,
        3338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the purposes of this article, we'll assume you've already added an account and selected a subscription with the resources you want to tag.",
      "pos": [
        3339,
        3481
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3483,
        3699
      ],
      "content": "Tagging is only available for resources and resource groups available from <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Resource Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn790568.aspx)</ept>, so the next thing we need to do is switch to use Resource Manager."
    },
    {
      "content": "Tags exist directly on resources and resource groups, so to see what tags are already applied, we can simply get a resource or resource group with <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureResource`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`Get-AzureResourceGroup`</ph>, respectively.",
      "pos": [
        3744,
        3953
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let's start with a resource group.",
      "pos": [
        3954,
        3988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This cmdlet returns several bits of metadata on the resource group including what tags have been applied, if any.",
      "pos": [
        5327,
        5440
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To tag a resource group, simply use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Set-AzureResourceGroup`</ph> command and specify a tag name and value.",
      "pos": [
        5441,
        5547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tags are updated as a whole, so if you are adding one tag to a resource that's already been tagged, you'll need to use an array with all the tags you want to keep.",
      "pos": [
        5937,
        6100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, you can first select the existing tags and add a new one.",
      "pos": [
        6101,
        6170
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To remove one or more tags, simply save the array without the ones you want to remove.",
      "pos": [
        6659,
        6745
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The process is the same for resources, except you'll use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureResource`</ph> and <ph id=\"ph2\">`Set-AzureResource`</ph> cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        6748,
        6861
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get resources or resource groups with a specific tag, use <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureResource`</ph> or <ph id=\"ph2\">`Get-AzureResourceGroup`</ph> cmdlet with the <ph id=\"ph3\">`-Tag`</ph> parameter.",
      "pos": [
        6862,
        7004
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7261,
        7357
      ],
      "content": "To get a list of all tags within a subscription using PowerShell, use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureTag`</ph> cmdlet."
    },
    {
      "content": "You may see tags that start with \"hidden-\" and \"link:\".",
      "pos": [
        7522,
        7577
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These are internal tags, which you should ignore and avoid changing.",
      "pos": [
        7578,
        7646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`New-AzureTag`</ph> cmdlet to add new tags to the taxonomy.",
      "pos": [
        7649,
        7711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These tags will be included in the autocomplete even though they haven't been applied to any resources or resource groups, yet.",
      "pos": [
        7712,
        7839
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To remove a tag name/value, first remove the tag from any resources it may be used with and then use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Remove-AzureTag`</ph> cmdlet to remove it from the taxonomy.",
      "pos": [
        7840,
        8001
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tagging with REST API",
      "pos": [
        8006,
        8027
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The portal and PowerShell both use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Resource Manager REST API<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn790568.aspx)</ept> behind the scenes.",
      "pos": [
        8029,
        8169
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need to integrate tagging into another environment, you can get tags with a GET on the resource id and update the set of tags with a PATCH call.",
      "pos": [
        8170,
        8321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tagging and billing",
      "pos": [
        8327,
        8346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For supported services, you can use tags to group your billing data.",
      "pos": [
        8348,
        8416
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Virtual Machines integrated with Azure Resource Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](/virtual-machines/virtual-machines-azurerm-versus-azuresm.md)</ept> enable",
      "pos": [
        8417,
        8556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "you to define and apply tags to organize the billing usage for virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        8558,
        8638
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are running multiple VMs for different organizations, you can use the tags to group usage by cost center.",
      "pos": [
        8639,
        8751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also use tags to categorize costs by runtime environment; such as, the billing usage for VMs running in production environment.",
      "pos": [
        8754,
        8889
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can retrieve information about tags through the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>usage api<ept id=\"p1\">](billing-usage-rate-card-overview.md)</ept> or the usage comma-separated values (CSV) file that you can download from",
      "pos": [
        8891,
        9065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure accounts portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://account.windowsazure.com/)</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>EA portal<ept id=\"p2\">](https://ea.azure.com)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9067,
        9167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about programmatic access to billing information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Gain insights into your Microsoft Azure resource consumption<ept id=\"p1\">](billing-usage-rate-card-overview.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9168,
        9343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you download the usage CSV for services that support tags with billing, the tags will appear in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tags<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column.",
      "pos": [
        9345,
        9466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Understand your bill for Microsoft Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](billing-understand-your-bill.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9467,
        9565
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See tags in billing",
      "pos": [
        9569,
        9588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        9645,
        9655
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9659,
        9828
      ],
      "content": "For an introduction to using Azure PowerShell when deploying resources, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](./powershell-azure-resource-manager.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9831,
        10020
      ],
      "content": "For an introduction to using Azure CLI when deploying resources, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using the Azure CLI for Mac, Linux, and Windows with Azure Resource Management<ept id=\"p1\">](./xplat-cli-azure-resource-manager.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10023,
        10167
      ],
      "content": "For an introduction to using the preview portal, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using the Azure preview portal to manage your Azure resources<ept id=\"p1\">](./resource-group-portal.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        10180,
        10184
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Using tags to organize your Azure resources\" \n    description=\"Shows how to apply tags to organize resources for billing and managing.\" \n    services=\"azure-resource-manager\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"tfitzmac\"\n    manager=\"wpickett\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"azure-resource-manager\" \n    ms.workload=\"multiple\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"AzurePortal\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"08/07/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"tomfitz\"/>\n\n\n# Using tags to organize your Azure resources\n\nResource Manager enables you to logically organize resources by applying tags. The tags consist of key/value pairs that identify resources with properties that you define. To mark resources as belonging to the same category, apply the same tag to those resources. \n\nWhen you view resources with a particular tag, you see resources from all of your resource groups. You are not limited to only resources in the same resource group which enables you to organize your resources in a way that is independent of the deployment relationships. Tags can be particularly helpful when you need to organize resources for billing or management. \n\nEach tag you add to a resource or resource group is automatically added to the subscription-wide taxonomy. You can also prepopulate the taxonomy for your subscription with tag names and values you'd like to use as resources are tagged in the future.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] You can only apply tags to resources that support Resource Manager operations. If you created a Virtual Machine, Virtual Network, or Storage through the classic deployment model (such as through the Azure portal or [Service Management API](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn948465.aspx)), you cannot apply a tag to that resource. You must re-deploy these resources through Resource Manager to support tagging. All other resources support tagging.\n\n\n## Tags in the preview portal\n\nTagging resources and resource groups in the preview portal is easy. Use the Browse hub to navigate to the resource or resource group you’d like to tag and click the Tags part in the Overview section at the top of the blade. \n\n![Tags part on resource and resource group blades](./media/resource-group-using-tags/tag-icon.png)\n\nThis will open a blade with the list of tags that have already been applied. If this is your first tag, the list will be empty. To add a tag, simply specify a name and value and press Enter. After you've added a few tags, you'll notice autocomplete options based on pre-existing tag names and values to better ensure a consistent taxonomy across your resources and to avoid common mistakes, like misspellings.\n\n![Tag resources with name/value pairs](./media/resource-group-using-tags/tag-resources.png)\n\nTo view your taxonomy of tags in the portal, use the Browse hub to view Everything and then select Tags.\n\n![Find tags via the Browse hub](./media/resource-group-using-tags/browse-tags.png)\n\nPin the most important tags to your Startboard for quick access and you're ready to go. Have fun!\n\n![Pin tags to the Startboard](./media/resource-group-using-tags/pin-tags.png)\n\n## Tagging with PowerShell\n\nIf you have not previously used Azure PowerShell with Resource Manager, see [Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager](../powershell-azure-resource-manager.md).\nFor the purposes of this article, we'll assume you've already added an account and selected a subscription with the resources you want to tag.\n\nTagging is only available for resources and resource groups available from [Resource Manager](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn790568.aspx), so the next thing we need to do is switch to use Resource Manager.\n\n    Switch-AzureMode AzureResourceManager\n\nTags exist directly on resources and resource groups, so to see what tags are already applied, we can simply get a resource or resource group with `Get-AzureResource` or `Get-AzureResourceGroup`, respectively. Let's start with a resource group.\n\n    PS C:\\> Get-AzureResourceGroup tag-demo\n\n    ResourceGroupName : tag-demo\n    Location          : southcentralus\n    ProvisioningState : Succeeded\n    Tags              :\n    Permissions       :\n                    Actions  NotActions\n                    =======  ==========\n                    *\n\n    Resources         :\n                    Name                             Type                                  Location\n                    ===============================  ====================================  ==============\n                    CPUHigh ExamplePlan              microsoft.insights/alertrules         eastus\n                    ForbiddenRequests tag-demo-site  microsoft.insights/alertrules         eastus\n                    LongHttpQueue ExamplePlan        microsoft.insights/alertrules         eastus\n                    ServerErrors tag-demo-site       microsoft.insights/alertrules         eastus\n                    ExamplePlan-tag-demo             microsoft.insights/autoscalesettings  eastus\n                    tag-demo-site                    microsoft.insights/components         centralus\n                    ExamplePlan                      Microsoft.Web/serverFarms             southcentralus\n                    tag-demo-site                    Microsoft.Web/sites                   southcentralus\n\n\nThis cmdlet returns several bits of metadata on the resource group including what tags have been applied, if any. To tag a resource group, simply use the `Set-AzureResourceGroup` command and specify a tag name and value.\n\n    PS C:\\> Set-AzureResourceGroup tag-demo -Tag @( @{ Name=\"project\"; Value=\"tags\" }, @{ Name=\"env\"; Value=\"demo\"} )\n\n    ResourceGroupName : tag-demo\n    Location          : southcentralus\n    ProvisioningState : Succeeded\n    Tags              :\n                    Name     Value\n                    =======  =====\n                    project  tags\n                    env      demo\n\nTags are updated as a whole, so if you are adding one tag to a resource that's already been tagged, you'll need to use an array with all the tags you want to keep. To do this, you can first select the existing tags and add a new one.\n\n    PS C:\\> $tags = (Get-AzureResourceGroup -Name tag-demo).Tags\n    PS C:\\> $tags += @{Name=\"status\";Value=\"approved\"}\n    PS C:\\> Set-AzureResourceGroup tag-demo -Tag $tags\n\n    ResourceGroupName : tag-demo\n    Location          : southcentralus\n    ProvisioningState : Succeeded\n    Tags              :\n                    Name     Value\n                    =======  ========\n                    project  tags\n                    env      demo\n                    status   approved\n\n\nTo remove one or more tags, simply save the array without the ones you want to remove. \n\nThe process is the same for resources, except you'll use the `Get-AzureResource` and `Set-AzureResource` cmdlets. To get resources or resource groups with a specific tag, use `Get-AzureResource` or `Get-AzureResourceGroup` cmdlet with the `-Tag` parameter.\n\n    PS C:\\> Get-AzureResourceGroup -Tag @{ Name=\"env\"; Value=\"demo\" } | %{ $_.ResourceGroupName }\n    rbacdemo-group\n    tag-demo\n    PS C:\\> Get-AzureResource -Tag @{ Name=\"env\"; Value=\"demo\" } | %{ $_.Name }\n    rbacdemo-web\n    rbacdemo-docdb\n    ...\n\nTo get a list of all tags within a subscription using PowerShell, use the `Get-AzureTag` cmdlet.\n\n    PS C:/> Get-AzureTag\n    Name                      Count\n    ----                      ------\n    env                       8\n    project                   1\n\nYou may see tags that start with \"hidden-\" and \"link:\". These are internal tags, which you should ignore and avoid changing. \n\nUse the `New-AzureTag` cmdlet to add new tags to the taxonomy. These tags will be included in the autocomplete even though they haven't been applied to any resources or resource groups, yet. To remove a tag name/value, first remove the tag from any resources it may be used with and then use the `Remove-AzureTag` cmdlet to remove it from the taxonomy.\n\n## Tagging with REST API\n\nThe portal and PowerShell both use the [Resource Manager REST API](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn790568.aspx) behind the scenes. If you need to integrate tagging into another environment, you can get tags with a GET on the resource id and update the set of tags with a PATCH call.\n\n\n## Tagging and billing\n\nFor supported services, you can use tags to group your billing data. For example, [Virtual Machines integrated with Azure Resource Manager](/virtual-machines/virtual-machines-azurerm-versus-azuresm.md) enable \nyou to define and apply tags to organize the billing usage for virtual machines. If you are running multiple VMs for different organizations, you can use the tags to group usage by cost center.  \nYou can also use tags to categorize costs by runtime environment; such as, the billing usage for VMs running in production environment.\n\nYou can retrieve information about tags through the [usage api](billing-usage-rate-card-overview.md) or the usage comma-separated values (CSV) file that you can download from \nthe [Azure accounts portal](https://account.windowsazure.com/) or [EA portal](https://ea.azure.com). For more information about programmatic access to billing information, see [Gain insights into your Microsoft Azure resource consumption](billing-usage-rate-card-overview.md).\n\nWhen you download the usage CSV for services that support tags with billing, the tags will appear in the **Tags** column. For more details, see [Understand your bill for Microsoft Azure](billing-understand-your-bill.md).\n\n![See tags in billing](./media/resource-group-using-tags/billing_csv.png)\n\n## Next Steps\n\n- For an introduction to using Azure PowerShell when deploying resources, see [Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager](./powershell-azure-resource-manager.md).\n- For an introduction to using Azure CLI when deploying resources, see [Using the Azure CLI for Mac, Linux, and Windows with Azure Resource Management](./xplat-cli-azure-resource-manager.md).\n- For an introduction to using the preview portal, see [Using the Azure preview portal to manage your Azure resources](./resource-group-portal.md)  \n  \n\n  \n\n\n\ntest\n"
}