{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "How to install and configure Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        27,
        72
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to install and configure Azure PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        91,
        143
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to install and configure Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        449,
        494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=\"/manage/install-and-configure-cli/\" title=\"Azure CLI\"&gt;</ph>Azure  CLI",
      "pos": [
        645,
        732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use Windows PowerShell to perform a variety of tasks in Azure, either interactively at a command prompt or automatically through scripts.",
      "pos": [
        744,
        889
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure PowerShell is a module that provides cmdlets to manage Azure through Windows PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        890,
        984
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the cmdlets to create, test, deploy, and manage solutions and services delivered through the Azure platform.",
      "pos": [
        985,
        1105
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In most cases, you can use the cmdlets to perform the same tasks that you can perform through the Azure Management Portal.",
      "pos": [
        1106,
        1228
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, you can create and configure cloud services, virtual machines, virtual networks, and web apps.",
      "pos": [
        1229,
        1336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The module is distributed as a downloadable file and the source code is managed through a publicly available repository.",
      "pos": [
        1338,
        1458
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A link to the downloadable files is provided in the installation instructions later in this topic.",
      "pos": [
        1459,
        1557
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information about the source code, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure PowerShell code repository<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/Azure/azure-powershell)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1558,
        1679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This guide provides basic information about installing and setting up Azure PowerShell to manage the Azure platform.",
      "pos": [
        1681,
        1797
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1803,
        1862
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a id=\"Prereq\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Prerequisites for using Azure PowerShell"
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure is a subscription-based platform.",
      "pos": [
        1864,
        1903
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that a subscription is required to use the platform.",
      "pos": [
        1904,
        1967
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In most cases, it also means that the cmdlets require subscription information to perform the tasks with your subscription.",
      "pos": [
        1968,
        2091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(Some of the storage-related cmdlets can be used without this information.) You provide this by configuring your computer to connect to your subscription.",
      "pos": [
        2092,
        2246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instructions are provided in this article, under \"How to: Connect to your subscription.\"",
      "pos": [
        2247,
        2335
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2339,
        2446
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Beginning in version 0.8.5, the Azure PowerShell modules require Microsoft .NET Framework 4.5."
    },
    {
      "content": "When you install the module, the installer checks your system for the required software and installs all dependencies, such as the correct version of Windows PowerShell and .NET Framework.",
      "pos": [
        2448,
        2636
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to: Install Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        2662,
        2694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download and install the Azure PowerShell modules by running the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Web Platform Installer<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320376)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2696,
        2853
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When prompted, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Run<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2854,
        2883
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Web Platform Installer installs the Azure PowerShell modules and all dependencies.",
      "pos": [
        2884,
        2970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Follow the prompts to complete the installation.",
      "pos": [
        2971,
        3019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> If you just want to download the PowerShell installer, please visit https://github.com/Azure/azure-powershell/releases.",
      "pos": [
        3023,
        3155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Source code for the PowerShell cmdlets can be found at this repo as well",
      "pos": [
        3156,
        3228
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3230,
        3374
      ],
      "content": "For more information about the command-line tools available for Azure, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Command-line tools<ept id=\"p1\">]( http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=320796)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Installing the module also installs a customized console for Azure PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        3376,
        3454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can run the cmdlets from either the standard Windows PowerShell console or the Azure PowerShell console.",
      "pos": [
        3455,
        3563
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The method you use to open either console depends on the version of Windows you're running:",
      "pos": [
        3565,
        3656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On a computer running at least Windows 8 or Windows Server 2012, you can use the built-in Search.",
      "pos": [
        3660,
        3757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From the Start screen, begin typing <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>power<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3758,
        3804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This returns a scoped list of apps that includes Windows PowerShell and Azure PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        3805,
        3894
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To open the console, click either app.",
      "pos": [
        3895,
        3933
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "(To pin the app to the Start screen, right-click the icon.)",
      "pos": [
        3934,
        3993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On a computer running a version earlier than Windows 8 or Windows Server 2012, use the Start menu.",
      "pos": [
        3997,
        4095
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From the Start menu, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All Programs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Azure<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Azure PowerShell<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4096,
        4194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to: Connect to your subscription",
      "pos": [
        4220,
        4256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use of Azure requires a subscription.",
      "pos": [
        4258,
        4295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don't have a subscription, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get Started with Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320795)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4296,
        4408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cmdlets need your subscription so they can manage your services.",
      "pos": [
        4410,
        4478
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two ways to provide your subscription information to Windows PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        4479,
        4561
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use a management certificate that contains the information or you can sign in to Azure using your Microsoft account or a work or school account.",
      "pos": [
        4562,
        4714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you sign in, Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) authenticates the credentials and returns an access token that lets Azure PowerShell manage your account.",
      "pos": [
        4715,
        4872
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To help you choose the authentication method that's appropriate for your needs, consider the following:",
      "pos": [
        4874,
        4977
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure AD is the recommended authentication method since it makes it easier to manage access to a subscription.",
      "pos": [
        4981,
        5091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With the update in version 0.8.6, it enables an automation scenario with Azure AD authentication as well if a work or school account is used.",
      "pos": [
        5092,
        5233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It works with Azure Resource Manager API as well.",
      "pos": [
        5234,
        5283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you use the certificate method, the subscription information is available as long as the subscription and the certificate are valid.",
      "pos": [
        5286,
        5423
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, this method makes it harder to manage access to a shared subscription, such as when more than one person is authorized to access the account.",
      "pos": [
        5424,
        5574
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Also, Azure Resource Manager API doesn't accept certificate authentication.",
      "pos": [
        5575,
        5650
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5652,
        5842
      ],
      "content": "For more information about authentication and subscription management in Azure, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage Accounts, Subscriptions, and Administrative Roles<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=324796)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the Azure AD method",
      "pos": [
        5848,
        5871
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5876,
        5973
      ],
      "content": "Open the Azure PowerShell console, as instructed in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Install Azure PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](#Install)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Type the following command:",
      "pos": [
        5978,
        6005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the window, type the email address and password associated with your account.",
      "pos": [
        6036,
        6116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure authenticates and saves the credential information, and then closes the window.",
      "pos": [
        6121,
        6206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting from 0.8.6, if you sign in using a work or school account, you can type the following command to bypass the pop up window.",
      "pos": [
        6211,
        6342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will pop up the standard Windows PowerShell credential window for you to enter your work or school account user name and password.",
      "pos": [
        6343,
        6478
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6561,
        6865
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> For more information on security and using credentials, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Best practices for deploying passwords and other sensitive data to ASP.NET and Azure Websites<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.asp.net/identity/overview/features-api/best-practices-for-deploying-passwords-and-other-sensitive-data-to-aspnet-and-azure)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> This non-interactive login method only works with a work or school account.",
      "pos": [
        6873,
        6961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A work or school account is a user that is managed by your work or school, and defined in the Azure Active Directory instance for your work or school.",
      "pos": [
        6963,
        7113
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not currently have a work or school account, and are using a Microsoft account to log in to your Azure subscription, you can easily create one using the following steps.",
      "pos": [
        7114,
        7293
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7309,
        7416
      ],
      "content": "Login to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://manage.windowsazure.com)</ept>, and click on <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Active Directory<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7432,
        7527
      ],
      "content": "If no directory exists, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create your directory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and provide the requested information."
    },
    {
      "content": "Select your directory and add a new user.",
      "pos": [
        7543,
        7584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This new user can sign in using a work or school account.",
      "pos": [
        7585,
        7642
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During the creation of the user, you will be supplied with both an e-mail address for the user and a temporary password.",
      "pos": [
        7659,
        7779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Save this  information as it is used in another step.",
      "pos": [
        7780,
        7833
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From the management portal, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and then select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Administrators<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        7849,
        7932
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and add the new user as a co-administrator.",
      "pos": [
        7933,
        7992
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This allows the work or school account to manage your Azure subscription.",
      "pos": [
        7993,
        8066
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Finally, log out of the Azure portal and then log back in using the work or school account.",
      "pos": [
        8082,
        8173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this is the first time logging in with this account, you will be prompted to change the password.",
      "pos": [
        8174,
        8274
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8286,
        8450
      ],
      "content": "For more information on signing up for Microsoft Azure with a work or school account, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Sign up for Microsoft Azure as an Organization<ept id=\"p1\">](sign-up-organization.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the certificate method",
      "pos": [
        8456,
        8482
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure module includes cmdlets that help you download and import the certificate.",
      "pos": [
        8484,
        8568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> The cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module require the Azure AD method (Add-AzureAccount).",
      "pos": [
        8572,
        8679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These cmdlets do not support publish settings files.",
      "pos": [
        8680,
        8732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Resource Manager Cmdlets<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=394765)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8733,
        8892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-AzurePublishSettingsFile<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet opens a web page on the",
      "pos": [
        8897,
        8964
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Management Portal, from which you can",
      "pos": [
        8965,
        9008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "download the subscription information.",
      "pos": [
        9009,
        9047
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The information is contained in a .publishsettings file.",
      "pos": [
        9048,
        9104
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Import-AzurePublishSettingsFile<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> imports the .publishsettings file for use by the module.",
      "pos": [
        9108,
        9204
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This file includes a management certificate that has security credentials.",
      "pos": [
        9205,
        9279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> We recommend that you delete the publishing profile that you",
      "pos": [
        9283,
        9361
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "downloaded using <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Get-AzurePublishSettingsFile<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph> after you import those",
      "pos": [
        9362,
        9437
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "settings.",
      "pos": [
        9438,
        9447
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because the management certificate includes security credentials, it",
      "pos": [
        9448,
        9516
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "should not be accessed by unauthorized users.",
      "pos": [
        9517,
        9562
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need information",
      "pos": [
        9563,
        9586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "about your subscriptions, you can get it from the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://manage.windowsazure.com/)</ept> or the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Microsoft Online Services Customer Portal<ept id=\"p2\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=324875)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9587,
        9796
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9801,
        9919
      ],
      "content": "Sign in to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Management Portal<ept id=\"p1\">](http://manage.windowsazure.com)</ept> using the credentials for your Azure account."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9924,
        10021
      ],
      "content": "Open the Azure PowerShell console, as instructed in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to: Install Azure PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](#Install)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Type the following command:",
      "pos": [
        10026,
        10053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When prompted, download and save the publishing profile and note the path and name of",
      "pos": [
        10096,
        10181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "the .publishsettings file.",
      "pos": [
        10182,
        10208
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This information is required when you run the",
      "pos": [
        10209,
        10254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Import-AzurePublishSettingsFile<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet to import the settings.",
      "pos": [
        10255,
        10321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The default",
      "pos": [
        10322,
        10333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "location and file name format is:",
      "pos": [
        10334,
        10367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Type a command similar to the following, substituting your Windows account name and the path and file name for the placeholders:",
      "pos": [
        10486,
        10614
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> If you are added to other subscriptions as a co-administrator after you import your publish settings, you'll need to repeat this",
      "pos": [
        10739,
        10880
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "process to download a new .publishsettings file, and then import those",
      "pos": [
        10881,
        10951
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "settings.",
      "pos": [
        10952,
        10961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information about adding co-administrators to help manage",
      "pos": [
        10962,
        11023
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "services for a subscription, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Add and Remove Co-Administrators for Your Azure Subscriptions<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windowsazure/gg456328.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11024,
        11183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "View account and subscription details",
      "pos": [
        11189,
        11226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can have multiple accounts and subscriptions available for use by Azure PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        11228,
        11315
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can add multiple accounts by running Add-AzureAccount more than once.",
      "pos": [
        11316,
        11389
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get the available Azure accounts, type:",
      "pos": [
        11391,
        11433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get your Azure subscriptions, type:",
      "pos": [
        11457,
        11495
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11527,
        11576
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a id=\"Ex\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>How to use the cmdlets: An example"
    },
    {
      "content": "After you've installed the module and configured your computer to connect to your subscription, you can create an Azure web app.",
      "pos": [
        11581,
        11709
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This example will get you started using the Azure cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        11710,
        11768
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Start the Azure PowerShell console.",
      "pos": [
        11773,
        11808
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose a name for your web app.",
      "pos": [
        11813,
        11844
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pick a name that conforms to DNS naming conventions.",
      "pos": [
        11845,
        11897
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Valid names can contain only letters 'a' through 'z', numbers '0' through '9', and a hyphen ('-').",
      "pos": [
        11898,
        11996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The web app name must be unique in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        12002,
        12043
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We'll use \"mySite\" in this example, but be sure to choose a different name, such as your account name followed by a number.",
      "pos": [
        12044,
        12167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you pick a name, type a command similar to the following.",
      "pos": [
        12175,
        12238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Substitute your web app name for \"mySite\".",
      "pos": [
        12239,
        12281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cmdlet creates the web app and returns an object that represents the new web app.",
      "pos": [
        12320,
        12405
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The object properties include useful information about the web app.",
      "pos": [
        12406,
        12473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get information about the web app, type this command.",
      "pos": [
        12478,
        12534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It returns a bit of information about all web apps in the subscription, including the one that you just created.",
      "pos": [
        12535,
        12647
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get more information about your web app, include the web app name in the command.",
      "pos": [
        12678,
        12762
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Be sure to substitute the name of your web app for \"mySite\".",
      "pos": [
        12763,
        12823
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Web apps are started after they are created.",
      "pos": [
        12867,
        12911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To stop the web app, type this command, including the name of your web app.",
      "pos": [
        12912,
        12987
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To verify that the site's state is 'stopped', run the Get-AzureWebsite command again.",
      "pos": [
        13032,
        13117
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To complete this test, delete the web app.",
      "pos": [
        13148,
        13190
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Type:",
      "pos": [
        13191,
        13196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To complete the task, confirm that the web app is deleted.",
      "pos": [
        13245,
        13303
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13346,
        13375
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a id=\"Help\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Getting Help"
    },
    {
      "content": "These resources provide help for specific cmdlets:",
      "pos": [
        13379,
        13429
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From within the console, you can use the built-in Help system.",
      "pos": [
        13436,
        13498
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-Help<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet provides access to this system.",
      "pos": [
        13499,
        13554
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following table provides some examples of commands you can use to get Help.",
      "pos": [
        13555,
        13634
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can get more information from within the console by typing <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>help<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        13635,
        13707
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13713,
        14231
      ],
      "content": "<table border=\"1\" cellspacing=\"4\" cellpadding=\"4\">\n<tbody>\n<tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n    <td><b>Command</b></td>\n    <td><b>Result</b></td>\n</tr>\n<tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n    <td>Get-Help</td>\n    <td>Describes how to use the Help system. <p><b>Note</b>: The description includes some information about Help files that does not apply to the Azure module. Specifically, Help files are installed when the module is installed. They are not available for download separately.</p>",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "    ",
        "    ",
        "    ",
        "    ",
        "    ",
        "    ",
        "    ",
        "    "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Command<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>",
          "pos": [
            98,
            112
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Result<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>",
          "pos": [
            126,
            139
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Get-Help",
          "pos": [
            190,
            198
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "Describes how to use the Help system. ",
          "pos": [
            212,
            250
          ],
          "nodes": [
            {
              "content": "Describes how to use the Help system.",
              "pos": [
                0,
                37
              ]
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "<b>Note</b>: The description includes some information about Help files that does not apply to the Azure module. Specifically, Help files are installed when the module is installed. They are not available for download separately.",
          "pos": [
            253,
            482
          ],
          "nodes": [
            {
              "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Note<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>: The description includes some information about Help files that does not apply to the Azure module.",
              "pos": [
                0,
                112
              ]
            },
            {
              "content": "Specifically, Help files are installed when the module is installed.",
              "pos": [
                113,
                181
              ]
            },
            {
              "content": "They are not available for download separately.",
              "pos": [
                182,
                229
              ]
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-Help Azure",
      "pos": [
        14295,
        14309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets all cmdlets in the Azure module.",
      "pos": [
        14327,
        14364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-Help &amp;lt;<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>language<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>&amp;gt;-dev",
      "pos": [
        14427,
        14463
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets cmdlets for developing and managing applications in a specific language.",
      "pos": [
        14481,
        14558
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, help node-dev, help php-dev, or help python-dev.",
      "pos": [
        14559,
        14620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-Help &amp;lt;<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>cmdlet<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>&amp;gt;",
      "pos": [
        14687,
        14717
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets help about a Windows PowerShell cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        14735,
        14779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replace",
      "pos": [
        14780,
        14787
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "with the cmdlet name.",
      "pos": [
        14797,
        14818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-Help &amp;lt;<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>cmdlet<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>&amp;gt; -Parameter *",
      "pos": [
        14881,
        14924
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets descriptions of the cmdlet parameters.",
      "pos": [
        14942,
        14985
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The asterisk (*) means \"all\".",
      "pos": [
        14986,
        15015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-Help &amp;lt;<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>cmdlet<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>&amp;gt; -Examples",
      "pos": [
        15078,
        15118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the syntax and examples of using the cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        15136,
        15185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-Help &amp;lt;<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>cmdlet<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph>&amp;gt; -Full",
      "pos": [
        15248,
        15284
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets all help for a cmdlet, including technical details.",
      "pos": [
        15302,
        15358
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reference information about the cmdlets in the Azure PowerShell modules is also available in the Azure library.",
      "pos": [
        15405,
        15516
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Cmdlet Reference<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windowsazure/jj554330.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        15517,
        15625
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For help from the community, try these popular forums:",
      "pos": [
        15627,
        15681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure forum on MSDN",
      "pos": [
        15686,
        15705
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stackoverflow",
      "pos": [
        15760,
        15773
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        15827,
        15869
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a id=\"Resources\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Additional Resources"
    },
    {
      "content": "These are some of the resources available that you can use to learn to use Azure and Windows PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        15874,
        15978
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        15982,
        16119
      ],
      "content": "To learn about how to access Azure Storage components, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Storage<ept id=\"p1\">](storage-powershell-guide-full.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16123,
        16292
      ],
      "content": "To provide feedback about the cmdlets, report issues, or access the source code, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure PowerShell code repository<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/WindowsAzure/azure-sdk-tools)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16296,
        16455
      ],
      "content": "To learn about the Windows PowerShell command line and scripting environment, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>TechNet Script Center<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320211)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16459,
        16635
      ],
      "content": "For information about installing, learning, using, and customizing Windows PowerShell, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Scripting with Windows PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320210)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "For information about what scripts are and how to run them in Windows PowerShell, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Running Scripts<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320627)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        16639,
        16792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article includes basic information about creating scripts and configuring your computer to run scripts.",
      "pos": [
        16793,
        16901
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16905,
        17045
      ],
      "content": "For information about cmdlets for Azure AD, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage Azure AD using Windows PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320628)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        17150,
        17154
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"How to install and configure Azure PowerShell\"\n    description=\"Learn how to install and configure Azure PowerShell.\"\n    editor=\"tysonn\"\n    manager=\"stevenka\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    services=\"\"\n    authors=\"coreyp-at-msft\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"multiple\"\n    ms.workload=\"multiple\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"powershell\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"02/20/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"coreyp\"/>\n\n# How to install and configure Azure PowerShell#\n\n<div class=\"dev-center-tutorial-selector sublanding\"><a href=\"/manage/install-and-configure-windows-powershell/\" title=\"PowerShell\" class=\"current\">PowerShell</a><a href=\"/manage/install-and-configure-cli/\" title=\"Azure CLI\">Azure  CLI</a></div>\n\nYou can use Windows PowerShell to perform a variety of tasks in Azure, either interactively at a command prompt or automatically through scripts. Azure PowerShell is a module that provides cmdlets to manage Azure through Windows PowerShell. You can use the cmdlets to create, test, deploy, and manage solutions and services delivered through the Azure platform. In most cases, you can use the cmdlets to perform the same tasks that you can perform through the Azure Management Portal. For example, you can create and configure cloud services, virtual machines, virtual networks, and web apps.\n\nThe module is distributed as a downloadable file and the source code is managed through a publicly available repository. A link to the downloadable files is provided in the installation instructions later in this topic. For information about the source code, see [Azure PowerShell code repository](https://github.com/Azure/azure-powershell).\n\nThis guide provides basic information about installing and setting up Azure PowerShell to manage the Azure platform.\n\n### <a id=\"Prereq\"></a>Prerequisites for using Azure PowerShell\n\nAzure is a subscription-based platform. This means that a subscription is required to use the platform. In most cases, it also means that the cmdlets require subscription information to perform the tasks with your subscription. (Some of the storage-related cmdlets can be used without this information.) You provide this by configuring your computer to connect to your subscription. Instructions are provided in this article, under \"How to: Connect to your subscription.\"\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Beginning in version 0.8.5, the Azure PowerShell modules require Microsoft .NET Framework 4.5.\n\nWhen you install the module, the installer checks your system for the required software and installs all dependencies, such as the correct version of Windows PowerShell and .NET Framework.\n\n<a id=\"Install\"></a>\n## How to: Install Azure PowerShell\n\nYou can download and install the Azure PowerShell modules by running the [Microsoft Web Platform Installer](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320376). When prompted, click **Run**. The Web Platform Installer installs the Azure PowerShell modules and all dependencies. Follow the prompts to complete the installation.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] If you just want to download the PowerShell installer, please visit https://github.com/Azure/azure-powershell/releases.\nSource code for the PowerShell cmdlets can be found at this repo as well\n\nFor more information about the command-line tools available for Azure, see [Command-line tools]( http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=320796).\n\nInstalling the module also installs a customized console for Azure PowerShell. You can run the cmdlets from either the standard Windows PowerShell console or the Azure PowerShell console.\n\nThe method you use to open either console depends on the version of Windows you're running:\n\n- On a computer running at least Windows 8 or Windows Server 2012, you can use the built-in Search. From the Start screen, begin typing **power**. This returns a scoped list of apps that includes Windows PowerShell and Azure PowerShell. To open the console, click either app. (To pin the app to the Start screen, right-click the icon.)\n\n- On a computer running a version earlier than Windows 8 or Windows Server 2012, use the Start menu. From the Start menu, click **All Programs**, click **Azure**, and then click **Azure PowerShell**.\n\n<a id=\"Connect\"></a>\n## How to: Connect to your subscription\n\nUse of Azure requires a subscription. If you don't have a subscription, see [Get Started with Azure](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320795).\n\nThe cmdlets need your subscription so they can manage your services. There are two ways to provide your subscription information to Windows PowerShell. You can use a management certificate that contains the information or you can sign in to Azure using your Microsoft account or a work or school account. When you sign in, Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) authenticates the credentials and returns an access token that lets Azure PowerShell manage your account.\n\nTo help you choose the authentication method that's appropriate for your needs, consider the following:\n\n- Azure AD is the recommended authentication method since it makes it easier to manage access to a subscription. With the update in version 0.8.6, it enables an automation scenario with Azure AD authentication as well if a work or school account is used. It works with Azure Resource Manager API as well.\n- When you use the certificate method, the subscription information is available as long as the subscription and the certificate are valid. However, this method makes it harder to manage access to a shared subscription, such as when more than one person is authorized to access the account. Also, Azure Resource Manager API doesn't accept certificate authentication.\n\nFor more information about authentication and subscription management in Azure, see [Manage Accounts, Subscriptions, and Administrative Roles](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=324796).\n\n### Use the Azure AD method\n\n1. Open the Azure PowerShell console, as instructed in [How to: Install Azure PowerShell](#Install).\n\n2. Type the following command:\n\n        Add-AzureAccount\n\n3. In the window, type the email address and password associated with your account.\n\n4. Azure authenticates and saves the credential information, and then closes the window.\n\n5. Starting from 0.8.6, if you sign in using a work or school account, you can type the following command to bypass the pop up window. This will pop up the standard Windows PowerShell credential window for you to enter your work or school account user name and password.\n\n        $cred = Get-Credential\n        Add-AzureAccount -Credential $cred\n\n    > [AZURE.NOTE] For more information on security and using credentials, see [Best practices for deploying passwords and other sensitive data to ASP.NET and Azure Websites](http://www.asp.net/identity/overview/features-api/best-practices-for-deploying-passwords-and-other-sensitive-data-to-aspnet-and-azure).\n\n    > [AZURE.NOTE] This non-interactive login method only works with a work or school account.  A work or school account is a user that is managed by your work or school, and defined in the Azure Active Directory instance for your work or school. If you do not currently have a work or school account, and are using a Microsoft account to log in to your Azure subscription, you can easily create one using the following steps.\n    >\n    > 1. Login to the [Azure Management Portal](https://manage.windowsazure.com), and click on **Active Directory**.\n    >\n    > 2. If no directory exists, select **Create your directory** and provide the requested information.\n    >\n    > 3. Select your directory and add a new user. This new user can sign in using a work or school account.\n    >\n    >     During the creation of the user, you will be supplied with both an e-mail address for the user and a temporary password. Save this  information as it is used in another step.\n    >\n    > 4. From the management portal, select **Settings** and then select **Administrators**. Select **Add**, and add the new user as a co-administrator. This allows the work or school account to manage your Azure subscription.\n    >\n    > 5. Finally, log out of the Azure portal and then log back in using the work or school account. If this is the first time logging in with this account, you will be prompted to change the password.\n    >\n    >For more information on signing up for Microsoft Azure with a work or school account, see [Sign up for Microsoft Azure as an Organization](sign-up-organization.md).\n\n### Use the certificate method\n\nThe Azure module includes cmdlets that help you download and import the certificate.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] The cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module require the Azure AD method (Add-AzureAccount). These cmdlets do not support publish settings files. For more information about the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module, see [Azure Resource Manager Cmdlets](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=394765).\n\n\n- The **Get-AzurePublishSettingsFile** cmdlet opens a web page on the\nAzure Management Portal, from which you can\ndownload the subscription information. The information is contained in a .publishsettings file.\n\n- The **Import-AzurePublishSettingsFile** imports the .publishsettings file for use by the module. This file includes a management certificate that has security credentials.\n\n> [AZURE.IMPORTANT] We recommend that you delete the publishing profile that you\ndownloaded using <b>Get-AzurePublishSettingsFile</b> after you import those\nsettings. Because the management certificate includes security credentials, it\nshould not be accessed by unauthorized users. If you need information\nabout your subscriptions, you can get it from the [Azure Management Portal](http://manage.windowsazure.com/) or the [Microsoft Online Services Customer Portal](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=324875).\n\n1. Sign in to the [Azure Management Portal](http://manage.windowsazure.com) using the credentials for your Azure account.\n\n2. Open the Azure PowerShell console, as instructed in [How to: Install Azure PowerShell](#Install).\n\n3. Type the following command:\n\n        Get-AzurePublishSettingsFile\n\n4. When prompted, download and save the publishing profile and note the path and name of\nthe .publishsettings file. This information is required when you run the\n**Import-AzurePublishSettingsFile** cmdlet to import the settings. The default\nlocation and file name format is:\n\n            C:\\\\Users\\<UserProfile>\\\\Download\\\\[*MySubscription*-...]-*downloadDate*-credentials.publishsettings\n\n5. Type a command similar to the following, substituting your Windows account name and the path and file name for the placeholders:\n\n        Import-AzurePublishSettingsFile C:\\Users\\<UserProfile>\\Downloads\\<SubscriptionName>-credentials.publishsettings\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] If you are added to other subscriptions as a co-administrator after you import your publish settings, you'll need to repeat this\nprocess to download a new .publishsettings file, and then import those\nsettings. For information about adding co-administrators to help manage\nservices for a subscription, see [Add and Remove Co-Administrators for Your Azure Subscriptions](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windowsazure/gg456328.aspx).\n\n### View account and subscription details\n\nYou can have multiple accounts and subscriptions available for use by Azure PowerShell. You can add multiple accounts by running Add-AzureAccount more than once.\n\nTo get the available Azure accounts, type:\n\n    Get-AzureAccount\n\nTo get your Azure subscriptions, type:\n\n    Get-AzureSubscription\n\n## <a id=\"Ex\"></a>How to use the cmdlets: An example ##\n\nAfter you've installed the module and configured your computer to connect to your subscription, you can create an Azure web app. This example will get you started using the Azure cmdlets.\n\n1. Start the Azure PowerShell console.\n\n2. Choose a name for your web app. Pick a name that conforms to DNS naming conventions. Valid names can contain only letters 'a' through 'z', numbers '0' through '9', and a hyphen ('-').\n\n    The web app name must be unique in Azure. We'll use \"mySite\" in this example, but be sure to choose a different name, such as your account name followed by a number.  \n\n    After you pick a name, type a command similar to the following. Substitute your web app name for \"mySite\".\n\n        New-AzureWebsite mySite\n\n    The cmdlet creates the web app and returns an object that represents the new web app. The object properties include useful information about the web app.\n\n3. To get information about the web app, type this command. It returns a bit of information about all web apps in the subscription, including the one that you just created.\n\n        Get-AzureWebsite\n\n4. To get more information about your web app, include the web app name in the command. Be sure to substitute the name of your web app for \"mySite\".\n\n        Get-AzureWebsite -Name mySite\n\n5. Web apps are started after they are created. To stop the web app, type this command, including the name of your web app.\n\n        Stop-AzureWebsite -Name mySite\n\n6. To verify that the site's state is 'stopped', run the Get-AzureWebsite command again.\n\n        Get-AzureWebsite\n\n7. To complete this test, delete the web app. Type:  \n\n        Remove-AzureWebsite -Name mySite\n\n7. To complete the task, confirm that the web app is deleted.\n\n        Get-AzureWebsite -Name mySite\n\n##<a id=\"Help\"></a>Getting Help##\n\nThese resources provide help for specific cmdlets:\n\n\n-   From within the console, you can use the built-in Help system. The **Get-Help** cmdlet provides access to this system. The following table provides some examples of commands you can use to get Help. You can get more information from within the console by typing **help**.\n\n    <table border=\"1\" cellspacing=\"4\" cellpadding=\"4\">\n    <tbody>\n    <tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n        <td><b>Command</b></td>\n        <td><b>Result</b></td>\n    </tr>\n    <tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n        <td>Get-Help</td>\n        <td>Describes how to use the Help system. <p><b>Note</b>: The description includes some information about Help files that does not apply to the Azure module. Specifically, Help files are installed when the module is installed. They are not available for download separately.</p>\n</td>\n    </tr>\n    <tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n        <td>Get-Help Azure</td>\n        <td>Gets all cmdlets in the Azure module.</td>\n    </tr>\n    <tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n        <td>Get-Help &lt;<b>language</b>&gt;-dev</td>\n        <td>Gets cmdlets for developing and managing applications in a specific language. For example, help node-dev, help php-dev, or help python-dev.</td>\n    </tr>\n        <tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n        <td>Get-Help &lt;<b>cmdlet</b>&gt;</td>\n        <td>Gets help about a Windows PowerShell cmdlet. Replace <cmdlet> with the cmdlet name.</td>\n    </tr>\n    <tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n        <td>Get-Help &lt;<b>cmdlet</b>&gt; -Parameter *</td>\n        <td>Gets descriptions of the cmdlet parameters. The asterisk (*) means \"all\".</td>\n    </tr>\n    <tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n        <td>Get-Help &lt;<b>cmdlet</b>&gt; -Examples</td>\n        <td>Gets the syntax and examples of using the cmdlet.</td>\n    </tr>\n    <tr align=\"left\" valign=\"top\">\n        <td>Get-Help &lt;<b>cmdlet</b>&gt; -Full</td>\n        <td>Gets all help for a cmdlet, including technical details.</td>\n    </tr>\n    </tbody>\n    </table>\n\n\n\n- Reference information about the cmdlets in the Azure PowerShell modules is also available in the Azure library. For information, see [Azure Cmdlet Reference](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/windowsazure/jj554330.aspx).\n\nFor help from the community, try these popular forums:\n\n- [Azure forum on MSDN]( http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320212)\n- [Stackoverflow](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=320213)\n\n\n## <a id=\"Resources\"></a>Additional Resources ##\n\nThese are some of the resources available that you can use to learn to use Azure and Windows PowerShell.\n\n- To learn about how to access Azure Storage components, see [Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Storage](storage-powershell-guide-full.md).\n\n- To provide feedback about the cmdlets, report issues, or access the source code, see [Azure PowerShell code repository](https://github.com/WindowsAzure/azure-sdk-tools).\n\n- To learn about the Windows PowerShell command line and scripting environment, see the [TechNet Script Center](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320211).\n\n- For information about installing, learning, using, and customizing Windows PowerShell, see [Scripting with Windows PowerShell](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320210).\n\n- For information about what scripts are and how to run them in Windows PowerShell, see [Running Scripts](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320627). This article includes basic information about creating scripts and configuring your computer to run scripts.\n\n- For information about cmdlets for Azure AD, see [Manage Azure AD using Windows PowerShell](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=320628).\n\n\n\n\n\n  [Microsoft Online Services Customer Portal]: https://mocp.microsoftonline.com/site/default.aspx\n\ntest\n"
}