{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Configure a Connection String to Azure Storage | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        28,
        92
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to configure a connection string to an Azure storage account.",
      "pos": [
        112,
        183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A connection string includes the information needed to authenticate programmatic access to resources in a storage account.",
      "pos": [
        184,
        306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The connection string may encapsulate your account access key for an account that you own, or it may include a shared access signature for accessing resources in an account without the access key.",
      "pos": [
        307,
        503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure Azure Storage Connection Strings",
      "pos": [
        810,
        852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        857,
        865
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A connection string includes the information necessary to access Azure Storage resources programmatically.",
      "pos": [
        867,
        973
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your application uses the connection string to provide to Azure Storage the information needed to authenticate access.",
      "pos": [
        974,
        1092
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can configure a connection string to:",
      "pos": [
        1094,
        1135
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connect to the Azure storage emulator while you are locally testing your service or application.",
      "pos": [
        1139,
        1235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connect to a storage account in Azure by using either the default endpoints for the storage services, or explicit endpoints that you have defined.",
      "pos": [
        1238,
        1384
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access resources in a storage account via a shared access signature (SAS).",
      "pos": [
        1387,
        1461
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storing your connection string",
      "pos": [
        1466,
        1496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your application will need to store the connection string in order to authenticate access to Azure Storage when it is running.",
      "pos": [
        1498,
        1624
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You have a few different options for storing your connection string:",
      "pos": [
        1625,
        1693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For an application running on the desktop or on a device, you can store the connection string in an app.config file or another configuration file.",
      "pos": [
        1697,
        1843
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using an app.config file, add the connection string to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AppSettings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section.",
      "pos": [
        1844,
        1938
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For an application running in an Azure cloud service, you can store your connection string in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure service configuration schema (.cscfg) file<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ee758710.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1941,
        2140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add the connection string to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ConfigurationSettings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of the service configuration file.",
      "pos": [
        2141,
        2242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storing your connection string within a configuration file makes it easy to update the connection string to switch between the storage emulator and an Azure storage account in the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        2244,
        2430
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You only need to edit the connection string to point to your storage account.",
      "pos": [
        2431,
        2508
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2511,
        2749
      ],
      "content": "You can use the Azure <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>CloudConfigurationManager<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/microsoft.windowsazure.cloudconfigurationmanager.aspx)</ept> class to access your connection string at runtime regardless of where your application is running."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a connection string to the storage emulator",
      "pos": [
        2754,
        2804
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2930,
        3068
      ],
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Use the Azure Storage Emulator for Development and Testing<ept id=\"p1\">](storage-use-emulator.md)</ept> for more information about the storage emulator."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a connection string to an Azure storage account",
      "pos": [
        3073,
        3127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a connection string to your Azure storage account, use the connection string format below.",
      "pos": [
        3129,
        3229
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Indicate whether you want to connect to the storage account through HTTP or HTTPS (recommended), replace <ph id=\"ph1\">`myAccountName`</ph> with the name of your storage account, and replace <ph id=\"ph2\">`myAccountKey`</ph> with your account access key:",
      "pos": [
        3230,
        3446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, your connection string will look similar to the following sample connection string:",
      "pos": [
        3541,
        3637
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3739,
        3862
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Azure Storage supports both HTTP and HTTPS in a connection string; however, using HTTPS is highly recommended."
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating a connection string to an explicit storage endpoint",
      "pos": [
        3871,
        3931
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can to explicitly specify the service endpoints in your connection string if:",
      "pos": [
        3933,
        4014
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You have mapped a custom domain name for your storage account with the Blob service.",
      "pos": [
        4018,
        4102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You possess a shared access signature for accessing storage resources in a storage account.",
      "pos": [
        4105,
        4196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a connection string that specifies an explicit Blob endpoint, specify the complete service endpoint for each service, including the protocol specification (HTTP or HTTPS), in the following format:",
      "pos": [
        4198,
        4404
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must specify at least one service endpoint, but you do not need to specify all of them.",
      "pos": [
        4562,
        4653
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you're creating a connection string for use with a custom blob endpoint, specifying the queue and table endpoints is optional.",
      "pos": [
        4654,
        4796
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that if you choose to omit the queue and table endpoints from the connection string, then you will not be able to access the Queue and Table services from your code by using that connection string.",
      "pos": [
        4797,
        4999
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5001,
        5143
      ],
      "content": "When you explicitly specify service endpoints in the connection string, you have two options for specifying <ph id=\"ph1\">`credentials`</ph> in the string above:"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5147,
        5240
      ],
      "content": "You can specify the account name and key: <ph id=\"ph1\">`AccountName=myAccountName;AccountKey=myAccountKey`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5244,
        5326
      ],
      "content": "You can specify a shared access signature: <ph id=\"ph1\">`SharedAccessSignature=base64Signature`</ph>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Specifying a Blob endpoint with a custom domain name",
      "pos": [
        5332,
        5384
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have registered a custom domain name for use with the Blob service, you may want to explicitly configure the blob endpoint in your connection string.",
      "pos": [
        5387,
        5543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The endpoint value that is listed in the connection string is used to construct the request URIs to the Blob service, and it dictates the form of any URIs that are returned to your code.",
      "pos": [
        5544,
        5730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, a connection string to a Blob endpoint on a custom domain may be similar to:",
      "pos": [
        5733,
        5822
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specifying a Blob endpoint with a shared access signature",
      "pos": [
        5962,
        6019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can create a connection string with explicit endpoints to access storage resources via a shared access signature.",
      "pos": [
        6022,
        6139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, you can specify the shared access signature for as part of the connection string, rather than the account name and key credentials.",
      "pos": [
        6140,
        6285
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The shared access signature token encapsulates information about the resource to be accessed, the period of time for which it is available, and the permissions being granted.",
      "pos": [
        6286,
        6460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about shared access signatures, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Delegating Access with a Shared Access Signature<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ee395415.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6461,
        6619
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a connection string that includes a shared access signature, specify the string in the following format:",
      "pos": [
        6621,
        6735
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The endpoint can be either the default service endpoint or a custom endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        6869,
        6946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <ph id=\"ph1\">`base64Signature`</ph> corresponds to the signature portion of a shared access signature.",
      "pos": [
        6947,
        7035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The signature is an HMAC computed over a valid string-to-sign and key using the SHA256 algorithm, that is then Base64-encoded.",
      "pos": [
        7036,
        7162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating a connection string with an endpoint suffix",
      "pos": [
        7168,
        7220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a connection string for storage service in regions or instances with different endpoint suffixes, such as for Azure China or Azure Governance, use the following connection string format.",
      "pos": [
        7222,
        7418
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Indicate whether you want to connect to the storage account through HTTP or HTTPS, replace <ph id=\"ph1\">`myAccountName`</ph> with the name of your storage account, replace <ph id=\"ph2\">`myAccountKey`</ph> with your account access key, and replace <ph id=\"ph3\">`mySuffix`</ph> with the URI suffix:",
      "pos": [
        7419,
        7661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, your connection string should look similar to the following sample connection string:",
      "pos": [
        7783,
        7881
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Configure a Connection String to Azure Storage | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"Learn how to configure a connection string to an Azure storage account. A connection string includes the information needed to authenticate programmatic access to resources in a storage account. The connection string may encapsulate your account access key for an account that you own, or it may include a shared access signature for accessing resources in an account without the access key.\" \n    services=\"storage\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"tamram\" \n    manager=\"adinah\" \n    editor=\"cgronlun\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"storage\" \n    ms.workload=\"storage\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"07/08/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"tamram\"/>\n\n# Configure Azure Storage Connection Strings\n\n## Overview\n\nA connection string includes the information necessary to access Azure Storage resources programmatically. Your application uses the connection string to provide to Azure Storage the information needed to authenticate access.\n\nYou can configure a connection string to:\n\n- Connect to the Azure storage emulator while you are locally testing your service or application.\n- Connect to a storage account in Azure by using either the default endpoints for the storage services, or explicit endpoints that you have defined.\n- Access resources in a storage account via a shared access signature (SAS).\n\n## Storing your connection string\n\nYour application will need to store the connection string in order to authenticate access to Azure Storage when it is running. You have a few different options for storing your connection string:\n\n- For an application running on the desktop or on a device, you can store the connection string in an app.config file or another configuration file. If you are using an app.config file, add the connection string to the **AppSettings** section.\n- For an application running in an Azure cloud service, you can store your connection string in the [Azure service configuration schema (.cscfg) file](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ee758710.aspx). Add the connection string to the **ConfigurationSettings** section of the service configuration file.\n\nStoring your connection string within a configuration file makes it easy to update the connection string to switch between the storage emulator and an Azure storage account in the cloud. You only need to edit the connection string to point to your storage account. \n\nYou can use the Azure [CloudConfigurationManager](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/microsoft.windowsazure.cloudconfigurationmanager.aspx) class to access your connection string at runtime regardless of where your application is running.\n\n## Create a connection string to the storage emulator\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [storage-emulator-connection-string-include](../../includes/storage-emulator-connection-string-include.md)]\n\nSee [Use the Azure Storage Emulator for Development and Testing](storage-use-emulator.md) for more information about the storage emulator.\n\n## Create a connection string to an Azure storage account\n\nTo create a connection string to your Azure storage account, use the connection string format below. Indicate whether you want to connect to the storage account through HTTP or HTTPS (recommended), replace `myAccountName` with the name of your storage account, and replace `myAccountKey` with your account access key:\n\n    DefaultEndpointsProtocol=[http|https];AccountName=myAccountName;AccountKey=myAccountKey\n\nFor example, your connection string will look similar to the following sample connection string:\n \n    DefaultEndpointsProtocol=https;\n    AccountName=storagesample;\n    AccountKey=<account-key>\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Azure Storage supports both HTTP and HTTPS in a connection string; however, using HTTPS is highly recommended.\n    \n## Creating a connection string to an explicit storage endpoint\n\nYou can to explicitly specify the service endpoints in your connection string if:\n\n- You have mapped a custom domain name for your storage account with the Blob service.\n- You possess a shared access signature for accessing storage resources in a storage account.\n\nTo create a connection string that specifies an explicit Blob endpoint, specify the complete service endpoint for each service, including the protocol specification (HTTP or HTTPS), in the following format:\n\n    BlobEndpoint=myBlobEndpoint;\n    QueueEndpoint=myQueueEndpoint;\n    TableEndpoint=myTableEndpoint;\n    FileEndpoint=myFileEndpoint;\n    [credentials]\n\n\nYou must specify at least one service endpoint, but you do not need to specify all of them. For example, if you're creating a connection string for use with a custom blob endpoint, specifying the queue and table endpoints is optional. Note that if you choose to omit the queue and table endpoints from the connection string, then you will not be able to access the Queue and Table services from your code by using that connection string.\n\nWhen you explicitly specify service endpoints in the connection string, you have two options for specifying `credentials` in the string above:\n\n- You can specify the account name and key: `AccountName=myAccountName;AccountKey=myAccountKey` \n- You can specify a shared access signature: `SharedAccessSignature=base64Signature`\n\n### Specifying a Blob endpoint with a custom domain name \n\nIf you have registered a custom domain name for use with the Blob service, you may want to explicitly configure the blob endpoint in your connection string. The endpoint value that is listed in the connection string is used to construct the request URIs to the Blob service, and it dictates the form of any URIs that are returned to your code. \n\nFor example, a connection string to a Blob endpoint on a custom domain may be similar to:\n\n    DefaultEndpointsProtocol=https;\n    BlobEndpoint=www.mydomain.com;\n    AccountName=storagesample;\n    AccountKey=<account-key> \n\n\n### Specifying a Blob endpoint with a shared access signature \n\nYou can create a connection string with explicit endpoints to access storage resources via a shared access signature. In this case, you can specify the shared access signature for as part of the connection string, rather than the account name and key credentials. The shared access signature token encapsulates information about the resource to be accessed, the period of time for which it is available, and the permissions being granted. For more information about shared access signatures, see [Delegating Access with a Shared Access Signature](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ee395415.aspx).\n\nTo create a connection string that includes a shared access signature, specify the string in the following format:\n\n    BlobEndpoint=myBlobEndpoint; QueueEndpoint=myQueueEndpoint;TableEndpoint=myTableEndpoint;SharedAccessSignature=base64Signature\n\nThe endpoint can be either the default service endpoint or a custom endpoint. The `base64Signature` corresponds to the signature portion of a shared access signature. The signature is an HMAC computed over a valid string-to-sign and key using the SHA256 algorithm, that is then Base64-encoded.\n\n### Creating a connection string with an endpoint suffix\n\nTo create a connection string for storage service in regions or instances with different endpoint suffixes, such as for Azure China or Azure Governance, use the following connection string format. Indicate whether you want to connect to the storage account through HTTP or HTTPS, replace `myAccountName` with the name of your storage account, replace `myAccountKey` with your account access key, and replace `mySuffix` with the URI suffix:\n\n\n    DefaultEndpointsProtocol=[http|https];AccountName=myAccountName;AccountKey=myAccountKey;EndpointSuffix=mySuffix;\n\n\nFor example, your connection string should look similar to the following sample connection string:\n\n    DefaultEndpointsProtocol=https;\n    AccountName=storagesample;\n    AccountKey=<account-key>;\n    EndpointSuffix=core.chinacloudapi.cn;\n\n\n "
}