{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Data Catalog prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        26,
        58
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What do I need to get started with Azure Data Catalog?",
      "pos": [
        76,
        130
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What do I need to get started with Azure Data Catalog?",
      "pos": [
        432,
        486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Data Catalog prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        491,
        523
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are a few things you’ll need to take care of before you can set up <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        525,
        621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Don’t worry – they won’t take long!",
      "pos": [
        622,
        657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory",
      "pos": [
        662,
        684
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) provides an easy way for your business to manage identity and access, both in the cloud and on-premises.",
      "pos": [
        686,
        824
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users can use a single work or school account for single sign-on to any cloud and on-premises web application.",
      "pos": [
        825,
        935
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Data Catalog uses Azure AD to authenticate sign-on.",
      "pos": [
        936,
        993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To learn more, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to get started using Azure AD<ept id=\"p1\">](active-directory-get-started.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        994,
        1082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Subscription",
      "pos": [
        1086,
        1104
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure subscriptions help you organize access to cloud service resources like Azure Data Catalog.",
      "pos": [
        1105,
        1201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They also help you control how resource usage is reported, billed, and paid for.",
      "pos": [
        1202,
        1282
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each subscription can have a different billing and payment setup, so you can have different subscriptions and different plans by department, project, regional office, and so on.",
      "pos": [
        1283,
        1460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Every cloud service belongs to a subscription, and you need to have a subscription before setting up Azure Data Catalog.",
      "pos": [
        1461,
        1581
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To learn more, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage Accounts, Subscriptions, and Administrative Roles<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh531793.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1582,
        1716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        1720,
        1724
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Azure Data Catalog prerequisites\"\n   description=\"What do I need to get started with Azure Data Catalog?\"\n   services=\"data-catalog\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"dvana\"\n   manager=\"mblythe\"\n   editor=\"\"\n   tags=\"\"/>\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"data-catalog\"\n   ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"data-catalog\"\n   ms.date=\"07/13/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"derrickv\"/>\n\n# What do I need to get started with Azure Data Catalog?\n\n## Azure Data Catalog prerequisites\n\nThere are a few things you’ll need to take care of before you can set up **Azure Data Catalog**. Don’t worry – they won’t take long!\n\n## Azure Active Directory\n\nAzure Active Directory (Azure AD) provides an easy way for your business to manage identity and access, both in the cloud and on-premises. Users can use a single work or school account for single sign-on to any cloud and on-premises web application. Azure Data Catalog uses Azure AD to authenticate sign-on. To learn more, see [How to get started using Azure AD](active-directory-get-started.md).\n\n##Azure Subscription\nAzure subscriptions help you organize access to cloud service resources like Azure Data Catalog. They also help you control how resource usage is reported, billed, and paid for. Each subscription can have a different billing and payment setup, so you can have different subscriptions and different plans by department, project, regional office, and so on. Every cloud service belongs to a subscription, and you need to have a subscription before setting up Azure Data Catalog. To learn more, see [Manage Accounts, Subscriptions, and Administrative Roles](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh531793.aspx).\n\n\n\ntest\n"
}