{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Get started with Internal load balancer | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        83
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure Internal Load balancer and how to implement them for Virtual Machines and Cloud deployments",
      "pos": [
        102,
        203
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get started configuring an internal load balancer",
      "pos": [
        527,
        576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[AZURE.SELECTOR]",
      "pos": [
        580,
        596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Classic steps",
      "pos": [
        600,
        619
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource Manager Powershell steps",
      "pos": [
        662,
        695
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Internal Load Balancing (ILB) provides load balancing between virtual machines that reside inside of a cloud service or a virtual network with a regional scope.",
      "pos": [
        740,
        906
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information about the use and configuration of virtual networks with a regional scope, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Regional Virtual Networks<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-networks-migrate-to-regional-vnet.md)</ept> in the Azure blog.",
      "pos": [
        907,
        1094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Existing virtual networks that have been configured for an affinity group cannot use ILB.",
      "pos": [
        1095,
        1184
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating an Internal load-balanced set for Virtual Machines",
      "pos": [
        1191,
        1250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create an Azure internal load-balanced set and the servers that will send their traffic to it, you must do the following:",
      "pos": [
        1252,
        1376
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create an ILB instance that will be the endpoint of incoming traffic to be load balanced across the servers of a load-balanced set.",
      "pos": [
        1381,
        1512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add endpoints corresponding to the virtual machines that will be receiving the incoming traffic.",
      "pos": [
        1517,
        1613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure the servers that will be sending the traffic to be load balanced to send their traffic to the virtual IP address (VIP) of the ILB instance.",
      "pos": [
        1618,
        1767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 1: Create an ILB instance",
      "pos": [
        1773,
        1803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For an existing cloud service or a cloud service deployed under a regional virtual network, you can create and ILB instance with the following Windows PowerShell commands:",
      "pos": [
        1805,
        1976
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use these commands, fill in the values and remove the &lt; and &gt;.",
      "pos": [
        2302,
        2367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example:",
      "pos": [
        2368,
        2387
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 2: Add endpoints to the ILB instance",
      "pos": [
        2608,
        2649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For existing virtual machines, you can add endpoints to the ILB instance with the following commands:",
      "pos": [
        2651,
        2752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use these commands, fill in the values and remove the &lt; and &gt;.",
      "pos": [
        3258,
        3323
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that this use of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Add-AzureEndpoint<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn495300.aspx)</ept> Windows PowerShell cmdlet uses the DefaultProbe parameter set.",
      "pos": [
        3325,
        3483
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information on additional parameter sets, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Add-AzureEndpoint<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn495300.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3484,
        3609
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example:",
      "pos": [
        3611,
        3630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 3: Configure your servers to send their traffic to the new ILB endpoint",
      "pos": [
        4015,
        4091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must configure the servers whose traffic is going to be load balanced to use the new IP address (the VIP) of the ILB instance.",
      "pos": [
        4093,
        4223
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is the address on which the ILB instance is listening.",
      "pos": [
        4224,
        4283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In most cases, you just need to add or modify a DNS record for the VIP of the ILB instance.",
      "pos": [
        4284,
        4375
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you specified the IP address during the creation of the ILB instance, you already have the VIP.",
      "pos": [
        4377,
        4475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Otherwise, you can see the VIP from the following commands:",
      "pos": [
        4476,
        4535
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use these commands, fill in the values and remove the &lt; and &gt;.",
      "pos": [
        4643,
        4708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example:",
      "pos": [
        4709,
        4728
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From the display of the Get-AzureInternalLoadBalancer command, note the IP address and make the necessary changes to your servers or DNS records to ensure that traffic gets sent to the VIP.",
      "pos": [
        4826,
        5015
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5018,
        5676
      ],
      "content": "[AZURE.NOTE] The Microsoft Azure platform uses a static, publicly routable IPv4 address for a variety of administrative scenarios. The IP address is 168.63.129.16. This IP address should not be blocked by any firewalls, as it can cause unexpected behavior.\nWith respect to the Azure ILB, this IP address is used by monitoring probes from the load balancer, to determine health state for VMs in a load balanced set. If a Network Security Group is used to restrict traffic to Azure Virtual Machines in an internally load-balanced set, or is applied to a Virtual Network Subnet, ensure that a Network Security Rule is added to allow traffic from 168.63.129.16.",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        ">"
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "[AZURE.NOTE] The Microsoft Azure platform uses a static, publicly routable IPv4 address for a variety of administrative scenarios. The IP address is 168.63.129.16. This IP address should not be blocked by any firewalls, as it can cause unexpected behavior.",
          "pos": [
            0,
            256
          ],
          "nodes": [
            {
              "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> The Microsoft Azure platform uses a static, publicly routable IPv4 address for a variety of administrative scenarios.",
              "pos": [
                0,
                130
              ]
            },
            {
              "content": "The IP address is 168.63.129.16.",
              "pos": [
                131,
                163
              ]
            },
            {
              "content": "This IP address should not be blocked by any firewalls, as it can cause unexpected behavior.",
              "pos": [
                164,
                256
              ]
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "With respect to the Azure ILB, this IP address is used by monitoring probes from the load balancer, to determine health state for VMs in a load balanced set. If a Network Security Group is used to restrict traffic to Azure Virtual Machines in an internally load-balanced set, or is applied to a Virtual Network Subnet, ensure that a Network Security Rule is added to allow traffic from 168.63.129.16.",
          "pos": [
            257,
            657
          ],
          "nodes": [
            {
              "content": "With respect to the Azure ILB, this IP address is used by monitoring probes from the load balancer, to determine health state for VMs in a load balanced set.",
              "pos": [
                0,
                157
              ]
            },
            {
              "content": "If a Network Security Group is used to restrict traffic to Azure Virtual Machines in an internally load-balanced set, or is applied to a Virtual Network Subnet, ensure that a Network Security Rule is added to allow traffic from 168.63.129.16.",
              "pos": [
                158,
                400
              ]
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "End-to-end examples of internal load balancing",
      "pos": [
        5683,
        5729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To step you through the end-to end process of creating a load-balanced set for two example configurations, see the following sections.",
      "pos": [
        5731,
        5865
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Internet-facing, multi-tier application",
      "pos": [
        5871,
        5913
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Contoso Corporation wants to provide load balancing between a set of Internet-facing web servers and a set of database servers.",
      "pos": [
        5915,
        6046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both sets of servers are hosted in a single Azure cloud service.",
      "pos": [
        6047,
        6111
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Web server traffic to TCP port 1433 must be distributed among three virtual machines in the database tier.",
      "pos": [
        6112,
        6218
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure 1 shows the configuration.",
      "pos": [
        6219,
        6252
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Internal load-balanced set for the database tier",
      "pos": [
        6256,
        6304
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure 1: Example of an Internet-facing, multi-tier application",
      "pos": [
        6363,
        6426
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The configuration consists of the following:",
      "pos": [
        6428,
        6472
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The existing cloud service hosting the virtual machines is named Contoso-PartnerSite.",
      "pos": [
        6476,
        6561
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The three existing database servers are named PARTNER-SQL-1, PARTNER-SQL-2, and PARTNER-SQL-3.",
      "pos": [
        6565,
        6659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Web servers in the web tier connect to the database servers in the database tier using the DNS name partner-sql.external.contoso.com.",
      "pos": [
        6663,
        6796
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following commands configure a new ILB instance named PARTNER-DBTIER and add endpoints to the virtual machines corresponding to the three database servers:",
      "pos": [
        6798,
        6957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, Contoso determined the VIP of the PARTNER-DBTIER ILB instance with the following command:",
      "pos": [
        7998,
        8093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From the display of this command, Contoso noted the VIP address of 100.64.65.211 and configured the DNS Address (A) record for the name partner-sql.external.contoso.com to use this new address.",
      "pos": [
        8167,
        8360
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An LOB application hosted in Azure",
      "pos": [
        8366,
        8400
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Contoso Corporation wants to host a line-of-business (LOB) application on a set of web servers in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        8402,
        8510
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Client traffic to TCP port 80 must be load-balanced among three virtual machines running in a cross-premises virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        8511,
        8636
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure 2 shows the configuration.",
      "pos": [
        8637,
        8670
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Internal load balancing for an LOB application",
      "pos": [
        8674,
        8720
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure 2: Example of an LOB application hosted in Azure",
      "pos": [
        8779,
        8834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The configuration consists of the following:",
      "pos": [
        8836,
        8880
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The existing cloud service hosting the virtual machines is named Contoso-Legal.",
      "pos": [
        8884,
        8963
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The subnet on which the LOB servers are located is named LOB-LEGAL and Contoso has chosen the address 198.168.99.145 as the VIP address for the internal load balancer.",
      "pos": [
        8967,
        9134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The three existing LOB servers are named LEGAL-1, LEGAL-2, and LEGAL-3.",
      "pos": [
        9138,
        9209
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Intranet web clients connect to them using the DNS name legalnet.corp.contoso.com.",
      "pos": [
        9213,
        9295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following commands create an ILB instance named LEGAL-ILB and add endpoints to the virtual machines corresponding to the three LOB servers:",
      "pos": [
        9297,
        9440
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, Contoso configured the DNS A record for the legalnet.corp.contoso.com name to use 198.168.99.145.",
      "pos": [
        10532,
        10635
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add a Virtual Machine to ILB",
      "pos": [
        10640,
        10668
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To add a virtual machine to an ILB instance as it is created, you can use the New-AzureInternalLoadBalancerConfig and New-AzureVMConfig cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        10670,
        10814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example:",
      "pos": [
        10816,
        10835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuring ILB for Cloud Services",
      "pos": [
        11457,
        11491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ILB is supported for both Virtual machines and Cloud Services",
      "pos": [
        11494,
        11555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An ILB endpoint created in a Cloud Service that is outside a Regional Virtual Network will be accessible only within the Cloud Service.",
      "pos": [
        11556,
        11691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The ILB configuration has to be set during the creation of the first deployment in the Cloud Service, as shown in the sample below.",
      "pos": [
        11693,
        11824
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> prerequisite to run the steps below is to have a virtual network already created for the cloud deployment.",
      "pos": [
        11827,
        11951
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You will need the virtual network name and subnet name to create the ILB.",
      "pos": [
        11952,
        12025
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 1",
      "pos": [
        12031,
        12037
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12039,
        12237
      ],
      "content": "Open the service configuration file (.cscfg) for your cloud deployment in visual studio and add the following section to create the ILB under the last \"<ph id=\"ph1\">`&lt;/Role&gt;`</ph>\" item for the network configuration."
    },
    {
      "content": "Let's add the values for the network configuration file to show how it will look like.",
      "pos": [
        12549,
        12635
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the example, assume you created a subnet called \"test_vnet\" with a subnet 10.0.0.0/24 called test_subnet and a static IP 10.0.0.4.",
      "pos": [
        12636,
        12769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The load balancer will be named testLB.",
      "pos": [
        12770,
        12809
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13087,
        13214
      ],
      "content": "More information about the load balancer schema see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>add load balancer<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn722411.aspx)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 2",
      "pos": [
        13220,
        13226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Change the service definition (.csdef) file to add endpoints to the ILB.",
      "pos": [
        13229,
        13301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The moment a role instance is created, the service definition file will add the role instances to the ILB.",
      "pos": [
        13302,
        13408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Following the same values from the example above, let's add the values to the service definition file",
      "pos": [
        13819,
        13920
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The network traffic  will be load balanced using testLB load balancer using port 80 for incoming requests, sending to worker role instances also on port 80.",
      "pos": [
        14173,
        14329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Removing ILB configuration",
      "pos": [
        14336,
        14362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To remove a virtual machine as an endpoint from an ILB instance, use the following commands:",
      "pos": [
        14364,
        14456
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use these commands, fill in the values, removing the &lt; and &gt;.",
      "pos": [
        14661,
        14725
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example:",
      "pos": [
        14727,
        14746
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To remove an ILB instance from a cloud service, use the following commands:",
      "pos": [
        14914,
        14989
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use these commands, fill in the value and remove the &lt; and &gt;.",
      "pos": [
        15079,
        15143
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example:",
      "pos": [
        15145,
        15164
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additional information about ILB cmdlets",
      "pos": [
        15246,
        15286
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To obtain additional information about ILB cmdlets, run the following commands at an Azure Windows PowerShell prompt:",
      "pos": [
        15289,
        15406
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-help New-AzureInternalLoadBalancerConfig -full",
      "pos": [
        15410,
        15460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-help Add-AzureInternalLoadBalancer -full",
      "pos": [
        15464,
        15508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-help Get-AzureInternalLoadbalancer -full",
      "pos": [
        15512,
        15556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-help Remove-AzureInternalLoadBalancer -full",
      "pos": [
        15560,
        15607
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See Also",
      "pos": [
        15612,
        15620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure a Load balancer distribution mode",
      "pos": [
        15623,
        15666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure idle TCP timeout settings for your load balancer",
      "pos": [
        15706,
        15764
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        15804,
        15808
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Get started with Internal load balancer | Microsoft Azure \"\n   description=\"Configure Internal Load balancer and how to implement them for Virtual Machines and Cloud deployments\"\n   services=\"load-balancer\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   authors=\"joaoma\"\n   manager=\"adinah\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"load-balancer\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"get-started-article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"09/01/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"joaoma\" />\n\n# Get started configuring an internal load balancer\n\n> [AZURE.SELECTOR]\n- [Azure Classic steps](load-balancer-internal-getstarted.md)\n- [Resource Manager Powershell steps](load-balancer-internal-arm-powershell.md)\n\nAzure Internal Load Balancing (ILB) provides load balancing between virtual machines that reside inside of a cloud service or a virtual network with a regional scope. For information about the use and configuration of virtual networks with a regional scope, see [Regional Virtual Networks](virtual-networks-migrate-to-regional-vnet.md) in the Azure blog. Existing virtual networks that have been configured for an affinity group cannot use ILB.\n\n\n\n## Creating an Internal load-balanced set for Virtual Machines\n\nTo create an Azure internal load-balanced set and the servers that will send their traffic to it, you must do the following:\n\n1. Create an ILB instance that will be the endpoint of incoming traffic to be load balanced across the servers of a load-balanced set.\n\n1. Add endpoints corresponding to the virtual machines that will be receiving the incoming traffic.\n\n1. Configure the servers that will be sending the traffic to be load balanced to send their traffic to the virtual IP address (VIP) of the ILB instance.\n\n### Step 1: Create an ILB instance\n\nFor an existing cloud service or a cloud service deployed under a regional virtual network, you can create and ILB instance with the following Windows PowerShell commands:\n\n    $svc=\"<Cloud Service Name>\"\n    $ilb=\"<Name of your ILB instance>\"\n    $subnet=\"<Name of the subnet within your virtual network>\"\n    $IP=\"<The IPv4 address to use on the subnet-optional>\"\n\n    Add-AzureInternalLoadBalancer -ServiceName $svc -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb –SubnetName $subnet –StaticVNetIPAddress $IP\n\n\nTo use these commands, fill in the values and remove the < and >. Here is an example:\n\n    $svc=\"WebCloud-NY\"\n    $ilb=\"SQL-BE\"\n    $subnet=\"Farm1\"\n    $IP=\"192.168.98.10\"\n    Add-AzureInternalLoadBalancer -ServiceName $svc -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb –SubnetName $subnet –StaticVNetIPAddress $IP\n\n\n### Step 2: Add endpoints to the ILB instance\n\nFor existing virtual machines, you can add endpoints to the ILB instance with the following commands:\n\n    $svc=\"<Cloud service name>\"\n    $vmname=\"<Name of the VM>\"\n    $epname=\"<Name of the endpoint>\"\n    $lbsetname=\"<Name of the load balancer set>\"\n    $prot=\"tcp\" or \"udp\"\n    $locport=<local port number>\n    $pubport=<public port number>\n    $ilb=\"<Name of your ILB instance>\"\n    Get-AzureVM –ServiceName $svc –Name $vmname | Add-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname -LbsetName $lbsetname -Protocol $prot -LocalPort $locport -PublicPort $pubport –DefaultProbe -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb | Update-AzureVM\n\nTo use these commands, fill in the values and remove the < and >.\n\nNote that this use of the [Add-AzureEndpoint](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn495300.aspx) Windows PowerShell cmdlet uses the DefaultProbe parameter set. For more information on additional parameter sets, see [Add-AzureEndpoint](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn495300.aspx).\n\nHere is an example:\n\n    $svc=\"AZ-LOB1\"\n    $vmname=\"SQL-LOBAZ1\"\n    $epname=\"SQL1\"\n    $lbsetname=\"SQL-LB\"\n    $prot=\"tcp\"\n    $locport=1433\n    $pubport=1433\n    $ilb=\"SQL ILB\"\n    Get-AzureVM –ServiceName $svc –Name $vmname | Add-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname -Lbset $lbsetname -Protocol $prot -LocalPort $locport -PublicPort $pubport –DefaultProbe -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb | Update-AzureVM\n\n\n### Step 3: Configure your servers to send their traffic to the new ILB endpoint\n\nYou must configure the servers whose traffic is going to be load balanced to use the new IP address (the VIP) of the ILB instance. This is the address on which the ILB instance is listening. In most cases, you just need to add or modify a DNS record for the VIP of the ILB instance.\n\nIf you specified the IP address during the creation of the ILB instance, you already have the VIP. Otherwise, you can see the VIP from the following commands:\n\n    $svc=\"<Cloud Service Name>\"\n    Get-AzureService -ServiceName $svc | Get-AzureInternalLoadBalancer\n\n\n\nTo use these commands, fill in the values and remove the < and >. Here is an example:\n\n    $svc=\"WebCloud-NY\"\n    Get-AzureService -ServiceName $svc | Get-AzureInternalLoadBalancer\n\n\nFrom the display of the Get-AzureInternalLoadBalancer command, note the IP address and make the necessary changes to your servers or DNS records to ensure that traffic gets sent to the VIP.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] The Microsoft Azure platform uses a static, publicly routable IPv4 address for a variety of administrative scenarios. The IP address is 168.63.129.16. This IP address should not be blocked by any firewalls, as it can cause unexpected behavior.\n>With respect to the Azure ILB, this IP address is used by monitoring probes from the load balancer, to determine health state for VMs in a load balanced set. If a Network Security Group is used to restrict traffic to Azure Virtual Machines in an internally load-balanced set, or is applied to a Virtual Network Subnet, ensure that a Network Security Rule is added to allow traffic from 168.63.129.16.\n\n\n\n## End-to-end examples of internal load balancing\n\nTo step you through the end-to end process of creating a load-balanced set for two example configurations, see the following sections.\n\n### An Internet-facing, multi-tier application\n\nThe Contoso Corporation wants to provide load balancing between a set of Internet-facing web servers and a set of database servers. Both sets of servers are hosted in a single Azure cloud service. Web server traffic to TCP port 1433 must be distributed among three virtual machines in the database tier. Figure 1 shows the configuration.\n\n![Internal load-balanced set for the database tier](./media/load-balancer-internal-getstarted/IC736321.png)\n\nFigure 1: Example of an Internet-facing, multi-tier application\n\nThe configuration consists of the following:\n\n- The existing cloud service hosting the virtual machines is named Contoso-PartnerSite.\n\n- The three existing database servers are named PARTNER-SQL-1, PARTNER-SQL-2, and PARTNER-SQL-3.\n\n- Web servers in the web tier connect to the database servers in the database tier using the DNS name partner-sql.external.contoso.com.\n\nThe following commands configure a new ILB instance named PARTNER-DBTIER and add endpoints to the virtual machines corresponding to the three database servers:\n\n    $svc=\"Contoso-PartnerSite\"\n    $ilb=\"PARTNER-DBTIER\"\n    Add-AzureInternalLoadBalancer -ServiceName $svc -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb\n\n    $prot=\"tcp\"\n    $locport=1433\n    $pubport=1433\n    $epname=\"DBTIER1\"\n    $lbsetname=\"SQL-LB\"\n    $vmname=\"PARTNER-SQL-1\"\n    Get-AzureVM –ServiceName $svc –Name $vmname | Add-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname -LbSetName $lbsetname -Protocol $prot -LocalPort $locport -PublicPort $pubport –DefaultProbe -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb | Update-AzureVM\n\n    $epname=\"DBTIER2\"\n    $vmname=\"PARTNER-SQL-2\"\n    Get-AzureVM –ServiceName $svc –Name $vmname | Add-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname -LbSetName $lbsetname -Protocol $prot -LocalPort $locport -PublicPort $pubport –DefaultProbe -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb | Update-AzureVM\n\n    $epname=\"DBTIER3\"\n    $vmname=\"PARTNER-SQL-3\"\n    Get-AzureVM –ServiceName $svc –Name $vmname | Add-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname -LbSetName $lbsetname -Protocol $prot -LocalPort $locport -PublicPort $pubport –DefaultProbe -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb | Update-AzureVM\n\nNext, Contoso determined the VIP of the PARTNER-DBTIER ILB instance with the following command:\n\n    Get-AzureService -ServiceName $svc | Get-AzureInternalLoadBalancer\n\nFrom the display of this command, Contoso noted the VIP address of 100.64.65.211 and configured the DNS Address (A) record for the name partner-sql.external.contoso.com to use this new address.\n\n### An LOB application hosted in Azure\n\nThe Contoso Corporation wants to host a line-of-business (LOB) application on a set of web servers in Azure. Client traffic to TCP port 80 must be load-balanced among three virtual machines running in a cross-premises virtual network. Figure 2 shows the configuration.\n\n![Internal load balancing for an LOB application](./media/load-balancer-internal-getstarted/IC744148.png)\n\nFigure 2: Example of an LOB application hosted in Azure\n\nThe configuration consists of the following:\n\n- The existing cloud service hosting the virtual machines is named Contoso-Legal.\n\n- The subnet on which the LOB servers are located is named LOB-LEGAL and Contoso has chosen the address 198.168.99.145 as the VIP address for the internal load balancer.\n\n- The three existing LOB servers are named LEGAL-1, LEGAL-2, and LEGAL-3.\n\n- Intranet web clients connect to them using the DNS name legalnet.corp.contoso.com.\n\nThe following commands create an ILB instance named LEGAL-ILB and add endpoints to the virtual machines corresponding to the three LOB servers:\n\n\n    $svc=\"Contoso-Legal\"\n    $ilb=\"LEGAL-ILB\"\n    $subnet=\"LOB-LEGAL\"\n    $IP=\"198.168.99.145\"\n    Add-AzureInternalLoadBalancer –ServiceName $svc -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb –SubnetName $subnet –StaticVNetIPAddress $IP\n\n    $prot=\"tcp\"\n    $locport=80\n    $pubport=80\n    $epname=\"LOB1\"\n    $lbsetname=\"LOB-LB\"\n    $vmname=\"LEGAL-1\"\n    Get-AzureVM –ServiceName $svc –Name $vmname | Add-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname-LbSetName $lbsetname -Protocol $prot -LocalPort $locport -PublicPort $pubport –DefaultProbe -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb | Update-AzureVM\n\n    $epname=\"LOB2\"\n    $vmname=\"LEGAL2\"\n    Get-AzureVM –ServiceName $svc –Name $vmname | Add-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname -LbSetName $lbsetname -Protocol $prot -LocalPort $locport -PublicPort $pubport –DefaultProbe -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb | Update-AzureVM\n\n    $epname=\"LOB3\"\n    $vmname=\"LEGAL3\"\n    Get-AzureVM –ServiceName $svc –Name $vmname | Add-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname -LbSetName $lbsetname -Protocol $prot -LocalPort $locport -PublicPort $pubport –DefaultProbe -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb | Update-AzureVM\n\n\nNext, Contoso configured the DNS A record for the legalnet.corp.contoso.com name to use 198.168.99.145.\n\n## Add a Virtual Machine to ILB\n\nTo add a virtual machine to an ILB instance as it is created, you can use the New-AzureInternalLoadBalancerConfig and New-AzureVMConfig cmdlets.\n\nHere is an example:\n\n    $svc=\"AZ-LOB1\"\n    $ilb=\"LOB-ILB\"\n    $vnet=\"LOBNet_Azure\"\n    $subnet=\"LOBServers\"\n    $vmname=\"LOB-WEB1\"\n    $adminuser=\"Lando\"\n    $adminpw=\"Platform327\"\n    $regionname=\"North Central US\"\n\n    $myilbconfig=New-AzureInternalLoadBalancerConfig -InternalLoadBalancerName $ilb -SubnetName $subnet\n    $images = Get-AzureVMImage\n    New-AzureVMConfig -Name $vmname -InstanceSize Small -ImageName $images[50].ImageName | Add-AzureProvisioningConfig -Windows -AdminUsername $adminuser -Password $adminpw | New-AzureVM -ServiceName $svc -InternalLoadBalancerConfig $myilbconfig -Location $regionname –VNetName $vnet\n\n## Configuring ILB for Cloud Services\n\n\nILB is supported for both Virtual machines and Cloud Services\nAn ILB endpoint created in a Cloud Service that is outside a Regional Virtual Network will be accessible only within the Cloud Service.\n\nThe ILB configuration has to be set during the creation of the first deployment in the Cloud Service, as shown in the sample below.\n\n>[AZURE.IMPORTANT] prerequisite to run the steps below is to have a virtual network already created for the cloud deployment. You will need the virtual network name and subnet name to create the ILB.\n\n### Step 1\n\nOpen the service configuration file (.cscfg) for your cloud deployment in visual studio and add the following section to create the ILB under the last \"`</Role>`\" item for the network configuration. \n\n\n\n\n    <NetworkConfiguration>\n      <LoadBalancers>\n        <LoadBalancer name=\"name of the load balancer\">\n          <FrontendIPConfiguration type=\"private\" subnet=\"subnet-name\" staticVirtualNetworkIPAddress=\"static-IP-address\"/>\n        </LoadBalancer>\n      </LoadBalancers>\n    </NetworkConfiguration>\n \n\nLet's add the values for the network configuration file to show how it will look like. In the example, assume you created a subnet called \"test_vnet\" with a subnet 10.0.0.0/24 called test_subnet and a static IP 10.0.0.4. The load balancer will be named testLB.\n\n    <NetworkConfiguration>\n      <LoadBalancers>\n        <LoadBalancer name=\"testLB\">\n          <FrontendIPConfiguration type=\"private\" subnet=\"test_subnet\" staticVirtualNetworkIPAddress=\"10.0.0.4\"/>\n        </LoadBalancer>\n      </LoadBalancers>\n    </NetworkConfiguration>\n\nMore information about the load balancer schema see [add load balancer](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn722411.aspx)\n\n### Step 2\n\n\nChange the service definition (.csdef) file to add endpoints to the ILB. The moment a role instance is created, the service definition file will add the role instances to the ILB.\n\n\n    <WorkerRole name=\"worker-role-name\" vmsize=\"worker-role-size\" enableNativeCodeExecution=\"[true|false]\">\n      <Endpoints>\n        <InputEndpoint name=\"input-endpoint-name\" protocol=\"[http|https|tcp|udp]\" localPort=\"local-port-number\" port=\"port-number\" certificate=\"certificate-name\" loadBalancerProbe=\"load-balancer-probe-name\" loadBalancer=\"load-balancer-name\" />\n      </Endpoints>\n    </WorkerRole>\n\nFollowing the same values from the example above, let's add the values to the service definition file \n\n    <WorkerRole name=WorkerRole1\" vmsize=\"A7\" enableNativeCodeExecution=\"[true|false]\">\n      <Endpoints>\n        <InputEndpoint name=\"endpoint1\" protocol=\"http\" localPort=\"80\" port=\"80\" loadBalancer=\"testLB\" />\n      </Endpoints>\n    </WorkerRole>\n\nThe network traffic  will be load balanced using testLB load balancer using port 80 for incoming requests, sending to worker role instances also on port 80. \n\n\n## Removing ILB configuration\n\nTo remove a virtual machine as an endpoint from an ILB instance, use the following commands:\n\n    $svc=\"<Cloud service name>\"\n    $vmname=\"<Name of the VM>\"\n    $epname=\"<Name of the endpoint>\"\n    Get-AzureVM -ServiceName $svc -Name $vmname | Remove-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname | Update-AzureVM\n\nTo use these commands, fill in the values, removing the < and >.\n\nHere is an example:\n\n    $svc=\"AZ-LOB1\"\n    $vmname=\"SQL-LOBAZ1\"\n    $epname=\"SQL1\"\n    Get-AzureVM -ServiceName $svc -Name $vmname | Remove-AzureEndpoint -Name $epname | Update-AzureVM\n\nTo remove an ILB instance from a cloud service, use the following commands:\n\n    $svc=\"<Cloud service name>\"\n    Remove-AzureInternalLoadBalancer -ServiceName $svc\n\nTo use these commands, fill in the value and remove the < and >.\n\nHere is an example:\n\n    $svc=\"AZ-LOB1\"\n    Remove-AzureInternalLoadBalancer -ServiceName $svc\n\n\n\n## Additional information about ILB cmdlets\n\n\nTo obtain additional information about ILB cmdlets, run the following commands at an Azure Windows PowerShell prompt:\n\n- Get-help New-AzureInternalLoadBalancerConfig -full\n\n- Get-help Add-AzureInternalLoadBalancer -full\n\n- Get-help Get-AzureInternalLoadbalancer -full\n\n- Get-help Remove-AzureInternalLoadBalancer -full\n\n## See Also\n\n[Configure a Load balancer distribution mode](load-balancer-distribution-mode.md)\n\n[Configure idle TCP timeout settings for your load balancer](load-balancer-tcp-idle-timeout.md)\n \n\ntest\n"
}