{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Backing up Azure Automation",
      "pos": [
        27,
        54
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Describes how to backup the contents of an automation account so that they can be retained after an automation account is deleted.",
      "pos": [
        72,
        202
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Backing up Azure Automation",
      "pos": [
        507,
        534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you delete an automation account in Microsoft Azure, all objects in the account are deleted including runbooks, modules, settings, jobs, and assets.",
      "pos": [
        536,
        689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The objects cannot be recovered after the account is deleted.",
      "pos": [
        690,
        751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the following information to backup the contents of your automation account before deleting it.",
      "pos": [
        753,
        860
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Runbooks",
      "pos": [
        866,
        874
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can export your runbooks to script files using either the Azure Management Portal or the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get-AzureAutomationRunbookDefinition<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn690269.aspx)</ept> cmdlet in Windows PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        876,
        1087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These script files can be imported into another automation account as discussed in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating or Importing a Runbook<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn643637.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1089,
        1256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Integration modules",
      "pos": [
        1262,
        1281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot export integration modules from Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        1283,
        1343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must ensure that they are available outside of the automation account.",
      "pos": [
        1345,
        1419
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Assets",
      "pos": [
        1424,
        1430
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot export <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>assets<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn939988.aspx)</ept> from Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        1432,
        1531
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using the Azure Management Portal, you must note the details of variables, credentials, certificates, connections, and schedules.",
      "pos": [
        1533,
        1662
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must then manually create any assets that are used by runbooks that you import into another automation.",
      "pos": [
        1664,
        1771
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1773,
        1993
      ],
      "content": "You can use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure cmdlets<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn690262.aspx)</ept> to retrieve details of unencrypted assets and either save them for future reference or create equivalent assets in another automation account."
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot retrieve the value for encrypted variables or the password field of credentials using cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        1995,
        2100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don't know these values, then you can retrieve them from a runbook using the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get-AutomationVariable<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn940012.aspx)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Get-AutomationPSCredential<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn940015.aspx)</ept> activities.",
      "pos": [
        2102,
        2355
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot export certificates from Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        2357,
        2410
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must ensure that any certificates are available outside of Azure.",
      "pos": [
        2412,
        2481
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Related articles",
      "pos": [
        2486,
        2502
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating or Importing a Runbook",
      "pos": [
        2507,
        2538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Automation assets",
      "pos": [
        2593,
        2610
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure cmdlets<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn690262.aspx)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        2664,
        2729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        2731,
        2735
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Backing up Azure Automation\"\n   description=\"Describes how to backup the contents of an automation account so that they can be retained after an automation account is deleted.\"\n   services=\"automation\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"bwren\"\n   manager=\"stevenka\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"automation\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"07/22/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"bwren\" />\n\n# Backing up Azure Automation\n\nWhen you delete an automation account in Microsoft Azure, all objects in the account are deleted including runbooks, modules, settings, jobs, and assets. The objects cannot be recovered after the account is deleted.  You can use the following information to backup the contents of your automation account before deleting it. \n\n## Runbooks\n\nYou can export your runbooks to script files using either the Azure Management Portal or the [Get-AzureAutomationRunbookDefinition](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn690269.aspx) cmdlet in Windows PowerShell.  These script files can be imported into another automation account as discussed in [Creating or Importing a Runbook](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn643637.aspx).\n\n\n## Integration modules\n\nYou cannot export integration modules from Azure Automation.  You must ensure that they are available outside of the automation account.\n\n## Assets\n\nYou cannot export [assets](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn939988.aspx) from Azure Automation.  Using the Azure Management Portal, you must note the details of variables, credentials, certificates, connections, and schedules.  You must then manually create any assets that are used by runbooks that you import into another automation.\n\nYou can use [Azure cmdlets](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn690262.aspx) to retrieve details of unencrypted assets and either save them for future reference or create equivalent assets in another automation account.\n\nYou cannot retrieve the value for encrypted variables or the password field of credentials using cmdlets.  If you don't know these values, then you can retrieve them from a runbook using the [Get-AutomationVariable](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn940012.aspx) and [Get-AutomationPSCredential](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn940015.aspx) activities.\n\nYou cannot export certificates from Azure Automation.  You must ensure that any certificates are available outside of Azure.\n\n## Related articles\n\n- [Creating or Importing a Runbook](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn643637.aspx)\n- [Automation assets](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn939988.aspx)\n- [Azure cmdlets](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn690262.aspx) \ntest\n"
}