{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "CDN Caching Policy in Media Services Extension",
      "pos": [
        28,
        74
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic gives an overview of a CDM caching policy in Media Services Extension.",
      "pos": [
        94,
        175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CDN Caching Policy in Media Services Extension",
      "pos": [
        467,
        513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Media Services provides HTTP based Adaptive Streaming and progressive download.",
      "pos": [
        515,
        600
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "HTTP based streaming is highly scalable with benefits of caching in proxy and CDN layers as well as client side caching.",
      "pos": [
        601,
        721
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Streaming endpoints provides general streaming capabilities and also configuration for HTTP cache headers.",
      "pos": [
        722,
        828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Streaming endpoints sets HTTP Cache-Control: max-age and Expires headers.",
      "pos": [
        829,
        902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can get more information for HTTP cache headers from <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>W3.org<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616-sec13.html)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        903,
        1025
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Default Caching headers",
      "pos": [
        1029,
        1052
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default streaming-endpoints apply 3 day cache headers for on-demand streaming data (actual media fragments/chunks) and manifest(playlist).",
      "pos": [
        1054,
        1195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For live streaming, streaming endpoints apply 3 day cache headers for data (actual media fragments/chunks) and 2 seconds cache header for manifest(playlist) requests.",
      "pos": [
        1196,
        1362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When live program turns to on-demand (live archive) then on-demand streaming cache headers apply.",
      "pos": [
        1363,
        1460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure CDN integration",
      "pos": [
        1464,
        1485
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Media services provides <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>integrated CDN<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/updates/azure-media-services-now-fully-integrated-with-azure-cdn/)</ept> for streaming-endpoints.",
      "pos": [
        1487,
        1652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cache-control headers applies in the same way as streaming endpoints to CDN enabled streaming endpoints.",
      "pos": [
        1653,
        1757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure CDN uses streaming endpoint configured cache values to define the life time of the internally cached objects and also uses this value to set the delivery cache headers.",
      "pos": [
        1758,
        1932
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using CDN enabled streaming endpoints it is not recommended to set small cache values.",
      "pos": [
        1933,
        2024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Setting small values will decrease the performance and reduce the benefit of CDN.",
      "pos": [
        2025,
        2106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is not allowed to set cache headers smaller than 600 seconds for CDN enabled streaming endpoints.",
      "pos": [
        2107,
        2207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuring cache headers with Azure Media Services",
      "pos": [
        2211,
        2262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use Azure Management portal or Azure Media Services APIs to configure cache header values.",
      "pos": [
        2264,
        2362
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2367,
        2550
      ],
      "content": "To configure cache headers using management portal please refer to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Manage Streaming Endpoints<ept id=\"p1\">](../media-services-manage-origins.md)</ept> section Configuring the Streaming Endpoint."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2554,
        2691
      ],
      "content": "Azure Media Services REST API, <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>StreamingEndpoint<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn783468.aspx#StreamingEndpointCacheControl)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2695,
        2816
      ],
      "content": "Azure Media Services .NET SDK, <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>StreamingEndpointCacheControl Properties<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=615302)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Cache configuration precedence order",
      "pos": [
        2820,
        2856
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Media Services configured cache value overrides default value.",
      "pos": [
        2861,
        2929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If there is no manual configuration, default values applies.",
      "pos": [
        2933,
        2993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default 2 seconds cache headers applies to live streaming manifest(playlist) regardless of Azure Media or Azure Storage configuration and overriding of this value is not available.",
      "pos": [
        2997,
        3180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        3183,
        3187
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"CDN Caching Policy in Media Services Extension\" \n    description=\"This topic gives an overview of a CDM caching policy in Media Services Extension.\" \n    services=\"cdn\" \n    documentationCenter=\".NET\" \n    authors=\"juliako\" \n    manager=\"dwrede\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"cdn\" \n    ms.workload=\"tbd\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"09/01/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"juliako\"/>\n\n#CDN Caching Policy in Media Services Extension\n\nAzure Media Services provides HTTP based Adaptive Streaming and progressive download. HTTP based streaming is highly scalable with benefits of caching in proxy and CDN layers as well as client side caching. Streaming endpoints provides general streaming capabilities and also configuration for HTTP cache headers. Streaming endpoints sets HTTP Cache-Control: max-age and Expires headers. You can get more information for HTTP cache headers from [W3.org](http://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616-sec13.html).\n\n##Default Caching headers\n\nBy default streaming-endpoints apply 3 day cache headers for on-demand streaming data (actual media fragments/chunks) and manifest(playlist). For live streaming, streaming endpoints apply 3 day cache headers for data (actual media fragments/chunks) and 2 seconds cache header for manifest(playlist) requests. When live program turns to on-demand (live archive) then on-demand streaming cache headers apply.\n\n##Azure CDN integration\n\nAzure Media services provides [integrated CDN](http://azure.microsoft.com/updates/azure-media-services-now-fully-integrated-with-azure-cdn/) for streaming-endpoints. Cache-control headers applies in the same way as streaming endpoints to CDN enabled streaming endpoints. Azure CDN uses streaming endpoint configured cache values to define the life time of the internally cached objects and also uses this value to set the delivery cache headers. When using CDN enabled streaming endpoints it is not recommended to set small cache values. Setting small values will decrease the performance and reduce the benefit of CDN. It is not allowed to set cache headers smaller than 600 seconds for CDN enabled streaming endpoints.\n\n##Configuring cache headers with Azure Media Services\n\nYou can use Azure Management portal or Azure Media Services APIs to configure cache header values.\n\n1. To configure cache headers using management portal please refer to [How to Manage Streaming Endpoints](../media-services-manage-origins.md) section Configuring the Streaming Endpoint.\n2. Azure Media Services REST API, [StreamingEndpoint](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn783468.aspx#StreamingEndpointCacheControl).\n3. Azure Media Services .NET SDK, [StreamingEndpointCacheControl Properties](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=615302).\n\n##Cache configuration precedence order\n\n1. Azure Media Services configured cache value overrides default value.\n2. If there is no manual configuration, default values applies.\n3. By default 2 seconds cache headers applies to live streaming manifest(playlist) regardless of Azure Media or Azure Storage configuration and overriding of this value is not available.\n \ntest\n"
}