{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Sample data in Azure HDInsight Hive tables | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        87
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Down sampling data in Azure HDInsight Hive Tables",
      "pos": [
        106,
        155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sample data in Azure HDInsight Hive tables",
      "pos": [
        520,
        562
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the dataset you plan to analyze is big, it is usually a good idea to down-sample the data to reduce it to a smaller but representative and more manageable size.",
      "pos": [
        564,
        727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This facilitates data understanding, exploration, and feature engineering.",
      "pos": [
        728,
        802
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Its role in the Advanced Analytics Process and Technology (ADAPT) of Azure Machine Learning, is to enable fast prototyping of the data processing functions and machine learning models.",
      "pos": [
        803,
        987
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this article, we describe how to down-sample data in Azure HDInsight Hive tables using Hive queries.",
      "pos": [
        989,
        1092
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We cover three popularly used sampling methods:",
      "pos": [
        1093,
        1140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Uniform random sampling",
      "pos": [
        1145,
        1168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "random sampling by groups",
      "pos": [
        1172,
        1197
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "stratified sampling",
      "pos": [
        1201,
        1220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should submit the Hive queries from the Hadoop Command Line console on the head node of the Hadoop cluster.",
      "pos": [
        1222,
        1333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, log into the head node of the Hadoop cluster, open the Hadoop Command Line console, and submit the Hive queries from there.",
      "pos": [
        1334,
        1469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For instructions on submitting Hive queries in the Hadoop Command Line console, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Submit Hive Queries<ept id=\"p1\">](machine-learning-data-science-process-hive-tables.md#submit)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1470,
        1644
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1649,
        1695
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"uniform\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> Uniform random sampling"
    },
    {
      "content": "Uniform random sampling means that each row in the data set has an equal chance of being sampled.",
      "pos": [
        1699,
        1796
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This can be implemented by adding an extra field rand() to the data set in the inner \"select\" query, and in the outer \"select\" query that condition on that random field.",
      "pos": [
        1797,
        1966
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example query:",
      "pos": [
        1968,
        1993
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2261,
        2354
      ],
      "content": "Here, <ph id=\"ph1\">`&lt;sample rate, 0-1&gt;`</ph> specifies the proportion of records that the users want to sample."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2359,
        2405
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"group\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> Random sampling by groups"
    },
    {
      "content": "When sampling categorical data, you may want to either include or exclude all of the instances of some particular value of a categorical variable.",
      "pos": [
        2410,
        2556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is what is meant by \"sampling by group\".",
      "pos": [
        2557,
        2602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you have a categorical variable \"State\", which has values NY, MA, CA, NJ, PA, etc, you want records of the same state be always together, whether they are sampled or not.",
      "pos": [
        2603,
        2789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example query that samples by group:",
      "pos": [
        2791,
        2838
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3383,
        3427
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"stratified\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Stratified sampling"
    },
    {
      "content": "Random sampling is stratified with respect to a categorical variable when the samples obtained have values of that categorical that are in the same ratio as in the parent population from which the samples were obtained.",
      "pos": [
        3429,
        3648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using the same example as above, suppose your data has sub-populations by states, say NJ has 100 observations, NY has 60 observations, and WA has 300 observations.",
      "pos": [
        3649,
        3812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you specify the rate of stratified sampling to be 0.5, then the sample obtained should have approximately 50, 30, and 150 observations of NJ, NY, and WA respectively.",
      "pos": [
        3813,
        3982
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example query:",
      "pos": [
        3984,
        4009
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4437,
        4619
      ],
      "content": "For information on more advanced sampling methods that are available in Hive, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>LanguageManual Sampling<ept id=\"p1\">](https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/Hive/LanguageManual+Sampling)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        4622,
        4626
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Sample data in Azure HDInsight Hive tables | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Down sampling data in Azure HDInsight Hive Tables\"\n    services=\"machine-learning,hdinsight\"\n    solutions=\"\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"hangzh-msft\"\n    manager=\"paulettm\" \n    editor=\"cgronlun\"  />\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"machine-learning\"\n    ms.workload=\"data-services\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"09/01/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"hangzh;bradsev\" />\n\n# Sample data in Azure HDInsight Hive tables\n\nIf the dataset you plan to analyze is big, it is usually a good idea to down-sample the data to reduce it to a smaller but representative and more manageable size. This facilitates data understanding, exploration, and feature engineering. Its role in the Advanced Analytics Process and Technology (ADAPT) of Azure Machine Learning, is to enable fast prototyping of the data processing functions and machine learning models.\n\nIn this article, we describe how to down-sample data in Azure HDInsight Hive tables using Hive queries. We cover three popularly used sampling methods: \n\n* Uniform random sampling \n* random sampling by groups \n* stratified sampling\n\nYou should submit the Hive queries from the Hadoop Command Line console on the head node of the Hadoop cluster. To do this, log into the head node of the Hadoop cluster, open the Hadoop Command Line console, and submit the Hive queries from there. For instructions on submitting Hive queries in the Hadoop Command Line console, see [How to Submit Hive Queries](machine-learning-data-science-process-hive-tables.md#submit).\n\n## <a name=\"uniform\"></a> Uniform random sampling ##\nUniform random sampling means that each row in the data set has an equal chance of being sampled. This can be implemented by adding an extra field rand() to the data set in the inner \"select\" query, and in the outer \"select\" query that condition on that random field.\n\nHere is an example query:\n\n    SET sampleRate=<sample rate, 0-1>;\n    select\n        field1, field2, …, fieldN\n    from\n        (\n        select\n            field1, field2, …, fieldN, rand() as samplekey\n        from <hive table name>\n        )a\n    where samplekey<='${hiveconf:sampleRate}'\n\nHere, `<sample rate, 0-1>` specifies the proportion of records that the users want to sample.\n\n## <a name=\"group\"></a> Random sampling by groups ##\n\nWhen sampling categorical data, you may want to either include or exclude all of the instances of some particular value of a categorical variable. This is what is meant by \"sampling by group\".\nFor example, if you have a categorical variable \"State\", which has values NY, MA, CA, NJ, PA, etc, you want records of the same state be always together, whether they are sampled or not.\n\nHere is an example query that samples by group:\n\n    SET sampleRate=<sample rate, 0-1>;\n    select\n        b.field1, b.field2, …, b.catfield, …, b.fieldN\n    from\n        (\n        select\n            field1, field2, …, catfield, …, fieldN\n        from <table name>\n        )b\n    join\n        (\n        select\n            catfield\n        from\n            (\n            select\n                catfield, rand() as samplekey\n            from <table name>\n            group by catfield\n            )a\n        where samplekey<='${hiveconf:sampleRate}'\n        )c\n    on b.catfield=c.catfield\n\n## <a name=\"stratified\"></a>Stratified sampling\n\nRandom sampling is stratified with respect to a categorical variable when the samples obtained have values of that categorical that are in the same ratio as in the parent population from which the samples were obtained. Using the same example as above, suppose your data has sub-populations by states, say NJ has 100 observations, NY has 60 observations, and WA has 300 observations. If you specify the rate of stratified sampling to be 0.5, then the sample obtained should have approximately 50, 30, and 150 observations of NJ, NY, and WA respectively.\n\nHere is an example query:\n\n    SET sampleRate=<sample rate, 0-1>;\n    select\n        field1, field2, field3, ..., fieldN, state\n    from\n        (\n        select\n            field1, field2, field3, ..., fieldN, state,\n            count(*) over (partition by state) as state_cnt,\n            rank() over (partition by state order by rand()) as state_rank\n        from <table name>\n        ) a\n    where state_rank <= state_cnt*'${hiveconf:sampleRate}'\n\n\nFor information on more advanced sampling methods that are available in Hive, see [LanguageManual Sampling](https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/Hive/LanguageManual+Sampling).\n \ntest\n"
}