{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Build advanced analytics solutions in Azure | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        28,
        89
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use this guide to understand the steps for using Azure for data science and machine learning in the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        109,
        215
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Build advanced analytics solutions in Azure",
      "pos": [
        594,
        637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This Advanced Analytics Process and Technology (ADAPT) guide outlines the data science tasks typically involved in building and deploying predictive models with Azure Machine Learning.",
      "pos": [
        639,
        823
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It shows how the Azure platform enables tasks such as ingesting data from various sources, preparing it for use in Azure Machine Learning, and then creating operationalized models with an Azure Machine Learning  experiment that can be consumed by end user applications, programmatically or otherwise.",
      "pos": [
        824,
        1124
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While the map shows the core series steps involved in a typical end-to-end data science exercise, not all steps are required and their precise sequence can vary depending on the location, size and complexity of the data.",
      "pos": [
        1125,
        1345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The step titled <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Advanced data processing in Azure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> links to a second guide that walks through the process of preparing data to be used in an Azure Machine Learning experiment.",
      "pos": [
        1441,
        1619
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are returning from that guide, continue from the subsequent step in this guide of ingesting the processed data in Azure Machine Learning studio through to the final step of consuming the model.",
      "pos": [
        1620,
        1820
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        2003,
        2007
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Build advanced analytics solutions in Azure | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"Use this guide to understand the steps for using Azure for data science and machine learning in the cloud.\" \n    services=\"machine-learning,hdinsight\" \n    solutions=\"\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"bradsev\" \n    videoId=\"\" \n    scriptId=\"\" \n    manager=\"paulettm\" />\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"machine-learning\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.workload=\"required\" \n    ms.date=\"06/03/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"bradsev;sachouks\" />\n\n# Build advanced analytics solutions in Azure\n\nThis Advanced Analytics Process and Technology (ADAPT) guide outlines the data science tasks typically involved in building and deploying predictive models with Azure Machine Learning. It shows how the Azure platform enables tasks such as ingesting data from various sources, preparing it for use in Azure Machine Learning, and then creating operationalized models with an Azure Machine Learning  experiment that can be consumed by end user applications, programmatically or otherwise. While the map shows the core series steps involved in a typical end-to-end data science exercise, not all steps are required and their precise sequence can vary depending on the location, size and complexity of the data.\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [machine-learning-free-trial](../../includes/machine-learning-free-trial.md)]\n\nThe step titled **Advanced data processing in Azure** links to a second guide that walks through the process of preparing data to be used in an Azure Machine Learning experiment. If you are returning from that guide, continue from the subsequent step in this guide of ingesting the processed data in Azure Machine Learning studio through to the final step of consuming the model.\n\n<object type=\"image/svg+xml\" data=\"https://sidneyhcontent.blob.core.windows.net/documentation/machine-learning-how-to-create-ml-service.svg\" width=\"100%\" height=\"100%\">\n</object>\n \ntest\n"
}