{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Reserved IP",
      "pos": [
        27,
        38
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Understand reserved IPs, VIP, ILPIP, and how to manage them",
      "pos": [
        56,
        115
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reserved IP Overview",
      "pos": [
        438,
        458
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "IP addresses in Azure fall into two categories: dynamic and reserved.",
      "pos": [
        459,
        528
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Public IP addresses managed by Azure are dynamic by default.",
      "pos": [
        529,
        589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "That means that the IP address used for a given cloud service (VIP) or to access a VM or role instance directly (ILPIP) can change from time to time, when resources are shutdown or deallocated.",
      "pos": [
        590,
        783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To prevent IP addresses from changing, you can reserve an IP address.",
      "pos": [
        785,
        854
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reserved IPs can be used only as a VIP, ensuring that the IP address for the cloud service will be the same even as resources are shutdown or deallocated.",
      "pos": [
        855,
        1009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Furthermore, you can convert existing dynamic IPs used as a VIP to a reserved IP address.",
      "pos": [
        1010,
        1099
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When do I need a reserved IP?",
      "pos": [
        1104,
        1133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>You want to ensure that the IP is reserved in your subscription<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1136,
        1204
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to reserve an IP address that will not be released from your subscription under any circumstance, you should use a reserved public IP.",
      "pos": [
        1205,
        1351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>You want your IP to stay with your cloud service even across stopped or deallocated state (VMs)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1356,
        1456
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want your service to be accessed by using an IP address that will not change even when VMs in the cloud service are stop or deallocated.",
      "pos": [
        1457,
        1600
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>You want to ensure that outbound traffic from Azure uses a predictable IP address<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1603,
        1689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You may have your on-premises firewall configured to allow only traffic from specific IP addresses.",
      "pos": [
        1690,
        1789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By reserving an IP, you will know the source IP address and won’t have to update your firewall rules due to an IP change.",
      "pos": [
        1790,
        1911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "FAQ",
      "pos": [
        1916,
        1919
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can I use a reserved IP for all Azure services?",
      "pos": [
        1923,
        1970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reserved IPs can only be used for VMs and cloud service instance roles.",
      "pos": [
        1977,
        2048
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How many reserved IPs can I have?",
      "pos": [
        2052,
        2085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At this time, all Azure subscriptions are authorized to use 20 reserved IPs.",
      "pos": [
        2092,
        2168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, you can request additional reserved IPs.",
      "pos": [
        2169,
        2218
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Subscription and Service Limits<ept id=\"p1\">](../azure-subscription-service-limits/)</ept> page for more information.",
      "pos": [
        2219,
        2326
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Is there a charge for reserved IPs?",
      "pos": [
        2330,
        2365
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2371,
        2484
      ],
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Reserved IP Address Pricing Details<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=398482)</ept> for pricing information."
    },
    {
      "content": "How do I reserve an IP address?",
      "pos": [
        2488,
        2519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use PowerShell or the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Management REST API<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn722420.aspx)</ept> to request a reserved IP from a particular region.",
      "pos": [
        2525,
        2689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure will reserve an IP address from that region and correlate it to your subscription.",
      "pos": [
        2690,
        2778
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can then use the reserved IP in that region.",
      "pos": [
        2779,
        2827
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot reserve an IP address by using the Management Portal.",
      "pos": [
        2828,
        2892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can I use this with affinity group based VNets?",
      "pos": [
        2896,
        2943
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reserved IPs are only supported in regional VNets.",
      "pos": [
        2949,
        2999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is not supported for VNets that are associated with affinity groups.",
      "pos": [
        3000,
        3071
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about associating a VNet with a region or an affinity group, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About Regional VNets and Affinity Groups<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-networks-migrate-to-regional-vnet.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3072,
        3247
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to manage reserved VIPs",
      "pos": [
        3253,
        3280
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you can use reserved IPs, you must add it to your subscription.",
      "pos": [
        3282,
        3352
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a reserved IP from the pool of public IP addresses available in the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Central US<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> location, run the following PowerShell command:",
      "pos": [
        3353,
        3491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Notice, however, that you cannot specify what IP is being reserved.",
      "pos": [
        3570,
        3637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To view what IP addresses are reserved in your subscription, run the following PowerShell command, and notice the values for <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>ReservedIPName<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Address<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>:",
      "pos": [
        3638,
        3794
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once an IP is reserved, it remains associated to your subscription until you delete it.",
      "pos": [
        4306,
        4393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To delete the reserved IP shown above, run the following PowerShell command:",
      "pos": [
        4394,
        4470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to associate a reserved IP to a new cloud service",
      "pos": [
        4534,
        4587
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4588,
        4694
      ],
      "content": "The script below creates a new reserved IP, then associates it to a new cloud service named <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>TestService<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> When you create a reserved IP to use with a cloud service, you’ll still need to refer to the VM by using <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>VIP:&amp;lt;port number&gt;<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> for inbound communication.",
      "pos": [
        5133,
        5300
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reserving an IP does not mean you can connect to the VM directly.",
      "pos": [
        5301,
        5366
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The reserved IP is assigned to the cloud service that the VM has been deployed to.",
      "pos": [
        5367,
        5449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to connect to a VM by IP directly, you have to configure an instance-level public IP.",
      "pos": [
        5450,
        5547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An instance-level public IP is a type of public IP (called a ILPIP) that is assigned directly to your VM.",
      "pos": [
        5548,
        5653
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It cannot be reserved.",
      "pos": [
        5654,
        5676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Instance-level Public IP (ILPIP)<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-networks-instance-level-public-ip)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        5677,
        5783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to remove a reserved IP from a running deployment",
      "pos": [
        5788,
        5841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To remove the reserved IP added to the new service created in the script above, run the following PowerShell command:",
      "pos": [
        5842,
        5959
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Removing a reserved IP from a running deployment does not remove the reservation from your subscription.",
      "pos": [
        6055,
        6172
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It simply frees the IP to be used by another resource in your subscription.",
      "pos": [
        6173,
        6248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to associate a reserved IP to a running deployment",
      "pos": [
        6253,
        6307
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6308,
        6492
      ],
      "content": "The script below creates a new cloud service named <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>TestService2<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> with a new VM named <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>TestVM2<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>, and then associates the existing reserved IP named <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>MyReservedIP<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept> to the cloud service."
    },
    {
      "content": "How to associate a reserved IP to a cloud service by using a service configuration file",
      "pos": [
        6920,
        7007
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also associate a reserved IP to a cloud service by using a service configuration (CSCFG) file.",
      "pos": [
        7008,
        7110
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The sample xml below shows how to configure a cloud service to use a reserved VIP named <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>MyReservedIP<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>:",
      "pos": [
        7111,
        7214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        7966,
        7976
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7980,
        8065
      ],
      "content": "Learn about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>reserved private IP addresses<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-networks-reserved-private-ip)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8069,
        8172
      ],
      "content": "Learn about <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Instance Level Public IP (ILPIP) addresses<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-networks-instance-level-public-ip)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        8176,
        8266
      ],
      "content": "Check the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>reserved IP REST APIs<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn722420.aspx)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Reserved IP\"\n   description=\"Understand reserved IPs, VIP, ILPIP, and how to manage them\"\n   services=\"virtual-network\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   authors=\"telmosampaio\"\n   manager=\"adinah\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"virtual-network\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"08/17/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"telmos\" />\n\n# Reserved IP Overview\nIP addresses in Azure fall into two categories: dynamic and reserved. Public IP addresses managed by Azure are dynamic by default. That means that the IP address used for a given cloud service (VIP) or to access a VM or role instance directly (ILPIP) can change from time to time, when resources are shutdown or deallocated.\n\nTo prevent IP addresses from changing, you can reserve an IP address. Reserved IPs can be used only as a VIP, ensuring that the IP address for the cloud service will be the same even as resources are shutdown or deallocated. Furthermore, you can convert existing dynamic IPs used as a VIP to a reserved IP address.\n\n## When do I need a reserved IP?\n- **You want to ensure that the IP is reserved in your subscription**. If you want to reserve an IP address that will not be released from your subscription under any circumstance, you should use a reserved public IP.  \n- **You want your IP to stay with your cloud service even across stopped or deallocated state (VMs)**. If you want your service to be accessed by using an IP address that will not change even when VMs in the cloud service are stop or deallocated.\n- **You want to ensure that outbound traffic from Azure uses a predictable IP address**. You may have your on-premises firewall configured to allow only traffic from specific IP addresses. By reserving an IP, you will know the source IP address and won’t have to update your firewall rules due to an IP change.\n\n## FAQ\n1. Can I use a reserved IP for all Azure services?  \n  - Reserved IPs can only be used for VMs and cloud service instance roles.\n1. How many reserved IPs can I have?  \n  - At this time, all Azure subscriptions are authorized to use 20 reserved IPs. However, you can request additional reserved IPs. See the [Subscription and Service Limits](../azure-subscription-service-limits/) page for more information.\n1. Is there a charge for reserved IPs? \n  - See [Reserved IP Address Pricing Details](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=398482) for pricing information.\n1. How do I reserve an IP address? \n  - You can use PowerShell or the [Azure Management REST API](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn722420.aspx) to request a reserved IP from a particular region. Azure will reserve an IP address from that region and correlate it to your subscription. You can then use the reserved IP in that region. You cannot reserve an IP address by using the Management Portal.\n1. Can I use this with affinity group based VNets? \n  - Reserved IPs are only supported in regional VNets. It is not supported for VNets that are associated with affinity groups. For more information about associating a VNet with a region or an affinity group, see [About Regional VNets and Affinity Groups](virtual-networks-migrate-to-regional-vnet.md). \n\n## How to manage reserved VIPs\n\nBefore you can use reserved IPs, you must add it to your subscription. To create a reserved IP from the pool of public IP addresses available in the *Central US* location, run the following PowerShell command:\n\n    New-AzureReservedIP –ReservedIPName MyReservedIP –Location “Central US”\n\nNotice, however, that you cannot specify what IP is being reserved. To view what IP addresses are reserved in your subscription, run the following PowerShell command, and notice the values for *ReservedIPName* and *Address*:\n\n    Get-AzureReservedIP\n\n    ReservedIPName       : MyReservedIP\n    Address              : 23.101.114.211\n    Id                   : d73be9dd-db12-4b5e-98c8-bc62e7c42041\n    Label                : \n    Location             : Central US\n    State                : Created\n    InUse                : False\n    ServiceName          : \n    DeploymentName       : \n    OperationDescription : Get-AzureReservedIP\n    OperationId          : 55e4f245-82e4-9c66-9bd8-273e815ce30a\n    OperationStatus      : Succeeded\n\nOnce an IP is reserved, it remains associated to your subscription until you delete it. To delete the reserved IP shown above, run the following PowerShell command:\n\n    Remove-AzureReservedIP -ReservedIPName \"MyReservedIP\"\n\n## How to associate a reserved IP to a new cloud service\nThe script below creates a new reserved IP, then associates it to a new cloud service named *TestService*.\n\n    New-AzureReservedIP –ReservedIPName MyReservedIP –Location “Central US”\n    $image = Get-AzureVMImage|?{$_.ImageName -like \"*RightImage-Windows-2012R2-x64*\"}\n    New-AzureVMConfig -Name TestVM -InstanceSize Small -ImageName $image.ImageName `\n    | Add-AzureProvisioningConfig -Windows -AdminUsername adminuser -Password MyP@ssw0rd!! `\n    | New-AzureVM -ServiceName TestService -ReservedIPName MyReservedIP -Location \"Central US\"\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] When you create a reserved IP to use with a cloud service, you’ll still need to refer to the VM by using *VIP:&lt;port number>* for inbound communication. Reserving an IP does not mean you can connect to the VM directly. The reserved IP is assigned to the cloud service that the VM has been deployed to. If you want to connect to a VM by IP directly, you have to configure an instance-level public IP. An instance-level public IP is a type of public IP (called a ILPIP) that is assigned directly to your VM. It cannot be reserved. See [Instance-level Public IP (ILPIP)](../virtual-networks-instance-level-public-ip) for more information.\n\n## How to remove a reserved IP from a running deployment\nTo remove the reserved IP added to the new service created in the script above, run the following PowerShell command:\n\n    Remove-AzureReservedIPAssociation -ReservedIPName MyReservedIP -ServiceName TestService\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] Removing a reserved IP from a running deployment does not remove the reservation from your subscription. It simply frees the IP to be used by another resource in your subscription.\n\n## How to associate a reserved IP to a running deployment\nThe script below creates a new cloud service named *TestService2* with a new VM named *TestVM2*, and then associates the existing reserved IP named *MyReservedIP* to the cloud service.\n\n    $image = Get-AzureVMImage|?{$_.ImageName -like \"*RightImage-Windows-2012R2-x64*\"}\n    New-AzureVMConfig -Name TestVM2 -InstanceSize Small -ImageName $image.ImageName `\n    | Add-AzureProvisioningConfig -Windows -AdminUsername adminuser -Password MyP@ssw0rd!! `\n    | New-AzureVM -ServiceName TestService2 -Location \"Central US\"\n    Set-AzureReservedIPAssociation -ReservedIPName MyReservedIP -ServiceName TestService2\n\n## How to associate a reserved IP to a cloud service by using a service configuration file\nYou can also associate a reserved IP to a cloud service by using a service configuration (CSCFG) file. The sample xml below shows how to configure a cloud service to use a reserved VIP named *MyReservedIP*: \n    \n    <?xml version=\"1.0\" encoding=\"utf-8\"?>\n    <ServiceConfiguration serviceName=\"ReservedIPSample\" xmlns=\"http://schemas.microsoft.com/ServiceHosting/2008/10/ServiceConfiguration\" osFamily=\"4\" osVersion=\"*\" schemaVersion=\"2014-01.2.3\">\n      <Role name=\"WebRole1\">\n        <Instances count=\"1\" />\n        <ConfigurationSettings>\n          <Setting name=\"Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Plugins.Diagnostics.ConnectionString\" value=\"UseDevelopmentStorage=true\" />\n        </ConfigurationSettings>\n      </Role>\n      <NetworkConfiguration>\n        <AddressAssignments>\n          <ReservedIPs>\n           <ReservedIP name=\"MyReservedIP\"/>\n          </ReservedIPs>\n        </AddressAssignments>\n      </NetworkConfiguration>\n    </ServiceConfiguration>\n\n## Next steps\n\n- Learn about [reserved private IP addresses](../virtual-networks-reserved-private-ip).\n\n- Learn about [Instance Level Public IP (ILPIP) addresses](../virtual-networks-instance-level-public-ip).\n\n- Check the [reserved IP REST APIs](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn722420.aspx).\n"
}