{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Choosing a framework",
      "pos": [
        26,
        46
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric offers two high-level frameworks for building services: the actor framework and the services framework.",
      "pos": [
        64,
        182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Understanding the value of each will help you make the right architectural decisions for your application.",
      "pos": [
        183,
        289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choosing a framework for your service",
      "pos": [
        582,
        619
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service Fabric offers two high-level frameworks for building services: the Reliable Actors APIs and the Reliable Services APIs.",
      "pos": [
        621,
        748
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While both are built on the same Service Fabric core, they make different tradeoffs between simplicity and flexibility in terms of concurrency, partitioning, and communication.",
      "pos": [
        749,
        925
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is useful to understand both models so that you can choose the appropriate framework for a particular service within your application.",
      "pos": [
        926,
        1063
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Comparing the Reliable Actors APIs and the Reliable Services APIs",
      "pos": [
        1068,
        1133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Actors APIs",
      "pos": [
        1138,
        1158
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reliable Services APIs",
      "pos": [
        1163,
        1185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your problem space involves many small independent units of state and logic",
      "pos": [
        1243,
        1318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You need to maintain logic across multiple components",
      "pos": [
        1319,
        1372
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You want to work with single-threaded objects while still being able to scale and maintain consistency",
      "pos": [
        1375,
        1477
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You want to use reliable collections (like .NET Dictionary and Queue) to store and manage your state",
      "pos": [
        1478,
        1578
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You want the framework to manage the concurrency and granularity of state",
      "pos": [
        1581,
        1654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You want to control the granularity and concurrency of your state",
      "pos": [
        1655,
        1720
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You want the platform to manage communication for you",
      "pos": [
        1723,
        1776
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You want to manage the communication and control the partitioning scheme for your service",
      "pos": [
        1777,
        1866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Keep in mind that it is perfectly reasonable to use different frameworks for different services within your app.",
      "pos": [
        1869,
        1981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For instance, you might have a stateful service that aggregates data generated by a number of actors.",
      "pos": [
        1982,
        2083
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        2088,
        2098
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn more about the Reliable Actors APIs",
      "pos": [
        2103,
        2144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn more about the Reliable Services APIs",
      "pos": [
        2197,
        2240
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Choosing a framework\"\n   description=\"Service Fabric offers two high-level frameworks for building services: the actor framework and the services framework. Understanding the value of each will help you make the right architectural decisions for your application.\"\n   services=\"service-fabric\"\n   documentationCenter=\".net\"\n   authors=\"seanmck\"\n   manager=\"timlt\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"service-fabric\"\n   ms.devlang=\"dotNet\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"NA\"\n   ms.date=\"07/09/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"seanmck\"/>\n\n# Choosing a framework for your service\n\nService Fabric offers two high-level frameworks for building services: the Reliable Actors APIs and the Reliable Services APIs. While both are built on the same Service Fabric core, they make different tradeoffs between simplicity and flexibility in terms of concurrency, partitioning, and communication. It is useful to understand both models so that you can choose the appropriate framework for a particular service within your application.\n\n## Comparing the Reliable Actors APIs and the Reliable Services APIs\n\n|**Reliable Actors APIs**|**Reliable Services APIs**|\n|-----------------------|--------------------------|\n|Your problem space involves many small independent units of state and logic|You need to maintain logic across multiple components|\n|You want to work with single-threaded objects while still being able to scale and maintain consistency|You want to use reliable collections (like .NET Dictionary and Queue) to store and manage your state|\n|You want the framework to manage the concurrency and granularity of state|You want to control the granularity and concurrency of your state|\n|You want the platform to manage communication for you|You want to manage the communication and control the partitioning scheme for your service|\n\nKeep in mind that it is perfectly reasonable to use different frameworks for different services within your app. For instance, you might have a stateful service that aggregates data generated by a number of actors.\n\n## Next steps\n\n- [Learn more about the Reliable Actors APIs](service-fabric-reliable-actors-introduction.md)\n- [Learn more about the Reliable Services APIs](../Service-Fabric/service-fabric-reliable-services-introduction.md)\n"
}