{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Mobile Engagement concepts | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        71
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement concepts",
      "pos": [
        90,
        122
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement concepts",
      "pos": [
        464,
        496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Mobile Engagement defines a few concepts common to all supported platforms.",
      "pos": [
        498,
        573
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article briefly describes those concepts.",
      "pos": [
        574,
        620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article is a good start if you are new to Mobile Engagement.",
      "pos": [
        622,
        687
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Also make sure to read the documentation specific to the platform you are using, as it will refine the concepts described in this article with more details and examples as well as possible limitations.",
      "pos": [
        688,
        889
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Devices and users",
      "pos": [
        894,
        911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Mobile Engagement identifies users by generating a unique identifier for each device.",
      "pos": [
        912,
        997
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This identifier is called the device identifier (or <ph id=\"ph1\">`deviceid`</ph>).",
      "pos": [
        998,
        1062
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is generated in such a way that all applications running of the same device share the same device identifier.",
      "pos": [
        1063,
        1175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Implicitly, it means that Mobile Engagement considers one device to belong to exactly one user, and thus, users and devices are equivalent concepts.",
      "pos": [
        1177,
        1325
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sessions and activities",
      "pos": [
        1330,
        1353
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A session is one use of the application performed by a user, from the time the user starts using it, until the user stops.",
      "pos": [
        1354,
        1476
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An activity is one use of a given sub-part of the application performed by one user (it is usually a screen, but it can be anything suitable to the application).",
      "pos": [
        1478,
        1639
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A user can only perform one activity at a time.",
      "pos": [
        1641,
        1688
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An activity is identified by a name (limited to 64 characters) and can optionally embed some extra data (in the limit of 1024 bytes).",
      "pos": [
        1690,
        1823
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sessions are automatically computed from the sequence of activities performed by users.",
      "pos": [
        1825,
        1912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A session starts when the user starts his first activity and stops when he finishes his last activity.",
      "pos": [
        1913,
        2015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that a session does not need to be explicitly started or stopped.",
      "pos": [
        2016,
        2092
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instead, activities are explicitly started or stopped.",
      "pos": [
        2093,
        2147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If no activity is reported, no session is reported.",
      "pos": [
        2148,
        2199
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Events",
      "pos": [
        2204,
        2210
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Events are used to report instant actions (like button pressed or articles read by users).",
      "pos": [
        2211,
        2301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An event can be related to the current session, to a running job, or it can be a standalone event.",
      "pos": [
        2303,
        2401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An event is identified by a name (limited to 64 characters) and can optionally embed some extra data (in the limit of 1024 bytes).",
      "pos": [
        2403,
        2533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Error",
      "pos": [
        2538,
        2543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Errors are used to report issues correctly detected by the application (like incorrect user actions, or API call failures).",
      "pos": [
        2544,
        2667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An error can be related to the current session, to a running job, or it can be a standalone error.",
      "pos": [
        2669,
        2767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An error is identified by a name (limited to 64 characters) and can optionally embed some extra data (in the limit of 1024 bytes).",
      "pos": [
        2769,
        2899
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Job",
      "pos": [
        2904,
        2907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Jobs are used to report actions having a duration (like duration of API calls, display time of ads, duration of background tasks or duration of user actions).",
      "pos": [
        2908,
        3066
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A job is not related to a session, because a task can be performed in the background, without any user interaction.",
      "pos": [
        3068,
        3183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A job is identified by a name (limited to 64 characters) and can optionally embed some extra data (in the limit of 1024 bytes).",
      "pos": [
        3185,
        3312
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Crash",
      "pos": [
        3317,
        3322
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Crashes are issued automatically by the Mobile Engagement SDK to report application failures where issues not detected by the application make it crash.",
      "pos": [
        3323,
        3475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application information",
      "pos": [
        3480,
        3503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application information (or app info) is used to tag users, that is, to associate some data to the users of an application (this is similar to web cookies, except that app info is stored on the server side on the Azure Mobile Engagement platform).",
      "pos": [
        3504,
        3751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App info can be registered by using the Mobile Engagement SDK API or by using the Mobile Engagement platform Device API.",
      "pos": [
        3753,
        3873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App info is a key/value pair associated to a device.",
      "pos": [
        3875,
        3927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The key is the name of the app info (limited to 64 ASCII letters [a-zA-Z], numbers [0-9] and underscores [_]).",
      "pos": [
        3928,
        4038
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The value (limited to 1024 characters) can be any string, integer, date (yyyy-MM-dd) or Boolean (true or false).",
      "pos": [
        4039,
        4151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any number of app info can be associated to a device, within the limits defined by the Mobile Engagement pricing terms.",
      "pos": [
        4153,
        4272
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For one given key, Mobile Engagement only keeps track of the latest value set (no history).",
      "pos": [
        4273,
        4364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Setting or changing the value of an app info forces Mobile Engagement to re-evaluate audience criteria set on this app info (if any) meaning that app info can be used to trigger realtime pushes.",
      "pos": [
        4365,
        4559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Extra data",
      "pos": [
        4564,
        4574
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Extra data (or extras) is some arbitrary data that can be attached to events, errors, activities and jobs.",
      "pos": [
        4575,
        4681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Extras are structured similarly to JSON objects: they are made of a tree of key/value pairs.",
      "pos": [
        4683,
        4775
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Keys are limited to 64 ASCII letters [a-zA-Z], numbers [0-9] and underscores [_]) and the total size of extras is limited to 1024 characters (once encoded in JSON by the Mobile Engagement SDK).",
      "pos": [
        4776,
        4969
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The whole tree of key/value pairs is stored as a JSON object.",
      "pos": [
        4971,
        5032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Nevertheless, only the first level of keys/values is decomposed to be directly accessible to some advanced functions like Segments (for example, you can easily define a segment called “SciFi fans” that is made of all users having sent at least 10 times the event named “content_viewed” with the extra key “content_type” set to the value “scifi” in the last month).",
      "pos": [
        5033,
        5397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is thus highly recommended to send only extras made of simple lists of key/value pairs using scalar values (for example, strings, dates, integers or Boolean).",
      "pos": [
        5398,
        5559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        5564,
        5574
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Universal SDK overview for Azure Mobile Engagement",
      "pos": [
        5579,
        5637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Phone Silverlight SDK overview for Azure Mobile Engagement",
      "pos": [
        5691,
        5757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "iOS SDK for Azure Mobile Engagement",
      "pos": [
        5811,
        5846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Android SDK for Azure Mobile Engagement",
      "pos": [
        5890,
        5929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        5975,
        5979
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Mobile Engagement concepts | Microsoft Azure\"\n    description=\"Azure Mobile Engagement concepts\"\n    services=\"mobile-engagement\"\n    documentationCenter=\"mobile\"\n    authors=\"piyushjo\"\n    manager=\"dwrede\"\n    editor=\"\" />\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"mobile-engagement\"\n    ms.workload=\"mobile\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"mobile-android\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"get-started-article\"\n    ms.date=\"08/10/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"piyushjo\" />\n\n# Azure Mobile Engagement concepts\n\nMobile Engagement defines a few concepts common to all supported platforms. This article briefly describes those concepts.\n\nThis article is a good start if you are new to Mobile Engagement. Also make sure to read the documentation specific to the platform you are using, as it will refine the concepts described in this article with more details and examples as well as possible limitations.\n\n## Devices and users\nMobile Engagement identifies users by generating a unique identifier for each device. This identifier is called the device identifier (or `deviceid`). It is generated in such a way that all applications running of the same device share the same device identifier.\n\nImplicitly, it means that Mobile Engagement considers one device to belong to exactly one user, and thus, users and devices are equivalent concepts.\n\n## Sessions and activities\nA session is one use of the application performed by a user, from the time the user starts using it, until the user stops.\n\nAn activity is one use of a given sub-part of the application performed by one user (it is usually a screen, but it can be anything suitable to the application).\n\nA user can only perform one activity at a time.\n\nAn activity is identified by a name (limited to 64 characters) and can optionally embed some extra data (in the limit of 1024 bytes).\n\nSessions are automatically computed from the sequence of activities performed by users. A session starts when the user starts his first activity and stops when he finishes his last activity. This means that a session does not need to be explicitly started or stopped. Instead, activities are explicitly started or stopped. If no activity is reported, no session is reported.\n\n## Events\nEvents are used to report instant actions (like button pressed or articles read by users).\n\nAn event can be related to the current session, to a running job, or it can be a standalone event.\n\nAn event is identified by a name (limited to 64 characters) and can optionally embed some extra data (in the limit of 1024 bytes).\n\n## Error\nErrors are used to report issues correctly detected by the application (like incorrect user actions, or API call failures).\n\nAn error can be related to the current session, to a running job, or it can be a standalone error.\n\nAn error is identified by a name (limited to 64 characters) and can optionally embed some extra data (in the limit of 1024 bytes).\n\n## Job\nJobs are used to report actions having a duration (like duration of API calls, display time of ads, duration of background tasks or duration of user actions).\n\nA job is not related to a session, because a task can be performed in the background, without any user interaction.\n\nA job is identified by a name (limited to 64 characters) and can optionally embed some extra data (in the limit of 1024 bytes).\n\n## Crash\nCrashes are issued automatically by the Mobile Engagement SDK to report application failures where issues not detected by the application make it crash.\n\n## Application information\nApplication information (or app info) is used to tag users, that is, to associate some data to the users of an application (this is similar to web cookies, except that app info is stored on the server side on the Azure Mobile Engagement platform).\n\nApp info can be registered by using the Mobile Engagement SDK API or by using the Mobile Engagement platform Device API.\n\nApp info is a key/value pair associated to a device. The key is the name of the app info (limited to 64 ASCII letters [a-zA-Z], numbers [0-9] and underscores [_]). The value (limited to 1024 characters) can be any string, integer, date (yyyy-MM-dd) or Boolean (true or false).\n\nAny number of app info can be associated to a device, within the limits defined by the Mobile Engagement pricing terms. For one given key, Mobile Engagement only keeps track of the latest value set (no history). Setting or changing the value of an app info forces Mobile Engagement to re-evaluate audience criteria set on this app info (if any) meaning that app info can be used to trigger realtime pushes.\n\n## Extra data\nExtra data (or extras) is some arbitrary data that can be attached to events, errors, activities and jobs.\n\nExtras are structured similarly to JSON objects: they are made of a tree of key/value pairs. Keys are limited to 64 ASCII letters [a-zA-Z], numbers [0-9] and underscores [_]) and the total size of extras is limited to 1024 characters (once encoded in JSON by the Mobile Engagement SDK).\n\nThe whole tree of key/value pairs is stored as a JSON object. Nevertheless, only the first level of keys/values is decomposed to be directly accessible to some advanced functions like Segments (for example, you can easily define a segment called “SciFi fans” that is made of all users having sent at least 10 times the event named “content_viewed” with the extra key “content_type” set to the value “scifi” in the last month). It is thus highly recommended to send only extras made of simple lists of key/value pairs using scalar values (for example, strings, dates, integers or Boolean).\n\n## Next steps\n\n- [Windows Universal SDK overview for Azure Mobile Engagement](mobile-engagement-windows-store-sdk-overview.md)\n- [Windows Phone Silverlight SDK overview for Azure Mobile Engagement](mobile-engagement-windows-phone-sdk-overview.md)\n- [iOS SDK for Azure Mobile Engagement](mobile-engagement-ios-sdk-overview.md)\n- [Android SDK for Azure Mobile Engagement](mobile-engagement-android-sdk-overview.md)\n\ntest\n"
}