{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "What is a Network Access Control List (ACL)?",
      "pos": [
        27,
        71
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn about ACLs",
      "pos": [
        89,
        105
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is a Network Access Control List (ACLs)?",
      "pos": [
        428,
        473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A Network Access Control List (ACL) is a security enhancement available for your Azure deployment.",
      "pos": [
        475,
        573
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An ACL provides the ability to selectively permit or deny traffic for a virtual machine endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        574,
        671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This packet filtering capability provides an additional layer of security.",
      "pos": [
        672,
        746
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can specify network ACLs for endpoints only.",
      "pos": [
        747,
        795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can't specify an ACL for a virtual network or a specific subnet contained in a virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        796,
        895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> It is recommended to use Network Security Groups (NSGs) instead of ACLs whenever possible.",
      "pos": [
        900,
        1008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To learn more about NSGs, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>What is a Network Security Group?<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-networks-nsg)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1009,
        1100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ACLs can be configured by using either PowerShell or the Management Portal.",
      "pos": [
        1102,
        1177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To configure a network ACL by using PowerShell, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Managing Access Control Lists (ACLs) for Endpoints by using PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-networks-acl-powershell.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1178,
        1339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To configure a network ACL by using the Management Portal, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Set Up Endpoints to a Virtual Machine<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-machines-set-up-endpoints/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1340,
        1489
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Network ACLs, you can do the following:",
      "pos": [
        1491,
        1536
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Selectively permit or deny incoming traffic based on remote subnet IPv4 address range to a virtual machine input endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        1540,
        1662
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Blacklist IP addresses",
      "pos": [
        1666,
        1688
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create multiple rules per virtual machine endpoint",
      "pos": [
        1692,
        1742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify up to 50 ACL rules per virtual machine endpoint",
      "pos": [
        1746,
        1801
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use rule ordering to ensure the correct set of rules are applied on a given virtual machine endpoint (lowest to highest)",
      "pos": [
        1805,
        1925
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify an ACL for a specific remote subnet IPv4 address.",
      "pos": [
        1929,
        1986
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How ACLs work",
      "pos": [
        1991,
        2004
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An ACL is an object that contains a list of rules.",
      "pos": [
        2006,
        2056
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create an ACL and apply it to a virtual machine endpoint, packet filtering takes place on the host node of your VM.",
      "pos": [
        2057,
        2181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means the traffic from remote IP addresses is filtered by the host node for matching ACL rules instead of on your VM.",
      "pos": [
        2182,
        2304
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This prevents your VM from spending the precious CPU cycles on packet filtering.",
      "pos": [
        2305,
        2385
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a virtual machine is created, a default ACL is put in place to block all incoming traffic.",
      "pos": [
        2387,
        2482
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, if an endpoint is created for (port 3389), then the default ACL is modified to allow all inbound traffic for that endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        2483,
        2615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inbound traffic from any remote subnet is then allowed to that endpoint and no firewall provisioning is required.",
      "pos": [
        2616,
        2729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All other ports are blocked for inbound traffic unless endpoints are created for those ports.",
      "pos": [
        2730,
        2823
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Outbound traffic is allowed by default.",
      "pos": [
        2824,
        2863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example Default ACL table",
      "pos": [
        2867,
        2892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rule",
      "pos": [
        2900,
        2904
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remote Subnet",
      "pos": [
        2913,
        2926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Endpoint",
      "pos": [
        2933,
        2941
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Permit/Deny",
      "pos": [
        2948,
        2959
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        3018,
        3021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "0.0.0.0/0",
      "pos": [
        3027,
        3036
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3389",
      "pos": [
        3043,
        3047
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Permit",
      "pos": [
        3054,
        3060
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Permit and deny",
      "pos": [
        3072,
        3087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can selectively permit or deny network traffic for a virtual machine input endpoint by creating rules that specify \"permit\" or \"deny\".",
      "pos": [
        3089,
        3227
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It's important to note that by default, when an endpoint is created, all traffic is denied to the endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        3228,
        3335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For that reason, it's important to understand how to create permit/deny rules and place them in the proper order of precedence if you want granular control over the network traffic that you choose to allow to reach the virtual machine endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        3336,
        3580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Points to consider:",
      "pos": [
        3582,
        3601
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3606,
        3690
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>No ACL –<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> By default when an endpoint is created, we permit all for the endpoint."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Permit -<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> When you add one or more \"permit\" ranges, you are denying all other ranges by default.",
      "pos": [
        3695,
        3794
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Only packets from the permitted IP range will be able to communicate with the virtual machine endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        3795,
        3898
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3903,
        4012
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deny -<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> When you add one or more \"deny\" ranges, you are permitting all other ranges of traffic by default."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4017,
        4176
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Combination of Permit and Deny -<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> You can use a combination of \"permit\" and \"deny\" when you want to carve out a specific IP range to be permitted or denied."
    },
    {
      "content": "Rules and rule precedence",
      "pos": [
        4181,
        4206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network ACLs can be set up on specific virtual machine endpoints.",
      "pos": [
        4208,
        4273
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, you can specify a network ACL for an RDP endpoint created on a virtual machine which locks down access for certain IP addresses.",
      "pos": [
        4274,
        4415
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The table below shows a way to grant access to public virtual IPs (VIPs) of a certain range to permit access for RDP.",
      "pos": [
        4416,
        4533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All other remote IPs are denied.",
      "pos": [
        4534,
        4566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We follow a <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>lowest takes precedence<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> rule order.",
      "pos": [
        4567,
        4616
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Multiple rules",
      "pos": [
        4622,
        4636
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the example below, if you want to allow access to the RDP endpoint only from two public IPv4 address ranges (65.0.0.0/8, and 159.0.0.0/8), you can achieve this by specifying two <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Permit<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> rules.",
      "pos": [
        4638,
        4834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, since RDP is created by default for a virtual machine, you may want to lock down access to the RDP port based on a remote subnet.",
      "pos": [
        4835,
        4978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The example below shows a way to grant access to public virtual IPs (VIPs) of a certain range to permit access for RDP.",
      "pos": [
        4979,
        5098
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All other remote IPs are denied.",
      "pos": [
        5099,
        5131
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This works because network ACLs can be set up for a specific virtual machine endpoint and access is denied by default.",
      "pos": [
        5132,
        5250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example – Multiple rules",
      "pos": [
        5254,
        5278
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rule",
      "pos": [
        5286,
        5290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remote Subnet",
      "pos": [
        5299,
        5312
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Endpoint",
      "pos": [
        5319,
        5327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Permit/Deny",
      "pos": [
        5334,
        5345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        5404,
        5407
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "65.0.0.0/8",
      "pos": [
        5413,
        5423
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3389",
      "pos": [
        5429,
        5433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Permit",
      "pos": [
        5440,
        5446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "200",
      "pos": [
        5456,
        5459
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "159.0.0.0/8",
      "pos": [
        5465,
        5476
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3389",
      "pos": [
        5481,
        5485
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Permit",
      "pos": [
        5492,
        5498
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rule order",
      "pos": [
        5511,
        5521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because multiple rules can be specified for an endpoint, there must be a way to organize rules in order to determine which rule takes precedence.",
      "pos": [
        5523,
        5668
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The rule order specifies precedence.",
      "pos": [
        5669,
        5705
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network ACLs follow a <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>lowest takes precedence<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> rule order.",
      "pos": [
        5706,
        5765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the example below, the endpoint on port 80 is selectively granted access to only certain IP address ranges.",
      "pos": [
        5766,
        5876
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To configure this, we have a deny rule (Rule \\# 100) for addresses in the 175.1.0.1/24 space.",
      "pos": [
        5877,
        5970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A second rule is then specified with precedence 200 that permits access to all other addresses under 175.0.0.0/8.",
      "pos": [
        5971,
        6084
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example – Rule precedence",
      "pos": [
        6088,
        6113
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rule",
      "pos": [
        6121,
        6125
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remote Subnet",
      "pos": [
        6134,
        6147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Endpoint",
      "pos": [
        6154,
        6162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Permit/Deny",
      "pos": [
        6169,
        6180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        6239,
        6242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "175.1.0.1/24",
      "pos": [
        6248,
        6260
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "80",
      "pos": [
        6264,
        6266
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deny",
      "pos": [
        6275,
        6279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "200",
      "pos": [
        6291,
        6294
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "175.0.0.0/8",
      "pos": [
        6300,
        6311
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "80",
      "pos": [
        6316,
        6318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Permit",
      "pos": [
        6327,
        6333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network ACLs and load balanced sets",
      "pos": [
        6345,
        6380
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network ACLs can be specified on a Load balanced set (LB Set) endpoint.",
      "pos": [
        6382,
        6453
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If an ACL is specified for a LB Set, the Network ACL is applied to all Virtual Machines in that LB Set.",
      "pos": [
        6454,
        6557
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if a LB Set is created with \"Port 80\" and the LB Set contains 3 VMs, the Network ACL created on endpoint \"Port 80\" of one VM will automatically apply to the other VMs.",
      "pos": [
        6558,
        6738
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Network ACLs and load balanced sets",
      "pos": [
        6742,
        6777
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        6826,
        6836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to manage Access Control Lists (ACLs) for Endpoints by using PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        6839,
        6914
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"What is a Network Access Control List (ACL)?\"\n   description=\"Learn about ACLs\"\n   services=\"virtual-network\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   authors=\"telmosampaio\"\n   manager=\"carolz\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"virtual-network\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"06/08/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"telmos\" />\n\n# What is a Network Access Control List (ACLs)?\n\nA Network Access Control List (ACL) is a security enhancement available for your Azure deployment. An ACL provides the ability to selectively permit or deny traffic for a virtual machine endpoint. This packet filtering capability provides an additional layer of security. You can specify network ACLs for endpoints only. You can't specify an ACL for a virtual network or a specific subnet contained in a virtual network. \n\n> [AZURE.IMPORTANT] It is recommended to use Network Security Groups (NSGs) instead of ACLs whenever possible. To learn more about NSGs, see [What is a Network Security Group?](../virtual-networks-nsg).\n\nACLs can be configured by using either PowerShell or the Management Portal. To configure a network ACL by using PowerShell, see [Managing Access Control Lists (ACLs) for Endpoints by using PowerShell](virtual-networks-acl-powershell.md). To configure a network ACL by using the Management Portal, see [How to Set Up Endpoints to a Virtual Machine](../virtual-machines-set-up-endpoints/).\n\nUsing Network ACLs, you can do the following:\n\n- Selectively permit or deny incoming traffic based on remote subnet IPv4 address range to a virtual machine input endpoint.\n\n- Blacklist IP addresses\n\n- Create multiple rules per virtual machine endpoint\n\n- Specify up to 50 ACL rules per virtual machine endpoint\n\n- Use rule ordering to ensure the correct set of rules are applied on a given virtual machine endpoint (lowest to highest)\n\n- Specify an ACL for a specific remote subnet IPv4 address.\n\n## How ACLs work\n\nAn ACL is an object that contains a list of rules. When you create an ACL and apply it to a virtual machine endpoint, packet filtering takes place on the host node of your VM. This means the traffic from remote IP addresses is filtered by the host node for matching ACL rules instead of on your VM. This prevents your VM from spending the precious CPU cycles on packet filtering.\n\nWhen a virtual machine is created, a default ACL is put in place to block all incoming traffic. However, if an endpoint is created for (port 3389), then the default ACL is modified to allow all inbound traffic for that endpoint. Inbound traffic from any remote subnet is then allowed to that endpoint and no firewall provisioning is required. All other ports are blocked for inbound traffic unless endpoints are created for those ports. Outbound traffic is allowed by default.\n\n**Example Default ACL table**\n\n| **Rule #** | **Remote Subnet** | **Endpoint** | **Permit/Deny** |\n|--------|---------------|----------|-------------|\n| 100    | 0.0.0.0/0     | 3389     | Permit      |\n\n## Permit and deny\n\nYou can selectively permit or deny network traffic for a virtual machine input endpoint by creating rules that specify \"permit\" or \"deny\". It's important to note that by default, when an endpoint is created, all traffic is denied to the endpoint. For that reason, it's important to understand how to create permit/deny rules and place them in the proper order of precedence if you want granular control over the network traffic that you choose to allow to reach the virtual machine endpoint.\n\nPoints to consider:\n\n1. **No ACL –** By default when an endpoint is created, we permit all for the endpoint.\n\n1. **Permit -** When you add one or more \"permit\" ranges, you are denying all other ranges by default. Only packets from the permitted IP range will be able to communicate with the virtual machine endpoint.\n\n1. **Deny -** When you add one or more \"deny\" ranges, you are permitting all other ranges of traffic by default.\n\n1. **Combination of Permit and Deny -** You can use a combination of \"permit\" and \"deny\" when you want to carve out a specific IP range to be permitted or denied.\n\n## Rules and rule precedence\n\nNetwork ACLs can be set up on specific virtual machine endpoints. For example, you can specify a network ACL for an RDP endpoint created on a virtual machine which locks down access for certain IP addresses. The table below shows a way to grant access to public virtual IPs (VIPs) of a certain range to permit access for RDP. All other remote IPs are denied. We follow a *lowest takes precedence* rule order.\n\n### Multiple rules\n\nIn the example below, if you want to allow access to the RDP endpoint only from two public IPv4 address ranges (65.0.0.0/8, and 159.0.0.0/8), you can achieve this by specifying two *Permit* rules. In this case, since RDP is created by default for a virtual machine, you may want to lock down access to the RDP port based on a remote subnet. The example below shows a way to grant access to public virtual IPs (VIPs) of a certain range to permit access for RDP. All other remote IPs are denied. This works because network ACLs can be set up for a specific virtual machine endpoint and access is denied by default.\n\n**Example – Multiple rules**\n\n| **Rule #** | **Remote Subnet** | **Endpoint** | **Permit/Deny** |\n|--------|---------------|----------|-------------|\n| 100    | 65.0.0.0/8    | 3389     | Permit      |\n| 200    | 159.0.0.0/8   | 3389     | Permit      |\n\n### Rule order\n\nBecause multiple rules can be specified for an endpoint, there must be a way to organize rules in order to determine which rule takes precedence. The rule order specifies precedence. Network ACLs follow a *lowest takes precedence* rule order. In the example below, the endpoint on port 80 is selectively granted access to only certain IP address ranges. To configure this, we have a deny rule (Rule \\# 100) for addresses in the 175.1.0.1/24 space. A second rule is then specified with precedence 200 that permits access to all other addresses under 175.0.0.0/8.\n\n**Example – Rule precedence**\n\n| **Rule #** | **Remote Subnet** | **Endpoint** | **Permit/Deny** |\n|--------|---------------|----------|-------------|\n| 100    | 175.1.0.1/24  | 80       | Deny        |\n| 200    | 175.0.0.0/8   | 80       | Permit      |\n\n## Network ACLs and load balanced sets\n\nNetwork ACLs can be specified on a Load balanced set (LB Set) endpoint. If an ACL is specified for a LB Set, the Network ACL is applied to all Virtual Machines in that LB Set. For example, if a LB Set is created with \"Port 80\" and the LB Set contains 3 VMs, the Network ACL created on endpoint \"Port 80\" of one VM will automatically apply to the other VMs.\n\n![Network ACLs and load balanced sets](./media/virtual-networks-acl/IC674733.png)\n\n## Next Steps\n\n[How to manage Access Control Lists (ACLs) for Endpoints by using PowerShell](../virtual-networks-acl-powershell) \n"
}