{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Configure a VPN Gateway in the Azure Portal | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        88
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article walks you through configuring your virtual network VPN gateway and changing a VPN gateway routing type from static to dynamic or dynamic to static.",
      "pos": [
        106,
        266
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure a VPN gateway in the Azure portal",
      "pos": [
        573,
        616
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to create a secure cross-premises connection between Azure and your on-premises location, you'll need to configure a VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        618,
        759
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are different types of gateways and the type of gateway you'll create depends both on your network design plan, and the on-premises VPN device you want to use.",
      "pos": [
        760,
        925
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, some connectivity options, such as a point-to-site connection, require a dynamic routing gateway.",
      "pos": [
        926,
        1036
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to configure your gateway to support both point-to-site (P2S) connections and a site-to-site (S2S) connection, you'll have to configure a dynamic routing gateway even though site-to-site can be configured with either gateway routing type.",
      "pos": [
        1037,
        1287
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additionally, you'll have to make sure the device you want to use for your site-to-site connection will support the gateway type that you want to create.",
      "pos": [
        1288,
        1441
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About VPN Gateways<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-about-vpngateways.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1442,
        1501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration overview",
      "pos": [
        1506,
        1528
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The procedure below will walk you through configuring your VPN gateway in the Azure Portal.",
      "pos": [
        1530,
        1621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These steps apply to gateways for VNets that were created using the Service Management mode and are visible in the Azure Portal.",
      "pos": [
        1622,
        1750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They are not the steps for using the Preview Portal or for VNets configured using the Resource Manager mode.",
      "pos": [
        1751,
        1859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can find information about creating VNet gateways for virtual networks created using the Resource Manager mode in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a virtual network with a site-to-site connection using Azure Resource Manager and PowerShell <ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-create-site-to-site-rm-powershell.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1860,
        2131
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you configure your gateway, you'll first need to create your virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        2133,
        2217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For steps to create a virtual network for cross-premises connectivity, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configure a virtual network with a site-to-site VPN connection<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-site-to-site-create.md)</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Configure a virtual network with a point-to-site VPN connection<ept id=\"p2\">](vpn-gateway-point-to-site-create.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2218,
        2501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then, use the steps below to configure the VPN gateway and gather the information you'll need to configure your VPN device.",
      "pos": [
        2502,
        2625
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2628,
        2783
      ],
      "content": "If you already have a VPN gateway and you want to change the routing type, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to change your VPN gateway type<ept id=\"p1\">](#how-to-change-your-vpn-gateway-type)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a VPN gateway",
      "pos": [
        2789,
        2809
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gather information for your VPN device configuration",
      "pos": [
        2839,
        2891
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure your VPN device",
      "pos": [
        2953,
        2978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify your local network ranges and VPN gateway IP address",
      "pos": [
        3013,
        3072
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a VPN gateway",
      "pos": [
        3140,
        3160
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3165,
        3281
      ],
      "content": "In the Azure Portal,on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Networks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, verify that the status column for your virtual network is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Created<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3286,
        3349
      ],
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column, click the name of your virtual network."
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, notice that this VNet doesn't have a gateway configured yet.",
      "pos": [
        3354,
        3441
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll see this status as you go through the steps to configure your gateway.",
      "pos": [
        3442,
        3519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gateway Not Created",
      "pos": [
        3523,
        3542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, at the bottom of the page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create Gateway<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3605,
        3663
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can select either <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Static Routing<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>Dynamic Routing<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3664,
        3724
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The routing type you select depends on a number of factors.",
      "pos": [
        3725,
        3784
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, what your VPN device will support and whether you need to support point-to-site connections.",
      "pos": [
        3785,
        3890
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About VPN Devices for Virtual Network Connectivity<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-about-vpn-devices.md)</ept> to verify the routing type that you need.",
      "pos": [
        3891,
        4025
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the gateway has been created, you can't change between gateway types without deleting and re-creating the gateway.",
      "pos": [
        4026,
        4145
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When the system prompts you to confirm that you want the gateway created, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4146,
        4234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gateway Type",
      "pos": [
        4238,
        4250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When your gateway is creating, notice the gateway graphic on the page changes to yellow and says <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Creating Gateway<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4312,
        4428
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It may take up to 25 minutes for the gateway to create.",
      "pos": [
        4429,
        4484
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll have to wait until the gateway is complete before you can move forward with other configuration settings.",
      "pos": [
        4485,
        4597
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gateway Creating",
      "pos": [
        4601,
        4617
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4679,
        4784
      ],
      "content": "When the gateway changes to <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Connecting<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>, you can gather the information you'll need for your VPN device."
    },
    {
      "content": "Gateway Connecting",
      "pos": [
        4788,
        4806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gather information for your VPN device configuration",
      "pos": [
        4871,
        4923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the gateway has been created, gather information for your VPN device configuration.",
      "pos": [
        4925,
        5014
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This information is located on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page for your virtual network:",
      "pos": [
        5015,
        5094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Gateway IP address -<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The IP address can be found on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.",
      "pos": [
        5099,
        5178
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You won't be able to see it until after your gateway has finished creating.",
      "pos": [
        5179,
        5254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Shared key -<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Manage Key<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> at the bottom of the screen.",
      "pos": [
        5259,
        5325
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the icon next to the key in order to copy it to your clipboard, and then paste and save the key.",
      "pos": [
        5326,
        5428
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that this button only works when there is a single S2S VPN tunnel.",
      "pos": [
        5429,
        5500
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have multiple S2S VPN tunnels, please use the Get Virtual Network Gateway Shared Key API or PowerShell cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        5501,
        5618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Manage Key",
      "pos": [
        5622,
        5632
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure your VPN device",
      "pos": [
        5698,
        5723
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After completing the previous steps, you or your network administrator will need configure the VPN device in order to create the connection.",
      "pos": [
        5725,
        5865
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About VPN Devices for Virtual Network Connectivity<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-about-vpn-devices.md)</ept> for more information about VPN devices.",
      "pos": [
        5866,
        5996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After the VPN device has been configured, you can view your updated connection information on the Dashboard page for your VNet.",
      "pos": [
        5998,
        6125
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also run one of the following commands to test your connection:",
      "pos": [
        6127,
        6198
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cisco ASA",
      "pos": [
        6225,
        6234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cisco ISR/ASR",
      "pos": [
        6249,
        6262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Juniper SSG/ISG",
      "pos": [
        6273,
        6288
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Juniper SRX/J",
      "pos": [
        6291,
        6304
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check main mode SAs",
      "pos": [
        6472,
        6491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "show crypto isakmp sa",
      "pos": [
        6497,
        6518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "show crypto isakmp sa",
      "pos": [
        6521,
        6542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "get ike cookie",
      "pos": [
        6545,
        6559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "show security ike security-association",
      "pos": [
        6563,
        6601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check quick mode SAs",
      "pos": [
        6610,
        6630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "show crypto ipsec sa",
      "pos": [
        6635,
        6655
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "show crypto ipsec sa",
      "pos": [
        6659,
        6679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "get sa",
      "pos": [
        6683,
        6689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "show security ipsec security-association",
      "pos": [
        6701,
        6741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify your local network ranges and VPN gateway IP address",
      "pos": [
        6749,
        6808
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify your VPN gateway IP address",
      "pos": [
        6814,
        6848
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For gateway to connect properly, the IP address for your VPN device must be correctly configured for the Local Network that you specified for your cross-premises configuration.",
      "pos": [
        6850,
        7026
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, this is configured during the site-to-site configuration process.",
      "pos": [
        7027,
        7103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, if you previously used this local network with a different device, or the IP address has changed for this local network, you'll want to edit the settings to specify the correct Gateway IP address.",
      "pos": [
        7104,
        7309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To verify your gateway IP address, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Networks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on the left portal pane and then select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Local Networks<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> at the top of the page.",
      "pos": [
        7314,
        7450
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You'll see the VPN Gateway Address for each local network that you have created.",
      "pos": [
        7451,
        7531
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To edit the IP address, select the VNet and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the bottom of the page.",
      "pos": [
        7532,
        7617
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7622,
        7751
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify your local network details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, edit the IP address, and then click the next arrow at the bottom of the page."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7756,
        7860
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify the address space<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click the checkmark on the lower right to save your settings."
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify the address ranges for your local networks",
      "pos": [
        7866,
        7915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the correct traffic to flow through the gateway to your on-premises location, you'll need to verify that you have listed each IP address range that you want to include in your local network configuration.",
      "pos": [
        7917,
        8125
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Depending on the network configuration of your on-premises location, this can be a somewhat large task because each range must be listed in your Azure <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Local Networks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> configuration.",
      "pos": [
        8126,
        8310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traffic that is bound for an IP address that is contained within the ranges listed will then be sent through the virtual network VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        8311,
        8452
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The IP address ranges that you list do not have to be private ranges, although you will want to verify that your on-premises configuration is able to receive the inbound traffic.",
      "pos": [
        8453,
        8631
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To add or edit the ranges for a Local Network, follow the procedure below.",
      "pos": [
        8633,
        8707
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To edit the IP address ranges for a local network, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Networks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on the left portal pane and then select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Local Networks<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> at the top of the page.",
      "pos": [
        8712,
        8864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the portal, the easiest way to view the ranges that you've listed is on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.",
      "pos": [
        8865,
        8958
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To see your ranges, select the VNet and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the bottom of the page.",
      "pos": [
        8959,
        9040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify your local network details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, don't make any changes.",
      "pos": [
        9045,
        9120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the next arrow at the bottom of the page.",
      "pos": [
        9121,
        9168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Specify the address space<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, make your network address space changes.",
      "pos": [
        9173,
        9256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then click the checkmark to save your configuration.",
      "pos": [
        9257,
        9309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to view gateway traffic",
      "pos": [
        9314,
        9341
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9343,
        9434
      ],
      "content": "You can view your gateway and gateway traffic from your Virtual Network <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9436,
        9489
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page you can view the following:"
    },
    {
      "content": "The amount of data that is flowing through your gateway, both data in and data out.",
      "pos": [
        9493,
        9576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The names of the DNS servers that are specified for your virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        9580,
        9653
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The connection between your gateway and your VPN device.",
      "pos": [
        9657,
        9713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The shared key that is used to configure your gateway connection to your VPN device.",
      "pos": [
        9717,
        9801
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to change your VPN gateway type",
      "pos": [
        9807,
        9842
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because some connectivity configurations are only available for certain gateway types, you may find that you need to change the gateway type of an existing VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        9844,
        10012
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, you may want to add point-to-site connectivity to an already existing site-to-site connection that has a static gateway.",
      "pos": [
        10013,
        10146
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Point-to-site requires a dynamic gateway, which means in order to configure it, you'll have to change your gateway type from static to dynamic.",
      "pos": [
        10147,
        10290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need to change a VPN gateway routing type, you'll delete the existing gateway, and then recreate it with the new routing type.",
      "pos": [
        10292,
        10425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You don't need to delete the entire virtual network in order to change the gateway routing type.",
      "pos": [
        10426,
        10522
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before changing your gateway type, be sure to verify that your VPN device will support the routing type that you want to use.",
      "pos": [
        10524,
        10649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To download new routing configuration samples and check VPN device requirements, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About VPN Devices for Virtual Network Connectivity<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-about-vpn-devices.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        10650,
        10822
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> When you delete a virtual network VPN gateway, the VIP assigned to the gateway is released.",
      "pos": [
        10825,
        10934
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you recreate the gateway, a new VIP will be assigned to it.",
      "pos": [
        10935,
        10999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete the existing VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        11006,
        11038
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dashboard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page for your virtual network, navigate to the bottom of the page and click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Delete Gateway<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11046,
        11162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Wait for the notification that the gateway has been deleted.",
      "pos": [
        11163,
        11223
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you receive notification on the screen that your gateway has been deleted, you can then create a new gateway.",
      "pos": [
        11224,
        11338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a new VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        11345,
        11370
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11378,
        11490
      ],
      "content": "Use the procedure at the top of the page to create a new gateway: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a VPN gateway<ept id=\"p1\">](#create-a-vpn-gateway)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        11496,
        11506
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11508,
        11696
      ],
      "content": "You can learn more about Virtual Network cross-premises connectivity in this article: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About secure cross-premises connections for virtual networks<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-cross-premises-options.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "You can add virtual machines to your virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        11698,
        11751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to create a custom virtual machine<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-machines/virtual-machines-create-custom.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11752,
        11852
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11854,
        11995
      ],
      "content": "If you want to configure a point-to-site VPN connection, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configure a point-to-site VPN connection<ept id=\"p1\">](vpn-gateway-point-to-site-create.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Configure a VPN Gateway in the Azure Portal | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"This article walks you through configuring your virtual network VPN gateway and changing a VPN gateway routing type from static to dynamic or dynamic to static.\"\n   services=\"vpn-gateway\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   authors=\"cherylmc\"\n   manager=\"carolz\"\n   editor=\"\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"vpn-gateway\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"08/25/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"cherylmc\" />\n\n# Configure a VPN gateway in the Azure portal\n\nIf you want to create a secure cross-premises connection between Azure and your on-premises location, you'll need to configure a VPN gateway. There are different types of gateways and the type of gateway you'll create depends both on your network design plan, and the on-premises VPN device you want to use. For example, some connectivity options, such as a point-to-site connection, require a dynamic routing gateway. If you want to configure your gateway to support both point-to-site (P2S) connections and a site-to-site (S2S) connection, you'll have to configure a dynamic routing gateway even though site-to-site can be configured with either gateway routing type. Additionally, you'll have to make sure the device you want to use for your site-to-site connection will support the gateway type that you want to create. See [About VPN Gateways](vpn-gateway-about-vpngateways.md).\n\n## Configuration overview\n\nThe procedure below will walk you through configuring your VPN gateway in the Azure Portal. These steps apply to gateways for VNets that were created using the Service Management mode and are visible in the Azure Portal. They are not the steps for using the Preview Portal or for VNets configured using the Resource Manager mode. You can find information about creating VNet gateways for virtual networks created using the Resource Manager mode in [Create a virtual network with a site-to-site connection using Azure Resource Manager and PowerShell ](vpn-gateway-create-site-to-site-rm-powershell.md).\n\nBefore you configure your gateway, you'll first need to create your virtual network. For steps to create a virtual network for cross-premises connectivity, see [Configure a virtual network with a site-to-site VPN connection](vpn-gateway-site-to-site-create.md), or [Configure a virtual network with a point-to-site VPN connection](vpn-gateway-point-to-site-create.md). Then, use the steps below to configure the VPN gateway and gather the information you'll need to configure your VPN device. \n\nIf you already have a VPN gateway and you want to change the routing type, see [How to change your VPN gateway type](#how-to-change-your-vpn-gateway-type).\n\n1. [Create a VPN gateway](#create-a-vpn-gateway)\n\n1. [Gather information for your VPN device configuration](#gather-information-for-your-vpn-device-configuration)\n\n1. [Configure your VPN device](#configure-your-vpn-device)\n\n1. [Verify your local network ranges and VPN gateway IP address](#verify-your-local-network-ranges-and-vpn-gateway-ip-address)\n\n## Create a VPN gateway\n\n1. In the Azure Portal,on the **Networks** page, verify that the status column for your virtual network is **Created**.\n\n1. In the **Name** column, click the name of your virtual network.\n\n1. On the **Dashboard** page, notice that this VNet doesn't have a gateway configured yet. You'll see this status as you go through the steps to configure your gateway.\n\n![Gateway Not Created](./media/vpn-gateway-configure-vpn-gateway-mp/IC717025.png)\n\n\nNext, at the bottom of the page, click **Create Gateway**. You can select either *Static Routing* or *Dynamic Routing*. The routing type you select depends on a number of factors. For example, what your VPN device will support and whether you need to support point-to-site connections. Check [About VPN Devices for Virtual Network Connectivity](vpn-gateway-about-vpn-devices.md) to verify the routing type that you need. Once the gateway has been created, you can't change between gateway types without deleting and re-creating the gateway. When the system prompts you to confirm that you want the gateway created, click **Yes**.\n\n![Gateway Type](./media/vpn-gateway-configure-vpn-gateway-mp/IC717026.png)\n\nWhen your gateway is creating, notice the gateway graphic on the page changes to yellow and says *Creating Gateway*. It may take up to 25 minutes for the gateway to create. You'll have to wait until the gateway is complete before you can move forward with other configuration settings.\n\n![Gateway Creating](./media/vpn-gateway-configure-vpn-gateway-mp/IC717027.png)\n\nWhen the gateway changes to *Connecting*, you can gather the information you'll need for your VPN device.\n\n![Gateway Connecting](./media/vpn-gateway-configure-vpn-gateway-mp/IC717028.png)\n\n## Gather information for your VPN device configuration\n\nAfter the gateway has been created, gather information for your VPN device configuration. This information is located on the **Dashboard** page for your virtual network:\n\n1. **Gateway IP address -** The IP address can be found on the **Dashboard** page. You won't be able to see it until after your gateway has finished creating.\n\n1. **Shared key -** Click **Manage Key** at the bottom of the screen. Click the icon next to the key in order to copy it to your clipboard, and then paste and save the key. Note that this button only works when there is a single S2S VPN tunnel. If you have multiple S2S VPN tunnels, please use the Get Virtual Network Gateway Shared Key API or PowerShell cmdlet.\n\n![Manage Key](./media/vpn-gateway-configure-vpn-gateway-mp/IC717029.png)\n\n\n## Configure your VPN device\n\nAfter completing the previous steps, you or your network administrator will need configure the VPN device in order to create the connection. See [About VPN Devices for Virtual Network Connectivity](vpn-gateway-about-vpn-devices.md) for more information about VPN devices.\n\nAfter the VPN device has been configured, you can view your updated connection information on the Dashboard page for your VNet.\n\nYou can also run one of the following commands to test your connection:\n\n|                      | Cisco ASA             | Cisco ISR/ASR         | Juniper SSG/ISG | Juniper SRX/J                            |\n|----------------------|-----------------------|-----------------------|-----------------|------------------------------------------|\n| **Check main mode SAs**  | show crypto isakmp sa | show crypto isakmp sa | get ike cookie  | show security ike security-association   |\n| **Check quick mode SAs** | show crypto ipsec sa  | show crypto ipsec sa  | get sa          | show security ipsec security-association |\n\n\n## Verify your local network ranges and VPN gateway IP address\n\n### Verify your VPN gateway IP address\n\nFor gateway to connect properly, the IP address for your VPN device must be correctly configured for the Local Network that you specified for your cross-premises configuration. Typically, this is configured during the site-to-site configuration process. However, if you previously used this local network with a different device, or the IP address has changed for this local network, you'll want to edit the settings to specify the correct Gateway IP address.\n\n1. To verify your gateway IP address, click **Networks** on the left portal pane and then select **Local Networks** at the top of the page. You'll see the VPN Gateway Address for each local network that you have created. To edit the IP address, select the VNet and click **Edit** at the bottom of the page.\n\n1. On the **Specify your local network details** page, edit the IP address, and then click the next arrow at the bottom of the page.\n\n1. On the **Specify the address space** page, click the checkmark on the lower right to save your settings.\n\n### Verify the address ranges for your local networks\n\nFor the correct traffic to flow through the gateway to your on-premises location, you'll need to verify that you have listed each IP address range that you want to include in your local network configuration. Depending on the network configuration of your on-premises location, this can be a somewhat large task because each range must be listed in your Azure **Local Networks** configuration. Traffic that is bound for an IP address that is contained within the ranges listed will then be sent through the virtual network VPN gateway. The IP address ranges that you list do not have to be private ranges, although you will want to verify that your on-premises configuration is able to receive the inbound traffic.\n\nTo add or edit the ranges for a Local Network, follow the procedure below.\n\n1. To edit the IP address ranges for a local network, click **Networks** on the left portal pane and then select **Local Networks** at the top of the page. In the portal, the easiest way to view the ranges that you've listed is on the **Edit** page. To see your ranges, select the VNet and click **Edit** at the bottom of the page.\n\n1. On the **Specify your local network details** page, don't make any changes. Click the next arrow at the bottom of the page.\n\n1. On the **Specify the address space** page, make your network address space changes. Then click the checkmark to save your configuration.\n\n## How to view gateway traffic\n\nYou can view your gateway and gateway traffic from your Virtual Network **Dashboard** page.\n\nOn the **Dashboard** page you can view the following:\n\n- The amount of data that is flowing through your gateway, both data in and data out.\n\n- The names of the DNS servers that are specified for your virtual network.\n\n- The connection between your gateway and your VPN device.\n\n- The shared key that is used to configure your gateway connection to your VPN device.\n\n\n## How to change your VPN gateway type\n\nBecause some connectivity configurations are only available for certain gateway types, you may find that you need to change the gateway type of an existing VPN gateway. For example, you may want to add point-to-site connectivity to an already existing site-to-site connection that has a static gateway. Point-to-site requires a dynamic gateway, which means in order to configure it, you'll have to change your gateway type from static to dynamic.\n\nIf you need to change a VPN gateway routing type, you'll delete the existing gateway, and then recreate it with the new routing type. You don't need to delete the entire virtual network in order to change the gateway routing type.\n\nBefore changing your gateway type, be sure to verify that your VPN device will support the routing type that you want to use. To download new routing configuration samples and check VPN device requirements, see [About VPN Devices for Virtual Network Connectivity](vpn-gateway-about-vpn-devices.md).\n\n>[AZURE.IMPORTANT] When you delete a virtual network VPN gateway, the VIP assigned to the gateway is released. When you recreate the gateway, a new VIP will be assigned to it.\n\n1. **Delete the existing VPN gateway.**\n\n    On the **Dashboard** page for your virtual network, navigate to the bottom of the page and click **Delete Gateway**. Wait for the notification that the gateway has been deleted. When you receive notification on the screen that your gateway has been deleted, you can then create a new gateway.\n\n1. **Create a new VPN gateway.**\n\n    Use the procedure at the top of the page to create a new gateway: [Create a VPN gateway](#create-a-vpn-gateway).\n\n\n## Next steps\n\nYou can learn more about Virtual Network cross-premises connectivity in this article: [About secure cross-premises connections for virtual networks](vpn-gateway-cross-premises-options.md).\n\nYou can add virtual machines to your virtual network. See [How to create a custom virtual machine](../virtual-machines/virtual-machines-create-custom.md).\n\nIf you want to configure a point-to-site VPN connection, see [Configure a point-to-site VPN connection](vpn-gateway-point-to-site-create.md).\n\n \n"
}