{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Creating a Snapshot of a Blob",
      "pos": [
        28,
        57
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A how to guide for creating Azure Storage Blob Snapshots",
      "pos": [
        77,
        133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a blob snapshot",
      "pos": [
        432,
        454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        459,
        467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A snapshot is a read-only version of a blob that's taken at a point in time.",
      "pos": [
        469,
        545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshots are useful for backing up blobs.",
      "pos": [
        546,
        588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once a snapshot has been created, you can read, copy, or delete it, but you cannot modify it.",
      "pos": [
        589,
        682
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A snapshot of a blob has the same name as the base blob from which the snapshot is taken, with a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DateTime<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value appended to indicate the time at which the snapshot was taken.",
      "pos": [
        685,
        863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if a page blob URI is <ph id=\"ph1\">`http://storagesample.core.blob.windows.net/mydrives/myvhd`</ph>, the snapshot URI will be similar to <ph id=\"ph2\">`http://storagesample.core.blob.windows.net/mydrives/myvhd?snapshot=2011-03-09T01:42:34.9360000Z`</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        864,
        1094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All of a blob's snapshots share its URI and are distinguished only by the appended <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DateTime<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value.",
      "pos": [
        1095,
        1197
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A blob may have any number of snapshots.",
      "pos": [
        1199,
        1239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshots persist until they are explicitly deleted.",
      "pos": [
        1240,
        1292
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that a snapshot cannot outlive its source blob.",
      "pos": [
        1293,
        1345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can enumerate the snapshots associated with your blob to track your current snapshots.",
      "pos": [
        1346,
        1436
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create a snapshot of a blob, the blob's system properties are copied to the snapshot with the same values.",
      "pos": [
        1438,
        1553
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any leases associated with the base blob do not affect the snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        1556,
        1624
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot acquire a lease on a snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        1625,
        1666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copying snapshots",
      "pos": [
        1671,
        1688
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy operations involving blobs and snapshots follow these rules:",
      "pos": [
        1691,
        1756
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can copy a snapshot over its base blob.",
      "pos": [
        1760,
        1803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By promoting a snapshot to the position of the base blob, you can restore an earlier version of a blob.",
      "pos": [
        1804,
        1907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The snapshot remains, but the base blob is overwritten with a writable copy of the snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        1908,
        2000
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can copy a snapshot to a destination blob with a different name.",
      "pos": [
        2004,
        2072
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The resulting destination blob is a writable blob and not a snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        2073,
        2142
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a source blob is copied, any snapshots of the source blob are not copied to the destination.",
      "pos": [
        2146,
        2243
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a destination blob is overwritten with a copy, any snapshots associated with the destination blob at the time it was overwritten remain intact under its name.",
      "pos": [
        2244,
        2407
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create a snapshot of a block blob, the blob's committed block list is also copied to the snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        2412,
        2519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any uncommitted blocks are not copied.",
      "pos": [
        2520,
        2558
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specifying an access condition",
      "pos": [
        2563,
        2593
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can specify an access condition so that the snapshot is created only if a condition is met.",
      "pos": [
        2596,
        2691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To specify an access condition, use the AccessCondition property.",
      "pos": [
        2692,
        2757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the specified condition is not met, the snapshot is not created, and the Blob service returns status code HTTPStatusCode.PreconditionFailed.",
      "pos": [
        2758,
        2901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deleting snapshots",
      "pos": [
        2906,
        2924
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A blob that has snapshots cannot be deleted unless the snapshots are also deleted.",
      "pos": [
        2927,
        3009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can delete a snapshot individually, or tell the storage service to delete all snapshots when deleting the source blob.",
      "pos": [
        3010,
        3132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you attempt to delete a blob that still has snapshots, you'll get an error.",
      "pos": [
        3133,
        3211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshots with Premium Storage",
      "pos": [
        3216,
        3246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using snapshots with Premium Storage follow these rules:",
      "pos": [
        3247,
        3303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The number of snapshots per page blob in a Premium Storage account is limited to 100.",
      "pos": [
        3307,
        3392
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If that limit is exceeded, the Snapshot Blob operation returns error code 409 (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SnapshotCountExceeded<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>).",
      "pos": [
        3393,
        3499
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A snapshot of a page blob in a Premium Storage account may be taken once every ten minutes.",
      "pos": [
        3503,
        3594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If that rate is exceeded, the Snapshot Blob operation returns error code 409 (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SnaphotOperationRateExceeded<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>).",
      "pos": [
        3595,
        3707
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reading a snapshot of a page blob in a Premium Storage account via Get Blob is not supported.",
      "pos": [
        3711,
        3804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Calling Get Blob on a snapshot in a Premium Storage account returns error code 400 (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>InvalidOperation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>).",
      "pos": [
        3805,
        3911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, calling Get Blob Properties and Get Blob Metadata against a snapshot is supported.",
      "pos": [
        3912,
        4003
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To read a snapshot, you can use the Copy Blob operation to copy a snapshot to another page blob in the account.",
      "pos": [
        4007,
        4118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The destination blob for the copy operation must not have any existing snapshots.",
      "pos": [
        4119,
        4200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the destination blob does have snapshots, then Copy Blob returns error code 409 (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SnapshotsPresent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>).",
      "pos": [
        4201,
        4307
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Returning the absolute URI to a snapshot",
      "pos": [
        4312,
        4352
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This C# code example creates a new snapshot and writes out the absolute URI for the primary location.",
      "pos": [
        4355,
        4456
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Understanding how snapshots accrue charges",
      "pos": [
        5232,
        5274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating a snapshot, which is a read-only copy of a blob, can result in additional data storage charges to your account.",
      "pos": [
        5276,
        5396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When designing your application, it is important to be aware how these charges may accrue so that you can minimize unnecessary costs.",
      "pos": [
        5397,
        5530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Important billing considerations",
      "pos": [
        5536,
        5568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following list includes key points to consider when creating a snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        5570,
        5646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Charges are incurred for unique blocks or pages, whether they are in the blob or in the snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        5650,
        5747
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your account does not incur additional charges for snapshots associated with a blob until you update the blob on which they are based.",
      "pos": [
        5748,
        5882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you update the base blob, it diverges from its snapshots, and you will be charged for the unique blocks or pages in each blob or snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        5883,
        6026
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you replace a block within a block blob, that block is subsequently charged as a unique block.",
      "pos": [
        6030,
        6129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is true even if the block has the same block ID and the same data as it has in the snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        6130,
        6227
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the block is committed again, it diverges from its counterpart in any snapshot, and you will be charged for its data.",
      "pos": [
        6228,
        6350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The same holds true for a page in a page blob that’s updated with identical data.",
      "pos": [
        6351,
        6432
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replacing a block blob by calling the UploadFile, UploadText, UploadStream, or UploadByteArray method replaces all of the blocks in that blob.",
      "pos": [
        6436,
        6578
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have a snapshot associated with that blob, all of the blocks in the base blob and snapshot will now diverge and you will be charged for all of the blocks in both blobs.",
      "pos": [
        6579,
        6754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is true even if the data in the base blob and the snapshot remain identical.",
      "pos": [
        6755,
        6836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure Blob service does not have a means to determine whether two blocks contain identical data.",
      "pos": [
        6840,
        6940
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each block that is uploaded and committed is treated as unique, even if it has the same data and the same block ID.",
      "pos": [
        6941,
        7056
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because charges accrue for unique blocks, it is important to consider that updating a blob that has a snapshot will result in additional unique blocks and additional charges.",
      "pos": [
        7057,
        7231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Best practices dictate that you manage snapshots carefully to avoid extra charges.",
      "pos": [
        7235,
        7330
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It’s recommended that you manage snapshots in the following manner:",
      "pos": [
        7331,
        7398
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete and re-create snapshots associated with a blob whenever you update the blob, even if you are updating with identical data, unless your application design requires that you maintain snapshots.",
      "pos": [
        7404,
        7602
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By deleting and re-creating the blob’s snapshots, you can ensure that the blob and snapshots do not diverge.",
      "pos": [
        7603,
        7711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are maintaining snapshots for a blob, avoid calling UploadFile, UploadText, UploadStream, or UploadByteArray to update the blob, as those methods replace all of the blocks in the blob.",
      "pos": [
        7717,
        7908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instead, update the fewest possible number of blocks by using the PutBlock and PutBlockList methods.",
      "pos": [
        7909,
        8009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Snapshot billing scenarios",
      "pos": [
        8016,
        8042
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following scenarios demonstrate how charges accrue for a block blob and its snapshots.",
      "pos": [
        8045,
        8135
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Scenario 1, the base blob has not been updated since the snapshot was taken, so charges are incurred only for unique blocks 1, 2, and 3.",
      "pos": [
        8138,
        8277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Storage Resources",
      "pos": [
        8281,
        8304
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Scenario 2, the base blob has been updated, but the snapshot has not.",
      "pos": [
        8385,
        8457
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Block 3 was updated, and even though it contains the same data and the same ID, it is not the same as block 3 in the snapshot.",
      "pos": [
        8458,
        8584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result, the account is charged for four blocks.",
      "pos": [
        8585,
        8637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Storage Resources",
      "pos": [
        8641,
        8664
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Scenario 3, the base blob has been updated, but the snapshot has not.",
      "pos": [
        8745,
        8817
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Block 3 was replaced with block 4 in the base blob, but the snapshot still reflects block 3.",
      "pos": [
        8818,
        8910
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result, the account is charged for four blocks.",
      "pos": [
        8911,
        8963
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Storage Resources",
      "pos": [
        8968,
        8991
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Scenario 4, the base blob has been completely updated and contains none of its original blocks.",
      "pos": [
        9072,
        9170
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a result, the account is charged for all eight unique blocks.",
      "pos": [
        9171,
        9235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This scenario can occur if you are using an update method such as UploadFile, UploadText, UploadFromStream, or UploadByteArray, because these methods replace all of the contents of a blob.",
      "pos": [
        9236,
        9424
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Storage Resources",
      "pos": [
        9428,
        9451
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Creating a Snapshot of a Blob\" \n    description=\"A how to guide for creating Azure Storage Blob Snapshots\" \n    services=\"storage\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"tamram\" \n    manager=\"adinah\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"storage\" \n    ms.workload=\"storage\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"09/01/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"tamram\"/>\n\n# Create a blob snapshot\n\n## Overview\n\nA snapshot is a read-only version of a blob that's taken at a point in time. Snapshots are useful for backing up blobs. Once a snapshot has been created, you can read, copy, or delete it, but you cannot modify it. \n\nA snapshot of a blob has the same name as the base blob from which the snapshot is taken, with a **DateTime** value appended to indicate the time at which the snapshot was taken. For example, if a page blob URI is `http://storagesample.core.blob.windows.net/mydrives/myvhd`, the snapshot URI will be similar to `http://storagesample.core.blob.windows.net/mydrives/myvhd?snapshot=2011-03-09T01:42:34.9360000Z`. All of a blob's snapshots share its URI and are distinguished only by the appended **DateTime** value.\n\nA blob may have any number of snapshots. Snapshots persist until they are explicitly deleted. Note that a snapshot cannot outlive its source blob. You can enumerate the snapshots associated with your blob to track your current snapshots.\n\nWhen you create a snapshot of a blob, the blob's system properties are copied to the snapshot with the same values. \n\nAny leases associated with the base blob do not affect the snapshot. You cannot acquire a lease on a snapshot.\n\n## Copying snapshots \n\nCopy operations involving blobs and snapshots follow these rules:\n\n- You can copy a snapshot over its base blob. By promoting a snapshot to the position of the base blob, you can restore an earlier version of a blob. The snapshot remains, but the base blob is overwritten with a writable copy of the snapshot.\n\n- You can copy a snapshot to a destination blob with a different name. The resulting destination blob is a writable blob and not a snapshot.\n\n- When a source blob is copied, any snapshots of the source blob are not copied to the destination. When a destination blob is overwritten with a copy, any snapshots associated with the destination blob at the time it was overwritten remain intact under its name. \n\n- When you create a snapshot of a block blob, the blob's committed block list is also copied to the snapshot. Any uncommitted blocks are not copied.\n\n## Specifying an access condition \n\nYou can specify an access condition so that the snapshot is created only if a condition is met. To specify an access condition, use the AccessCondition property. If the specified condition is not met, the snapshot is not created, and the Blob service returns status code HTTPStatusCode.PreconditionFailed.\n\n## Deleting snapshots \n\nA blob that has snapshots cannot be deleted unless the snapshots are also deleted. You can delete a snapshot individually, or tell the storage service to delete all snapshots when deleting the source blob. If you attempt to delete a blob that still has snapshots, you'll get an error.\n\n## Snapshots with Premium Storage\nUsing snapshots with Premium Storage follow these rules:\n\n- The number of snapshots per page blob in a Premium Storage account is limited to 100. If that limit is exceeded, the Snapshot Blob operation returns error code 409 (**SnapshotCountExceeded**).\n\n- A snapshot of a page blob in a Premium Storage account may be taken once every ten minutes. If that rate is exceeded, the Snapshot Blob operation returns error code 409 (**SnaphotOperationRateExceeded**).\n\n- Reading a snapshot of a page blob in a Premium Storage account via Get Blob is not supported. Calling Get Blob on a snapshot in a Premium Storage account returns error code 400 (**InvalidOperation**). However, calling Get Blob Properties and Get Blob Metadata against a snapshot is supported.\n\n- To read a snapshot, you can use the Copy Blob operation to copy a snapshot to another page blob in the account. The destination blob for the copy operation must not have any existing snapshots. If the destination blob does have snapshots, then Copy Blob returns error code 409 (**SnapshotsPresent**).\n\n## Returning the absolute URI to a snapshot \n\nThis C# code example creates a new snapshot and writes out the absolute URI for the primary location.\n\n    //Create the blob service client object.\n    CloudStorageAccount storageAccount = CloudStorageAccount.Parse(CloudConfigurationManager.GetSetting(\"StorageConnectionString\"));\n    CloudBlobClient blobClient = storageAccount.CreateCloudBlobClient();\n    \n    //Get a reference to a container.\n    CloudBlobContainer container = blobClient.GetContainerReference(\"sample-container\");\n    container.CreateIfNotExists();\n\n    //Get a reference to a blob.\n    CloudBlockBlob blob = container.GetBlockBlobReference(\"sampleblob.txt\");\n    blob.UploadText(\"This is a blob.\");\n\n    //Create a snapshot of the blob and write out its primary URI.\n    CloudBlockBlob blobSnapshot = blob.CreateSnapshot();\n    Console.WriteLine(blobSnapshot.SnapshotQualifiedStorageUri.PrimaryUri);\n\n## Understanding how snapshots accrue charges\n\nCreating a snapshot, which is a read-only copy of a blob, can result in additional data storage charges to your account. When designing your application, it is important to be aware how these charges may accrue so that you can minimize unnecessary costs.\n\n### Important billing considerations\n\nThe following list includes key points to consider when creating a snapshot.\n\n- Charges are incurred for unique blocks or pages, whether they are in the blob or in the snapshot. Your account does not incur additional charges for snapshots associated with a blob until you update the blob on which they are based. Once you update the base blob, it diverges from its snapshots, and you will be charged for the unique blocks or pages in each blob or snapshot.\n\n- When you replace a block within a block blob, that block is subsequently charged as a unique block. This is true even if the block has the same block ID and the same data as it has in the snapshot. Once the block is committed again, it diverges from its counterpart in any snapshot, and you will be charged for its data. The same holds true for a page in a page blob that’s updated with identical data.\n\n- Replacing a block blob by calling the UploadFile, UploadText, UploadStream, or UploadByteArray method replaces all of the blocks in that blob. If you have a snapshot associated with that blob, all of the blocks in the base blob and snapshot will now diverge and you will be charged for all of the blocks in both blobs. This is true even if the data in the base blob and the snapshot remain identical.\n\n- The Azure Blob service does not have a means to determine whether two blocks contain identical data. Each block that is uploaded and committed is treated as unique, even if it has the same data and the same block ID. Because charges accrue for unique blocks, it is important to consider that updating a blob that has a snapshot will result in additional unique blocks and additional charges.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Best practices dictate that you manage snapshots carefully to avoid extra charges. It’s recommended that you manage snapshots in the following manner:\n\n> - Delete and re-create snapshots associated with a blob whenever you update the blob, even if you are updating with identical data, unless your application design requires that you maintain snapshots. By deleting and re-creating the blob’s snapshots, you can ensure that the blob and snapshots do not diverge.\n\n> - If you are maintaining snapshots for a blob, avoid calling UploadFile, UploadText, UploadStream, or UploadByteArray to update the blob, as those methods replace all of the blocks in the blob. Instead, update the fewest possible number of blocks by using the PutBlock and PutBlockList methods.\n\n\n### Snapshot billing scenarios\n\n\nThe following scenarios demonstrate how charges accrue for a block blob and its snapshots. \n\nIn Scenario 1, the base blob has not been updated since the snapshot was taken, so charges are incurred only for unique blocks 1, 2, and 3.\n\n![Azure Storage Resources](./media/storage-blob-snapshots/storage-blob-snapshots-billing-scenario-1.png)\n\nIn Scenario 2, the base blob has been updated, but the snapshot has not. Block 3 was updated, and even though it contains the same data and the same ID, it is not the same as block 3 in the snapshot. As a result, the account is charged for four blocks.\n\n![Azure Storage Resources](./media/storage-blob-snapshots/storage-blob-snapshots-billing-scenario-2.png)\n\nIn Scenario 3, the base blob has been updated, but the snapshot has not. Block 3 was replaced with block 4 in the base blob, but the snapshot still reflects block 3. As a result, the account is charged for four blocks.\n \n![Azure Storage Resources](./media/storage-blob-snapshots/storage-blob-snapshots-billing-scenario-3.png)\n\nIn Scenario 4, the base blob has been completely updated and contains none of its original blocks. As a result, the account is charged for all eight unique blocks. This scenario can occur if you are using an update method such as UploadFile, UploadText, UploadFromStream, or UploadByteArray, because these methods replace all of the contents of a blob.\n\n![Azure Storage Resources](./media/storage-blob-snapshots/storage-blob-snapshots-billing-scenario-4.png) "
}