{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Mobile Engagement Overview",
      "pos": [
        28,
        54
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview of Azure Mobile Engagement",
      "pos": [
        74,
        109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement Overview",
      "pos": [
        450,
        482
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement is a SaaS-delivered, data-driven user engagement platform that enables real-time fine-grain user segmentation, app user analytics, and contextually-aware smart push notifications and in-app messaging across all connected devices.",
      "pos": [
        484,
        737
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview video",
      "pos": [
        742,
        756
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With Azure Mobile Engagement, app publishers and marketing professionals can create cutting-edge interactions.",
      "pos": [
        807,
        917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Real time actionable analytics to increase app usage",
      "pos": [
        921,
        973
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Trigger engagement scenarios according to app user behavior and demographics by combining Big Data collection with real time processing.",
      "pos": [
        975,
        1111
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement can answer nearly any question relevant to your particular business needs.",
      "pos": [
        1112,
        1210
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, you can create custom dashboards to measure KPIs, rapidly find and fix usage bottlenecks in the user path, track retention and stickiness, and by that determine what campaigns are driving the highest ROI.",
      "pos": [
        1211,
        1428
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement’s 360° user path view, allows you to easily and continually enhance and optimize the user experience – driving higher retention rates and increased app usage.",
      "pos": [
        1429,
        1611
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Value added push and communications platform",
      "pos": [
        1615,
        1659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement works flawlessly with native push notifications gateways such as Google’s GCM, Apple’s APNS or Microsoft MPNS, but it goes beyond and gives you the power to create targeted campaigns , by providing intelligent customer segments and in-app messaging capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        1661,
        1947
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This benefits app developers by reaching their customers in a highly effective and non-intrusive manner.",
      "pos": [
        1949,
        2053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open APIs and ease of integration",
      "pos": [
        2057,
        2090
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By providing open APIs and ease of integration you can leverage existing data from CRM, CMS and other business related systems.",
      "pos": [
        2092,
        2219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This allows you to further improve your audience targeting and protect your investments.",
      "pos": [
        2220,
        2308
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Protection &amp; Privacy across the Globe",
      "pos": [
        2312,
        2354
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft has a longstanding commitment to privacy, which is an integral part of our product and service lifecycle.",
      "pos": [
        2356,
        2471
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We work to be transparent in our privacy practices, offering customers meaningful privacy choices, and manage responsibly of the data we store.",
      "pos": [
        2472,
        2615
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As with all Azure services, Mobile Engagement does not share or sell information derived from customers’ property.",
      "pos": [
        2616,
        2730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement is a globally deployable solution, allowing for regional or country specific data privacy laws to be upheld.",
      "pos": [
        2731,
        2863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps:",
      "pos": [
        2868,
        2879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting Started (Marketers)",
      "pos": [
        2882,
        2909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting Started (Developers)",
      "pos": [
        2975,
        3003
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        3052,
        3056
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Mobile Engagement Overview\" \n    description=\"Overview of Azure Mobile Engagement\"\n    services=\"mobile-engagement\" \n    documentationCenter=\"mobile\" \n    authors=\"piyushjo\" \n    manager=\"dwrede\" \n    editor=\"\" />\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"mobile-engagement\" \n    ms.workload=\"mobile\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"mobile-multiple\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"07/28/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"piyushjo\" />\n\n#Azure Mobile Engagement Overview\n\nAzure Mobile Engagement is a SaaS-delivered, data-driven user engagement platform that enables real-time fine-grain user segmentation, app user analytics, and contextually-aware smart push notifications and in-app messaging across all connected devices.\n\n###Overview video\n> [AZURE.VIDEO azure-mobile-engagement-overview]\n\nWith Azure Mobile Engagement, app publishers and marketing professionals can create cutting-edge interactions.\n\n##Real time actionable analytics to increase app usage\n\nTrigger engagement scenarios according to app user behavior and demographics by combining Big Data collection with real time processing. Azure Mobile Engagement can answer nearly any question relevant to your particular business needs. For example, you can create custom dashboards to measure KPIs, rapidly find and fix usage bottlenecks in the user path, track retention and stickiness, and by that determine what campaigns are driving the highest ROI. Azure Mobile Engagement’s 360° user path view, allows you to easily and continually enhance and optimize the user experience – driving higher retention rates and increased app usage.\n\n##Value added push and communications platform\n\nAzure Mobile Engagement works flawlessly with native push notifications gateways such as Google’s GCM, Apple’s APNS or Microsoft MPNS, but it goes beyond and gives you the power to create targeted campaigns , by providing intelligent customer segments and in-app messaging capabilities.\n\nThis benefits app developers by reaching their customers in a highly effective and non-intrusive manner.\n\n##Open APIs and ease of integration\n\nBy providing open APIs and ease of integration you can leverage existing data from CRM, CMS and other business related systems. This allows you to further improve your audience targeting and protect your investments.\n\n##Data Protection & Privacy across the Globe\n\nMicrosoft has a longstanding commitment to privacy, which is an integral part of our product and service lifecycle. We work to be transparent in our privacy practices, offering customers meaningful privacy choices, and manage responsibly of the data we store. As with all Azure services, Mobile Engagement does not share or sell information derived from customers’ property. Azure Mobile Engagement is a globally deployable solution, allowing for regional or country specific data privacy laws to be upheld.\n\n###Next Steps:\n\n[Getting Started (Marketers)](mobile-engagement-define-your-mobile-engagement-strategy.md) \n\n[Getting Started (Developers)](/documentation/services/mobile-engagement/)\n \n\ntest\n"
}