{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager",
      "pos": [
        28,
        78
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use Azure PowerShell to deploy multiple resources as a resource group to Azure.",
      "pos": [
        98,
        177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager",
      "pos": [
        520,
        570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[AZURE.SELECTOR]",
      "pos": [
        574,
        590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        594,
        610
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure CLI",
      "pos": [
        653,
        662
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Resource Manager introduces an entirely new way of thinking about your Azure resources.",
      "pos": [
        702,
        795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instead of creating and managing individual resources, you begin by imagining a complex service, such as a blog, a photo gallery, a SharePoint portal, or a wiki.",
      "pos": [
        796,
        957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You use a template -- a resource model of the service --  to create a resource group with the resources that you need to support the service.",
      "pos": [
        958,
        1099
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then, you can manage and deploy that resource group as a logical unit.",
      "pos": [
        1100,
        1170
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this tutorial, you learn how to use Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager for Microsoft Azure.",
      "pos": [
        1173,
        1277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It walks you through the process of creating and deploying a resource group for an Azure-hosted web app with a SQL database, complete with all of the resources that you need to support it.",
      "pos": [
        1278,
        1466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Prerequisites",
      "pos": [
        1471,
        1484
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To complete this tutorial, you must have Azure PowerShell version 0.8.0 or later.",
      "pos": [
        1486,
        1567
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To install the latest version and associate it with your Azure subscription, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to install and configure Azure PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](powershell-install-configure.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1568,
        1730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tutorial is designed for PowerShell beginners, but it assumes that you understand the basic concepts, such as modules, cmdlets, and sessions.",
      "pos": [
        1732,
        1878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about Windows PowerShell, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Getting Started with Windows PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh857337.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1879,
        2024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get detailed help for any cmdlet that you see in this tutorial, use the Get-Help cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        2026,
        2117
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, to get help for the Add-AzureAccount cmdlet, type:",
      "pos": [
        2158,
        2221
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "About the Azure PowerShell Modules",
      "pos": [
        2267,
        2301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Beginning in version 0.8.0, the Azure PowerShell installation includes more than one PowerShell module.",
      "pos": [
        2302,
        2405
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must explicitly decide whether to use the commands that are available in the Azure module or the Azure Resource Manager module.",
      "pos": [
        2406,
        2537
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To make it easy to switch between them, we have added a new cmdlet, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Switch-AzureMode<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, to the Azure Profile module.",
      "pos": [
        2538,
        2656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you use Azure PowerShell, the cmdlets in the Azure module are imported by default.",
      "pos": [
        2658,
        2745
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To switch to the Azure Resource Manager module, use the Switch-AzureMode cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        2746,
        2826
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It removes the Azure module from your session and imports the Azure Resource Manager and Azure Profile modules.",
      "pos": [
        2827,
        2938
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To switch to the AzureResoureManager module, type:",
      "pos": [
        2940,
        2990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To switch back to the Azure module, type:",
      "pos": [
        3049,
        3090
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default, Switch-AzureMode affects only the current session.",
      "pos": [
        3151,
        3213
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To make the switch effective in all PowerShell sessions, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Global<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter of Switch-AzureMode.",
      "pos": [
        3214,
        3320
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3322,
        3472
      ],
      "content": "For help with the Switch-AzureMode cmdlet, type: <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-Help Switch-AzureMode`</ph> or see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Switch-AzureMode<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=394398)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "To get a list of cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module with a help synopsis, type:",
      "pos": [
        3476,
        3563
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The output will look similar to the following excerpt:",
      "pos": [
        3661,
        3715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get full help for a cmdlet, type a command with the format:",
      "pos": [
        4196,
        4258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example,",
      "pos": [
        4294,
        4306
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4347,
        4484
      ],
      "content": "For the full set of Azure Resource Manager commands, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Resource Manager Cmdlets<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=394765)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a resource group",
      "pos": [
        4492,
        4515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This section of the tutorial guides you through the process of creating and deploying a resource group for a web app with a SQL database.",
      "pos": [
        4517,
        4654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You don't need to be an expert in Azure, SQL, web apps, or resource management to do this task.",
      "pos": [
        4657,
        4752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The templates provide a model of the resource group with all of the resources that you're likely to need.",
      "pos": [
        4753,
        4858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "And because we're using Windows PowerShell to automate the tasks, you can use these process as a model for scripting large-scale tasks.",
      "pos": [
        4859,
        4994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 1: Switch to Azure Resource Manager",
      "pos": [
        5000,
        5040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Start PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        5045,
        5062
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use any host program that you like, such as the Azure PowerShell console or Windows PowerShell ISE.",
      "pos": [
        5063,
        5170
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5175,
        5286
      ],
      "content": "Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Switch-AzureMode<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet to import the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager and AzureProfile modules."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5347,
        5444
      ],
      "content": "To add your Azure account to the Windows PowerShell session, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add-AzureAccount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet."
    },
    {
      "content": "The cmdlet prompts you for the login credentials for your Azure account.",
      "pos": [
        5481,
        5553
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After logging in, it downloads your account settings so they are available to Windows PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        5554,
        5651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The account settings expire, so you need to refresh them occasionally.",
      "pos": [
        5654,
        5724
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To refresh the account settings, run <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add-AzureAccount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> again.",
      "pos": [
        5725,
        5789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> The AzureResourceManager module requires Add-AzureAccount.",
      "pos": [
        5793,
        5864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A Publish Settings file is not sufficient.",
      "pos": [
        5865,
        5907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 2: Select a gallery template",
      "pos": [
        5918,
        5951
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are several ways to create a resource group and its resources, but the easiest way  is to use a resource group template.",
      "pos": [
        5953,
        6079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>resource group template<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> is JSON string that defines the resources in a resource group.",
      "pos": [
        6080,
        6170
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The string includes placeholders called \"parameters\" for user-defined values, like names and sizes.",
      "pos": [
        6171,
        6270
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure hosts a gallery of resource group templates and you can create your own templates, either from scratch or by editing a gallery template.",
      "pos": [
        6272,
        6414
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this tutorial, we'll use a gallery template.",
      "pos": [
        6415,
        6462
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To see all of the templates in the Azure resource group template gallery, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-AzureResourceGroupGalleryTemplate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet; however, this command returns a large number of templates.",
      "pos": [
        6465,
        6655
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To see a more manageable number of templates, specify a publisher parameter.",
      "pos": [
        6656,
        6732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At the Powershell prompt, type:",
      "pos": [
        6735,
        6766
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cmdlet returns a list of gallery templates with Microsoft as the publisher.",
      "pos": [
        6844,
        6923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Identity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property to identify the template in the commands.",
      "pos": [
        6924,
        6999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview template looks interesting.",
      "pos": [
        7001,
        7075
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you run the command, the version of the template may be slightly different because a new version has been released.",
      "pos": [
        7076,
        7196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the latest version of the template.",
      "pos": [
        7197,
        7236
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get more information about a gallery template, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Identity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter.",
      "pos": [
        7237,
        7318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The value of the Identity parameter is Identity of the template.",
      "pos": [
        7319,
        7383
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cmdlet returns an object with much more information about the template, including a summary and description.",
      "pos": [
        7489,
        7601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This template looks like it will meet our needs.",
      "pos": [
        7603,
        7651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let's save it to disk and look at it more closely.",
      "pos": [
        7652,
        7702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 3: Examine the Template",
      "pos": [
        7708,
        7736
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let's save the template to a JSON file on disk.",
      "pos": [
        7738,
        7785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This step is not required, but it makes it easier to view the template.",
      "pos": [
        7786,
        7857
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To save the template, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save-AzureResourceGroupGalleryTemplate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        7858,
        7938
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use its <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Identity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter to specify the template and the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Path<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> parameter to specify a path on disk.",
      "pos": [
        7939,
        8047
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Save-AzureResourceGroupGalleryTemplate saves the template and returns the path a file name of the JSON template file.",
      "pos": [
        8049,
        8166
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can view the template file in a text editor, such as Notepad.",
      "pos": [
        8402,
        8467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each template has a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section and a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>resources<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> section.",
      "pos": [
        8468,
        8539
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of the template is a collection of the parameters that are defined in all of the resources.",
      "pos": [
        8541,
        8659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It includes property values you can provide when setting up your resource group.",
      "pos": [
        8660,
        8740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some parameters have a default value.",
      "pos": [
        8952,
        8989
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you use the template, you are not required to supply values for these parameters.",
      "pos": [
        8990,
        9076
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not specify a value, the default value is used.",
      "pos": [
        9077,
        9134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When parameters have enumerated values, the valid values are listed with the parameter.",
      "pos": [
        9241,
        9328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sku<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter can take values of Free, Shared, Basic, or Standard.",
      "pos": [
        9329,
        9416
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don't specify a value for the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sku<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter, it uses the default value, Free.",
      "pos": [
        9417,
        9505
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>administratorLoginPassword<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter uses a secure string, not plain text.",
      "pos": [
        9686,
        9778
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you provide a value for a secure string, the value is obscured.",
      "pos": [
        9779,
        9847
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>resources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of the template lists the resources that the template creates.",
      "pos": [
        9923,
        10011
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This template creates a SQL database server and SQL database, a server farm and website, and several management settings.",
      "pos": [
        10012,
        10133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The definition of each resource includes its properties, such as name, type and location, and parameters for user-defined values.",
      "pos": [
        10137,
        10266
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, this section of the template defines the SQL database.",
      "pos": [
        10267,
        10334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It includes parameters for the database name ([parameters('databaseName')]), the database server location [parameters('serverLocation')], and the collation property [parameters('collation')].",
      "pos": [
        10335,
        10526
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We're almost ready to use the template, but before we do, we need to find locations for each of the resources.",
      "pos": [
        11089,
        11199
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 4: Get resource type locations",
      "pos": [
        11205,
        11240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Most templates ask you to specify a location for each of the resources in a resource group.",
      "pos": [
        11242,
        11333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Every resource is located in an Azure data center, but not every Azure data center supports every resource type.",
      "pos": [
        11334,
        11446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select any location that supports the resource type.",
      "pos": [
        11449,
        11501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You do not have to create all of the resources in a resource group in the same location; however, whenever possible, you will want to create resources in the same location to optimize performance.",
      "pos": [
        11502,
        11698
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In particular, you will want to make sure that your database is in the same location as the app accessing it.",
      "pos": [
        11699,
        11808
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get the locations that support each resource type, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-AzureLocation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        11811,
        11902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To limit your output to a specific type of of resource, such as ResourceGroup, use:",
      "pos": [
        11903,
        11986
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The output will look similar to:",
      "pos": [
        12094,
        12126
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Now, we have the information that we need to create the resource group.",
      "pos": [
        12486,
        12557
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 5: Create a resource group",
      "pos": [
        12563,
        12594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this step, we'll use the resource group template to create the resource group.",
      "pos": [
        12597,
        12678
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For reference, open the New_WebSite_And_Database.json file on disk and follow along.",
      "pos": [
        12679,
        12763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The template file can be very helpful for determining parameter values to pass, such as the correct ApiVersion for a resource.",
      "pos": [
        12764,
        12890
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12892,
        12962
      ],
      "content": "To create a resource group, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New-AzureResourceGroup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet."
    },
    {
      "content": "The command uses the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter to specify a name for the resource group and the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Location<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> parameter to specify its location.",
      "pos": [
        12964,
        13100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the output of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-AzureLocation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to select a location for the resource group.",
      "pos": [
        13101,
        13185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It uses the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GalleryTemplateIdentity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter to specify the gallery template.",
      "pos": [
        13186,
        13268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As soon as you type the template name, New-AzureResourceGroup fetches the template, parses it, and adds the template parameters to the command dynamically.",
      "pos": [
        13427,
        13582
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This makes it very easy to specify the template parameter values.",
      "pos": [
        13583,
        13648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "And, if you forget a required parameter value, Windows PowerShell prompts you for the value.",
      "pos": [
        13649,
        13741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Dynamic Template Parameters",
      "pos": [
        13745,
        13772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To get the parameters, type a minus sign (-) to indicate a parameter name and then press the TAB key.",
      "pos": [
        13776,
        13877
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Or, type the first few letters of a parameter name, such as siteName and then press the TAB key.",
      "pos": [
        13878,
        13974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerShell completes the parameter name.",
      "pos": [
        14126,
        14166
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To cycle through the parameter names, press TAB repeatedly.",
      "pos": [
        14167,
        14226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enter a name for the website and repeat the TAB process for each of the parameters.",
      "pos": [
        14379,
        14462
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The parameters with a default value are optional.",
      "pos": [
        14463,
        14512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To accept the default value, omit the parameter from the command.",
      "pos": [
        14513,
        14578
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a template parameter has enumerated values, such as the sku parameter in this template, to cycle through the parameter values, press the TAB key.",
      "pos": [
        14581,
        14731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example of a New-AzureResourceGroup command that specifies only the required template parameters and the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Verbose<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> common parameter.",
      "pos": [
        15252,
        15397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>administratorLoginPassword<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is omitted.",
      "pos": [
        15398,
        15454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you enter the command, you are prompted for the missing mandatory parameter, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>administratorLoginPassword<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        15775,
        15888
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "And, when you type the password, the secure string value is obscured.",
      "pos": [
        15889,
        15958
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This strategy eliminates the risk of providing a password in plain text.",
      "pos": [
        15959,
        16031
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16214,
        16297
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New-AzureResourceGroup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> returns the resource group that it created and deployed."
    },
    {
      "content": "In just a few steps, we created and deployed the resources required for a complex website.",
      "pos": [
        16300,
        16390
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The gallery template provided almost all of the information that we needed to do this task.",
      "pos": [
        16392,
        16483
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "And, the task is easily automated.",
      "pos": [
        16484,
        16518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get information about your resource groups",
      "pos": [
        16524,
        16566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After creating a resource group, you can use the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module to manage your resource groups.",
      "pos": [
        16568,
        16691
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16695,
        16793
      ],
      "content": "To get all of the resource groups in your subscription, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-AzureResourceGroup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet:"
    },
    {
      "content": "To get the resources in the resource group, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-AzureResource<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet and its ResourceGroupName parameter.",
      "pos": [
        17097,
        17214
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Without parameters, Get-AzureResource gets all resources in your Azure subscription.",
      "pos": [
        17215,
        17299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Add to a resource group",
      "pos": [
        18408,
        18431
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To add a resource to the resource group, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New-AzureResource<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        18435,
        18513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command adds a new website to the TestRG resource group.",
      "pos": [
        18514,
        18575
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command is a bit more complex, because it does not use a template.",
      "pos": [
        18576,
        18647
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        18901,
        19016
      ],
      "content": "To add a new template-based deployment to the resource group, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New-AzureResourceGroupDeployment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> command."
    },
    {
      "content": "Move a resource",
      "pos": [
        19283,
        19298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can move existing resources to a new resource group.",
      "pos": [
        19300,
        19356
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For examples, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Move Resources to New Resource Group or Subscription<ept id=\"p1\">](resource-group-move-resources.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        19357,
        19464
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete a resource group",
      "pos": [
        19469,
        19492
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To delete a resource from the resource group, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Remove-AzureResource<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        19496,
        19582
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This cmdlet deletes the resource, but does not delete the resource group.",
      "pos": [
        19583,
        19656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command removes the TestSite2 website from the TestRG resource group.",
      "pos": [
        19662,
        19736
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To delete a resource group, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Remove-AzureResourceGroup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        19871,
        19944
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This cmdlet deletes the resource group and its resources.",
      "pos": [
        19945,
        20002
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Troubleshoot a resource group",
      "pos": [
        20227,
        20256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As you experiment with the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager modules, you are likely to encounter errors.",
      "pos": [
        20257,
        20364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the tips in this section to resolve them.",
      "pos": [
        20365,
        20410
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Preventing errors",
      "pos": [
        20416,
        20433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The AzureResourceManager module includes cmdlets that help you to prevent errors.",
      "pos": [
        20435,
        20516
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-AzureLocation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: This cmdlet gets the locations that support each type of resource.",
      "pos": [
        20521,
        20610
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before you enter a location for a resource, use this cmdlet to verify that the location supports the resource type.",
      "pos": [
        20611,
        20726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Test-AzureResourceGroupTemplate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: Test your template and template parameter before you use them.",
      "pos": [
        20731,
        20830
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enter a custom or gallery template and the template parameter values you plan to use.",
      "pos": [
        20831,
        20916
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This cmdlet tests whether the template is internally consistent and whether your parameter value set matches the template.",
      "pos": [
        20917,
        21039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Fixing errors",
      "pos": [
        21048,
        21061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-AzureResourceGroupLog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: This cmdlet gets the entries in the log for each  deployment of the resource group.",
      "pos": [
        21065,
        21179
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If something goes wrong, begin by examining the deployment logs.",
      "pos": [
        21180,
        21244
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Verbose and Debug<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:  The cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module call REST APIs that do the actual work.",
      "pos": [
        21249,
        21359
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To see the messages that the APIs return, set the $DebugPreference variable to \"Continue\" and use the Verbose common parameter in your commands.",
      "pos": [
        21360,
        21504
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The messages often provide vital clues about the cause of any failures.",
      "pos": [
        21505,
        21576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Your Azure credentials have not been set up or have expired<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:  To refresh the credentials in your Windows PowerShell session, use the Add-AzureAccount cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        21580,
        21741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The credentials in a publish settings file are not sufficient for the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module.",
      "pos": [
        21742,
        21855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        21861,
        21871
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        21875,
        22017
      ],
      "content": "To learn about creating Resource Manager templates, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Authoring Azure Resource Manager Templates<ept id=\"p1\">](./resource-group-authoring-templates.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        22020,
        22158
      ],
      "content": "To learn about deploying templates, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Deploy an application with Azure Resource Manager Template<ept id=\"p1\">](./resource-group-template-deploy.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        22161,
        22327
      ],
      "content": "For a detailed example of deploying a project, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Deploy microservices predictably in Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-web/app-service-deploy-complex-application-predictably.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        22330,
        22334
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager\" \n    description=\"Use Azure PowerShell to deploy multiple resources as a resource group to Azure.\" \n    services=\"azure-resource-manager\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"tfitzmac\" \n    manager=\"wpickett\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"azure-resource-manager\" \n    ms.workload=\"multiple\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"powershell\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"07/15/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"tomfitz\"/>\n\n# Using Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager\n\n> [AZURE.SELECTOR]\n- [Azure PowerShell](powershell-azure-resource-manager.md)\n- [Azure CLI](xplat-cli-azure-resource-manager.md)\n\nAzure Resource Manager introduces an entirely new way of thinking about your Azure resources. Instead of creating and managing individual resources, you begin by imagining a complex service, such as a blog, a photo gallery, a SharePoint portal, or a wiki. You use a template -- a resource model of the service --  to create a resource group with the resources that you need to support the service. Then, you can manage and deploy that resource group as a logical unit. \n\nIn this tutorial, you learn how to use Azure PowerShell with Azure Resource Manager for Microsoft Azure. It walks you through the process of creating and deploying a resource group for an Azure-hosted web app with a SQL database, complete with all of the resources that you need to support it.\n\n## Prerequisites\n\nTo complete this tutorial, you must have Azure PowerShell version 0.8.0 or later. To install the latest version and associate it with your Azure subscription, see [How to install and configure Azure PowerShell](powershell-install-configure.md).\n\nThis tutorial is designed for PowerShell beginners, but it assumes that you understand the basic concepts, such as modules, cmdlets, and sessions. For more information about Windows PowerShell, see [Getting Started with Windows PowerShell](http://technet.microsoft.com/library/hh857337.aspx).\n\nTo get detailed help for any cmdlet that you see in this tutorial, use the Get-Help cmdlet. \n\n    Get-Help <cmdlet-name> -Detailed\n\nFor example, to get help for the Add-AzureAccount cmdlet, type:\n\n    Get-Help Add-AzureAccount -Detailed\n\n## About the Azure PowerShell Modules\nBeginning in version 0.8.0, the Azure PowerShell installation includes more than one PowerShell module. You must explicitly decide whether to use the commands that are available in the Azure module or the Azure Resource Manager module. To make it easy to switch between them, we have added a new cmdlet, **Switch-AzureMode**, to the Azure Profile module.\n\nWhen you use Azure PowerShell, the cmdlets in the Azure module are imported by default. To switch to the Azure Resource Manager module, use the Switch-AzureMode cmdlet. It removes the Azure module from your session and imports the Azure Resource Manager and Azure Profile modules.\n\nTo switch to the AzureResoureManager module, type:\n\n    PS C:\\> Switch-AzureMode -Name AzureResourceManager\n\nTo switch back to the Azure module, type:\n\n    PS C:\\> Switch-AzureMode -Name AzureServiceManagement\n\nBy default, Switch-AzureMode affects only the current session. To make the switch effective in all PowerShell sessions, use the **Global** parameter of Switch-AzureMode.\n\nFor help with the Switch-AzureMode cmdlet, type: `Get-Help Switch-AzureMode` or see [Switch-AzureMode](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=394398).\n  \nTo get a list of cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module with a help synopsis, type: \n\n    PS C:\\> Get-Command -Module AzureResourceManager | Get-Help | Format-Table Name, Synopsis\n\nThe output will look similar to the following excerpt:\n\n    Name                                   Synopsis\n    ----                                   --------\n    Add-AlertRule                          Adds or updates an alert rule of either metric, event, o...\n    Add-AzureAccount                       Adds the Azure account to Windows PowerShell\n    Add-AzureEnvironment                   Creates an Azure environment\n    Add-AzureKeyVaultKey                   Creates a key in a vault or imports a key into a vault.\n        ...\n\nTo get full help for a cmdlet, type a command with the format:\n\n    Get-Help <cmdlet-name> -Full\n\nFor example, \n\n    Get-Help Get-AzureLocation -Full\n\nFor the full set of Azure Resource Manager commands, see [Azure Resource Manager Cmdlets](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=394765). \n  \n## Create a resource group\n\nThis section of the tutorial guides you through the process of creating and deploying a resource group for a web app with a SQL database. \n\nYou don't need to be an expert in Azure, SQL, web apps, or resource management to do this task. The templates provide a model of the resource group with all of the resources that you're likely to need. And because we're using Windows PowerShell to automate the tasks, you can use these process as a model for scripting large-scale tasks.\n\n### Step 1: Switch to Azure Resource Manager \n1. Start PowerShell. You can use any host program that you like, such as the Azure PowerShell console or Windows PowerShell ISE.\n\n2. Use the **Switch-AzureMode** cmdlet to import the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager and AzureProfile modules. \n\n        PS C:\\> Switch-AzureMode AzureResourceManager\n\n3. To add your Azure account to the Windows PowerShell session, use the **Add-AzureAccount** cmdlet. \n\n        PS C:\\> Add-AzureAccount\n\nThe cmdlet prompts you for the login credentials for your Azure account. After logging in, it downloads your account settings so they are available to Windows PowerShell. \n\nThe account settings expire, so you need to refresh them occasionally. To refresh the account settings, run **Add-AzureAccount** again. \n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] The AzureResourceManager module requires Add-AzureAccount. A Publish Settings file is not sufficient.     \n\n### Step 2: Select a gallery template\n\nThere are several ways to create a resource group and its resources, but the easiest way  is to use a resource group template. A *resource group template* is JSON string that defines the resources in a resource group. The string includes placeholders called \"parameters\" for user-defined values, like names and sizes.\n\nAzure hosts a gallery of resource group templates and you can create your own templates, either from scratch or by editing a gallery template. In this tutorial, we'll use a gallery template. \n\nTo see all of the templates in the Azure resource group template gallery, use the **Get-AzureResourceGroupGalleryTemplate** cmdlet; however, this command returns a large number of templates. To see a more manageable number of templates, specify a publisher parameter. \n\nAt the Powershell prompt, type:\n    \n    PS C:\\> Get-AzureResourceGroupGalleryTemplate -Publisher Microsoft\n\nThe cmdlet returns a list of gallery templates with Microsoft as the publisher. You use the **Identity** property to identify the template in the commands.\n\nThe Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview template looks interesting. When you run the command, the version of the template may be slightly different because a new version has been released. Use the latest version of the template. To get more information about a gallery template, use the **Identity** parameter. The value of the Identity parameter is Identity of the template.\n\n    PS C:\\> Get-AzureResourceGroupGalleryTemplate -Identity Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview\n\nThe cmdlet returns an object with much more information about the template, including a summary and description.\n\nThis template looks like it will meet our needs. Let's save it to disk and look at it more closely.\n\n### Step 3: Examine the Template\n\nLet's save the template to a JSON file on disk. This step is not required, but it makes it easier to view the template. To save the template, use the **Save-AzureResourceGroupGalleryTemplate** cmdlet. Use its **Identity** parameter to specify the template and the **Path** parameter to specify a path on disk.\n\nSave-AzureResourceGroupGalleryTemplate saves the template and returns the path a file name of the JSON template file. \n\n    PS C:\\> Save-AzureResourceGroupGalleryTemplate -Identity Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview -Path C:\\Azure\\Templates\\New_WebSite_And_Database.json\n\n    Path\n    ----\n    C:\\Azure\\Templates\\New_WebSite_And_Database.json\n\n\nYou can view the template file in a text editor, such as Notepad. Each template has a **parameters** section and a **resources** section.\n\nThe **parameters** section of the template is a collection of the parameters that are defined in all of the resources. It includes property values you can provide when setting up your resource group.\n\n    \"parameters\": {\n      \"siteName\": {\n        \"type\": \"string\"\n      },\n      \"hostingPlanName\": {\n        \"type\": \"string\"\n      },\n      \"siteLocation\": {\n        \"type\": \"string\"\n      },\n      ...\n    }\n\nSome parameters have a default value. When you use the template, you are not required to supply values for these parameters. If you do not specify a value, the default value is used. \n\n    \"collation\": {\n      \"type\": \"string\",\n      \"defaultValue\": \"SQL_Latin1_General_CP1_CI_AS\"\n    },\n\nWhen parameters have enumerated values, the valid values are listed with the parameter. For example, the **sku** parameter can take values of Free, Shared, Basic, or Standard. If you don't specify a value for the **sku** parameter, it uses the default value, Free.\n\n    \"sku\": {\n      \"type\": \"string\",\n      \"allowedValues\": [\n        \"Free\",\n        \"Shared\",\n        \"Basic\",\n        \"Standard\"\n      ],\n      \"defaultValue\": \"Free\"\n    },\n\n\nNote that the **administratorLoginPassword** parameter uses a secure string, not plain text. When you provide a value for a secure string, the value is obscured. \n\n    \"administratorLoginPassword\": {\n      \"type\": \"securestring\"\n    },\n\nThe **resources** section of the template lists the resources that the template creates. This template creates a SQL database server and SQL database, a server farm and website, and several management settings.\n  \nThe definition of each resource includes its properties, such as name, type and location, and parameters for user-defined values. For example, this section of the template defines the SQL database. It includes parameters for the database name ([parameters('databaseName')]), the database server location [parameters('serverLocation')], and the collation property [parameters('collation')].\n\n    {\n        \"name\": \"[parameters('databaseName')]\",\n        \"type\": \"databases\",\n        \"location\": \"[parameters('serverLocation')]\",\n        \"apiVersion\": \"2.0\",\n        \"dependsOn\": [\n          \"[concat('Microsoft.Sql/servers/', parameters('serverName'))]\"\n        ],\n        \"properties\": {\n          \"edition\": \"[parameters('edition')]\",\n          \"collation\": \"[parameters('collation')]\",\n          \"maxSizeBytes\": \"[parameters('maxSizeBytes')]\",\n          \"requestedServiceObjectiveId\": \"[parameters('requestedServiceObjectiveId')]\"\n        }\n    },\n\n\nWe're almost ready to use the template, but before we do, we need to find locations for each of the resources.\n\n### Step 4: Get resource type locations\n\nMost templates ask you to specify a location for each of the resources in a resource group. Every resource is located in an Azure data center, but not every Azure data center supports every resource type. \n\nSelect any location that supports the resource type. You do not have to create all of the resources in a resource group in the same location; however, whenever possible, you will want to create resources in the same location to optimize performance. In particular, you will want to make sure that your database is in the same location as the app accessing it. \n\nTo get the locations that support each resource type, use the **Get-AzureLocation** cmdlet. To limit your output to a specific type of of resource, such as ResourceGroup, use:\n\n    Get-AzureLocation | Where-Object Name -eq \"ResourceGroup\" | Format-Table Name, LocationsString -Wrap\n\nThe output will look similar to:\n\n    Name                                 LocationsString\n    ----                                 ---------------\n    ResourceGroup                        East Asia, South East Asia, East US, West US, North\n                                         Central US, South Central US, Central US, North Europe,\n                                         West Europe\n\nNow, we have the information that we need to create the resource group.\n\n### Step 5: Create a resource group\n \nIn this step, we'll use the resource group template to create the resource group. For reference, open the New_WebSite_And_Database.json file on disk and follow along. The template file can be very helpful for determining parameter values to pass, such as the correct ApiVersion for a resource.\n\nTo create a resource group, use the **New-AzureResourceGroup** cmdlet.\n\nThe command uses the **Name** parameter to specify a name for the resource group and the **Location** parameter to specify its location. Use the output of **Get-AzureLocation** to select a location for the resource group. It uses the **GalleryTemplateIdentity** parameter to specify the gallery template.\n\n    PS C:\\> New-AzureResourceGroup -Name TestRG1 -Location \"East Asia\" -GalleryTemplateIdentity Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview\n            ....\n\nAs soon as you type the template name, New-AzureResourceGroup fetches the template, parses it, and adds the template parameters to the command dynamically. This makes it very easy to specify the template parameter values. And, if you forget a required parameter value, Windows PowerShell prompts you for the value.\n\n**Dynamic Template Parameters**\n\nTo get the parameters, type a minus sign (-) to indicate a parameter name and then press the TAB key. Or, type the first few letters of a parameter name, such as siteName and then press the TAB key. \n\n    PS C:\\> New-AzureResourceGroup -Name TestRG1 -Location \"East Asia\" -GalleryTemplateIdentity Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview -si<TAB>\n\nPowerShell completes the parameter name. To cycle through the parameter names, press TAB repeatedly.\n\n    PS C:\\> New-AzureResourceGroup -Name TestRG1 -Location \"East Asia\" -GalleryTemplateIdentity Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview -siteName \n\nEnter a name for the website and repeat the TAB process for each of the parameters. The parameters with a default value are optional. To accept the default value, omit the parameter from the command. \n\nWhen a template parameter has enumerated values, such as the sku parameter in this template, to cycle through the parameter values, press the TAB key.\n\n    PS C:\\> New-AzureResourceGroup -Name TestRG1 -Location \"East Asia\" -GalleryTemplateIdentity Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview -siteName TestSite -sku <TAB>\n\n    PS C:\\> New-AzureResourceGroup -Name TestRG1 -Location \"East Asia\" -GalleryTemplateIdentity Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview -siteName TestSite -sku Basic<TAB>\n\n    PS C:\\> New-AzureResourceGroup -Name TestRG1 -Location \"East Asia\" -GalleryTemplateIdentity Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview -siteName TestSite -sku Free<TAB>\n\nHere is an example of a New-AzureResourceGroup command that specifies only the required template parameters and the **Verbose** common parameter. Note that the **administratorLoginPassword** is omitted.\n\n    PS C:\\> New-AzureResourceGroup -Name TestRG -Location \"East Asia\" -GalleryTemplateIdentity Microsoft.WebSiteSQLDatabase.0.2.6-preview -siteName TestSite -hostingPlanName TestPlan -siteLocation \"East Asia\" -serverName testserver -serverLocation \"East Asia\" -administratorLogin Admin01 -databaseName TestDB -Verbose\n\nWhen you enter the command, you are prompted for the missing mandatory parameter, **administratorLoginPassword**. And, when you type the password, the secure string value is obscured. This strategy eliminates the risk of providing a password in plain text.\n\n    cmdlet New-AzureResourceGroup at command pipeline position 1\n    Supply values for the following parameters:\n    (Type !? for Help.)\n    administratorLoginPassword: **********\n\n**New-AzureResourceGroup** returns the resource group that it created and deployed. \n\nIn just a few steps, we created and deployed the resources required for a complex website. \nThe gallery template provided almost all of the information that we needed to do this task.\nAnd, the task is easily automated. \n\n## Get information about your resource groups\n\nAfter creating a resource group, you can use the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module to manage your resource groups.\n\n- To get all of the resource groups in your subscription, use the **Get-AzureResourceGroup** cmdlet:\n\n        PS C:>Get-AzureResourceGroup\n\n        ResourceGroupName : TestRG\n        Location          : eastasia\n        ProvisioningState : Succeeded\n        Tags              :\n        ResourceId        : /subscriptions/xxxxxxxx-xxxx-xxxx-xxxx-xxxxxxxxxxxx/resourceGroups/TestRG\n        \n        ...\n\n- To get the resources in the resource group, use the **Get-AzureResource** cmdlet and its ResourceGroupName parameter. Without parameters, Get-AzureResource gets all resources in your Azure subscription.\n\n        PS C:\\> Get-AzureResource -ResourceGroupName TestRG\n        \n        ResourceGroupName : TestRG\n        Location          : eastasia\n        ProvisioningState : Succeeded\n        Tags              :\n        \n        Resources         :\n                Name                   Type                          Location\n                ----                   ------------                  --------\n                ServerErrors-TestSite  microsoft.insights/alertrules         eastasia\n                TestPlan-TestRG        microsoft.insights/autoscalesettings  eastus\n                TestSite               microsoft.insights/components         centralus\n                testserver             Microsoft.Sql/servers                 eastasia\n                TestDB                 Microsoft.Sql/servers/databases       eastasia\n                TestPlan               Microsoft.Web/serverFarms             eastasia\n                TestSite               Microsoft.Web/sites                   eastasia\n        ResourceId        : /subscriptions/xxxxxxxx-xxxx-xxxx-xxxx-xxxxxxxxxxxx/resourceGroups/TestRG\n\n## Add to a resource group\n\n- To add a resource to the resource group, use the **New-AzureResource** cmdlet. This command adds a new website to the TestRG resource group. This command is a bit more complex, because it does not use a template. \n\n        PS C:\\>New-AzureResource -Name TestSite2 -Location \"North Europe\" -ResourceGroupName TestRG -ResourceType \"Microsoft.Web/sites\" -ApiVersion 2014-06-01 -PropertyObject @{\"name\" = \"TestSite2\"; \"siteMode\"= \"Limited\"; \"computeMode\" = \"Shared\"}\n\n- To add a new template-based deployment to the resource group, use the **New-AzureResourceGroupDeployment** command. \n\n        PS C:\\>New-AzureResourceGroupDeployment ` \n        -ResourceGroupName TestRG `\n        -GalleryTemplateIdentity Microsoft.WebSite.0.2.6-preview `\n        -siteName TestWeb2 `\n        -hostingPlanName TestDeploy2 `\n        -siteLocation \"North Europe\" \n\n## Move a resource\n\nYou can move existing resources to a new resource group. For examples, see [Move Resources to New Resource Group or Subscription](resource-group-move-resources.md).\n\n## Delete a resource group\n\n- To delete a resource from the resource group, use the **Remove-AzureResource** cmdlet. This cmdlet deletes the resource, but does not delete the resource group.\n\n    This command removes the TestSite2 website from the TestRG resource group.\n\n        Remove-AzureResource -Name TestSite2 -ResourceGroupName TestRG -ResourceType \"Microsoft.Web/sites\" -ApiVersion 2014-06-01\n\n- To delete a resource group, use the **Remove-AzureResourceGroup** cmdlet. This cmdlet deletes the resource group and its resources.\n\n        PS C:\\ps-test> Remove-AzureResourceGroup -Name TestRG\n        \n        Confirm\n        Are you sure you want to remove resource group 'TestRG'\n        [Y] Yes  [N] No  [S] Suspend  [?] Help (default is \"Y\"): Y\n\n\n## Troubleshoot a resource group\nAs you experiment with the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager modules, you are likely to encounter errors. Use the tips in this section to resolve them.\n\n### Preventing errors\n\nThe AzureResourceManager module includes cmdlets that help you to prevent errors.\n\n\n- **Get-AzureLocation**: This cmdlet gets the locations that support each type of resource. Before you enter a location for a resource, use this cmdlet to verify that the location supports the resource type.\n\n\n- **Test-AzureResourceGroupTemplate**: Test your template and template parameter before you use them. Enter a custom or gallery template and the template parameter values you plan to use. This cmdlet tests whether the template is internally consistent and whether your parameter value set matches the template. \n\n\n\n### Fixing errors\n\n- **Get-AzureResourceGroupLog**: This cmdlet gets the entries in the log for each  deployment of the resource group. If something goes wrong, begin by examining the deployment logs. \n\n- **Verbose and Debug**:  The cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module call REST APIs that do the actual work. To see the messages that the APIs return, set the $DebugPreference variable to \"Continue\" and use the Verbose common parameter in your commands. The messages often provide vital clues about the cause of any failures.\n\n- **Your Azure credentials have not been set up or have expired**:  To refresh the credentials in your Windows PowerShell session, use the Add-AzureAccount cmdlet. The credentials in a publish settings file are not sufficient for the cmdlets in the AzureResourceManager module.\n\n\n## Next Steps\n\n- To learn about creating Resource Manager templates, see [Authoring Azure Resource Manager Templates](./resource-group-authoring-templates.md).\n- To learn about deploying templates, see [Deploy an application with Azure Resource Manager Template](./resource-group-template-deploy.md).\n- For a detailed example of deploying a project, see [Deploy microservices predictably in Azure](app-service-web/app-service-deploy-complex-application-predictably.md).\n\n\ntest\n"
}