{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Secure a database in SQL Data Warehouse | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        83
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tips for securing a database in Azure SQL Data Warehouse for developing solutions.",
      "pos": [
        101,
        183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Secure a database in SQL Data Warehouse",
      "pos": [
        491,
        530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article walks through the basics of securing your Azure SQL Data Warehouse database.",
      "pos": [
        532,
        621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In particular, this articles will get you started with resources for limiting access, protecting data, and monitoring activities on a database.",
      "pos": [
        622,
        765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connection security",
      "pos": [
        770,
        789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connection Security refers to how you restrict and secure connections to your database using firewall rules and connection encryption.",
      "pos": [
        791,
        925
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Firewall rules are used by both the server and the database to reject connection attempts from IP addresses that have not been explicitly whitelisted.",
      "pos": [
        927,
        1077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To allow your application or client machine's public IP address to attempt connecting to a new database, you must first create a server-level firewall rule using the Azure Management Portal, REST API, or PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        1078,
        1293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a best practice, you should restrict the IP address ranges allowed through your server firewall as much as possible.",
      "pos": [
        1294,
        1413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see [Azure SQL Database firewall][].",
      "pos": [
        1414,
        1472
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authentication",
      "pos": [
        1478,
        1492
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authentication refers to how you prove your identity when connecting to the database.",
      "pos": [
        1494,
        1579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Data Warehouse currently supports SQL Authentication with a username and password.",
      "pos": [
        1580,
        1666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you created the logical server for your database, you specified a \"server admin\" login with a username and password.",
      "pos": [
        1668,
        1789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using these credentials, you can authenticate to any database on that server as the database owner, or \"dbo.\"",
      "pos": [
        1790,
        1899
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, as a best practice your organization’s users should use a different account to authenticate -- this way you can limit the permissions granted to the application and reduce the risks of malicious activity in case your application code is vulnerable to a SQL injection attack.",
      "pos": [
        1901,
        2184
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The recommended approach is to create a contained database user, which allows your app to authenticate directly to a single database with a username and password.",
      "pos": [
        2185,
        2347
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can create a contained database user by executing the following T-SQL while connected to your user database with your server admin login:",
      "pos": [
        2348,
        2489
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information on authenticating to a SQL Database, see [Managing databases and logins in Azure SQL Database][].",
      "pos": [
        2563,
        2681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authorization",
      "pos": [
        2687,
        2700
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authorization refers to what you can do within an Azure SQL Data Warehouse database, and this is controlled by your user account's role memberships and permissions.",
      "pos": [
        2702,
        2866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a best practice, you should grant users the least privileges necessary.",
      "pos": [
        2867,
        2941
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure SQL Data Warehouse makes this easy to manage with roles in T-SQL:",
      "pos": [
        2942,
        3013
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The server admin account you are connecting with is a member of db_owner, which has authority to do anything within the database.",
      "pos": [
        3209,
        3338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Save this account for deploying schema upgrades and other management operations.",
      "pos": [
        3339,
        3419
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the \"ApplicationUser\" account with more limited permissions to connect from your application to the database with the least privileges needed by your application.",
      "pos": [
        3420,
        3586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are ways to further limit what a user can do with Azure SQL Database:",
      "pos": [
        3588,
        3663
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Database roles][] other than db_datareader and db_datawriter can be used to create more powerful application user accounts or less powerful management accounts.",
      "pos": [
        3666,
        3827
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Granular [Permissions][] let you control which operations you can do on individual columns, tables, views, procedures, and other objects in the database.",
      "pos": [
        3830,
        3983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Stored procedures][] can be used to limit the actions that can be taken on the database.",
      "pos": [
        3986,
        4075
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Managing databases and logical servers from the Azure Management Portal or using the Azure Resource Manager API is controlled by your portal user account's role assignments.",
      "pos": [
        4077,
        4250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information on this topic, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Role-based access control in Azure preview portal<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4251,
        4345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Encryption",
      "pos": [
        4352,
        4362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure SQL Data Warehouse can help protect your data by encrypting your data when it is \"at rest,\" or stored in database files and backups, using [Transparent Data Encryption][].",
      "pos": [
        4364,
        4541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To encrypt your database, connect as a database owner and execute:",
      "pos": [
        4542,
        4608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also enable Transparent Data Encryption from database settings in the [Azure Portal][].",
      "pos": [
        4673,
        4768
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Auditing",
      "pos": [
        4775,
        4783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Auditing and tracking database events can help you maintain regulatory compliance and identify suspicious activity.",
      "pos": [
        4785,
        4900
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Data Warehouse Auditing allows you to record events in your database to an audit log in your Azure Storage account.",
      "pos": [
        4901,
        5020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Data Warehouse Auditing also integrates with Microsoft Power BI to facilitate drill-down reports and analyses.",
      "pos": [
        5021,
        5135
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see [Get started with SQL Database Auditing][].",
      "pos": [
        5136,
        5205
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        5212,
        5222
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5223,
        5279
      ],
      "content": "For more development tips, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>development overview<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Secure a database in SQL Data Warehouse | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"Tips for securing a database in Azure SQL Data Warehouse for developing solutions.\"\n   services=\"sql-data-warehouse\"\n   documentationCenter=\"NA\"\n   authors=\"sahaj08\"\n   manager=\"barbkess\"\n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"sql-data-warehouse\"\n   ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"data-services\"\n   ms.date=\"06/22/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"sahajs\"/>\n\n# Secure a database in SQL Data Warehouse\n\nThis article walks through the basics of securing your Azure SQL Data Warehouse database. In particular, this articles will get you started with resources for limiting access, protecting data, and monitoring activities on a database.\n\n## Connection security\n\nConnection Security refers to how you restrict and secure connections to your database using firewall rules and connection encryption.\n\nFirewall rules are used by both the server and the database to reject connection attempts from IP addresses that have not been explicitly whitelisted. To allow your application or client machine's public IP address to attempt connecting to a new database, you must first create a server-level firewall rule using the Azure Management Portal, REST API, or PowerShell. As a best practice, you should restrict the IP address ranges allowed through your server firewall as much as possible. For more information, see [Azure SQL Database firewall][].\n\n\n## Authentication\n\nAuthentication refers to how you prove your identity when connecting to the database. SQL Data Warehouse currently supports SQL Authentication with a username and password.\n\nWhen you created the logical server for your database, you specified a \"server admin\" login with a username and password. Using these credentials, you can authenticate to any database on that server as the database owner, or \"dbo.\"\n\nHowever, as a best practice your organization’s users should use a different account to authenticate -- this way you can limit the permissions granted to the application and reduce the risks of malicious activity in case your application code is vulnerable to a SQL injection attack. The recommended approach is to create a contained database user, which allows your app to authenticate directly to a single database with a username and password. You can create a contained database user by executing the following T-SQL while connected to your user database with your server admin login:\n\n```\nCREATE USER ApplicationUser WITH PASSWORD = 'strong_password';\n```\n\nFor more information on authenticating to a SQL Database, see [Managing databases and logins in Azure SQL Database][].\n\n\n## Authorization\n\nAuthorization refers to what you can do within an Azure SQL Data Warehouse database, and this is controlled by your user account's role memberships and permissions. As a best practice, you should grant users the least privileges necessary. Azure SQL Data Warehouse makes this easy to manage with roles in T-SQL:\n\n```\nALTER ROLE db_datareader ADD MEMBER ApplicationUser; -- allows ApplicationUser to read data\nALTER ROLE db_datawriter ADD MEMBER ApplicationUser; -- allows ApplicationUser to write data\n```\n\nThe server admin account you are connecting with is a member of db_owner, which has authority to do anything within the database. Save this account for deploying schema upgrades and other management operations. Use the \"ApplicationUser\" account with more limited permissions to connect from your application to the database with the least privileges needed by your application.\n\nThere are ways to further limit what a user can do with Azure SQL Database:\n- [Database roles][] other than db_datareader and db_datawriter can be used to create more powerful application user accounts or less powerful management accounts.\n- Granular [Permissions][] let you control which operations you can do on individual columns, tables, views, procedures, and other objects in the database.\n- [Stored procedures][] can be used to limit the actions that can be taken on the database.\n\nManaging databases and logical servers from the Azure Management Portal or using the Azure Resource Manager API is controlled by your portal user account's role assignments. For more information on this topic, see [Role-based access control in Azure preview portal][].\n\n\n\n## Encryption\n\nAzure SQL Data Warehouse can help protect your data by encrypting your data when it is \"at rest,\" or stored in database files and backups, using [Transparent Data Encryption][]. To encrypt your database, connect as a database owner and execute:\n\n\n```\n\nALTER DATABASE [AdventureWorks] SET ENCRYPTION ON;\n\n```\n\nYou can also enable Transparent Data Encryption from database settings in the [Azure Portal][].\n\n\n\n## Auditing\n\nAuditing and tracking database events can help you maintain regulatory compliance and identify suspicious activity. SQL Data Warehouse Auditing allows you to record events in your database to an audit log in your Azure Storage account. SQL Data Warehouse Auditing also integrates with Microsoft Power BI to facilitate drill-down reports and analyses. For more information, see [Get started with SQL Database Auditing][].\n\n\n\n## Next steps\nFor more development tips, see [development overview][].\n\n<!--Image references-->\n\n<!--Article references-->\n[development overview]: sql-data-warehouse-overview-develop.md\n\n\n<!--MSDN references-->\n[Azure SQL Database firewall]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ee621782.aspx\n[Database roles]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ms189121.aspx\n[Managing databases and logins in Azure SQL Database]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ee336235.aspx\n[Permissions]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ms191291.aspx\n[Stored procedures]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/ms190782.aspx \n[Transparent Data Encryption]: http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=526242\n[Get started with SQL Database Auditing]: sql-database-auditing-get-started.md\n[Azure Portal]: https://portal.azure.com/\n\n<!--Other Web references-->\n[Role-based access control in Azure preview portal]: http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/articles/role-based-access-control-configure.aspx\n"
}