{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Site Recovery: Performance and scaling testing: On-premises to on-premises",
      "pos": [
        27,
        107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article discusses the testing of the performance impact of replication using Azure Site Recovery in an on-premises to on-premises deployment.",
      "pos": [
        126,
        272
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Performance and scaling testing: On-premises to on-premises",
      "pos": [
        607,
        666
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Azure Site Recovery orchestrates and manages replication of your primary data center to a second location so that your data is backed up and recoverable in the case of planned and unplanned outages.",
      "pos": [
        668,
        876
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can backup up on-premises private clouds located on System Center Virtual Machine Manager (VMM) to another on-premises location, or to Microsoft Azure storage.",
      "pos": [
        877,
        1040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To perform the replication, VMM uses Hyper-V Replica, a replication mechanism that is built into Hyper-V in Windows Server 2012 and Windows Server 2012 R2.",
      "pos": [
        1041,
        1196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It provides asynchronous replication of Hyper-V virtual machines between two hosting servers.",
      "pos": [
        1197,
        1290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any server workload that can be virtualized in Hyper-V can be replicated.",
      "pos": [
        1291,
        1364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replication works over any ordinary IP-based network Hyper-V Replica works with standalone servers, failover clusters, or a mixture of both.",
      "pos": [
        1365,
        1505
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic discusses the testing of the performance impact of replication using Azure Site Recovery in an on-premises to on-premises deployment.",
      "pos": [
        1507,
        1651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It provides detailed information about the parameters and configuration settings used in the test, shows the test deployment step, and provided detailed test results.",
      "pos": [
        1652,
        1818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test goals",
      "pos": [
        1823,
        1833
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The goal is to examine how Azure Site Recovery performs during steady state replication.",
      "pos": [
        1835,
        1923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Steady state replication occurs when virtual machines have completed initial replication and are synchronizing delta changes.",
      "pos": [
        1924,
        2049
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It’s important to measure performance using steady state because it’s the state in which most virtual machines remain unless unexpected outages occur.",
      "pos": [
        2050,
        2200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Running the test deployment",
      "pos": [
        2205,
        2232
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The test deployment consisted of two on-premises sites with a VMM server in each.",
      "pos": [
        2234,
        2315
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both VMM servers are registered in an Azure Site Recovery vault.",
      "pos": [
        2316,
        2380
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This test deployment is typical of a head office/branch office deployment, with head office acting as the primary site and the branch office as the secondary or recovery site.",
      "pos": [
        2381,
        2556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test deployment steps",
      "pos": [
        2562,
        2583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Created virtual machines using VMM templates.",
      "pos": [
        2588,
        2633
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Started virtual machines and capture baseline performance metrics over 12 hours.",
      "pos": [
        2638,
        2718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Created clouds on primary and recovery VMM servers.",
      "pos": [
        2723,
        2774
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configured cloud protection in Azure Site Recovery, including mapping of source and recovery clouds.",
      "pos": [
        2779,
        2879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enabled protection for virtual machines and allow them to complete initial replication.",
      "pos": [
        2884,
        2971
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Waited a couple of hours for system stabilization.",
      "pos": [
        2976,
        3026
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Captured performance metrics over 12 hours, ensuring that all virtual machines remained in an expected replication state for those 12 hours.",
      "pos": [
        3031,
        3171
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Measure the delta between the baseline performance metrics and the replication performance metrics.",
      "pos": [
        3176,
        3275
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test deployment results",
      "pos": [
        3280,
        3303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary server performance",
      "pos": [
        3309,
        3335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V Replica asynchronously tracks changes to a log file with minimum storage overhead on the primary server.",
      "pos": [
        3339,
        3451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V Replica utilizes self-maintained memory cache to minimize IOPS overhead for tracking.",
      "pos": [
        3455,
        3548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It stores writes to the VHDX in memory and flushes them into the log file before the time that the log is sent to the recovery site.",
      "pos": [
        3549,
        3681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A disk flush also happens if the writes hit a predetermined limit.",
      "pos": [
        3682,
        3748
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The graph below shows the steady state IOPS overhead for replication.",
      "pos": [
        3752,
        3821
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We can see that the IOPS overhead due to replication is around 5% which is quite low.",
      "pos": [
        3822,
        3907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary results",
      "pos": [
        3911,
        3926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V Replica utilizes memory on the primary server to optimize disk performance.",
      "pos": [
        4024,
        4107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As shown in the following graph, memory overhead on all servers in the primary cluster is marginal.",
      "pos": [
        4108,
        4207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The memory overhead shown is the percentage of memory used by replication compared to the total installed memory on the Hyper-V server.",
      "pos": [
        4208,
        4343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary results",
      "pos": [
        4347,
        4362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V Replica has minimum CPU overhead.",
      "pos": [
        4460,
        4501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As shown in the graph, replication overhead is in the range of 2-3%.",
      "pos": [
        4502,
        4570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary results",
      "pos": [
        4574,
        4589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Secondary (recovery) server performance",
      "pos": [
        4691,
        4730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V Replica uses a small amount of memory on the recovery server to optimize the number of storage operations.",
      "pos": [
        4732,
        4846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The graph summarizes the memory usage on the recovery server.",
      "pos": [
        4847,
        4908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The memory overhead shown is the percentage of memory used by replication compared to the total installed memory on the Hyper-V server.",
      "pos": [
        4909,
        5044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Secondary results",
      "pos": [
        5048,
        5065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The amount of I/O operations on the recovery site is a function of the number of write operations on the primary site.",
      "pos": [
        5163,
        5281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let’s look at the total I/O operations on the recovery site in comparison with the total I/O operations and write operations on the primary site.",
      "pos": [
        5282,
        5427
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The graphs show that the total IOPS on the recovery site is",
      "pos": [
        5428,
        5487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Around 1.5 times the write IOPS on the primary.",
      "pos": [
        5491,
        5538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Around 37% of the total IOPS on the primary site.",
      "pos": [
        5542,
        5591
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Secondary results",
      "pos": [
        5595,
        5612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Secondary results",
      "pos": [
        5712,
        5729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Effect of replication on network utilization",
      "pos": [
        5831,
        5875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An average of 275 MB per second of network bandwidth was used between the primary and recovery nodes (with compression enabled) against an existing bandwidth of 5 GB per second.",
      "pos": [
        5877,
        6054
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Results network utilization",
      "pos": [
        6058,
        6085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Effect of replication on virtual machine performance",
      "pos": [
        6187,
        6239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An important consideration is the impact of replication on production workloads running on the virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        6241,
        6353
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the primary site is adequately provisioned for replication, there shouldn’t be any impact on the workloads.",
      "pos": [
        6354,
        6464
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V Replica’s lightweight tracking mechanism ensures that workloads running in the virtual machines are not impacted during steady-state replication.",
      "pos": [
        6465,
        6618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is illustrated in the following graphs.",
      "pos": [
        6619,
        6663
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This graph shows IOPS performed by virtual machines running different workloads before and after replication was enabled.",
      "pos": [
        6665,
        6786
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can observe that there is no difference between the two.",
      "pos": [
        6787,
        6847
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replica effect results",
      "pos": [
        6851,
        6873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following graph shows the throughput of virtual machines running different workloads before and after replication was enabled.",
      "pos": [
        6971,
        7101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can observe that replication has no significant impact.",
      "pos": [
        7102,
        7161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Results replica effects",
      "pos": [
        7165,
        7188
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Conclusion",
      "pos": [
        7290,
        7300
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The results clearly show that Azure Site Recovery, coupled with Hyper-V Replica, scales well with minimum overhead for a large cluster.",
      "pos": [
        7302,
        7437
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Site Recovery provides simple deployment, replication, management and monitoring.",
      "pos": [
        7439,
        7526
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V Replica provides the necessary infrastructure for successful replication scaling.",
      "pos": [
        7527,
        7616
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For planning an optimum deployment we suggest you download the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Hyper-V Replica Capacity Planner<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=39057)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        7617,
        7779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test deployment environment",
      "pos": [
        7784,
        7811
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary site",
      "pos": [
        7817,
        7829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The primary site has a cluster containing five Hyper-V servers running 470 virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        7833,
        7925
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The virtual machines run different workloads, and all have Azure Site Recovery protection enabled.",
      "pos": [
        7929,
        8027
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage for the cluster node is provided by an iSCSI SAN.",
      "pos": [
        8031,
        8088
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Model – Hitachi HUS130.",
      "pos": [
        8089,
        8112
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each cluster server has four network cards (NICs) of one Gbps each.",
      "pos": [
        8116,
        8183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Two of the network cards are connected to an iSCSI private network and two are connected to an external enterprise network.",
      "pos": [
        8187,
        8310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One of the external networks is reserved for cluster communications only.",
      "pos": [
        8311,
        8384
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary hardware requirements",
      "pos": [
        8388,
        8417
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server",
      "pos": [
        8516,
        8522
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RAM",
      "pos": [
        8523,
        8526
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Model",
      "pos": [
        8527,
        8532
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Processor",
      "pos": [
        8533,
        8542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Number of processors",
      "pos": [
        8543,
        8563
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "NIC",
      "pos": [
        8564,
        8567
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Software",
      "pos": [
        8568,
        8576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V servers in cluster:",
      "pos": [
        8609,
        8636
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST11",
      "pos": [
        8643,
        8656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST12",
      "pos": [
        8662,
        8675
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST13",
      "pos": [
        8681,
        8694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST14",
      "pos": [
        8700,
        8713
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST25",
      "pos": [
        8719,
        8732
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "128ESTLAB-HOST25 has 256",
      "pos": [
        8733,
        8757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Dell ™ PowerEdge ™ R820",
      "pos": [
        8758,
        8781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-4620 0 @ 2.20GHz",
      "pos": [
        8782,
        8822
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4",
      "pos": [
        8823,
        8824
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "I Gbps x 4",
      "pos": [
        8825,
        8835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server Datacenter 2012 R2 (x64) + Hyper-V role",
      "pos": [
        8836,
        8890
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VMM Server",
      "pos": [
        8893,
        8903
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        8904,
        8905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        8908,
        8909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1 Gbps",
      "pos": [
        8910,
        8916
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server Database 2012 R2 (x64) + VMM 2012 R2",
      "pos": [
        8917,
        8968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Secondary (recovery) site",
      "pos": [
        8975,
        9000
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The secondary site has a six-node failover cluster.",
      "pos": [
        9004,
        9055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage for the cluster node is provided by an iSCSI SAN.",
      "pos": [
        9059,
        9116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Model – Hitachi HUS130.",
      "pos": [
        9117,
        9140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary hardware specification",
      "pos": [
        9144,
        9174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server",
      "pos": [
        9273,
        9279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RAM",
      "pos": [
        9280,
        9283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Model",
      "pos": [
        9284,
        9289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Processor",
      "pos": [
        9290,
        9299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Number of processors",
      "pos": [
        9300,
        9320
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "NIC",
      "pos": [
        9321,
        9324
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Software",
      "pos": [
        9325,
        9333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hyper-V servers in cluster:",
      "pos": [
        9366,
        9393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST07",
      "pos": [
        9400,
        9413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST08",
      "pos": [
        9419,
        9432
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST09",
      "pos": [
        9438,
        9451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST10",
      "pos": [
        9457,
        9470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "96",
      "pos": [
        9471,
        9473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Dell ™ PowerEdge ™ R720",
      "pos": [
        9474,
        9497
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-2630 0 @ 2.30GHz",
      "pos": [
        9498,
        9538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        9539,
        9540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "I Gbps x 4",
      "pos": [
        9541,
        9551
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server Datacenter 2012 R2 (x64) + Hyper-V role",
      "pos": [
        9552,
        9606
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST17",
      "pos": [
        9609,
        9622
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "128",
      "pos": [
        9623,
        9626
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Dell ™ PowerEdge ™ R820",
      "pos": [
        9627,
        9650
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-4620 0 @ 2.20GHz",
      "pos": [
        9651,
        9691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4",
      "pos": [
        9692,
        9693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server Datacenter 2012 R2 (x64) + Hyper-V role",
      "pos": [
        9695,
        9749
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ESTLAB-HOST24",
      "pos": [
        9752,
        9765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "256",
      "pos": [
        9766,
        9769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Dell ™ PowerEdge ™ R820",
      "pos": [
        9770,
        9793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-4620 0 @ 2.20GHz",
      "pos": [
        9794,
        9834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        9835,
        9836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server Datacenter 2012 R2 (x64) + Hyper-V role",
      "pos": [
        9838,
        9892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VMM Server",
      "pos": [
        9895,
        9905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        9906,
        9907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        9910,
        9911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1 Gbps",
      "pos": [
        9912,
        9918
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows Server Database 2012 R2 (x64) + VMM 2012 R2",
      "pos": [
        9919,
        9970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server workloads",
      "pos": [
        9977,
        9993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For test purposes we picked workloads commonly used in enterprise customer scenarios.",
      "pos": [
        9997,
        10082
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10086,
        10199
      ],
      "content": "We use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>IOMeter<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.iometer.org)</ept> with the workload characteristic summarized in the table for simulation."
    },
    {
      "content": "All IOMeter profiles are set to write random bytes to simulate worst-case write patterns for workloads.",
      "pos": [
        10203,
        10306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Workload",
      "pos": [
        10309,
        10317
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "I/O size (KB)",
      "pos": [
        10318,
        10331
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "% Access",
      "pos": [
        10332,
        10340
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "%Read",
      "pos": [
        10341,
        10346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Outstanding I/Os",
      "pos": [
        10347,
        10363
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "I/O pattern",
      "pos": [
        10364,
        10375
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "File Server",
      "pos": [
        10404,
        10415
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "48163264",
      "pos": [
        10416,
        10424
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "60%20%5%5%10%",
      "pos": [
        10425,
        10438
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "80%80%80%80%80%",
      "pos": [
        10439,
        10454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "88888",
      "pos": [
        10455,
        10460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All 100% random",
      "pos": [
        10461,
        10476
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Server (volume 1)SQL Server (volume 2)",
      "pos": [
        10479,
        10521
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "864",
      "pos": [
        10522,
        10525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100%100%",
      "pos": [
        10526,
        10534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "70%0%",
      "pos": [
        10535,
        10540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "88",
      "pos": [
        10541,
        10543
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100% random100% sequential",
      "pos": [
        10544,
        10570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exchange",
      "pos": [
        10573,
        10581
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "32",
      "pos": [
        10582,
        10584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100%",
      "pos": [
        10585,
        10589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "67%",
      "pos": [
        10590,
        10593
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "8",
      "pos": [
        10594,
        10595
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100% random",
      "pos": [
        10596,
        10607
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Workstation/VDI",
      "pos": [
        10610,
        10625
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "464",
      "pos": [
        10626,
        10629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "66%34%",
      "pos": [
        10630,
        10636
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "70%95%",
      "pos": [
        10637,
        10643
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "11",
      "pos": [
        10644,
        10646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both 100% random",
      "pos": [
        10647,
        10663
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Web File Server",
      "pos": [
        10666,
        10681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4864",
      "pos": [
        10682,
        10686
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "33%34%33%",
      "pos": [
        10687,
        10696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "95%95%95%",
      "pos": [
        10697,
        10706
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "888",
      "pos": [
        10707,
        10710
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All 75% random",
      "pos": [
        10711,
        10725
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual machine configuration",
      "pos": [
        10732,
        10761
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "470 virtual machines on the primary cluster.",
      "pos": [
        10765,
        10809
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All virtual machines with VHDX disk.",
      "pos": [
        10813,
        10849
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual machines running workloads summarized in the table.",
      "pos": [
        10853,
        10912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All were created with VMM templates.",
      "pos": [
        10913,
        10949
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Workload",
      "pos": [
        10952,
        10960
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VMs",
      "pos": [
        10963,
        10966
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Minimum RAM (GB)",
      "pos": [
        10967,
        10983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Maximum RAM (GB)",
      "pos": [
        10984,
        11000
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Logical disk size (GB) per VM",
      "pos": [
        11001,
        11030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Maximum IOPS",
      "pos": [
        11031,
        11043
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Server",
      "pos": [
        11072,
        11082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "51",
      "pos": [
        11083,
        11085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        11086,
        11087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4",
      "pos": [
        11088,
        11089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "167",
      "pos": [
        11090,
        11093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "10",
      "pos": [
        11094,
        11096
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exchange Server",
      "pos": [
        11099,
        11114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "71",
      "pos": [
        11115,
        11117
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        11118,
        11119
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4",
      "pos": [
        11120,
        11121
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "552",
      "pos": [
        11122,
        11125
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "10",
      "pos": [
        11126,
        11128
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "File Server",
      "pos": [
        11131,
        11142
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "50",
      "pos": [
        11143,
        11145
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        11146,
        11147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        11148,
        11149
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "552",
      "pos": [
        11150,
        11153
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "22",
      "pos": [
        11154,
        11156
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VDI",
      "pos": [
        11159,
        11162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "149",
      "pos": [
        11163,
        11166
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ".5",
      "pos": [
        11167,
        11169
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        11170,
        11171
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "80",
      "pos": [
        11172,
        11174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "6",
      "pos": [
        11175,
        11176
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Web server",
      "pos": [
        11179,
        11189
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "149",
      "pos": [
        11190,
        11193
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ".5",
      "pos": [
        11194,
        11196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        11197,
        11198
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "80",
      "pos": [
        11199,
        11201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "6",
      "pos": [
        11202,
        11203
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "TOTAL",
      "pos": [
        11206,
        11211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "470",
      "pos": [
        11212,
        11215
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "96.83 TB",
      "pos": [
        11218,
        11226
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4108",
      "pos": [
        11227,
        11231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Site Recovery settings",
      "pos": [
        11238,
        11266
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Site Recovery was configured for on-premises to on-premises protection",
      "pos": [
        11270,
        11346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The VMM server has four clouds configured, containing the Hyper-V cluster servers and their virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        11350,
        11459
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Primary VMM cloud",
      "pos": [
        11462,
        11479
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Protected virtual machines in the cloud",
      "pos": [
        11480,
        11519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replication frequency",
      "pos": [
        11520,
        11541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additional recovery points",
      "pos": [
        11542,
        11568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PrimaryCloudRpo15m",
      "pos": [
        11589,
        11607
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "142",
      "pos": [
        11608,
        11611
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "15 mins",
      "pos": [
        11612,
        11619
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "None",
      "pos": [
        11620,
        11624
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PrimaryCloudRpo30s",
      "pos": [
        11627,
        11645
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "47",
      "pos": [
        11646,
        11648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "30 secs",
      "pos": [
        11649,
        11656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "None",
      "pos": [
        11657,
        11661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PrimaryCloudRpo30sArp1",
      "pos": [
        11664,
        11686
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "47",
      "pos": [
        11687,
        11689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "30 secs",
      "pos": [
        11690,
        11697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        11698,
        11699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PrimaryCloudRpo5m",
      "pos": [
        11702,
        11719
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "235",
      "pos": [
        11720,
        11723
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "5 mins",
      "pos": [
        11724,
        11730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "None",
      "pos": [
        11731,
        11735
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Performance metrics",
      "pos": [
        11742,
        11761
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The table summarizes the performance metrics and counters that were measured in the deployment.",
      "pos": [
        11763,
        11858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Metric",
      "pos": [
        11861,
        11867
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Counter",
      "pos": [
        11868,
        11875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CPU",
      "pos": [
        11888,
        11891
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\Processor(_Total)\\% Processor Time",
      "pos": [
        11892,
        11927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Available memory",
      "pos": [
        11930,
        11946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\Memory\\Available MBytes",
      "pos": [
        11947,
        11971
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "IOPS",
      "pos": [
        11974,
        11978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\PhysicalDisk(_Total)\\Disk Transfers/sec",
      "pos": [
        11979,
        12019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM read (IOPS) operations/sec",
      "pos": [
        12022,
        12051
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\Hyper-V Virtual Storage Device(",
      "pos": [
        12052,
        12084
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ")\\Read Operations/Sec",
      "pos": [
        12089,
        12110
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM write (IOPS) operations/sec",
      "pos": [
        12113,
        12143
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\Hyper-V Virtual Storage Device(",
      "pos": [
        12144,
        12176
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ")\\Write Operations/S",
      "pos": [
        12181,
        12201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM read throughput",
      "pos": [
        12204,
        12222
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\Hyper-V Virtual Storage Device(",
      "pos": [
        12223,
        12255
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ")\\Read Bytes/sec",
      "pos": [
        12260,
        12276
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "VM write throughput",
      "pos": [
        12279,
        12298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "\\Hyper-V Virtual Storage Device(",
      "pos": [
        12299,
        12331
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ")\\Write Bytes/sec",
      "pos": [
        12336,
        12353
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        12360,
        12370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To start deploying ASR:",
      "pos": [
        12372,
        12395
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up protection between an on-premises VMM site and Azure",
      "pos": [
        12400,
        12459
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up protection between an on-premises Hyper-V site and Azure",
      "pos": [
        12495,
        12558
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up protection between two on-premises VMM sites",
      "pos": [
        12603,
        12654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up protection between two on-premises VMM sites with SAN",
      "pos": [
        12688,
        12748
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set up protection with a single VMM server",
      "pos": [
        12779,
        12821
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Azure Site Recovery: Performance and scaling testing: On-premises to on-premises\"\n    description=\"This article discusses the testing of the performance impact of replication using Azure Site Recovery in an on-premises to on-premises deployment.\"\n    services=\"site-recovery\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"csilauraa\"\n    manager=\"jwhit\"\n    editor=\"tysonn\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"site-recovery\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"get-started-article\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.workload=\"storage-backup-recovery\"\n    ms.date=\"08/05/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"lauraa\"/>\n\n# Performance and scaling testing: On-premises to on-premises\n\nMicrosoft Azure Site Recovery orchestrates and manages replication of your primary data center to a second location so that your data is backed up and recoverable in the case of planned and unplanned outages. You can backup up on-premises private clouds located on System Center Virtual Machine Manager (VMM) to another on-premises location, or to Microsoft Azure storage. To perform the replication, VMM uses Hyper-V Replica, a replication mechanism that is built into Hyper-V in Windows Server 2012 and Windows Server 2012 R2. It provides asynchronous replication of Hyper-V virtual machines between two hosting servers. Any server workload that can be virtualized in Hyper-V can be replicated. Replication works over any ordinary IP-based network Hyper-V Replica works with standalone servers, failover clusters, or a mixture of both.\n\nThis topic discusses the testing of the performance impact of replication using Azure Site Recovery in an on-premises to on-premises deployment. It provides detailed information about the parameters and configuration settings used in the test, shows the test deployment step, and provided detailed test results.\n\n## Test goals\n\nThe goal is to examine how Azure Site Recovery performs during steady state replication. Steady state replication occurs when virtual machines have completed initial replication and are synchronizing delta changes. It’s important to measure performance using steady state because it’s the state in which most virtual machines remain unless unexpected outages occur.\n\n## Running the test deployment\n\nThe test deployment consisted of two on-premises sites with a VMM server in each. Both VMM servers are registered in an Azure Site Recovery vault. This test deployment is typical of a head office/branch office deployment, with head office acting as the primary site and the branch office as the secondary or recovery site.\n\n### Test deployment steps\n\n1. Created virtual machines using VMM templates.\n\n1. Started virtual machines and capture baseline performance metrics over 12 hours.\n\n1. Created clouds on primary and recovery VMM servers.\n\n1. Configured cloud protection in Azure Site Recovery, including mapping of source and recovery clouds.\n\n1. Enabled protection for virtual machines and allow them to complete initial replication.\n\n1. Waited a couple of hours for system stabilization.\n\n1. Captured performance metrics over 12 hours, ensuring that all virtual machines remained in an expected replication state for those 12 hours.\n\n1. Measure the delta between the baseline performance metrics and the replication performance metrics.\n\n## Test deployment results\n\n### Primary server performance\n\n- Hyper-V Replica asynchronously tracks changes to a log file with minimum storage overhead on the primary server.\n\n- Hyper-V Replica utilizes self-maintained memory cache to minimize IOPS overhead for tracking. It stores writes to the VHDX in memory and flushes them into the log file before the time that the log is sent to the recovery site. A disk flush also happens if the writes hit a predetermined limit.\n\n- The graph below shows the steady state IOPS overhead for replication. We can see that the IOPS overhead due to replication is around 5% which is quite low.\n\n![Primary results](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744913.png)\n\nHyper-V Replica utilizes memory on the primary server to optimize disk performance. As shown in the following graph, memory overhead on all servers in the primary cluster is marginal. The memory overhead shown is the percentage of memory used by replication compared to the total installed memory on the Hyper-V server.\n\n![Primary results](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744914.png)\n\nHyper-V Replica has minimum CPU overhead. As shown in the graph, replication overhead is in the range of 2-3%.\n\n![Primary results](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744915.png)\n\n### Secondary (recovery) server performance\n\nHyper-V Replica uses a small amount of memory on the recovery server to optimize the number of storage operations. The graph summarizes the memory usage on the recovery server. The memory overhead shown is the percentage of memory used by replication compared to the total installed memory on the Hyper-V server.\n\n![Secondary results](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744916.png)\n\nThe amount of I/O operations on the recovery site is a function of the number of write operations on the primary site. Let’s look at the total I/O operations on the recovery site in comparison with the total I/O operations and write operations on the primary site. The graphs show that the total IOPS on the recovery site is\n\n- Around 1.5 times the write IOPS on the primary.\n\n- Around 37% of the total IOPS on the primary site.\n\n![Secondary results](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744917.png)\n\n![Secondary results](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744918.png)\n\n### Effect of replication on network utilization\n\nAn average of 275 MB per second of network bandwidth was used between the primary and recovery nodes (with compression enabled) against an existing bandwidth of 5 GB per second.\n\n![Results network utilization](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744919.png)\n\n### Effect of replication on virtual machine performance\n\nAn important consideration is the impact of replication on production workloads running on the virtual machines. If the primary site is adequately provisioned for replication, there shouldn’t be any impact on the workloads. Hyper-V Replica’s lightweight tracking mechanism ensures that workloads running in the virtual machines are not impacted during steady-state replication. This is illustrated in the following graphs.\n\nThis graph shows IOPS performed by virtual machines running different workloads before and after replication was enabled. You can observe that there is no difference between the two.\n\n![Replica effect results](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744920.png)\n\nThe following graph shows the throughput of virtual machines running different workloads before and after replication was enabled. You can observe that replication has no significant impact.\n\n![Results replica effects](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744921.png)\n\n### Conclusion\n\nThe results clearly show that Azure Site Recovery, coupled with Hyper-V Replica, scales well with minimum overhead for a large cluster.  Azure Site Recovery provides simple deployment, replication, management and monitoring. Hyper-V Replica provides the necessary infrastructure for successful replication scaling. For planning an optimum deployment we suggest you download the [Hyper-V Replica Capacity Planner](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=39057).\n\n## Test deployment environment\n\n### Primary site\n\n- The primary site has a cluster containing five Hyper-V servers running 470 virtual machines.\n\n- The virtual machines run different workloads, and all have Azure Site Recovery protection enabled.\n\n- Storage for the cluster node is provided by an iSCSI SAN. Model – Hitachi HUS130.\n\n- Each cluster server has four network cards (NICs) of one Gbps each.\n\n- Two of the network cards are connected to an iSCSI private network and two are connected to an external enterprise network. One of the external networks is reserved for cluster communications only.\n\n![Primary hardware requirements](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744922.png)\n\n|Server|RAM|Model|Processor|Number of processors|NIC|Software|\n|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|\n|Hyper-V servers in cluster: <br />ESTLAB-HOST11<br />ESTLAB-HOST12<br />ESTLAB-HOST13<br />ESTLAB-HOST14<br />ESTLAB-HOST25|128ESTLAB-HOST25 has 256|Dell ™ PowerEdge ™ R820|Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-4620 0 @ 2.20GHz|4|I Gbps x 4|Windows Server Datacenter 2012 R2 (x64) + Hyper-V role|\n|VMM Server|2|||2|1 Gbps|Windows Server Database 2012 R2 (x64) + VMM 2012 R2|\n\n### Secondary (recovery) site\n\n- The secondary site has a six-node failover cluster.\n\n- Storage for the cluster node is provided by an iSCSI SAN. Model – Hitachi HUS130.\n\n![Primary hardware specification](./media/site-recovery-performance-and-scaling-testing-on-premises-to-on-premises/IC744923.png)\n\n|Server|RAM|Model|Processor|Number of processors|NIC|Software|\n|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|\n|Hyper-V servers in cluster: <br />ESTLAB-HOST07<br />ESTLAB-HOST08<br />ESTLAB-HOST09<br />ESTLAB-HOST10|96|Dell ™ PowerEdge ™ R720|Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-2630 0 @ 2.30GHz|2|I Gbps x 4|Windows Server Datacenter 2012 R2 (x64) + Hyper-V role|\n|ESTLAB-HOST17|128|Dell ™ PowerEdge ™ R820|Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-4620 0 @ 2.20GHz|4||Windows Server Datacenter 2012 R2 (x64) + Hyper-V role|\n|ESTLAB-HOST24|256|Dell ™ PowerEdge ™ R820|Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-4620 0 @ 2.20GHz|2||Windows Server Datacenter 2012 R2 (x64) + Hyper-V role|\n|VMM Server|2|||2|1 Gbps|Windows Server Database 2012 R2 (x64) + VMM 2012 R2|\n\n### Server workloads\n\n- For test purposes we picked workloads commonly used in enterprise customer scenarios.\n\n- We use [IOMeter](http://www.iometer.org) with the workload characteristic summarized in the table for simulation.\n\n- All IOMeter profiles are set to write random bytes to simulate worst-case write patterns for workloads.\n\n|Workload|I/O size (KB)|% Access|%Read|Outstanding I/Os|I/O pattern|\n|---|---|---|---|---|---|\n|File Server|48163264|60%20%5%5%10%|80%80%80%80%80%|88888|All 100% random|\n|SQL Server (volume 1)SQL Server (volume 2)|864|100%100%|70%0%|88|100% random100% sequential|\n|Exchange|32|100%|67%|8|100% random|\n|Workstation/VDI|464|66%34%|70%95%|11|Both 100% random|\n|Web File Server|4864|33%34%33%|95%95%95%|888|All 75% random|\n\n### Virtual machine configuration\n\n- 470 virtual machines on the primary cluster.\n\n- All virtual machines with VHDX disk.\n\n- Virtual machines running workloads summarized in the table. All were created with VMM templates.\n\n|Workload|# VMs|Minimum RAM (GB)|Maximum RAM (GB)|Logical disk size (GB) per VM|Maximum IOPS|\n|---|---|---|---|---|---|\n|SQL Server|51|1|4|167|10|\n|Exchange Server|71|1|4|552|10|\n|File Server|50|1|2|552|22|\n|VDI|149|.5|1|80|6|\n|Web server|149|.5|1|80|6|\n|TOTAL|470|||96.83 TB|4108|\n\n### Azure Site Recovery settings\n\n- Azure Site Recovery was configured for on-premises to on-premises protection\n\n- The VMM server has four clouds configured, containing the Hyper-V cluster servers and their virtual machines.\n\n|Primary VMM cloud|Protected virtual machines in the cloud|Replication frequency|Additional recovery points|\n|---|---|---|---|\n|PrimaryCloudRpo15m|142|15 mins|None|\n|PrimaryCloudRpo30s|47|30 secs|None|\n|PrimaryCloudRpo30sArp1|47|30 secs|1|\n|PrimaryCloudRpo5m|235|5 mins|None|\n\n### Performance metrics\n\nThe table summarizes the performance metrics and counters that were measured in the deployment.\n\n|Metric|Counter|\n|---|---|\n|CPU|\\Processor(_Total)\\% Processor Time|\n|Available memory|\\Memory\\Available MBytes|\n|IOPS|\\PhysicalDisk(_Total)\\Disk Transfers/sec|\n|VM read (IOPS) operations/sec|\\Hyper-V Virtual Storage Device(<VHD>)\\Read Operations/Sec|\n|VM write (IOPS) operations/sec|\\Hyper-V Virtual Storage Device(<VHD>)\\Write Operations/S|\n|VM read throughput|\\Hyper-V Virtual Storage Device(<VHD>)\\Read Bytes/sec|\n|VM write throughput|\\Hyper-V Virtual Storage Device(<VHD>)\\Write Bytes/sec|\n\n\n## Next steps\n\nTo start deploying ASR:\n\n- [Set up protection between an on-premises VMM site and Azure](site-recovery-vmm-to-azure.md)\n- [Set up protection between an on-premises Hyper-V site and Azure](site-recovery-hyper-v-site-to-azure.md)\n- [Set up protection between two on-premises VMM sites](site-recovery-vmm-to-vmm.md)\n- [Set up protection between two on-premises VMM sites with SAN](site-recovery-vmm-san.md)\n- [Set up protection with a single VMM server](site-recovery-single-vmm.md)\n "
}