{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Manage Azure Traffic Manager using Azure Automation",
      "pos": [
        25,
        76
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn about how the Azure Automation service can be used to manage Azure Traffic Manager.",
      "pos": [
        93,
        182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Managing Azure Traffic Manager using Azure Automation",
      "pos": [
        495,
        548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This guide will introduce you to the Azure Automation service, and how it can be used to simplify management of Azure Traffic Manager.",
      "pos": [
        550,
        684
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Azure Automation?",
      "pos": [
        689,
        714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Automation<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/services/automation/)</ept> is an Azure service for simplifying cloud management through process automation.",
      "pos": [
        716,
        864
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using Azure Automation, long-running, manual, error-prone, and frequently repeated tasks can be automated to increase reliability, efficiency, and time to value for your organization.",
      "pos": [
        865,
        1048
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation provides a highly-reliable and highly-available workflow execution engine that scales to meet your needs as your organization grows.",
      "pos": [
        1050,
        1199
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Azure Automation, processes can be kicked off manually, by 3rd-party systems, or at scheduled intervals so that tasks happen exactly when needed.",
      "pos": [
        1200,
        1348
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Lower operational overhead and free up IT / DevOps staff to focus on work that adds business value by moving your cloud management tasks to be run automatically by Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        1350,
        1531
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How can Azure Automation help manage Azure Traffic Manager?",
      "pos": [
        1538,
        1597
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traffic Manager can be managed in Azure Automation by using the PowerShell cmdlets that are available in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure PowerShell tools<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj156055.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1599,
        1789
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation can call these PowerShell cmdlets, so that you can perform all of your Traffic Manager management tasks within the service.",
      "pos": [
        1790,
        1930
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also pair these cmdlets in Azure Automation with the cmdlets for other Azure services, to automate complex tasks across Azure services and 3rd party systems.",
      "pos": [
        1931,
        2096
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next Steps",
      "pos": [
        2102,
        2112
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Now that you've learned the basics of Azure Automation and how it can be used to manage Azure Traffic Manager, follow these links to learn more about Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        2114,
        2281
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2285,
        2386
      ],
      "content": "Check out the Azure Automation <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Getting Started Guide<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=390560)</ept>"
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n pageTitle=\"Manage Azure Traffic Manager using Azure Automation\" \n description=\"Learn about how the Azure Automation service can be used to manage Azure Traffic Manager.\" \n services=\"traffic-manager, automation\" \n documentationCenter=\"\" \n authors=\"eamonoreilly\" \n manager=\"adinah\" \n editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n ms.service=\"traffic-manager\" \n ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\" \n ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n ms.devlang=\"na\" \n ms.topic=\"article\" \n ms.date=\"08/12/2015\" \n ms.author=\"joaoma\"/>\n\n\n#Managing Azure Traffic Manager using Azure Automation\n\nThis guide will introduce you to the Azure Automation service, and how it can be used to simplify management of Azure Traffic Manager.\n\n## What is Azure Automation?\n\n[Azure Automation](http://azure.microsoft.com/services/automation/) is an Azure service for simplifying cloud management through process automation. Using Azure Automation, long-running, manual, error-prone, and frequently repeated tasks can be automated to increase reliability, efficiency, and time to value for your organization.\n\nAzure Automation provides a highly-reliable and highly-available workflow execution engine that scales to meet your needs as your organization grows. In Azure Automation, processes can be kicked off manually, by 3rd-party systems, or at scheduled intervals so that tasks happen exactly when needed.\n\nLower operational overhead and free up IT / DevOps staff to focus on work that adds business value by moving your cloud management tasks to be run automatically by Azure Automation. \n\n\n## How can Azure Automation help manage Azure Traffic Manager?\n\nTraffic Manager can be managed in Azure Automation by using the PowerShell cmdlets that are available in the [Azure PowerShell tools](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj156055.aspx). Azure Automation can call these PowerShell cmdlets, so that you can perform all of your Traffic Manager management tasks within the service. You can also pair these cmdlets in Azure Automation with the cmdlets for other Azure services, to automate complex tasks across Azure services and 3rd party systems.\n\n\n## Next Steps\n\nNow that you've learned the basics of Azure Automation and how it can be used to manage Azure Traffic Manager, follow these links to learn more about Azure Automation.\n\n* Check out the Azure Automation [Getting Started Guide](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=390560)\n "
}