{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Monitor, diagnose, and troubleshoot Storage | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        28,
        89
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use features such as storage analytics, client-side logging, and other third-party tools to identify, diagnose, and troubleshoot Azure Storage-related issues.",
      "pos": [
        109,
        267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitor, diagnose, and troubleshoot Microsoft Azure Storage",
      "pos": [
        574,
        633
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Diagnosing and troubleshooting issues in a distributed application hosted in a cloud environment can be more complex than in traditional environments.",
      "pos": [
        636,
        786
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Applications can be deployed in a PaaS or IaaS infrastructure, on premises, on a mobile device, or in some combination of these.",
      "pos": [
        787,
        915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, your application’s network traffic may traverse public and private networks and your application may use multiple storage technologies such as Microsoft Azure Storage Tables, Blobs, Queues, or Files in addition to other data stores such as relational and document databases.",
      "pos": [
        916,
        1201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To manage such applications successfully you should monitor them proactively and understand how to diagnose and troubleshoot all aspects of them and their dependent technologies.",
      "pos": [
        1203,
        1381
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a user of Azure Storage services, you should continuously monitor the Storage services your application uses for any unexpected changes in behavior (such as slower than usual response times), and use logging to collect more detailed data and to analyze a problem in depth.",
      "pos": [
        1382,
        1657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The diagnostics information you obtain from both monitoring and logging will help you to determine the root cause of the issue your application encountered.",
      "pos": [
        1658,
        1814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then you can troubleshoot the issue and determine the appropriate steps you can take to remediate it.",
      "pos": [
        1815,
        1916
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Storage is a core Azure service, and forms an important part of the majority of solutions that customers deploy to the Azure infrastructure.",
      "pos": [
        1917,
        2063
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Storage includes capabilities to simplify monitoring, diagnosing, and troubleshooting storage issues in your cloud-based applications.",
      "pos": [
        2064,
        2204
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2207,
        2425
      ],
      "content": "For a hands-on guide to end-to-end troubleshooting in Azure Storage applications, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>End-to-End Troubleshooting using Azure Storage Metrics and Logging, AzCopy, and Message Analyzer<ept id=\"p1\">](../storage-e2e-troubleshooting/)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "[Introduction]",
      "pos": [
        2429,
        2443
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[How this guide is organized]",
      "pos": [
        2450,
        2479
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Monitoring your storage service]",
      "pos": [
        2482,
        2515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Monitoring service health]",
      "pos": [
        2522,
        2549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Monitoring capacity]",
      "pos": [
        2556,
        2577
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Monitoring availability]",
      "pos": [
        2584,
        2609
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Monitoring performance]",
      "pos": [
        2616,
        2640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Diagnosing storage issues]",
      "pos": [
        2643,
        2670
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Service health issues]",
      "pos": [
        2677,
        2700
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Performance issues]",
      "pos": [
        2707,
        2727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Diagnosing errors]",
      "pos": [
        2734,
        2753
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Storage emulator issues]",
      "pos": [
        2760,
        2785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Storage logging tools]",
      "pos": [
        2792,
        2815
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Using network logging tools]",
      "pos": [
        2822,
        2851
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[End-to-end tracing]",
      "pos": [
        2854,
        2874
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Correlating log data]",
      "pos": [
        2881,
        2903
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Client request ID]",
      "pos": [
        2910,
        2929
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Server request ID]",
      "pos": [
        2936,
        2955
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Timestamps]",
      "pos": [
        2962,
        2974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Troubleshooting guidance]",
      "pos": [
        2977,
        3003
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show high AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency]",
      "pos": [
        3010,
        3076
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show low AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency but the client is experiencing high latency]",
      "pos": [
        3083,
        3192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show high AverageServerLatency]",
      "pos": [
        3199,
        3239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[You are experiencing unexpected delays in message delivery on a queue]",
      "pos": [
        3246,
        3317
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError]",
      "pos": [
        3324,
        3376
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show an increase in PercentTimeoutError]",
      "pos": [
        3383,
        3432
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show an increase in PercentNetworkError]",
      "pos": [
        3439,
        3488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[The client is receiving HTTP 403 (Forbidden) messages]",
      "pos": [
        3495,
        3550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[The client is receiving HTTP 404 (Not found) messages]",
      "pos": [
        3557,
        3612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[The client is receiving HTTP 409 (Conflict) messages]",
      "pos": [
        3619,
        3673
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show low PercentSuccess or analytics log entries have operations with transaction status of ClientOtherErrors]",
      "pos": [
        3680,
        3799
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Capacity metrics show an unexpected increase in storage capacity usage]",
      "pos": [
        3806,
        3878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[You are experiencing unexpected reboots of Virtual Machines that have a large number of attached VHDs]",
      "pos": [
        3885,
        3988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Your issue arises from using the storage emulator for development or test]",
      "pos": [
        3995,
        4070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[You are encountering problems installing the Azure SDK for .NET]",
      "pos": [
        4077,
        4142
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[You have a different issue with a storage service]",
      "pos": [
        4149,
        4200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Appendices]",
      "pos": [
        4203,
        4215
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Appendix 1: Using Fiddler to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic]",
      "pos": [
        4222,
        4283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic]",
      "pos": [
        4290,
        4346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic]",
      "pos": [
        4353,
        4426
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Appendix 4: Using Excel to view metrics and log data]",
      "pos": [
        4433,
        4487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Appendix 5: Monitoring with Application Insights for Visual Studio Online]",
      "pos": [
        4494,
        4569
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4574,
        4613
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"introduction\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Introduction"
    },
    {
      "content": "This guide shows you how to use features such as Azure Storage Analytics, client-side logging in the Azure Storage Client Library, and other third-party tools to identify, diagnose, and troubleshoot Azure Storage related issues.",
      "pos": [
        4615,
        4843
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure 1 Monitoring, Diagnostics, and Troubleshooting",
      "pos": [
        4854,
        4907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This guide is intended to be read primarily by developers of online services that use Azure Storage Services and IT Pros responsible for managing such online services.",
      "pos": [
        4910,
        5077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The goals of this guide are:",
      "pos": [
        5078,
        5106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To help you maintain the health and performance of your Azure Storage accounts.",
      "pos": [
        5110,
        5189
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To provide you with the necessary processes and tools to help you decide if an issue or problem in an application relates to Azure Storage.",
      "pos": [
        5192,
        5331
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To provide you with actionable guidance for resolving problems related to Azure Storage.",
      "pos": [
        5334,
        5422
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5428,
        5497
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"how-this-guide-is-organized\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>How this guide is organized"
    },
    {
      "content": "The section \"[Monitoring your storage service]\" describes how to monitor the health and performance of your Azure Storage services using Azure Storage Analytics Metrics (Storage Metrics).",
      "pos": [
        5499,
        5686
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The section \"[Diagnosing storage issues]\" describes how to diagnose issues using Azure Storage Analytics Logging (Storage Logging).",
      "pos": [
        5688,
        5819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It also describes how to enable client-side logging using the facilities in one of the client libraries such as the Storage Client Library for .NET or the Azure SDK for Java.",
      "pos": [
        5820,
        5994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The section \"[End-to-end tracing]\" describes how you can correlate the information contained in various log files and metrics data.",
      "pos": [
        5996,
        6127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The section \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" provides troubleshooting guidance for some of the common storage-related issues you might encounter.",
      "pos": [
        6129,
        6270
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The \"[Appendices]\" include information about using other tools such as Wireshark and Netmon for analyzing network packet data, Fiddler for analyzing HTTP/HTTPS messages, and Microsoft Message Analyzer for correlating log data.",
      "pos": [
        6272,
        6498
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6504,
        6581
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"monitoring-your-storage-service\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Monitoring your storage service"
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are familiar with Windows performance monitoring, you can think of Storage Metrics as being an Azure Storage equivalent of Windows Performance Monitor counters.",
      "pos": [
        6583,
        6750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Storage Metrics you will find a comprehensive set of metrics (counters in Windows Performance Monitor terminology) such as service availability, total number of requests to service, or percentage of successful requests to service (for a full list of the available metrics, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343264.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Storage Analytics Metrics Table Schema<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN).",
      "pos": [
        6751,
        7163
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can specify whether you want the storage service to collect and aggregate metrics every hour or every minute.",
      "pos": [
        7164,
        7277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about how to enable metrics and monitor your storage accounts, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=510865\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Enabling storage metrics<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN.",
      "pos": [
        7278,
        7475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can choose which hourly metrics you want to display in the Azure portal and configure rules that notify administrators by email whenever an hourly metric exceeds a particular threshold (for more information, see the page <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn306638.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>How to: Receive Alert Notifications and Manage Alert Rules in Azure<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>).",
      "pos": [
        7477,
        7855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The storage service collects metrics using a best effort, but may not record every storage operation.",
      "pos": [
        7856,
        7957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure 2 below shows the Monitor page in the portal where you can view metrics such as availability, total requests, and average latency numbers for a storage account.",
      "pos": [
        7959,
        8126
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A notification rule has also been set up to alert an administrator if availability drops below a certain level.",
      "pos": [
        8127,
        8238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From viewing this data, one possible area for investigation is the table service success percentage being below 100% (for more information, see the section \"[Metrics show low PercentSuccess or analytics log entries have operations with transaction status of ClientOtherErrors]\").",
      "pos": [
        8239,
        8518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Figure 2 Viewing storage metrics in the portal",
      "pos": [
        8529,
        8575
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should continuously monitor your Azure applications to ensure they are healthy and performing as expected by:",
      "pos": [
        8578,
        8691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Establishing some baseline metrics for application that will enable you to compare current data and identify any significant changes in the behavior of Azure storage and your application.",
      "pos": [
        8695,
        8882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The values of your baseline metrics will, in many cases, be application specific and you should establish them when you are performance testing your application.",
      "pos": [
        8883,
        9044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Recording minute metrics and using them to monitor actively for unexpected errors and anomalies such as spikes in error counts or request rates.",
      "pos": [
        9047,
        9191
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Recording hourly metrics and using them to monitor average values such as average error counts and request rates.",
      "pos": [
        9195,
        9308
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Investigating potential issues using diagnostics tools as discussed later in the section \"[Diagnosing storage issues].\"",
      "pos": [
        9312,
        9431
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The charts in Figure 3 below illustrate how the averaging that occurs for hourly metrics can hide spikes in activity.",
      "pos": [
        9433,
        9550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The hourly metrics appear to show a steady rate of requests, while the minute metrics reveal the fluctuations that are really taking place.",
      "pos": [
        9551,
        9690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The remainder of this section describes what metrics you should monitor and why.",
      "pos": [
        9700,
        9780
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9787,
        9852
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"monitoring-service-health\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Monitoring service health"
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the Microsoft Azure Portal at <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"https://portal.azure.com\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>https://portal.azure.com<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> to view the health of the Storage service (and other Azure services) in all the Azure regions around the world.",
      "pos": [
        9854,
        10087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This enables you to see immediately if an issue outside of your control is affecting the Storage service in the region you use for your application.",
      "pos": [
        10088,
        10236
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure Portal can also provide with notifications of incidents that affect the various Azure services.",
      "pos": [
        10239,
        10344
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note: This information was previously available, along with historical data, on the Azure Service Dashboard at <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://status.azure.com\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>http://status.azure.com<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        10345,
        10534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While the portal collects health information from inside the Azure datacenters (inside-out monitoring), you could also consider adopting an outside-in approach to generate synthetic transactions that periodically access your Azure-hosted web application from multiple locations.",
      "pos": [
        10536,
        10814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The services offered by <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.keynote.com/solutions/monitoring/web-monitoring\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Keynote<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>, <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;a href=\"https://www.gomeznetworks.com/?g=1\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Gomez<ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>, and Application Insights for Visual Studio Online are examples of this outside-in approach.",
      "pos": [
        10815,
        11100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about Application Insights for Visual Studio Online, see the appendix \"[Appendix 5: Monitoring with Application Insights for Visual Studio Online].\"",
      "pos": [
        11101,
        11270
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11276,
        11329
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"monitoring-capacity\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Monitoring capacity"
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage Metrics only stores capacity metrics for the blob service because blobs typically account for the largest proportion of stored data (at the time of writing, it is not possible to use Storage Metrics to monitor the capacity of your tables and queues).",
      "pos": [
        11331,
        11589
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can find this data in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>$MetricsCapacityBlob<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> table if you have enabled monitoring for the Blob service.",
      "pos": [
        11590,
        11703
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage Metrics records this data once per day, and you can use the value of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>RowKey<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to determine whether the row contains an entity that relates to user data (value <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>data<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>) or analytics data (value <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>analytics<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>).",
      "pos": [
        11704,
        11927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each stored entity contains information about the amount of storage used (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Capacity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> measured in bytes) and the current number of containers (<bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ContainerCount<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>) and blobs (<bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>ObjectCount<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>) in use in the storage account.",
      "pos": [
        11928,
        12150
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about the capacity metrics stored in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>$MetricsCapacityBlob<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> table, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343264.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Storage Analytics Metrics Table Schema<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN.",
      "pos": [
        12151,
        12380
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> You should monitor these values for an early warning that you are approaching the capacity limits of your storage account.",
      "pos": [
        12384,
        12519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the Azure portal, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Monitor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page for your storage account, you can add alert rules to notify you if aggregate storage use exceeds or falls below thresholds that you specify.",
      "pos": [
        12520,
        12705
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12707,
        13050
      ],
      "content": "For help estimating the size of various storage objects such as blobs, see the blog post <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2010/07/09/understanding-windows-azure-storage-billing-bandwidth-transactions-and-capacity.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Understanding Azure Storage Billing – Bandwidth, Transactions, and Capacity<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13056,
        13117
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"monitoring-availability\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Monitoring availability"
    },
    {
      "content": "You should monitor the availability of the storage services in your storage account by monitoring the value in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Availability<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column in the hourly or minute metrics tables — <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>$MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsBlob<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>$MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsTable<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>$MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsQueue<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>$MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsBlob<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>$MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsTable<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt>$MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsQueue<ept id=\"p7\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p8\">**</bpt>$MetricsCapacityBlob<ept id=\"p8\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        13119,
        13580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Availability<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column contains a percentage value that indicates the availability of the service or the API operation represented by the row (the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>RowKey<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> shows if the row contains metrics for the service as a whole or for a specific API operation).",
      "pos": [
        13581,
        13838
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Any value less than 100% indicates that some storage requests are failing.",
      "pos": [
        13841,
        13915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can see why they are failing by examining the other columns in the metrics data that show the numbers of requests with different error types such as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ServerTimeoutError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        13916,
        14092
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should expect to see <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Availability<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> fall temporarily below 100% for reasons such as transient server timeouts while the service moves partitions to better load-balance request; the retry logic in your client application should handle such intermittent conditions.",
      "pos": [
        14093,
        14362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The page <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343260.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> lists the transaction types that Storage Metrics includes in its <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Availability<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> calculation.",
      "pos": [
        14363,
        14551
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        14553,
        14737
      ],
      "content": "In the Azure portal, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Monitor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page for your storage account, you can add alert rules to notify you if <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Availability<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> for a service falls below a threshold that you specify."
    },
    {
      "content": "The \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" section of this guide describes some common storage service issues related to availability.",
      "pos": [
        14739,
        14863
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        14869,
        14928
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"monitoring-performance\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Monitoring performance"
    },
    {
      "content": "To monitor the performance of the storage services, you can use the following metrics from the hourly and minute metrics tables.",
      "pos": [
        14930,
        15058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The values in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AverageE2ELatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>AverageServerLatency<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> show the average time the storage service or API operation type is taking to process requests.",
      "pos": [
        15062,
        15225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AverageE2ELatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is a measure of end-to-end latency that includes the time taken to read the request and send the response in addition to the time taken to process the request (therefore includes network latency once the request reaches the storage service); <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>AverageServerLatency<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> is a measure of just the processing time and therefore excludes any network latency related to communicating with the client.",
      "pos": [
        15226,
        15640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the section \"[Metrics show high AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency]\" later in this guide for a discussion of why there might be a significant difference between these two values.",
      "pos": [
        15641,
        15835
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        15838,
        16034
      ],
      "content": "The values in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>TotalIngress<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>TotalEgress<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> columns show the total amount of data, in bytes, coming in to and going out of your storage service or through a specific API operation type."
    },
    {
      "content": "The values in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>TotalRequests<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column show the total number of requests that the storage service of API operation is receiving.",
      "pos": [
        16037,
        16169
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>TotalRequests<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is the total number of requests that the storage service receives.",
      "pos": [
        16170,
        16254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, you will monitor for unexpected changes in any of these values as an indicator that you have an issue that requires investigation.",
      "pos": [
        16257,
        16398
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16400,
        16610
      ],
      "content": "In the Azure portal, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Monitor<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page for your storage account, you can add alert rules to notify you if any of the performance metrics for this service fall below or exceed a threshold that you specify."
    },
    {
      "content": "The \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" section of this guide describes some common storage service issues related to performance.",
      "pos": [
        16612,
        16735
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16741,
        16806
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"diagnosing-storage-issues\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Diagnosing storage issues"
    },
    {
      "content": "There are a number of ways that you might become aware of a problem or issue in your application, these include:",
      "pos": [
        16808,
        16920
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A major failure that causes the application to crash or to stop working.",
      "pos": [
        16924,
        16996
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Significant changes from baseline values in the metrics you are monitoring as described in the previous section \"[Monitoring your storage service].\"",
      "pos": [
        16999,
        17147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reports from users of your application that some particular operation didn't complete as expected or that some feature is not working.",
      "pos": [
        17151,
        17285
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Errors generated within your application that appear in log files or through some other notification method.",
      "pos": [
        17288,
        17396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, issues related to Azure storage services fall into one of four broad categories:",
      "pos": [
        17398,
        17489
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your application has a performance issue, either reported by your users, or revealed by changes in the performance metrics.",
      "pos": [
        17493,
        17616
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There is a problem with the Azure Storage infrastructure in one or more regions.",
      "pos": [
        17619,
        17699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your application is encountering an error, either reported by your users, or revealed by an increase in one of the error count metrics you monitor.",
      "pos": [
        17703,
        17850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During development and test, you may be using the local storage emulator; you may encounter some issues that relate specifically to usage of the storage emulator.",
      "pos": [
        17853,
        18015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following sections outline the steps you should follow to diagnose and troubleshoot issues in each of these four categories.",
      "pos": [
        18017,
        18145
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The section \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" later in this guide provides more detail for some common issues you may encounter.",
      "pos": [
        18146,
        18269
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        18275,
        18332
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"service-health-issues\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Service health issues"
    },
    {
      "content": "Service health issues are typically outside of your control.",
      "pos": [
        18334,
        18394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure Portal provides information about any ongoing issues with Azure services including storage services.",
      "pos": [
        18395,
        18505
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you opted for Read-Access Geo-Redundant Storage when you created your storage account, then in the event of your data being unavailable in the primary location, your application could switch temporarily to the read-only copy in the secondary location.",
      "pos": [
        18506,
        18760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, your application must be able to switch between using the primary and secondary storage locations, and be able to work in a reduced functionality mode with read-only data.",
      "pos": [
        18761,
        18944
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure Storage Client libraries allow you to define a retry policy that can read from secondary storage in case a read from primary storage fails.",
      "pos": [
        18945,
        19094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your application also needs to be aware that the data in the secondary location is eventually consistent.",
      "pos": [
        19095,
        19200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see the blog post <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2013/12/04/introducing-read-access-geo-replicated-storage-ra-grs-for-windows-azure-storage.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Azure Storage Redundancy Options and Read Access Geo Redundant Storage<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        19201,
        19490
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        19496,
        19547
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"performance-issues\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Performance issues"
    },
    {
      "content": "The performance of an application can be subjective, especially from a user perspective.",
      "pos": [
        19549,
        19637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Therefore, it is important to have baseline metrics available to help you identify where there might be a performance issue.",
      "pos": [
        19638,
        19762
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Many factors might affect the performance of an Azure storage service from the client application perspective.",
      "pos": [
        19763,
        19873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These factors might operate in the storage service, in the client, or in the network infrastructure; therefore it is important to have a strategy for identifying the origin of the performance issue.",
      "pos": [
        19874,
        20072
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you have identified the likely location of the cause of the performance issue from the metrics, you can then use the log files to find detailed information to diagnose and troubleshoot the problem further.",
      "pos": [
        20074,
        20285
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The section \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" later in this guide provides more information about some common performance related issues you may encounter.",
      "pos": [
        20287,
        20437
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        20443,
        20492
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"diagnosing-errors\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Diagnosing errors"
    },
    {
      "content": "Users of your application may notify you of errors reported by the client application.",
      "pos": [
        20494,
        20580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage Metrics also records counts of different error types from your storage services such as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>NetworkError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ClientTimeoutError<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>AuthorizationError<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        20581,
        20745
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While Storage Metrics only records counts of different error types, you can obtain more detail about individual requests by examining server-side, client-side, and network logs.",
      "pos": [
        20746,
        20923
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, the HTTP status code returned by the storage service will give an indication of why the request failed.",
      "pos": [
        20924,
        21038
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        21043,
        21200
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Remember that you should expect to see some intermittent errors: for example, errors due to transient network conditions, or application errors."
    },
    {
      "content": "The following resources on MSDN are useful for understanding storage-related status and error codes:",
      "pos": [
        21202,
        21302
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        21306,
        21417
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179357.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Common REST API Error Codes<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        21420,
        21528
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179439.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Blob Service Error Codes<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        21531,
        21640
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179446.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Queue Service Error Codes<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        21643,
        21752
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179438.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Table Service Error Codes<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        21758,
        21819
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"storage-emulator-issues\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Storage emulator issues"
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure SDK includes a storage emulator you can run on a development workstation.",
      "pos": [
        21821,
        21904
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This emulator simulates most of the behavior of the Azure storage services and is useful during development and test, enabling you to run applications that use Azure storage services without the need for an Azure subscription and an Azure storage account.",
      "pos": [
        21905,
        22160
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" section of this guide describes some common issues encountered using the storage emulator.",
      "pos": [
        22162,
        22285
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        22291,
        22348
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"storage-logging-tools\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Storage logging tools"
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage Logging provides server-side logging of storage requests in your Azure storage account.",
      "pos": [
        22350,
        22445
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about how to enable server-side logging and access the log data, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=510867\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Using server-side logging<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN.",
      "pos": [
        22446,
        22646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Storage Client Library for .NET enables you to collect client-side log data that relates to storage operations performed by your application.",
      "pos": [
        22648,
        22793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about how to enable client-side logging and access the log data, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=510868\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Client-side logging using the Storage Client Library<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN.",
      "pos": [
        22794,
        23021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> In some circumstances (such as SAS authorization failures), a user may report an error for which you can find no request data in the server-side Storage logs.",
      "pos": [
        23025,
        23196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the logging capabilities of the Storage Client Library to investigate if the cause of the issue is on the client or use network monitoring tools to investigate the network.",
      "pos": [
        23197,
        23381
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        23387,
        23456
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"using-network-logging-tools\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Using network logging tools"
    },
    {
      "content": "You can capture the traffic between the client and server to provide detailed information about the data the client and server are exchanging and the underlying network conditions.",
      "pos": [
        23458,
        23638
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Useful network logging tools include:",
      "pos": [
        23639,
        23676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Fiddler (<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.telerik.com/fiddler\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>http://www.telerik.com/fiddler<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>) is a free web debugging proxy that enables you to examine the headers and payload data of HTTP and HTTPS request and response messages.",
      "pos": [
        23680,
        23917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see \"[Appendix 1: Using Fiddler to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic]\".",
      "pos": [
        23918,
        24008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Network Monitor (Netmon) (<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=4865\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>http://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=4865<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>) and Wireshark (<ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.wireshark.org/\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>http://www.wireshark.org/<ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>) are free network protocol analyzers that enable you to view detailed packet information for a wide range of network protocols.",
      "pos": [
        24011,
        24412
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about Wireshark, see \"[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic]\".",
      "pos": [
        24413,
        24514
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft Message Analyzer is a tool from Microsoft that supersedes Netmon and that in addition to capturing network packet data, helps you to view and analyze the log data captured from other tools.",
      "pos": [
        24517,
        24716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see \"[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic]\".",
      "pos": [
        24717,
        24819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to perform a basic connectivity test to check that your client machine can connect to the Azure storage service over the network, you cannot do this using the standard <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ping<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tool on the client.",
      "pos": [
        24822,
        25030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, you can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>tcping<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tool to check connectivity.",
      "pos": [
        25031,
        25094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tcping<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is available for download at <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.elifulkerson.com/projects/tcping.php\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>http://www.elifulkerson.com/projects/tcping.php<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        25095,
        25261
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In many cases, the log data from Storage Logging and the Storage Client Library will be sufficient to diagnose an issue, but in some scenarios, you may need the more detailed information that these network logging tools can provide.",
      "pos": [
        25263,
        25495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, using Fiddler to view HTTP and HTTPS messages enables you to view header and payload data sent to and from the storage services, which would enable you to examine how a client application retries storage operations.",
      "pos": [
        25496,
        25724
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Protocol analyzers such as Wireshark operate at the packet level enabling you to view TCP data, which would enable you to troubleshoot lost packets and connectivity issues.",
      "pos": [
        25725,
        25897
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Message Analyzer can operate at both HTTP and TCP layers.",
      "pos": [
        25898,
        25955
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        25960,
        26011
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"end-to-end-tracing\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>End-to-end tracing"
    },
    {
      "content": "End-to-end tracing using a variety of log files is a useful technique for investigating potential issues.",
      "pos": [
        26013,
        26118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the date/time information from your metrics data as an indication of where to start looking in the log files for the detailed information that will help you troubleshoot the issue.",
      "pos": [
        26119,
        26311
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        26321,
        26376
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"correlating-log-data\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Correlating log data"
    },
    {
      "content": "When viewing logs from client applications, network traces, and server-side storage logging it is critical to be able to correlate requests across the different log files.",
      "pos": [
        26378,
        26549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The log files include a number of different fields that are useful as correlation identifiers.",
      "pos": [
        26550,
        26644
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The client request id is the most useful field to use to correlate entries in the different logs.",
      "pos": [
        26645,
        26742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However sometimes, it can be useful to use either the server request id or timestamps.",
      "pos": [
        26743,
        26829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following sections provide more details about these options.",
      "pos": [
        26830,
        26894
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        26900,
        26949
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"client-request-id\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Client request ID"
    },
    {
      "content": "The Storage Client Library automatically generates a unique client request id for every request.",
      "pos": [
        26951,
        27047
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        27051,
        27223
      ],
      "content": "In the client-side log that the Storage Client Library creates, the client request id appears in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Client Request ID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field of every log entry relating to the request."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        27226,
        27383
      ],
      "content": "In a network trace such as one captured by Fiddler, the client request id is visible in request messages as the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x-ms-client-request-id<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> HTTP header value."
    },
    {
      "content": "In the server-side Storage Logging log, the client request id appears in the Client request ID column.",
      "pos": [
        27386,
        27488
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        27492,
        27868
      ],
      "content": "[AZURE.NOTE] It is possible for multiple requests to share the same client request id because the client can assign this value (although the Storage Client Library assigns a \nnew value automatically). In the case of retries from the client, all attempts share the same client request id. In the case of a batch sent from the client, the batch has a single client request id.",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "> "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> It is possible for multiple requests to share the same client request id because the client can assign this value (although the Storage Client Library assigns a",
          "pos": [
            0,
            173
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "new value automatically). In the case of retries from the client, all attempts share the same client request id. In the case of a batch sent from the client, the batch has a single client request id.",
          "pos": [
            175,
            374
          ],
          "nodes": [
            {
              "content": "new value automatically).",
              "pos": [
                0,
                25
              ]
            },
            {
              "content": "In the case of retries from the client, all attempts share the same client request id.",
              "pos": [
                26,
                112
              ]
            },
            {
              "content": "In the case of a batch sent from the client, the batch has a single client request id.",
              "pos": [
                113,
                199
              ]
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        27875,
        27924
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"server-request-id\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Server request ID"
    },
    {
      "content": "The storage service automatically generates server request ids.",
      "pos": [
        27926,
        27989
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        27993,
        28096
      ],
      "content": "In the server-side Storage Logging log, the server request id appears the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Request ID header<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        28099,
        28247
      ],
      "content": "In a network trace such as one captured by Fiddler, the server request id appears in response messages as the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x-ms-request-id<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> HTTP header value."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        28250,
        28434
      ],
      "content": "In the client-side log that the Storage Client Library creates, the server request id appears in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Operation Text<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column for the log entry showing details of the server response."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        28438,
        28653
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> The storage service always assigns a unique server request id to every request it receives, so every retry attempt from the client and every operation included in a batch has a unique server request id."
    },
    {
      "content": "If the Storage Client Library throws a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>StorageException<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the client, the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>RequestInformation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> property contains a <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>RequestResult<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> object that includes a <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>ServiceRequestID<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> property.",
      "pos": [
        28655,
        28848
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also access a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>RequestResult<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> object from an <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OperationContext<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> instance.",
      "pos": [
        28849,
        28934
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The code sample below demonstrates how to set a custom <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ClientRequestId<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value by attaching an <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OperationContext<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> object the request to the storage service.",
      "pos": [
        28936,
        29096
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It also shows how to retrieve the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ServerRequestId<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value from the response message.",
      "pos": [
        29097,
        29183
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        30669,
        30704
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"timestamps\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Timestamps"
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also use timestamps to locate related log entries, but be careful of any clock skew between the client and server that may exist.",
      "pos": [
        30706,
        30843
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should search plus or minus 15 minutes for matching server-side entries based on the timestamp on the client.",
      "pos": [
        30844,
        30957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remember that the blob metadata for the blobs containing metrics indicates the time range for the metrics stored in the blob; this is useful if you have many metrics blobs for the same minute or hour.",
      "pos": [
        30958,
        31158
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        31163,
        31226
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"troubleshooting-guidance\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Troubleshooting guidance"
    },
    {
      "content": "This section will help you with the diagnosis and troubleshooting of some of the common issues your application may encounter when using the Azure storage services.",
      "pos": [
        31228,
        31392
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the list below to locate the information relevant to your specific issue.",
      "pos": [
        31393,
        31470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Troubleshooting Decision Tree",
      "pos": [
        31474,
        31503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Does your issue relate to the performance of one of the storage services?",
      "pos": [
        31519,
        31592
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show high AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency]",
      "pos": [
        31596,
        31662
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show low AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency but the client is experiencing high latency]",
      "pos": [
        31665,
        31774
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show high AverageServerLatency]",
      "pos": [
        31777,
        31817
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[You are experiencing unexpected delays in message delivery on a queue]",
      "pos": [
        31820,
        31891
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Does your issue relate to the availability of one of the storage services?",
      "pos": [
        31905,
        31979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError]",
      "pos": [
        31983,
        32035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show an increase in PercentTimeoutError]",
      "pos": [
        32038,
        32087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show an increase in PercentNetworkError]",
      "pos": [
        32090,
        32139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Is your client application receiving an HTTP 4XX (such as 404) response from a storage service?",
      "pos": [
        32153,
        32248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[The client is receiving HTTP 403 (Forbidden) messages]",
      "pos": [
        32252,
        32307
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[The client is receiving HTTP 404 (Not found) messages]",
      "pos": [
        32310,
        32365
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[The client is receiving HTTP 409 (Conflict) messages]",
      "pos": [
        32368,
        32422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Metrics show low PercentSuccess or analytics log entries have operations with transaction status of ClientOtherErrors]",
      "pos": [
        32436,
        32555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Capacity metrics show an unexpected increase in storage capacity usage]",
      "pos": [
        32569,
        32641
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[You are experiencing unexpected reboots of Virtual Machines that have a large number of attached VHDs]",
      "pos": [
        32655,
        32758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Your issue arises from using the storage emulator for development or test]",
      "pos": [
        32772,
        32847
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[You are encountering problems installing the Azure SDK for .NET]",
      "pos": [
        32861,
        32926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[You have a different issue with a storage service]",
      "pos": [
        32940,
        32991
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        33009,
        33152
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"metrics-show-high-AverageE2ELatency-and-low-AverageServerLatency\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Metrics show high AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        33154,
        33315
      ],
      "content": "The illustration blow from the portal monitoring tool shows an example where the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AverageE2ELatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is significantly higher than the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>AverageServerLatency<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the storage service only calculates the metric <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AverageE2ELatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for successful requests and, unlike <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>AverageServerLatency<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, includes the time the client takes to send the data and receive acknowledgement from the storage service.",
      "pos": [
        33325,
        33571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Therefore, a difference between <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AverageE2ELatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>AverageServerLatency<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> could be either due to the client application being slow to respond, or due to conditions on the network.",
      "pos": [
        33572,
        33760
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        33764,
        33898
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> You can also view <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>E2ELatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ServerLatency<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> for individual storage operations in the Storage Logging log data."
    },
    {
      "content": "Investigating client performance issues",
      "pos": [
        33905,
        33944
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Possible reasons for the client responding slowly include having a limited number of available connections or threads.",
      "pos": [
        33946,
        34064
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You may be able to resolve the issue by modifying the client code to be more efficient (for example by using asynchronous calls to the storage service), or by using a larger Virtual Machine (with more cores and more memory).",
      "pos": [
        34065,
        34289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the table and queue services, the Nagle algorithm can also cause high <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AverageE2ELatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as compared to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>AverageServerLatency<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>: for more information see the post <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2010/06/25/nagle-s-algorithm-is-not-friendly-towards-small-requests.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Nagle’s Algorithm is Not Friendly towards Small Requests<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on the Microsoft Azure Storage Team Blog.",
      "pos": [
        34291,
        34715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can disable the Nagle algorithm in code by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ServicePointManager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> class in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>System.Net<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> namespace.",
      "pos": [
        34716,
        34835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should do this before you make any calls to the table or queue services in your application since this does not affect connections that are already open.",
      "pos": [
        34836,
        34993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following example comes from the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Application_Start<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method in a worker role.",
      "pos": [
        34994,
        35077
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        35449,
        35896
      ],
      "content": "You should check the client-side logs to see how many requests your client application is submitting, and check for general .NET related performance bottlenecks in your client such as CPU, .NET garbage collection, network utilization, or memory (as a starting point for troubleshooting .NET client applications, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/7fe0dd2y(v=vs.110).aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Debugging, Tracing, and Profiling<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN)."
    },
    {
      "content": "Investigating network latency issues",
      "pos": [
        35903,
        35939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, high end-to-end latency caused by the network is due to transient conditions.",
      "pos": [
        35941,
        36029
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can investigate both transient and persistent network issues such as dropped packets by using tools such as Wireshark or Microsoft Message Analyzer.",
      "pos": [
        36030,
        36182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about using Wireshark to troubleshoot network issues, see \"[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic].\"",
      "pos": [
        36184,
        36322
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about using Microsoft Message Analyzer to troubleshoot network issues, see \"[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic].\"",
      "pos": [
        36324,
        36496
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        36502,
        36687
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"metrics-show-low-AverageE2ELatency-and-low-AverageServerLatency\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Metrics show low AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency but the client is experiencing high latency"
    },
    {
      "content": "In this scenario, the most likely cause is a delay in the storage requests reaching the storage service.",
      "pos": [
        36689,
        36793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should investigate why requests from the client are not making it through to the blob service.",
      "pos": [
        36794,
        36892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Possible reasons for the client delaying sending requests include having a limited number of available connections or threads.",
      "pos": [
        36895,
        37021
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should also check if the client is performing multiple retries, and investigate the reason if this is the case.",
      "pos": [
        37022,
        37137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can do this programmatically by looking in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OperationContext<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> object associated with the request and retrieving the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ServerRequestId<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> value.",
      "pos": [
        37138,
        37290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see the code sample in the section \"[Server request ID].\"",
      "pos": [
        37291,
        37370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If there are no issues in the client, you should investigate potential network issues such as packet loss.",
      "pos": [
        37372,
        37478
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use tools such as Wireshark or Microsoft Message Analyzer to investigate network issues.",
      "pos": [
        37479,
        37575
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about using Wireshark to troubleshoot network issues, see \"[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic].\"",
      "pos": [
        37577,
        37715
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about using Microsoft Message Analyzer to troubleshoot network issues, see \"[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic].\"",
      "pos": [
        37717,
        37889
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        37895,
        37986
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"metrics-show-high-AverageServerLatency\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Metrics show high AverageServerLatency"
    },
    {
      "content": "In the case of high <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AverageServerLatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for blob download requests, you should use the Storage Logging logs to see if there are repeated requests for the same blob (or set of blobs).",
      "pos": [
        37988,
        38175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For blob upload requests, you should investigate what block size the client is using (for example, blocks less than 64K in size can result in overheads unless the reads are also in less than 64K chunks), and if multiple clients are uploading blocks to the same blob in parallel.",
      "pos": [
        38176,
        38454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should also check the per-minute metrics for spikes in the number of requests that result in exceeding the per second scalability targets: also see \"[Metrics show an increase in PercentTimeoutError].\"",
      "pos": [
        38455,
        38659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are seeing high <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AverageServerLatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for blob download requests when there are repeated requests the same blob or set of blobs, then you should consider caching these blobs using Azure Cache or the Azure Content Delivery Network (CDN).",
      "pos": [
        38662,
        38908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For upload requests, you can improve the throughput by using a larger block size.",
      "pos": [
        38909,
        38990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For queries to tables, it is also possible to implement client-side caching on clients that perform the same query operations and where the data doesn’t change frequently.",
      "pos": [
        38991,
        39162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "High <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AverageServerLatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> values can also be a symptom of poorly designed tables or queries that result in scan operations or that follow the append/prepend anti-pattern.",
      "pos": [
        39165,
        39339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See \"[Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError]\" for more information.",
      "pos": [
        39340,
        39420
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        39425,
        39591
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> You can find a comprehensive checklist including other issues to be aware here: \"Designing Scalable and Performant Storage Based Applications Checklist.\""
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        39598,
        39740
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"you-are-experiencing-unexpected-delays-in-message-delivery\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>You are experiencing unexpected delays in message delivery on a queue"
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are experiencing a delay between the time an application adds a message to a queue and the time it becomes available to read from the queue, then you should take the following steps to diagnose the issue:",
      "pos": [
        39742,
        39953
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify the application is successfully adding the messages to the queue.",
      "pos": [
        39957,
        40029
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check that the application is not retrying the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AddMessage<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method several times before succeeding.",
      "pos": [
        40030,
        40131
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Storage Client Library logs will show any repeated retries of storage operations.",
      "pos": [
        40132,
        40217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify there is no clock skew between the worker role that adds the message to the queue and the worker role that reads the message from the queue that makes it appear as if there is a delay in processing.",
      "pos": [
        40220,
        40425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check if the worker role that reads the messages from the queue is failing.",
      "pos": [
        40428,
        40503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a queue client calls the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GetMessage<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method but fails to respond with an acknowledgement, the message will remain invisible on the queue until the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>invisibilityTimeout<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> period expires.",
      "pos": [
        40504,
        40696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At this point, the message becomes available for processing again.",
      "pos": [
        40697,
        40763
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check if the queue length is growing over time.",
      "pos": [
        40766,
        40813
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This can occur if you do not have sufficient workers available to process all of the messages that other workers are placing on the queue.",
      "pos": [
        40814,
        40952
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should also check the metrics to see if delete requests are failing and the dequeue count on messages, which might indicate repeated failed attempts to delete the message.",
      "pos": [
        40953,
        41128
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        41131,
        41304
      ],
      "content": "Examine the Storage Logging logs for any queue operations that have higher than expected <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>E2ELatency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ServerLatency<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> values over a longer period of time than usual."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        41311,
        41426
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"metrics-show-an-increase-in-PercentThrottlingError\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError"
    },
    {
      "content": "Throttling errors occur when you exceed the scalability targets of a storage service.",
      "pos": [
        41428,
        41513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The storage service does this to ensure that no single client or tenant can use the service at the expense of others.",
      "pos": [
        41514,
        41631
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn249410.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Azure Storage Scalability and Performance Targets<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> for details on scalability targets for storage accounts and performance targets for partitions within storage accounts.",
      "pos": [
        41632,
        41911
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        41914,
        42089
      ],
      "content": "If the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentThrottlingError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> metric show an increase in the percentage of requests that are failing with a throttling error, you need to investigate one of two scenarios:"
    },
    {
      "content": "[Transient increase in PercentThrottlingError]",
      "pos": [
        42093,
        42139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Permanent increase in PercentThrottlingError error]",
      "pos": [
        42142,
        42194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An increase in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentThrottlingError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> often occurs at the same time as an increase in the number of storage requests, or when you are initially load testing your application.",
      "pos": [
        42196,
        42374
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This may also manifest itself in the client as \"503 Server Busy\" or \"500 Operation Timeout\" HTTP status messages from storage operations.",
      "pos": [
        42375,
        42512
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        42519,
        42622
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"transient-increase-in-PercentThrottlingError\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Transient increase in PercentThrottlingError"
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are seeing spikes in the value of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentThrottlingError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> that coincide with periods of high activity for the application, you should implement an exponential (not linear) back off strategy for retries in your client: this will reduce the immediate load on the partition and help your application to smooth out spikes in traffic.",
      "pos": [
        42624,
        42963
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about how to implement retry policies using the Storage Client Library, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.storage.retrypolicies.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage.RetryPolicies Namespace<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN.",
      "pos": [
        42964,
        43244
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        43248,
        43494
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> You may also see spikes in the value of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentThrottlingError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> that do not coincide with periods of high activity for the application: the most likely cause here is the storage service moving partitions to improve load balancing."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        43501,
        43610
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"permanent-increase-in-PercentThrottlingError\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Permanent increase in PercentThrottlingError error"
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are seeing a consistently high value for <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentThrottlingError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> following a permanent increase in your transaction volumes, or when you are performing your initial load tests on your application, then you need to evaluate how your application is using storage partitions and whether it is approaching the scalability targets for a storage account.",
      "pos": [
        43612,
        43970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you are seeing throttling errors on a queue (which counts as a single partition), then you should consider using additional queues to spread the transactions across multiple partitions.",
      "pos": [
        43971,
        44172
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are seeing throttling errors on a table, you need to consider using a different partitioning scheme to spread your transactions across multiple partitions by using a wider range of partition key values.",
      "pos": [
        44173,
        44382
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One common cause of this issue is the prepend/append anti-pattern where you select the date as the partition key and then all data on a particular day is written to one partition: under load, this can result in a write bottleneck.",
      "pos": [
        44383,
        44613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should either consider a different partitioning design or evaluate whether using blob storage might be a better solution.",
      "pos": [
        44614,
        44739
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should also check if the throttling is occurring as a result of spikes in your traffic and investigate ways of smoothing your pattern of requests.",
      "pos": [
        44740,
        44890
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you distribute your transactions across multiple partitions, you must still be aware of the scalability limits set for the storage account.",
      "pos": [
        44892,
        45034
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you used ten queues each processing the maximum of 2,000 1KB messages per second, you will be at the overall limit of 20,000 messages per second for the storage account.",
      "pos": [
        45035,
        45220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you need to process more than 20,000 entities per second, you should consider using multiple storage accounts.",
      "pos": [
        45221,
        45334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should also bear in mind that the size of your requests and entities has an impact on when the storage service throttles your clients: if you have larger requests and entities, you may be throttled sooner.",
      "pos": [
        45335,
        45544
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Inefficient query design can also cause you to hit the scalability limits for table partitions.",
      "pos": [
        45546,
        45641
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, a query with a filter that only selects one percent of the entities in a partition but that scans all the entities in a partition will need to access each entity.",
      "pos": [
        45642,
        45817
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Every entity read will count towards the total number of transactions in that partition; therefore, you can easily reach the scalability targets.",
      "pos": [
        45818,
        45963
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        45967,
        46069
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Your performance testing should reveal any inefficient query designs in your application."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        46075,
        46184
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"metrics-show-an-increase-in-PercentTimeoutError\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Metrics show an increase in PercentTimeoutError"
    },
    {
      "content": "Your metrics show an increase in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentTimeoutError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for one of your storage services.",
      "pos": [
        46186,
        46276
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At the same time, the client receives a high volume of \"500 Operation Timeout\" HTTP status messages from storage operations.",
      "pos": [
        46277,
        46401
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        46405,
        46541
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> You may see timeout errors temporarily as the storage service load balances requests by moving a partition to a new server."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        46544,
        46794
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentTimeoutError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> metric is an aggregation of the following metrics: <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ClientTimeoutError<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>AnonymousClientTimeoutError<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>SASClientTimeoutError<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>ServerTimeoutError<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>AnonymousServerTimeoutError<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt>SASServerTimeoutError<ept id=\"p7\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "The server timeouts are caused by an error on the server.",
      "pos": [
        46796,
        46853
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The client timeouts happen because an operation on the server has exceeded the timeout specified by the client; for example, a client using the Storage Client Library can set a timeout for an operation by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ServerTimeout<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>QueueRequestOptions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> class.",
      "pos": [
        46854,
        47133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Server timeouts indicate a problem with the storage service that requires further investigation.",
      "pos": [
        47135,
        47231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use metrics to see if you are hitting the scalability limits for the service and to identify any spikes in traffic that might be causing this problem.",
      "pos": [
        47232,
        47390
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the problem is intermittent, it may be due to load-balancing activity in the service.",
      "pos": [
        47391,
        47479
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the problem is persistent and is not caused by your application hitting the scalability limits of the service, you should raise a support issue.",
      "pos": [
        47480,
        47627
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For client timeouts, you must decide if the timeout is set to an appropriate value in the client and either change the timeout value set in the client or investigate how you can improve the performance of the operations in the storage service, for example by optimizing your table queries or reducing the size of your messages.",
      "pos": [
        47628,
        47955
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        47961,
        48070
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"metrics-show-an-increase-in-PercentNetworkError\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Metrics show an increase in PercentNetworkError"
    },
    {
      "content": "Your metrics show an increase in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentNetworkError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for one of your storage services.",
      "pos": [
        48072,
        48162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentNetworkError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> metric is an aggregation of the following metrics: <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>NetworkError<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>AnonymousNetworkError<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>SASNetworkError<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        48163,
        48311
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These occur when the storage service detects a network error when the client makes a storage request.",
      "pos": [
        48312,
        48413
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The most common cause of this error is a client disconnecting before a timeout expires in the storage service.",
      "pos": [
        48415,
        48525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should investigate the code in your client to understand why and when the client disconnects from the storage service.",
      "pos": [
        48526,
        48648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also use Wireshark, Microsoft Message Analyzer, or Tcping to investigate network connectivity issues from the client.",
      "pos": [
        48649,
        48774
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These tools are described in the [Appendices].",
      "pos": [
        48775,
        48821
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        48827,
        48931
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"the-client-is-receiving-403-messages\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>The client is receiving HTTP 403 (Forbidden) messages"
    },
    {
      "content": "If your client application is throwing HTTP 403 (Forbidden) errors, a likely cause is that the client is using an expired Shared Access Signature (SAS) when it sends a storage request (although other possible causes include clock skew, invalid keys, and empty headers).",
      "pos": [
        48933,
        49202
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If an expired SAS key is the cause, you will not see any entries in the server-side Storage Logging log data.",
      "pos": [
        49203,
        49312
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following table shows a sample from the client-side log generated by the Storage Client Library that illustrates this issue occurring:",
      "pos": [
        49313,
        49451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Source",
      "pos": [
        49453,
        49459
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verbosity",
      "pos": [
        49460,
        49469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verbosity",
      "pos": [
        49470,
        49479
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Client request id",
      "pos": [
        49480,
        49497
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation text",
      "pos": [
        49498,
        49512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage",
      "pos": [
        49533,
        49563
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information",
      "pos": [
        49564,
        49575
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3",
      "pos": [
        49576,
        49577
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "85d077ab-…",
      "pos": [
        49578,
        49588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting operation with location Primary per location mode PrimaryOnly.",
      "pos": [
        49589,
        49660
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage",
      "pos": [
        49661,
        49691
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information",
      "pos": [
        49692,
        49703
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3",
      "pos": [
        49704,
        49705
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "85d077ab -…",
      "pos": [
        49706,
        49717
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting synchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.netazureimblobcontainer/blobCreatedViaSAS.txt?sv=2014-02-14&amp;amp;sr=c&amp;amp;si=mypolicy&amp;amp;sig=OFnd4Rd7z01fIvh%2BmcR6zbudIH2F5Ikm%2FyhNYZEmJNQ%3D&amp;amp;api-version=2014-02-14.",
      "pos": [
        49718,
        49960
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage",
      "pos": [
        49961,
        49991
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information",
      "pos": [
        49992,
        50003
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3",
      "pos": [
        50004,
        50005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "85d077ab -…",
      "pos": [
        50006,
        50017
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Waiting for response.",
      "pos": [
        50018,
        50039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage",
      "pos": [
        50040,
        50070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Warning",
      "pos": [
        50071,
        50078
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        50079,
        50080
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "85d077ab -…",
      "pos": [
        50081,
        50092
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exception thrown while waiting for response: The remote server returned an error: (403) Forbidden..",
      "pos": [
        50093,
        50192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage",
      "pos": [
        50193,
        50223
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information",
      "pos": [
        50224,
        50235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3",
      "pos": [
        50236,
        50237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "85d077ab -…",
      "pos": [
        50238,
        50249
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Response received.",
      "pos": [
        50250,
        50268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Status code = 403, Request ID = 9d67c64a-64ed-4b0d-9515-3b14bbcdc63d, Content-MD5 = , ETag = .",
      "pos": [
        50269,
        50363
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage",
      "pos": [
        50364,
        50394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Warning",
      "pos": [
        50395,
        50402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2",
      "pos": [
        50403,
        50404
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "85d077ab -…",
      "pos": [
        50405,
        50416
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exception thrown during the operation: The remote server returned an error: (403) Forbidden..",
      "pos": [
        50417,
        50510
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage",
      "pos": [
        50511,
        50541
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information",
      "pos": [
        50542,
        50553
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3",
      "pos": [
        50554,
        50555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "85d077ab -…",
      "pos": [
        50557,
        50568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Checking if the operation should be retried.",
      "pos": [
        50569,
        50613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retry count = 0, HTTP status code = 403, Exception = The remote server returned an error: (403) Forbidden..",
      "pos": [
        50614,
        50721
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage",
      "pos": [
        50723,
        50753
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information",
      "pos": [
        50754,
        50765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3",
      "pos": [
        50766,
        50767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "85d077ab -…",
      "pos": [
        50768,
        50779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The next location has been set to Primary, based on the location mode.",
      "pos": [
        50780,
        50850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage",
      "pos": [
        50851,
        50881
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Error",
      "pos": [
        50882,
        50887
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        50888,
        50889
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "85d077ab -…",
      "pos": [
        50890,
        50901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retry policy did not allow for a retry.",
      "pos": [
        50902,
        50941
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Failing with The remote server returned an error: (403) Forbidden.",
      "pos": [
        50942,
        51008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this scenario, you should investigate why the SAS token is expiring before the client sends the token to the server:",
      "pos": [
        51010,
        51129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, you should not set a start time when you create a SAS for a client to use immediately.",
      "pos": [
        51133,
        51230
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If there are small clock differences between the host generating the SAS using the current time and the storage service, then it is possible for the storage service to receive a SAS that is not yet valid.",
      "pos": [
        51231,
        51435
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should not set a very short expiry time on a SAS.",
      "pos": [
        51438,
        51491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Again, small clock differences between the host generating the SAS and the storage service can lead to a SAS apparently expiring earlier than anticipated.",
      "pos": [
        51492,
        51646
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Does the version parameter in the SAS key (for example <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sv=2012-02-12<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>) match the version of the Storage Client Library you are using.",
      "pos": [
        51649,
        51785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should always use the latest version of the Storage Client Library.",
      "pos": [
        51786,
        51857
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information on SAS token versioning and dependencies on client library version see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2014/05/14/what-s-new-for-microsoft-azure-storage-at-teched-2014.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        51858,
        52103
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you regenerate your storage access keys (click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Manage Access Keys<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on any page in your storage account in the Azure portal) this can invalidate any existing SAS tokens.",
      "pos": [
        52107,
        52281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This may be an issue if you generate SAS tokens with a long expiry time for client applications to cache.",
      "pos": [
        52282,
        52387
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using the Storage Client Library to generate SAS tokens, then it is easy to build a valid token.",
      "pos": [
        52389,
        52496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, if you are using the Storage REST API and constructing the SAS tokens by hand you should carefully read the topic <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee395415.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Delegating Access with a Shared Access Signature<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN.",
      "pos": [
        52497,
        52761
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        52767,
        52871
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"the-client-is-receiving-404-messages\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>The client is receiving HTTP 404 (Not found) messages"
    },
    {
      "content": "If the client application receives an HTTP 404 (Not found) message from the server, this implies that the object the client was attempting to use (such as an entity, table, blob, container, or queue) does not exist in the storage service.",
      "pos": [
        52872,
        53110
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are a number of possible reasons for this, such as:",
      "pos": [
        53111,
        53168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[The client or another process previously deleted the object]",
      "pos": [
        53172,
        53233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[A Shared Access Signature (SAS) authorization issue]",
      "pos": [
        53236,
        53289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Client-side JavaScript code does not have permission to access the object]",
      "pos": [
        53292,
        53367
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Network failure]",
      "pos": [
        53370,
        53387
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        53394,
        53504
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"client-previously-deleted-the-object\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>The client or another process previously deleted the object"
    },
    {
      "content": "In scenarios where the client is attempting to read, update, or delete data in a storage service it is usually easy to identify in the server-side logs a previous operation that deleted the object in question from the storage service.",
      "pos": [
        53505,
        53739
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Very often, the log data shows that another user or process deleted the object.",
      "pos": [
        53740,
        53819
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the server-side Storage Logging log, the operation-type and requested-object-key columns show when a client deleted an object.",
      "pos": [
        53820,
        53949
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the scenario where a client is attempting to insert an object, it may not be immediately obvious why this results in an HTTP 404 (Not found) response given that the client is creating a new object.",
      "pos": [
        53951,
        54151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, if the client is creating a blob it must be able to find the blob container, if the client is creating a message it must be able to find a queue, and if the client is adding a row it must be able to find the table.",
      "pos": [
        54152,
        54375
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the client-side log from the Storage Client Library to gain a more detailed understanding of when the client sends specific requests to the storage service.",
      "pos": [
        54378,
        54546
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following client-side log generated by the Storage Client library illustrates the problem when the client cannot find the container for the blob it is creating.",
      "pos": [
        54548,
        54712
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This log includes details of the following storage operations:",
      "pos": [
        54713,
        54775
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Request ID",
      "pos": [
        54777,
        54787
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation",
      "pos": [
        54788,
        54797
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        54806,
        54818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DeleteIfExists<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method to delete the blob container.",
      "pos": [
        54819,
        54874
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that this operation includes a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>HEAD<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> request to check for the existence of the container.",
      "pos": [
        54875,
        54972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78…",
      "pos": [
        54973,
        54982
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CreateIfNotExists<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method to create the blob container.",
      "pos": [
        54983,
        55041
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that this operation includes a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>HEAD<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> request that checks for the existence of the container.",
      "pos": [
        55042,
        55142
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>HEAD<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> returns a 404 message but continues.",
      "pos": [
        55143,
        55192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        55193,
        55205
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>UploadFromStream<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method to create the blob.",
      "pos": [
        55206,
        55253
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PUT<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> request fails with a 404 message",
      "pos": [
        55254,
        55298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log entries:",
      "pos": [
        55300,
        55312
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Request ID",
      "pos": [
        55314,
        55324
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation Text",
      "pos": [
        55328,
        55342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        55351,
        55363
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting synchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer.",
      "pos": [
        55364,
        55460
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        55461,
        55473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StringToSign = HEAD............x-ms-client-request-id:07b26a5d-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:11 GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer.restype:container.",
      "pos": [
        55474,
        55658
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        55659,
        55671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Waiting for response.",
      "pos": [
        55672,
        55693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        55694,
        55706
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Response received.",
      "pos": [
        55709,
        55727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Status code = 200, Request ID = eeead849-...Content-MD5 = , ETag =    &amp;quot;0x8D14D2DC63D059B&amp;quot;.",
      "pos": [
        55728,
        55828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        55829,
        55841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Response headers were processed successfully, proceeding with the rest of the operation.",
      "pos": [
        55844,
        55932
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        55933,
        55945
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Downloading response body.",
      "pos": [
        55948,
        55974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        55975,
        55987
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation completed successfully.",
      "pos": [
        55990,
        56023
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        56024,
        56036
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting synchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer.",
      "pos": [
        56039,
        56135
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        56136,
        56148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StringToSign = DELETE............x-ms-client-request-id:07b26a5d-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:12    GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer.restype:container.",
      "pos": [
        56151,
        56340
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        56341,
        56353
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Waiting for response.",
      "pos": [
        56356,
        56377
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        56378,
        56390
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Response received.",
      "pos": [
        56393,
        56411
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Status code = 202, Request ID = 6ab2a4cf-..., Content-MD5 = , ETag = .",
      "pos": [
        56412,
        56482
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        56483,
        56495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Response headers were processed successfully, proceeding with the rest of the operation.",
      "pos": [
        56498,
        56586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        56587,
        56599
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Downloading response body.",
      "pos": [
        56602,
        56628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "07b26a5d-...",
      "pos": [
        56629,
        56641
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation completed successfully.",
      "pos": [
        56644,
        56677
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        56678,
        56690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting asynchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer.",
      "pos": [
        56693,
        56790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        56796,
        56808
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StringToSign = HEAD............x-ms-client-request-id:e2d06d78-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:12 GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer.restype:container.",
      "pos": [
        56811,
        56995
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        56996,
        57008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Waiting for response.",
      "pos": [
        57010,
        57031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        57032,
        57044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting synchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer/blobCreated.txt.",
      "pos": [
        57047,
        57159
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        57160,
        57172
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StringToSign = PUT...64.qCmF+TQLPhq/YYK50mP9ZQ==........x-ms-blob-type:BlockBlob.x-ms-client-request-id:de8b1c3c-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:12 GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer/blobCreated.txt.",
      "pos": [
        57176,
        57408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        57409,
        57421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Preparing to write request data.",
      "pos": [
        57424,
        57456
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        57457,
        57469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exception thrown while waiting for response: The remote server returned an error: (404) Not Found..",
      "pos": [
        57472,
        57571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        57572,
        57584
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Response received.",
      "pos": [
        57587,
        57605
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Status code = 404, Request ID = 353ae3bc-..., Content-MD5 = , ETag = .",
      "pos": [
        57606,
        57676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        57677,
        57689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Response headers were processed successfully, proceeding with the rest of the operation.",
      "pos": [
        57692,
        57780
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        57781,
        57793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Downloading response body.",
      "pos": [
        57796,
        57822
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        57823,
        57835
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation completed successfully.",
      "pos": [
        57838,
        57871
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        57872,
        57884
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting asynchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer.",
      "pos": [
        57887,
        57984
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        57985,
        57997
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StringToSign = PUT...0.........x-ms-client-request-id:e2d06d78-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:12 GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer.restype:container.",
      "pos": [
        57998,
        58182
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        58183,
        58195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Waiting for response.",
      "pos": [
        58198,
        58219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        58220,
        58232
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Writing request data.",
      "pos": [
        58235,
        58256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        58257,
        58269
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Waiting for response.",
      "pos": [
        58272,
        58293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        58295,
        58307
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exception thrown while waiting for response: The remote server returned an error: (409) Conflict..",
      "pos": [
        58310,
        58408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        58409,
        58421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Response received.",
      "pos": [
        58424,
        58442
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Status code = 409, Request ID = c27da20e-..., Content-MD5 = , ETag = .",
      "pos": [
        58443,
        58513
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        58514,
        58526
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Downloading error response body.",
      "pos": [
        58529,
        58561
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        58562,
        58574
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exception thrown while waiting for response: The remote server returned an error: (404) Not Found..",
      "pos": [
        58577,
        58676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        58677,
        58689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Response received.",
      "pos": [
        58692,
        58710
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Status code = 404, Request ID = 0eaeab3e-..., Content-MD5 = , ETag = .",
      "pos": [
        58711,
        58781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        58782,
        58794
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Exception thrown during the operation: The remote server returned an error: (404) Not Found..",
      "pos": [
        58796,
        58889
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "de8b1c3c-...",
      "pos": [
        58890,
        58902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retry policy did not allow for a retry.",
      "pos": [
        58905,
        58944
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Failing with The remote server returned an error: (404) Not Found..",
      "pos": [
        58945,
        59012
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "e2d06d78-...",
      "pos": [
        59013,
        59025
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Retry policy did not allow for a retry.",
      "pos": [
        59028,
        59067
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Failing with The remote server returned an error: (409) Conflict..",
      "pos": [
        59068,
        59134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example, the log shows that the client is interleaving requests from the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CreateIfNotExists<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method (request id e2d06d78…) with the requests from the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>UploadFromStream<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> method (de8b1c3c-...); this is happening because the client application is invoking these methods asynchronously.",
      "pos": [
        59136,
        59430
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should modify the asynchronous code in the client to ensure that it creates the container before attempting to upload any data to a blob in that container.",
      "pos": [
        59431,
        59590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ideally, you should create all your containers in advance.",
      "pos": [
        59591,
        59649
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        59656,
        59745
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"SAS-authorization-issue\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>A Shared Access Signature (SAS) authorization issue"
    },
    {
      "content": "If the client application attempts to use a SAS key that does not include the necessary permissions for the operation, the storage service returns an HTTP 404 (Not found) message to the client.",
      "pos": [
        59747,
        59940
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At the same time, you will also see a non-zero value for <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SASAuthorizationError<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the metrics.",
      "pos": [
        59941,
        60039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following table shows a sample server-side log message from the Storage Logging log file:",
      "pos": [
        60041,
        60134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Request start time",
      "pos": [
        60159,
        60177
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2014-05-30T06:17:48.4473697Z",
      "pos": [
        60191,
        60219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation type",
      "pos": [
        60248,
        60262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "GetBlobProperties",
      "pos": [
        60276,
        60293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Request status",
      "pos": [
        60322,
        60336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SASAuthorizationError",
      "pos": [
        60350,
        60371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "HTTP status code",
      "pos": [
        60400,
        60416
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "404",
      "pos": [
        60430,
        60433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Authentication type",
      "pos": [
        60462,
        60481
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sas",
      "pos": [
        60495,
        60498
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service type",
      "pos": [
        60527,
        60539
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Blob",
      "pos": [
        60553,
        60557
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Request URL",
      "pos": [
        60586,
        60597
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Request id header",
      "pos": [
        60835,
        60852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "a1f348d5-8032-4912-93ef-b393e5252a3b",
      "pos": [
        60866,
        60902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Client request ID",
      "pos": [
        60931,
        60948
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2d064953-8436-4ee0-aa0c-65cb874f7929",
      "pos": [
        60962,
        60998
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should investigate why your client application is attempting to perform an operation it has not been granted permissions for.",
      "pos": [
        61022,
        61151
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        61158,
        61286
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"JavaScript-code-does-not-have-permission\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Client-side JavaScript code does not have permission to access the object"
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using a JavaScript client and the storage service is returning HTTP 404 messages, you check for the following JavaScript errors in the browser:",
      "pos": [
        61288,
        61442
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        61615,
        61820
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> You can use the F12 Developer Tools in Internet Explorer to trace the messages exchanged between the browser and the storage service when you are troubleshooting client-side JavaScript issues."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        61823,
        62105
      ],
      "content": "These errors occur because the web browser implements the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.w3.org/Security/wiki/Same_Origin_Policy\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>same-origin policy<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> security restriction that prevents a web page from calling an API in a different domain from the domain the page comes from."
    },
    {
      "content": "To work around the JavaScript issue, you can configure Cross Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) for the storage service the client is accessing.",
      "pos": [
        62108,
        62248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn535601.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) Support for Azure Storage Services<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN.",
      "pos": [
        62249,
        62439
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following code sample shows how to configure your blob service to allow JavaScript running in the Contoso domain to access a blob in your blob storage service:",
      "pos": [
        62441,
        62604
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        63213,
        63258
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"network-failure\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Network Failure"
    },
    {
      "content": "In some circumstances, lost network packets can lead to the storage service returning HTTP 404 messages to the client.",
      "pos": [
        63261,
        63379
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, when your client application is deleting an entity from the table service you see the client throw a storage exception reporting an \"HTTP 404 (Not Found)\" status message from the table service.",
      "pos": [
        63380,
        63586
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you investigate the table in the table storage service, you see that the service did delete the entity as requested.",
      "pos": [
        63587,
        63708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The exception details in the client include the request id (7e84f12d…) assigned by the table service for the request: you can use this information to locate the request details in the server-side storage logs by searching in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>request-id-header<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column in the log file.",
      "pos": [
        63710,
        63984
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You could also use the metrics to identify when failures such as this occur and then search the log files based on the time the metrics recorded this error.",
      "pos": [
        63985,
        64141
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This log entry shows that the delete failed with an \"HTTP (404) Client Other Error\" status message.",
      "pos": [
        64142,
        64241
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The same log entry also includes the request id generated by the client in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>client-request-id<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column (813ea74f…).",
      "pos": [
        64242,
        64362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The server-side log also includes another entry with the same <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>client-request-id<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> value (813ea74f…) for a successful delete operation for the same entity, and from the same client.",
      "pos": [
        64364,
        64546
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This successful delete operation took place very shortly before the failed delete request.",
      "pos": [
        64547,
        64637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The most likely cause of this scenario is that the client sent a delete request for the entity to the table service, which succeeded, but did not receive an acknowledgement from the server (perhaps due to a temporary network issue).",
      "pos": [
        64639,
        64871
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The client then automatically retried the operation (using the same <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>client-request-id<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>), and this retry failed because the entity had already been deleted.",
      "pos": [
        64872,
        65030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If this problem occurs frequently, you should investigate why the client is failing to receive acknowledgements from the table service.",
      "pos": [
        65032,
        65167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the problem is intermittent, you should trap the \"HTTP (404) Not Found\" error and log it in the client, but allow the client to continue.",
      "pos": [
        65168,
        65308
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        65314,
        65417
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"the-client-is-receiving-409-messages\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>The client is receiving HTTP 409 (Conflict) messages"
    },
    {
      "content": "The following table shows an extract from the server-side log for two client operations: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DeleteIfExists<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> followed immediately by <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>CreateIfNotExists<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> using the same blob container name.",
      "pos": [
        65419,
        65608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that each client operation results in two requests sent to the server, first a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GetContainerProperties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> request to check if the container exists, followed by the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DeleteContainer<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>CreateContainer<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> request.",
      "pos": [
        65609,
        65829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Timestamp",
      "pos": [
        65831,
        65840
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operation",
      "pos": [
        65841,
        65850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Result",
      "pos": [
        65851,
        65857
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Container name",
      "pos": [
        65858,
        65872
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Client request id",
      "pos": [
        65873,
        65890
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "05:10:13.7167225",
      "pos": [
        65911,
        65927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "GetContainerProperties",
      "pos": [
        65928,
        65950
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "200",
      "pos": [
        65951,
        65954
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "mmcont",
      "pos": [
        65955,
        65961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "c9f52c89-…",
      "pos": [
        65962,
        65972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "05:10:13.8167325",
      "pos": [
        65973,
        65989
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DeleteContainer",
      "pos": [
        65990,
        66005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "202",
      "pos": [
        66006,
        66009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "mmcont",
      "pos": [
        66010,
        66016
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "c9f52c89-…",
      "pos": [
        66017,
        66027
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "05:10:13.8987407",
      "pos": [
        66028,
        66044
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "GetContainerProperties",
      "pos": [
        66045,
        66067
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "404",
      "pos": [
        66068,
        66071
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "mmcont",
      "pos": [
        66072,
        66078
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "bc881924-…",
      "pos": [
        66079,
        66089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "05:10:14.2147723",
      "pos": [
        66090,
        66106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CreateContainer",
      "pos": [
        66107,
        66122
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "409",
      "pos": [
        66123,
        66126
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "mmcont",
      "pos": [
        66127,
        66133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "bc881924-…",
      "pos": [
        66134,
        66144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The code in the client application deletes and then immediately recreates a blob container using the same name: the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CreateIfNotExists<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method (Client request ID bc881924-…) eventually fails with the HTTP 409 (Conflict) error.",
      "pos": [
        66146,
        66374
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a client deletes blob containers, tables, or queues there is a brief period before the name becomes available again.",
      "pos": [
        66375,
        66496
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The client application should use unique container names whenever it creates new containers if the delete/recreate pattern is common.",
      "pos": [
        66498,
        66631
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        66637,
        66801
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"metrics-show-low-percent-success\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Metrics show low PercentSuccess or analytics log entries have operations with transaction status of ClientOtherErrors"
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentSuccess<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> metric captures the percent of operations that were successful based on their HTTP Status Code.",
      "pos": [
        66803,
        66921
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operations with status codes of 2XX count as successful, whereas operations with status codes in 3XX, 4XX and 5XX ranges are counted as unsuccessful and lower the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>PercentSucess<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> metric value.",
      "pos": [
        66922,
        67116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the server-side storage log files, these operations are recorded with a transaction status of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ClientOtherErrors<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        67117,
        67236
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is important to note that these operations have completed successfully and therefore do not affect other metrics such as availability.",
      "pos": [
        67239,
        67376
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some examples of operations that execute successfully but that can result in unsuccessful HTTP status codes include:",
      "pos": [
        67377,
        67493
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        67496,
        67595
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ResourceNotFound<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (Not Found 404), for example from a GET request to a blob that does not exist."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        67598,
        67723
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ResouceAlreadyExists<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (Conflict 409), for example from a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>CreateIfNotExist<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> operation where the resource already exists."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        67726,
        67963
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ConditionNotMet<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (Not Modified 304), for example from a conditional operation such as when a client sends an <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ETag<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> value and an HTTP <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>If-None-Match<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> header to request an image only if it has been updated since the last operation."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        67965,
        68173
      ],
      "content": "You can find a list of common REST API error codes that the storage services return on the page <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179357.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Common REST API Error Codes<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        68180,
        68309
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"capacity-metrics-show-an-unexpected-increase\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Capacity metrics show an unexpected increase in storage capacity usage"
    },
    {
      "content": "If you see sudden, unexpected changes in capacity usage in your storage account, you can investigate the reasons by first looking at your availability metrics; for example, an increase in the number of failed delete requests might lead to an increase in the amount of blob storage you are using as application specific cleanup operations you might have expected to be freeing up space may not be working as expected (for example, because the SAS tokens used for freeing up space have expired).",
      "pos": [
        68312,
        68805
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        68812,
        68967
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"you-are-experiencing-unexpected-reboots\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>You are experiencing unexpected reboots of Virtual Machines that have a large number of attached VHDs"
    },
    {
      "content": "If a Virtual Machine (VM) has a large number of attached VHDs that are in the same storage account, you could exceed the scalability targets for an individual storage account causing the VM to fail.",
      "pos": [
        68969,
        69167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should check the minute metrics for the storage account (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>TotalRequests<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>/<bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>TotalIngress<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>/<bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>TotalEgress<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>) for spikes that exceed the scalability targets for a storage account.",
      "pos": [
        69168,
        69350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the section \"[Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError]\" for assistance in determining if throttling has occurred on your storage account.",
      "pos": [
        69351,
        69503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In general, each individual input or output operation on a VHD from a Virtual Machine translates to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get Page<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Put Page<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> operations on the underlying page blob.",
      "pos": [
        69506,
        69674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Therefore, you can use the estimated IOPS for your environment to tune how many VHDs you can have in a single storage account based on the specific behavior of your application.",
      "pos": [
        69675,
        69852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We do not recommend having more than 40 disks in a single storage account.",
      "pos": [
        69853,
        69927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn249410.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Azure Storage Scalability and Performance Targets<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> for details of the current scalability targets for storage accounts, in particular the total request rate and total bandwidth for the type of storage account you are using.",
      "pos": [
        69928,
        70238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are exceeding the scalability targets for your storage account, you should place your VHDs in multiple different storage accounts to reduce the activity in each individual account.",
      "pos": [
        70240,
        70427
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        70433,
        70570
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"your-issue-arises-from-using-the-storage-emulator\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Your issue arises from using the storage emulator for development or test"
    },
    {
      "content": "You typically use the storage emulator during development and test to avoid the requirement for an Azure storage account.",
      "pos": [
        70572,
        70693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The common issues that can occur when you are using the storage emulator are:",
      "pos": [
        70694,
        70771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Feature \"X\" is not working in the storage emulator]",
      "pos": [
        70775,
        70827
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Error \"The value for one of the HTTP headers is not in the correct format\" when using the storage emulator]",
      "pos": [
        70830,
        70938
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "[Running the storage emulator requires administrative privileges]",
      "pos": [
        70941,
        71006
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        71013,
        71102
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"feature-X-is-not-working\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Feature \"X\" is not working in the storage emulator"
    },
    {
      "content": "The storage emulator does not support all of the features of the Azure storage services such as the file service.",
      "pos": [
        71104,
        71217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/gg433135.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Differences Between the Storage Emulator and Azure Storage Services<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN.",
      "pos": [
        71218,
        71404
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For those features that the storage emulator does not support, use the Azure storage service in the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        71406,
        71512
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        71519,
        71676
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"error-HTTP-header-not-correct-format\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Error \"The value for one of the HTTP headers is not in the correct format\" when using the storage emulator"
    },
    {
      "content": "You are testing your application that use the Storage Client Library against the local storage emulator and method calls such as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CreateIfNotExists<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> fail with the error message \"The value for one of the HTTP headers is not in the correct format.\"",
      "pos": [
        71678,
        71926
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This indicates that the version of the storage emulator you are using does not support the version of the storage client library you are using.",
      "pos": [
        71927,
        72070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Storage Client Library adds the header <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x-ms-version<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to all the requests it makes.",
      "pos": [
        72071,
        72160
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the storage emulator does not recognize the value in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x-ms-version<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> header, it rejects the request.",
      "pos": [
        72161,
        72269
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the Storage Library Client logs to see the value of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x-ms-version header<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> it is sending.",
      "pos": [
        72271,
        72377
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also see the value of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>x-ms-version header<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> if you use Fiddler to trace the requests from your client application.",
      "pos": [
        72378,
        72506
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This scenario typically occurs if you install and use the latest version of the Storage Client Library without updating the storage emulator.",
      "pos": [
        72508,
        72649
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should either install the latest version of the storage emulator, or use cloud storage instead of the emulator for development and test.",
      "pos": [
        72650,
        72790
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        72797,
        72926
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"storage-emulator-requires-administrative-privileges\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Running the storage emulator requires administrative privileges"
    },
    {
      "content": "You are prompted for administrator credentials when you run the storage emulator.",
      "pos": [
        72928,
        73009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This only occurs when you are initializing the storage emulator for the first time.",
      "pos": [
        73010,
        73093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you have initialized the storage emulator, you do not need administrative privileges to run it again.",
      "pos": [
        73094,
        73201
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        73204,
        73500
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/gg433132.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Initialize the Storage Emulator by Using the Command-Line Tool<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on MSDN (you can also initialize the storage emulator in Visual Studio, which will also require administrative privileges)."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        73506,
        73646
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"you-are-encountering-problems-installing-the-Windows-Azure-SDK\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>You are encountering problems installing the Azure SDK for .NET"
    },
    {
      "content": "When you try to install the SDK, it fails trying to install the storage emulator on your local machine.",
      "pos": [
        73648,
        73751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The installation log contains one of the following messages:",
      "pos": [
        73752,
        73812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CAQuietExec:  Error: Unable to access SQL instance",
      "pos": [
        73816,
        73866
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "CAQuietExec:  Error: Unable to create database",
      "pos": [
        73869,
        73915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cause is an issue with existing LocalDB installation.",
      "pos": [
        73917,
        73974
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default, the storage emulator uses LocalDB to persist data when it simulates the Azure storage services.",
      "pos": [
        73975,
        74082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can reset your LocalDB instance by running the following commands in a command-prompt window before trying to install the SDK.",
      "pos": [
        74083,
        74213
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        74347,
        74453
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>delete<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> command removes any old database files from previous installations of the storage emulator."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        74459,
        74572
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"you-have-a-different-issue-with-a-storage-service\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>You have a different issue with a storage service"
    },
    {
      "content": "If the previous troubleshooting sections do not include the issue you are having with a storage service, you should adopt the following approach to diagnosing and troubleshooting your issue.",
      "pos": [
        74574,
        74764
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check your metrics to see if there is any change from your expected base-line behavior.",
      "pos": [
        74768,
        74855
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From the metrics, you may be able to determine whether the issue is transient or permanent, and which storage operations the issue is affecting.",
      "pos": [
        74856,
        75000
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the metrics information to help you search your server-side log data for more detailed information about any errors that are occurring.",
      "pos": [
        75003,
        75150
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This information may help you troubleshoot and resolve the issue.",
      "pos": [
        75151,
        75216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the information in the server-side logs is not sufficient to troubleshoot the issue successfully, you can use the Storage Client Library client-side logs to investigate the behavior of your client application, and tools such as Fiddler, Wireshark, and Microsoft Message Analyzer to investigate your network.",
      "pos": [
        75219,
        75529
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about using Fiddler, see \"[Appendix 1: Using Fiddler to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic].\"",
      "pos": [
        75531,
        75641
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about using Wireshark, see \"[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic].\"",
      "pos": [
        75643,
        75750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about using Microsoft Message Analyzer, see \"[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic].\"",
      "pos": [
        75752,
        75893
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        75898,
        75933
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"appendices\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Appendices"
    },
    {
      "content": "The appendices describe several tools that you may find useful when you are diagnosing and troubleshooting issues with Azure Storage (and other services).",
      "pos": [
        75935,
        76089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These tools are not part of Azure Storage and some are third-party products.",
      "pos": [
        76090,
        76166
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As such, the tools discussed in these appendices are not covered by any support agreement you may have with Microsoft Azure or Azure Storage, and therefore as part of your evaluation process you should examine the licensing and support options available from the providers of these tools.",
      "pos": [
        76167,
        76455
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        76461,
        76545
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"appendix-1\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Appendix 1: Using Fiddler to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic"
    },
    {
      "content": "Fiddler is a useful tool for analyzing the HTTP and HTTPS traffic between your client application and the Azure storage service you are using.",
      "pos": [
        76547,
        76689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download Fiddler from <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.telerik.com/fiddler\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>http://www.telerik.com/fiddler<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        76690,
        76812
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        76816,
        76991
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Fiddler can decode HTTPS traffic; you should read the Fiddler documentation carefully to understand how it does this, and to understand the security implications."
    },
    {
      "content": "This appendix provides a brief walkthrough of how to configure Fiddler to capture traffic between the local machine where you have installed Fiddler and the Azure storage services.",
      "pos": [
        76993,
        77173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you have launched Fiddler, it will begin capturing HTTP and HTTPS traffic on your local machine.",
      "pos": [
        77175,
        77277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following are some useful commands for controlling Fiddler:",
      "pos": [
        77278,
        77341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Stop and start capturing traffic.",
      "pos": [
        77345,
        77378
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the main menu, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>File<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Capture Traffic<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to toggle capturing on and off.",
      "pos": [
        77379,
        77478
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Save captured traffic data.",
      "pos": [
        77481,
        77508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the main menu, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>File<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>All Sessions<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>: this enables you to save the traffic in a Session Archive file.",
      "pos": [
        77509,
        77655
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can reload a Session Archive later for analysis, or send it if requested to Microsoft support.",
      "pos": [
        77656,
        77754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To limit the amount of traffic that Fiddler captures, you can use filters that you configure in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Filters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.",
      "pos": [
        77756,
        77872
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following screenshot shows a filter that captures only traffic sent to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>contosoemaildist.table.core.windows.net<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> storage endpoint:",
      "pos": [
        77873,
        78013
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        78027,
        78106
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"appendix-2\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic"
    },
    {
      "content": "Wireshark is a network protocol analyzer that enables you to view detailed packet information for a wide range of network protocols.",
      "pos": [
        78108,
        78240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download Wireshark from <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.wireshark.org/\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>http://www.wireshark.org/<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        78241,
        78355
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following procedure shows you how to capture detailed packet information for traffic from the local machine where you installed Wireshark to the table service in your Azure storage account.",
      "pos": [
        78357,
        78550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Launch Wireshark on your local machine.",
      "pos": [
        78556,
        78595
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        78600,
        78710
      ],
      "content": "In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Start<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section, select the local network interface or interfaces that are connected to the internet."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        78715,
        78741
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Capture Options<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Add a filter to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Capture Filter<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> textbox.",
      "pos": [
        78746,
        78793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>host contosoemaildist.table.core.windows.net<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> will configure Wireshark to capture only packets sent to or from the table service endpoint in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>contosoemaildist<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> storage account.",
      "pos": [
        78794,
        78992
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a complete list of Capture Filters see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://wiki.wireshark.org/CaptureFilters\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>http://wiki.wireshark.org/CaptureFilters<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        78993,
        79148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Start<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        79167,
        79183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Wireshark will now capture all the packets send to or from the table service endpoint as you use your client application on your local machine.",
      "pos": [
        79184,
        79327
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        79332,
        79409
      ],
      "content": "When you have finished, on the main menu click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Capture<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and then <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Stop<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        79414,
        79519
      ],
      "content": "To save the captured data in a Wireshark Capture File, on the main menu click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>File<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and then <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "WireShark will highlight any errors that exist in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>packetlist<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> window.",
      "pos": [
        79521,
        79597
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Expert Info<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> window (click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Analyze<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, then <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Expert Info<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>) to view a summary of errors and warnings.",
      "pos": [
        79598,
        79725
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also chose to view the TCP data as the application layer sees it by right-clicking on the TCP data and selecting <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Follow TCP Stream<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        79735,
        79878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is particularly useful if you captured your dump without a capture filter.",
      "pos": [
        79879,
        79958
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsug_html_chunked/ChAdvFollowTCPSection.html\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>here<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        79959,
        80094
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        80106,
        80272
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> For more information about using Wireshark, see the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;a href=\"http://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsug_html_chunked/\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Wireshark Users Guide<ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        80278,
        80374
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"appendix-3\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic"
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic in a similar way to Fiddler, and capture network traffic in a similar way to Wireshark.",
      "pos": [
        80376,
        80536
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure a web tracing session using Microsoft Message Analyzer",
      "pos": [
        80543,
        80607
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To configure a web tracing session for HTTP and HTTPS traffic using Microsoft Message Analyzer, run the Microsoft Message Analyzer application and then on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>File<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Capture/Trace<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        80609,
        80807
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the list of available trace scenarios, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Web Proxy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        80808,
        80871
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Trace Scenario Configuration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> panel, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>HostnameFilter<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> textbox, add the names of your storage endpoints (you can look up these names in the Azure portal).",
      "pos": [
        80872,
        81049
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if the name of your Azure storage account is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>contosodata<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you should add the following to the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>HostnameFilter<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> textbox:",
      "pos": [
        81050,
        81188
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        81305,
        81360
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> A space character separates the hostnames."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        81363,
        81446
      ],
      "content": "When you are ready to start collecting trace data, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Start With<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        81448,
        81645
      ],
      "content": "For more information about the Microsoft Message Analyzer <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Web Proxy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> trace, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj674814.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>PEF-WebProxy Provider<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on TechNet."
    },
    {
      "content": "The built-in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Web Proxy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> trace in Microsoft Message Analyzer is based on Fiddler; it can capture client-side HTTPS traffic and display unencrypted HTTPS messages.",
      "pos": [
        81647,
        81811
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Web Proxy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> trace works by configuring a local proxy for all HTTP and HTTPS traffic that gives it access to unencrypted messages.",
      "pos": [
        81812,
        81947
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Diagnosing network issues using Microsoft Message Analyzer",
      "pos": [
        81954,
        82012
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition to using the Microsoft Message Analyzer <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Web Proxy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> trace to capture details of the HTTP/HTTPs traffic between the client application and the storage service, you can also use the built-in <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Local Link Layer<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> trace to capture network packet information.",
      "pos": [
        82014,
        82282
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This enables you to capture data similar to that which you can capture with Wireshark, and diagnose network issues such as dropped packets.",
      "pos": [
        82283,
        82422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following screenshot shows an example <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Local Link Layer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> trace with some <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>informational<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> messages in the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>DiagnosisTypes<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> column.",
      "pos": [
        82424,
        82563
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Clicking on an icon in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DiagnosisTypes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column shows the details of the message.",
      "pos": [
        82564,
        82650
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example, the server retransmitted message #305 because it did not receive an acknowledgement from the client:",
      "pos": [
        82651,
        82768
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create the trace session in Microsoft Message Analyzer, you can specify filters to reduce the amount of noise in the trace.",
      "pos": [
        82778,
        82910
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Capture / Trace<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page where you define the trace, click on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> link next to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Microsoft-Windows-NDIS-PacketCapture<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        82911,
        83052
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following screenshot shows a configuration that filters TCP traffic for the IP addresses of three storage services:",
      "pos": [
        83053,
        83172
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        83183,
        83393
      ],
      "content": "For more information about the Microsoft Message Analyzer Local Link Layer trace, see <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj659264.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>PEF-NDIS-PacketCapture Provider<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> on TechNet."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        83399,
        83476
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"appendix-4\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Appendix 4: Using Excel to view metrics and log data"
    },
    {
      "content": "Many tools enable you to download the Storage Metrics data from Azure table storage in a delimited format that makes it easy to load the data into Excel for viewing and analysis.",
      "pos": [
        83478,
        83656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage Logging data from Azure blob storage is already in a delimited format that you can load into Excel.",
      "pos": [
        83657,
        83764
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, you will need to add appropriate column headings based in the information at <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343259.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Storage Analytics Log Format<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> and <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343264.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Storage Analytics Metrics Table Schema<ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        83765,
        84091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To import your Storage Logging data into Excel after you download it from blob storage:",
      "pos": [
        84093,
        84180
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        84184,
        84226
      ],
      "content": "On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>From Text<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        84229,
        84290
      ],
      "content": "Browse to the log file you want to view and click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Import<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        84293,
        84355
      ],
      "content": "On step 1 of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Text Import Wizard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Delimited<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "On step 1 of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Text Import Wizard<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Semicolon<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> as the only delimiter and choose double-quote as the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Text qualifier<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        84357,
        84491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Finish<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and choose where to place the data in your workbook.",
      "pos": [
        84492,
        84566
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        84572,
        84670
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"appendix-5\"&gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Appendix 5: Monitoring with Application Insights for Visual Studio Online"
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also use the Application Insights feature for Visual Studio Online as part of your performance and availability monitoring.",
      "pos": [
        84672,
        84803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tool can:",
      "pos": [
        84804,
        84818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Make sure your web service is available and responsive.",
      "pos": [
        84823,
        84878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Whether your app is a web site or a device app that uses a web service, it can test your URL every few minutes from locations around the world, and let you know if there’s a problem.",
      "pos": [
        84879,
        85061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Quickly diagnose any performance issues or exceptions in your web service.",
      "pos": [
        85065,
        85139
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Find out if CPU or other resources are being stretched, get stack traces from exceptions, and easily search through log traces.",
      "pos": [
        85140,
        85267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the app’s performance drops below acceptable limits, we can send you an email.",
      "pos": [
        85268,
        85349
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can monitor both .NET and Java web services.",
      "pos": [
        85350,
        85398
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At the time of writing Application Insights is in preview.",
      "pos": [
        85400,
        85458
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can find more information at <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn481095.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"&gt;</ph>Application Insights for Visual Studio Online on MSDN<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        85459,
        85630
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Monitor, diagnose, and troubleshoot Storage | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"Use features such as storage analytics, client-side logging, and other third-party tools to identify, diagnose, and troubleshoot Azure Storage-related issues.\" \n    services=\"storage\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"dominicbetts\" \n    manager=\"adinah\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"storage\" \n    ms.workload=\"storage\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"06/22/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"v-dobett\"/>\n\n# Monitor, diagnose, and troubleshoot Microsoft Azure Storage \n\nDiagnosing and troubleshooting issues in a distributed application hosted in a cloud environment can be more complex than in traditional environments. Applications can be deployed in a PaaS or IaaS infrastructure, on premises, on a mobile device, or in some combination of these. Typically, your application’s network traffic may traverse public and private networks and your application may use multiple storage technologies such as Microsoft Azure Storage Tables, Blobs, Queues, or Files in addition to other data stores such as relational and document databases.\n\nTo manage such applications successfully you should monitor them proactively and understand how to diagnose and troubleshoot all aspects of them and their dependent technologies. As a user of Azure Storage services, you should continuously monitor the Storage services your application uses for any unexpected changes in behavior (such as slower than usual response times), and use logging to collect more detailed data and to analyze a problem in depth. The diagnostics information you obtain from both monitoring and logging will help you to determine the root cause of the issue your application encountered. Then you can troubleshoot the issue and determine the appropriate steps you can take to remediate it. Azure Storage is a core Azure service, and forms an important part of the majority of solutions that customers deploy to the Azure infrastructure. Azure Storage includes capabilities to simplify monitoring, diagnosing, and troubleshooting storage issues in your cloud-based applications. \n\nFor a hands-on guide to end-to-end troubleshooting in Azure Storage applications, see [End-to-End Troubleshooting using Azure Storage Metrics and Logging, AzCopy, and Message Analyzer](../storage-e2e-troubleshooting/).\n\n+ [Introduction]\n    + [How this guide is organized]\n+ [Monitoring your storage service]\n    + [Monitoring service health]\n    + [Monitoring capacity]\n    + [Monitoring availability]\n    + [Monitoring performance]\n+ [Diagnosing storage issues]\n    + [Service health issues]\n    + [Performance issues]\n    + [Diagnosing errors]\n    + [Storage emulator issues]\n    + [Storage logging tools]\n    + [Using network logging tools]\n+ [End-to-end tracing]\n    + [Correlating log data]\n    + [Client request ID]\n    + [Server request ID]\n    + [Timestamps]\n+ [Troubleshooting guidance]\n    + [Metrics show high AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency]\n    + [Metrics show low AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency but the client is experiencing high latency]\n    + [Metrics show high AverageServerLatency]\n    + [You are experiencing unexpected delays in message delivery on a queue]\n    + [Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError]\n    + [Metrics show an increase in PercentTimeoutError]\n    + [Metrics show an increase in PercentNetworkError]\n    + [The client is receiving HTTP 403 (Forbidden) messages]\n    + [The client is receiving HTTP 404 (Not found) messages]\n    + [The client is receiving HTTP 409 (Conflict) messages]\n    + [Metrics show low PercentSuccess or analytics log entries have operations with transaction status of ClientOtherErrors]\n    + [Capacity metrics show an unexpected increase in storage capacity usage]\n    + [You are experiencing unexpected reboots of Virtual Machines that have a large number of attached VHDs]\n    + [Your issue arises from using the storage emulator for development or test]\n    + [You are encountering problems installing the Azure SDK for .NET]\n    + [You have a different issue with a storage service]\n+ [Appendices]\n    + [Appendix 1: Using Fiddler to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic]\n    + [Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic]\n    + [Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic]\n    + [Appendix 4: Using Excel to view metrics and log data]\n    + [Appendix 5: Monitoring with Application Insights for Visual Studio Online]\n\n## <a name=\"introduction\"></a>Introduction\n\nThis guide shows you how to use features such as Azure Storage Analytics, client-side logging in the Azure Storage Client Library, and other third-party tools to identify, diagnose, and troubleshoot Azure Storage related issues.\n\n![][1]\n\n*Figure 1 Monitoring, Diagnostics, and Troubleshooting*\n\nThis guide is intended to be read primarily by developers of online services that use Azure Storage Services and IT Pros responsible for managing such online services. The goals of this guide are:\n\n- To help you maintain the health and performance of your Azure Storage accounts.\n- To provide you with the necessary processes and tools to help you decide if an issue or problem in an application relates to Azure Storage.\n- To provide you with actionable guidance for resolving problems related to Azure Storage.\n\n### <a name=\"how-this-guide-is-organized\"></a>How this guide is organized\n\nThe section \"[Monitoring your storage service]\" describes how to monitor the health and performance of your Azure Storage services using Azure Storage Analytics Metrics (Storage Metrics).\n\nThe section \"[Diagnosing storage issues]\" describes how to diagnose issues using Azure Storage Analytics Logging (Storage Logging). It also describes how to enable client-side logging using the facilities in one of the client libraries such as the Storage Client Library for .NET or the Azure SDK for Java.\n\nThe section \"[End-to-end tracing]\" describes how you can correlate the information contained in various log files and metrics data.\n\nThe section \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" provides troubleshooting guidance for some of the common storage-related issues you might encounter.\n\nThe \"[Appendices]\" include information about using other tools such as Wireshark and Netmon for analyzing network packet data, Fiddler for analyzing HTTP/HTTPS messages, and Microsoft Message Analyzer for correlating log data.\n\n\n## <a name=\"monitoring-your-storage-service\"></a>Monitoring your storage service\n\nIf you are familiar with Windows performance monitoring, you can think of Storage Metrics as being an Azure Storage equivalent of Windows Performance Monitor counters. In Storage Metrics you will find a comprehensive set of metrics (counters in Windows Performance Monitor terminology) such as service availability, total number of requests to service, or percentage of successful requests to service (for a full list of the available metrics, see <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343264.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Storage Analytics Metrics Table Schema</a> on MSDN). You can specify whether you want the storage service to collect and aggregate metrics every hour or every minute. For more information about how to enable metrics and monitor your storage accounts, see <a href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=510865\" target=\"_blank\">Enabling storage metrics</a> on MSDN.\n\nYou can choose which hourly metrics you want to display in the Azure portal and configure rules that notify administrators by email whenever an hourly metric exceeds a particular threshold (for more information, see the page <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn306638.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">How to: Receive Alert Notifications and Manage Alert Rules in Azure</a>). The storage service collects metrics using a best effort, but may not record every storage operation.\n\nFigure 2 below shows the Monitor page in the portal where you can view metrics such as availability, total requests, and average latency numbers for a storage account. A notification rule has also been set up to alert an administrator if availability drops below a certain level. From viewing this data, one possible area for investigation is the table service success percentage being below 100% (for more information, see the section \"[Metrics show low PercentSuccess or analytics log entries have operations with transaction status of ClientOtherErrors]\").\n\n![][2]\n\n*Figure 2 Viewing storage metrics in the portal*\n\nYou should continuously monitor your Azure applications to ensure they are healthy and performing as expected by:\n\n- Establishing some baseline metrics for application that will enable you to compare current data and identify any significant changes in the behavior of Azure storage and your application. The values of your baseline metrics will, in many cases, be application specific and you should establish them when you are performance testing your application.\n- Recording minute metrics and using them to monitor actively for unexpected errors and anomalies such as spikes in error counts or request rates. \n- Recording hourly metrics and using them to monitor average values such as average error counts and request rates. \n- Investigating potential issues using diagnostics tools as discussed later in the section \"[Diagnosing storage issues].\"\n\nThe charts in Figure 3 below illustrate how the averaging that occurs for hourly metrics can hide spikes in activity. The hourly metrics appear to show a steady rate of requests, while the minute metrics reveal the fluctuations that are really taking place.\n\n![][3]\n\nThe remainder of this section describes what metrics you should monitor and why. \n\n### <a name=\"monitoring-service-health\"></a>Monitoring service health\n\nYou can use the Microsoft Azure Portal at <a href=\"https://portal.azure.com\" target=\"_blank\">https://portal.azure.com</a> to view the health of the Storage service (and other Azure services) in all the Azure regions around the world. This enables you to see immediately if an issue outside of your control is affecting the Storage service in the region you use for your application. \n\nThe Azure Portal can also provide with notifications of incidents that affect the various Azure services.\nNote: This information was previously available, along with historical data, on the Azure Service Dashboard at <a href=\"http://status.azure.com\" target=\"_blank\">http://status.azure.com</a>.\n\nWhile the portal collects health information from inside the Azure datacenters (inside-out monitoring), you could also consider adopting an outside-in approach to generate synthetic transactions that periodically access your Azure-hosted web application from multiple locations. The services offered by <a href=\"http://www.keynote.com/solutions/monitoring/web-monitoring\" target=\"_blank\">Keynote</a>, <a href=\"https://www.gomeznetworks.com/?g=1\" target=\"_blank\">Gomez</a>, and Application Insights for Visual Studio Online are examples of this outside-in approach. For more information about Application Insights for Visual Studio Online, see the appendix \"[Appendix 5: Monitoring with Application Insights for Visual Studio Online].\"\n\n### <a name=\"monitoring-capacity\"></a>Monitoring capacity\n\nStorage Metrics only stores capacity metrics for the blob service because blobs typically account for the largest proportion of stored data (at the time of writing, it is not possible to use Storage Metrics to monitor the capacity of your tables and queues). You can find this data in the **$MetricsCapacityBlob** table if you have enabled monitoring for the Blob service. Storage Metrics records this data once per day, and you can use the value of the **RowKey** to determine whether the row contains an entity that relates to user data (value **data**) or analytics data (value **analytics**). Each stored entity contains information about the amount of storage used (**Capacity** measured in bytes) and the current number of containers (**ContainerCount**) and blobs (**ObjectCount**) in use in the storage account. For more information about the capacity metrics stored in the **$MetricsCapacityBlob** table, see <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343264.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Storage Analytics Metrics Table Schema</a> on MSDN.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] You should monitor these values for an early warning that you are approaching the capacity limits of your storage account. In the Azure portal, on the **Monitor** page for your storage account, you can add alert rules to notify you if aggregate storage use exceeds or falls below thresholds that you specify.\n\nFor help estimating the size of various storage objects such as blobs, see the blog post <a href=\"http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2010/07/09/understanding-windows-azure-storage-billing-bandwidth-transactions-and-capacity.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Understanding Azure Storage Billing – Bandwidth, Transactions, and Capacity</a>.\n\n### <a name=\"monitoring-availability\"></a>Monitoring availability\n\nYou should monitor the availability of the storage services in your storage account by monitoring the value in the **Availability** column in the hourly or minute metrics tables — **$MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsBlob**, **$MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsTable**, **$MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsQueue**, **$MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsBlob**, **$MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsTable**, **$MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsQueue**, **$MetricsCapacityBlob**. The **Availability** column contains a percentage value that indicates the availability of the service or the API operation represented by the row (the **RowKey** shows if the row contains metrics for the service as a whole or for a specific API operation). \n\nAny value less than 100% indicates that some storage requests are failing. You can see why they are failing by examining the other columns in the metrics data that show the numbers of requests with different error types such as **ServerTimeoutError**. You should expect to see **Availability** fall temporarily below 100% for reasons such as transient server timeouts while the service moves partitions to better load-balance request; the retry logic in your client application should handle such intermittent conditions. The page <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343260.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"></a> lists the transaction types that Storage Metrics includes in its **Availability** calculation.\n\nIn the Azure portal, on the **Monitor** page for your storage account, you can add alert rules to notify you if **Availability** for a service falls below a threshold that you specify.\n\nThe \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" section of this guide describes some common storage service issues related to availability.\n\n### <a name=\"monitoring-performance\"></a>Monitoring performance\n\nTo monitor the performance of the storage services, you can use the following metrics from the hourly and minute metrics tables.\n\n- The values in the **AverageE2ELatency** and **AverageServerLatency** show the average time the storage service or API operation type is taking to process requests. **AverageE2ELatency** is a measure of end-to-end latency that includes the time taken to read the request and send the response in addition to the time taken to process the request (therefore includes network latency once the request reaches the storage service); **AverageServerLatency** is a measure of just the processing time and therefore excludes any network latency related to communicating with the client. See the section \"[Metrics show high AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency]\" later in this guide for a discussion of why there might be a significant difference between these two values.\n- The values in the **TotalIngress** and **TotalEgress** columns show the total amount of data, in bytes, coming in to and going out of your storage service or through a specific API operation type.\n- The values in the **TotalRequests** column show the total number of requests that the storage service of API operation is receiving. **TotalRequests** is the total number of requests that the storage service receives. \n\nTypically, you will monitor for unexpected changes in any of these values as an indicator that you have an issue that requires investigation.\n\nIn the Azure portal, on the **Monitor** page for your storage account, you can add alert rules to notify you if any of the performance metrics for this service fall below or exceed a threshold that you specify.\n\nThe \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" section of this guide describes some common storage service issues related to performance.\n\n\n## <a name=\"diagnosing-storage-issues\"></a>Diagnosing storage issues\n\nThere are a number of ways that you might become aware of a problem or issue in your application, these include:\n\n- A major failure that causes the application to crash or to stop working.\n- Significant changes from baseline values in the metrics you are monitoring as described in the previous section \"[Monitoring your storage service].\" \n- Reports from users of your application that some particular operation didn't complete as expected or that some feature is not working.\n- Errors generated within your application that appear in log files or through some other notification method.\n\nTypically, issues related to Azure storage services fall into one of four broad categories:\n\n- Your application has a performance issue, either reported by your users, or revealed by changes in the performance metrics.\n- There is a problem with the Azure Storage infrastructure in one or more regions. \n- Your application is encountering an error, either reported by your users, or revealed by an increase in one of the error count metrics you monitor.\n- During development and test, you may be using the local storage emulator; you may encounter some issues that relate specifically to usage of the storage emulator.\n\nThe following sections outline the steps you should follow to diagnose and troubleshoot issues in each of these four categories. The section \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" later in this guide provides more detail for some common issues you may encounter.\n\n### <a name=\"service-health-issues\"></a>Service health issues\n\nService health issues are typically outside of your control. The Azure Portal provides information about any ongoing issues with Azure services including storage services. If you opted for Read-Access Geo-Redundant Storage when you created your storage account, then in the event of your data being unavailable in the primary location, your application could switch temporarily to the read-only copy in the secondary location. To do this, your application must be able to switch between using the primary and secondary storage locations, and be able to work in a reduced functionality mode with read-only data. The Azure Storage Client libraries allow you to define a retry policy that can read from secondary storage in case a read from primary storage fails. Your application also needs to be aware that the data in the secondary location is eventually consistent. For more information, see the blog post <a href=\"http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2013/12/04/introducing-read-access-geo-replicated-storage-ra-grs-for-windows-azure-storage.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Azure Storage Redundancy Options and Read Access Geo Redundant Storage</a>.\n\n### <a name=\"performance-issues\"></a>Performance issues\n\nThe performance of an application can be subjective, especially from a user perspective. Therefore, it is important to have baseline metrics available to help you identify where there might be a performance issue. Many factors might affect the performance of an Azure storage service from the client application perspective. These factors might operate in the storage service, in the client, or in the network infrastructure; therefore it is important to have a strategy for identifying the origin of the performance issue.\n\nAfter you have identified the likely location of the cause of the performance issue from the metrics, you can then use the log files to find detailed information to diagnose and troubleshoot the problem further.\n\nThe section \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" later in this guide provides more information about some common performance related issues you may encounter.\n\n### <a name=\"diagnosing-errors\"></a>Diagnosing errors\n\nUsers of your application may notify you of errors reported by the client application. Storage Metrics also records counts of different error types from your storage services such as **NetworkError**, **ClientTimeoutError**, or **AuthorizationError**. While Storage Metrics only records counts of different error types, you can obtain more detail about individual requests by examining server-side, client-side, and network logs. Typically, the HTTP status code returned by the storage service will give an indication of why the request failed. \n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Remember that you should expect to see some intermittent errors: for example, errors due to transient network conditions, or application errors.\n\nThe following resources on MSDN are useful for understanding storage-related status and error codes:\n\n- <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179357.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Common REST API Error Codes</a>\n- <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179439.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Blob Service Error Codes</a>\n- <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179446.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Queue Service Error Codes</a>\n- <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179438.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Table Service Error Codes</a>\n\n### <a name=\"storage-emulator-issues\"></a>Storage emulator issues\n\nThe Azure SDK includes a storage emulator you can run on a development workstation. This emulator simulates most of the behavior of the Azure storage services and is useful during development and test, enabling you to run applications that use Azure storage services without the need for an Azure subscription and an Azure storage account.\n\nThe \"[Troubleshooting guidance]\" section of this guide describes some common issues encountered using the storage emulator.\n\n### <a name=\"storage-logging-tools\"></a>Storage logging tools\n\nStorage Logging provides server-side logging of storage requests in your Azure storage account. For more information about how to enable server-side logging and access the log data, see <a href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=510867\" target=\"_blank\">Using server-side logging</a> on MSDN.\n\nThe Storage Client Library for .NET enables you to collect client-side log data that relates to storage operations performed by your application. For more information about how to enable client-side logging and access the log data, see <a href=\"http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=510868\" target=\"_blank\">Client-side logging using the Storage Client Library</a> on MSDN.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] In some circumstances (such as SAS authorization failures), a user may report an error for which you can find no request data in the server-side Storage logs. You can use the logging capabilities of the Storage Client Library to investigate if the cause of the issue is on the client or use network monitoring tools to investigate the network.\n\n### <a name=\"using-network-logging-tools\"></a>Using network logging tools\n\nYou can capture the traffic between the client and server to provide detailed information about the data the client and server are exchanging and the underlying network conditions. Useful network logging tools include:\n\n- Fiddler (<a href=\"http://www.telerik.com/fiddler\" target=\"_blank\">http://www.telerik.com/fiddler</a>) is a free web debugging proxy that enables you to examine the headers and payload data of HTTP and HTTPS request and response messages. For more information, see \"[Appendix 1: Using Fiddler to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic]\".\n- Microsoft Network Monitor (Netmon) (<a href=\"http://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=4865\" target=\"_blank\">http://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=4865</a>) and Wireshark (<a href=\"http://www.wireshark.org/\" target=\"_blank\">http://www.wireshark.org/</a>) are free network protocol analyzers that enable you to view detailed packet information for a wide range of network protocols. For more information about Wireshark, see \"[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic]\".\n- Microsoft Message Analyzer is a tool from Microsoft that supersedes Netmon and that in addition to capturing network packet data, helps you to view and analyze the log data captured from other tools. For more information, see \"[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic]\".\n- If you want to perform a basic connectivity test to check that your client machine can connect to the Azure storage service over the network, you cannot do this using the standard **ping** tool on the client. However, you can use the **tcping** tool to check connectivity. **Tcping** is available for download at <a href=\"http://www.elifulkerson.com/projects/tcping.php\" target=\"_blank\">http://www.elifulkerson.com/projects/tcping.php</a>.\n\nIn many cases, the log data from Storage Logging and the Storage Client Library will be sufficient to diagnose an issue, but in some scenarios, you may need the more detailed information that these network logging tools can provide. For example, using Fiddler to view HTTP and HTTPS messages enables you to view header and payload data sent to and from the storage services, which would enable you to examine how a client application retries storage operations. Protocol analyzers such as Wireshark operate at the packet level enabling you to view TCP data, which would enable you to troubleshoot lost packets and connectivity issues. Message Analyzer can operate at both HTTP and TCP layers.\n\n## <a name=\"end-to-end-tracing\"></a>End-to-end tracing\n\nEnd-to-end tracing using a variety of log files is a useful technique for investigating potential issues. You can use the date/time information from your metrics data as an indication of where to start looking in the log files for the detailed information that will help you troubleshoot the issue.\n    \n### <a name=\"correlating-log-data\"></a>Correlating log data\n\nWhen viewing logs from client applications, network traces, and server-side storage logging it is critical to be able to correlate requests across the different log files. The log files include a number of different fields that are useful as correlation identifiers. The client request id is the most useful field to use to correlate entries in the different logs. However sometimes, it can be useful to use either the server request id or timestamps. The following sections provide more details about these options.\n\n### <a name=\"client-request-id\"></a>Client request ID\n\nThe Storage Client Library automatically generates a unique client request id for every request.\n\n- In the client-side log that the Storage Client Library creates, the client request id appears in the **Client Request ID** field of every log entry relating to the request.\n- In a network trace such as one captured by Fiddler, the client request id is visible in request messages as the **x-ms-client-request-id** HTTP header value.\n- In the server-side Storage Logging log, the client request id appears in the Client request ID column.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] It is possible for multiple requests to share the same client request id because the client can assign this value (although the Storage Client Library assigns a \n> new value automatically). In the case of retries from the client, all attempts share the same client request id. In the case of a batch sent from the client, the batch has a single client request id.\n\n\n### <a name=\"server-request-id\"></a>Server request ID\n\nThe storage service automatically generates server request ids.\n\n- In the server-side Storage Logging log, the server request id appears the **Request ID header** column.\n- In a network trace such as one captured by Fiddler, the server request id appears in response messages as the **x-ms-request-id** HTTP header value.\n- In the client-side log that the Storage Client Library creates, the server request id appears in the **Operation Text** column for the log entry showing details of the server response.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] The storage service always assigns a unique server request id to every request it receives, so every retry attempt from the client and every operation included in a batch has a unique server request id.\n\nIf the Storage Client Library throws a **StorageException** in the client, the **RequestInformation** property contains a **RequestResult** object that includes a **ServiceRequestID** property. You can also access a **RequestResult** object from an **OperationContext** instance.\n\nThe code sample below demonstrates how to set a custom **ClientRequestId** value by attaching an **OperationContext** object the request to the storage service. It also shows how to retrieve the **ServerRequestId** value from the response message. \n\n    CloudStorageAccount storageAccount = CloudStorageAccount.Parse(CloudConfigurationManager.GetSetting(\"StorageConnectionString\"));\n    CloudBlobClient blobClient = storageAccount.CreateCloudBlobClient();\n\n    // Create an Operation Context that includes custom ClientRequestId string based on constants defined within the application along with a Guid. \n    OperationContext oc = new OperationContext();\n    oc.ClientRequestID = String.Format(\"{0} {1} {2} {3}\", HOSTNAME, APPNAME, USERID, Guid.NewGuid().ToString());\n\n    try\n    {\n        CloudBlobContainer container = blobClient.GetContainerReference(\"democontainer\");\n        ICloudBlob blob = container.GetBlobReferenceFromServer(\"testImage.jpg\", null, null, oc);  \n        var downloadToPath = string.Format(\"./{0}\", blob.Name);\n        using (var fs = File.OpenWrite(downloadToPath))\n        {\n            blob.DownloadToStream(fs, null, null, oc);\n            Console.WriteLine(\"\\t Blob downloaded to file: {0}\", downloadToPath);\n        }\n    }\n    catch (StorageException storageException)\n    {\n        Console.WriteLine(\"Storage exception {0} occurred\", storageException.Message); \n        // Multiple results may exist due to client side retry logic - each retried operation will have a unique ServiceRequestId\n        foreach (var result in oc.RequestResults)\n        {\n                Console.WriteLine(\"HttpStatus: {0}, ServiceRequestId {1}\", result.HttpStatusCode, result.ServiceRequestID); \n        }\n    }\n\n\n### <a name=\"timestamps\"></a>Timestamps\n\nYou can also use timestamps to locate related log entries, but be careful of any clock skew between the client and server that may exist. You should search plus or minus 15 minutes for matching server-side entries based on the timestamp on the client. Remember that the blob metadata for the blobs containing metrics indicates the time range for the metrics stored in the blob; this is useful if you have many metrics blobs for the same minute or hour.\n\n## <a name=\"troubleshooting-guidance\"></a>Troubleshooting guidance\n\nThis section will help you with the diagnosis and troubleshooting of some of the common issues your application may encounter when using the Azure storage services. Use the list below to locate the information relevant to your specific issue.\n\n**Troubleshooting Decision Tree**\n\n----------\n\nDoes your issue relate to the performance of one of the storage services?\n\n- [Metrics show high AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency]\n- [Metrics show low AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency but the client is experiencing high latency]\n- [Metrics show high AverageServerLatency]\n- [You are experiencing unexpected delays in message delivery on a queue]\n\n----------\n\nDoes your issue relate to the availability of one of the storage services?\n\n- [Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError]\n- [Metrics show an increase in PercentTimeoutError]\n- [Metrics show an increase in PercentNetworkError]\n\n----------\n\nIs your client application receiving an HTTP 4XX (such as 404) response from a storage service?\n\n- [The client is receiving HTTP 403 (Forbidden) messages]\n- [The client is receiving HTTP 404 (Not found) messages]\n- [The client is receiving HTTP 409 (Conflict) messages]\n\n----------\n\n[Metrics show low PercentSuccess or analytics log entries have operations with transaction status of ClientOtherErrors]\n\n----------\n\n[Capacity metrics show an unexpected increase in storage capacity usage]\n\n----------\n\n[You are experiencing unexpected reboots of Virtual Machines that have a large number of attached VHDs]\n\n----------\n\n[Your issue arises from using the storage emulator for development or test]\n\n----------\n\n[You are encountering problems installing the Azure SDK for .NET]\n\n----------\n\n[You have a different issue with a storage service]\n\n----------\n\n### <a name=\"metrics-show-high-AverageE2ELatency-and-low-AverageServerLatency\"></a>Metrics show high AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency\n\nThe illustration blow from the portal monitoring tool shows an example where the **AverageE2ELatency** is significantly higher than the **AverageServerLatency**.\n\n![][4]\n\nNote that the storage service only calculates the metric **AverageE2ELatency** for successful requests and, unlike **AverageServerLatency**, includes the time the client takes to send the data and receive acknowledgement from the storage service. Therefore, a difference between **AverageE2ELatency** and **AverageServerLatency** could be either due to the client application being slow to respond, or due to conditions on the network.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] You can also view **E2ELatency** and **ServerLatency** for individual storage operations in the Storage Logging log data.\n\n#### Investigating client performance issues\n\nPossible reasons for the client responding slowly include having a limited number of available connections or threads. You may be able to resolve the issue by modifying the client code to be more efficient (for example by using asynchronous calls to the storage service), or by using a larger Virtual Machine (with more cores and more memory).\n\nFor the table and queue services, the Nagle algorithm can also cause high **AverageE2ELatency** as compared to **AverageServerLatency**: for more information see the post <a href=\"http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2010/06/25/nagle-s-algorithm-is-not-friendly-towards-small-requests.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Nagle’s Algorithm is Not Friendly towards Small Requests</a> on the Microsoft Azure Storage Team Blog. You can disable the Nagle algorithm in code by using the **ServicePointManager** class in the **System.Net** namespace. You should do this before you make any calls to the table or queue services in your application since this does not affect connections that are already open. The following example comes from the **Application_Start** method in a worker role.\n\n    var storageAccount = CloudStorageAccount.Parse(connStr);\n    ServicePoint tableServicePoint = ServicePointManager.FindServicePoint(storageAccount.TableEndpoint);\n    tableServicePoint.UseNagleAlgorithm = false;\n    ServicePoint queueServicePoint = ServicePointManager.FindServicePoint(storageAccount.QueueEndpoint);\n    queueServicePoint.UseNagleAlgorithm = false;\n\nYou should check the client-side logs to see how many requests your client application is submitting, and check for general .NET related performance bottlenecks in your client such as CPU, .NET garbage collection, network utilization, or memory (as a starting point for troubleshooting .NET client applications, see <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/7fe0dd2y(v=vs.110).aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Debugging, Tracing, and Profiling</a> on MSDN).\n\n#### Investigating network latency issues\n\nTypically, high end-to-end latency caused by the network is due to transient conditions. You can investigate both transient and persistent network issues such as dropped packets by using tools such as Wireshark or Microsoft Message Analyzer.\n\nFor more information about using Wireshark to troubleshoot network issues, see \"[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic].\"\n\nFor more information about using Microsoft Message Analyzer to troubleshoot network issues, see \"[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic].\"\n\n### <a name=\"metrics-show-low-AverageE2ELatency-and-low-AverageServerLatency\"></a>Metrics show low AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency but the client is experiencing high latency\n\nIn this scenario, the most likely cause is a delay in the storage requests reaching the storage service. You should investigate why requests from the client are not making it through to the blob service. \n\nPossible reasons for the client delaying sending requests include having a limited number of available connections or threads. You should also check if the client is performing multiple retries, and investigate the reason if this is the case. You can do this programmatically by looking in the **OperationContext** object associated with the request and retrieving the **ServerRequestId** value. For more information, see the code sample in the section \"[Server request ID].\"\n\nIf there are no issues in the client, you should investigate potential network issues such as packet loss. You can use tools such as Wireshark or Microsoft Message Analyzer to investigate network issues.\n\nFor more information about using Wireshark to troubleshoot network issues, see \"[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic].\"\n\nFor more information about using Microsoft Message Analyzer to troubleshoot network issues, see \"[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic].\"\n\n### <a name=\"metrics-show-high-AverageServerLatency\"></a>Metrics show high AverageServerLatency\n\nIn the case of high **AverageServerLatency** for blob download requests, you should use the Storage Logging logs to see if there are repeated requests for the same blob (or set of blobs). For blob upload requests, you should investigate what block size the client is using (for example, blocks less than 64K in size can result in overheads unless the reads are also in less than 64K chunks), and if multiple clients are uploading blocks to the same blob in parallel. You should also check the per-minute metrics for spikes in the number of requests that result in exceeding the per second scalability targets: also see \"[Metrics show an increase in PercentTimeoutError].\" \n\nIf you are seeing high **AverageServerLatency** for blob download requests when there are repeated requests the same blob or set of blobs, then you should consider caching these blobs using Azure Cache or the Azure Content Delivery Network (CDN). For upload requests, you can improve the throughput by using a larger block size. For queries to tables, it is also possible to implement client-side caching on clients that perform the same query operations and where the data doesn’t change frequently. \n\nHigh **AverageServerLatency** values can also be a symptom of poorly designed tables or queries that result in scan operations or that follow the append/prepend anti-pattern. See \"[Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError]\" for more information. \n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] You can find a comprehensive checklist including other issues to be aware here: \"Designing Scalable and Performant Storage Based Applications Checklist.\" \n\n### <a name=\"you-are-experiencing-unexpected-delays-in-message-delivery\"></a>You are experiencing unexpected delays in message delivery on a queue\n\nIf you are experiencing a delay between the time an application adds a message to a queue and the time it becomes available to read from the queue, then you should take the following steps to diagnose the issue:\n\n- Verify the application is successfully adding the messages to the queue. Check that the application is not retrying the **AddMessage** method several times before succeeding. The Storage Client Library logs will show any repeated retries of storage operations.\n- Verify there is no clock skew between the worker role that adds the message to the queue and the worker role that reads the message from the queue that makes it appear as if there is a delay in processing.\n- Check if the worker role that reads the messages from the queue is failing. If a queue client calls the **GetMessage** method but fails to respond with an acknowledgement, the message will remain invisible on the queue until the **invisibilityTimeout** period expires. At this point, the message becomes available for processing again.\n- Check if the queue length is growing over time. This can occur if you do not have sufficient workers available to process all of the messages that other workers are placing on the queue. You should also check the metrics to see if delete requests are failing and the dequeue count on messages, which might indicate repeated failed attempts to delete the message.\n- Examine the Storage Logging logs for any queue operations that have higher than expected **E2ELatency** and **ServerLatency** values over a longer period of time than usual.\n\n\n### <a name=\"metrics-show-an-increase-in-PercentThrottlingError\"></a>Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError\n\nThrottling errors occur when you exceed the scalability targets of a storage service. The storage service does this to ensure that no single client or tenant can use the service at the expense of others. For more information, see <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn249410.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Azure Storage Scalability and Performance Targets</a> for details on scalability targets for storage accounts and performance targets for partitions within storage accounts. \n\nIf the **PercentThrottlingError** metric show an increase in the percentage of requests that are failing with a throttling error, you need to investigate one of two scenarios:\n\n- [Transient increase in PercentThrottlingError]\n- [Permanent increase in PercentThrottlingError error]\n\nAn increase in **PercentThrottlingError** often occurs at the same time as an increase in the number of storage requests, or when you are initially load testing your application. This may also manifest itself in the client as \"503 Server Busy\" or \"500 Operation Timeout\" HTTP status messages from storage operations.\n\n#### <a name=\"transient-increase-in-PercentThrottlingError\"></a>Transient increase in PercentThrottlingError\n\nIf you are seeing spikes in the value of **PercentThrottlingError** that coincide with periods of high activity for the application, you should implement an exponential (not linear) back off strategy for retries in your client: this will reduce the immediate load on the partition and help your application to smooth out spikes in traffic. For more information about how to implement retry policies using the Storage Client Library, see <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/microsoft.windowsazure.storage.retrypolicies.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Microsoft.WindowsAzure.Storage.RetryPolicies Namespace</a> on MSDN.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] You may also see spikes in the value of **PercentThrottlingError** that do not coincide with periods of high activity for the application: the most likely cause here is the storage service moving partitions to improve load balancing.\n\n#### <a name=\"permanent-increase-in-PercentThrottlingError\"></a>Permanent increase in PercentThrottlingError error\n\nIf you are seeing a consistently high value for **PercentThrottlingError** following a permanent increase in your transaction volumes, or when you are performing your initial load tests on your application, then you need to evaluate how your application is using storage partitions and whether it is approaching the scalability targets for a storage account. For example, if you are seeing throttling errors on a queue (which counts as a single partition), then you should consider using additional queues to spread the transactions across multiple partitions. If you are seeing throttling errors on a table, you need to consider using a different partitioning scheme to spread your transactions across multiple partitions by using a wider range of partition key values. One common cause of this issue is the prepend/append anti-pattern where you select the date as the partition key and then all data on a particular day is written to one partition: under load, this can result in a write bottleneck. You should either consider a different partitioning design or evaluate whether using blob storage might be a better solution. You should also check if the throttling is occurring as a result of spikes in your traffic and investigate ways of smoothing your pattern of requests.\n\nIf you distribute your transactions across multiple partitions, you must still be aware of the scalability limits set for the storage account. For example, if you used ten queues each processing the maximum of 2,000 1KB messages per second, you will be at the overall limit of 20,000 messages per second for the storage account. If you need to process more than 20,000 entities per second, you should consider using multiple storage accounts. You should also bear in mind that the size of your requests and entities has an impact on when the storage service throttles your clients: if you have larger requests and entities, you may be throttled sooner.\n\nInefficient query design can also cause you to hit the scalability limits for table partitions. For example, a query with a filter that only selects one percent of the entities in a partition but that scans all the entities in a partition will need to access each entity. Every entity read will count towards the total number of transactions in that partition; therefore, you can easily reach the scalability targets.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Your performance testing should reveal any inefficient query designs in your application.\n\n### <a name=\"metrics-show-an-increase-in-PercentTimeoutError\"></a>Metrics show an increase in PercentTimeoutError\n\nYour metrics show an increase in **PercentTimeoutError** for one of your storage services. At the same time, the client receives a high volume of \"500 Operation Timeout\" HTTP status messages from storage operations.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] You may see timeout errors temporarily as the storage service load balances requests by moving a partition to a new server.\n \nThe **PercentTimeoutError** metric is an aggregation of the following metrics: **ClientTimeoutError**, **AnonymousClientTimeoutError**, **SASClientTimeoutError**, **ServerTimeoutError**, **AnonymousServerTimeoutError**, and **SASServerTimeoutError**.\n\nThe server timeouts are caused by an error on the server. The client timeouts happen because an operation on the server has exceeded the timeout specified by the client; for example, a client using the Storage Client Library can set a timeout for an operation by using the **ServerTimeout** property of the **QueueRequestOptions** class.\n\nServer timeouts indicate a problem with the storage service that requires further investigation. You can use metrics to see if you are hitting the scalability limits for the service and to identify any spikes in traffic that might be causing this problem. If the problem is intermittent, it may be due to load-balancing activity in the service. If the problem is persistent and is not caused by your application hitting the scalability limits of the service, you should raise a support issue. For client timeouts, you must decide if the timeout is set to an appropriate value in the client and either change the timeout value set in the client or investigate how you can improve the performance of the operations in the storage service, for example by optimizing your table queries or reducing the size of your messages.\n\n### <a name=\"metrics-show-an-increase-in-PercentNetworkError\"></a>Metrics show an increase in PercentNetworkError\n\nYour metrics show an increase in **PercentNetworkError** for one of your storage services. The **PercentNetworkError** metric is an aggregation of the following metrics: **NetworkError**, **AnonymousNetworkError**, and **SASNetworkError**. These occur when the storage service detects a network error when the client makes a storage request.\n\nThe most common cause of this error is a client disconnecting before a timeout expires in the storage service. You should investigate the code in your client to understand why and when the client disconnects from the storage service. You can also use Wireshark, Microsoft Message Analyzer, or Tcping to investigate network connectivity issues from the client. These tools are described in the [Appendices].\n\n### <a name=\"the-client-is-receiving-403-messages\"></a>The client is receiving HTTP 403 (Forbidden) messages\n\nIf your client application is throwing HTTP 403 (Forbidden) errors, a likely cause is that the client is using an expired Shared Access Signature (SAS) when it sends a storage request (although other possible causes include clock skew, invalid keys, and empty headers). If an expired SAS key is the cause, you will not see any entries in the server-side Storage Logging log data. The following table shows a sample from the client-side log generated by the Storage Client Library that illustrates this issue occurring:\n\nSource|Verbosity|Verbosity|Client request id|Operation text\n---|---|---|---|---\nMicrosoft.WindowsAzure.Storage|Information|3|85d077ab-…|Starting operation with location Primary per location mode PrimaryOnly.\nMicrosoft.WindowsAzure.Storage|Information|3|85d077ab -…|Starting synchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.netazureimblobcontainer/blobCreatedViaSAS.txt?sv=2014-02-14&amp;sr=c&amp;si=mypolicy&amp;sig=OFnd4Rd7z01fIvh%2BmcR6zbudIH2F5Ikm%2FyhNYZEmJNQ%3D&amp;api-version=2014-02-14.\nMicrosoft.WindowsAzure.Storage|Information|3|85d077ab -…|Waiting for response.\nMicrosoft.WindowsAzure.Storage|Warning|2|85d077ab -…|Exception thrown while waiting for response: The remote server returned an error: (403) Forbidden..\nMicrosoft.WindowsAzure.Storage|Information|3|85d077ab -…|Response received. Status code = 403, Request ID = 9d67c64a-64ed-4b0d-9515-3b14bbcdc63d, Content-MD5 = , ETag = .\nMicrosoft.WindowsAzure.Storage|Warning|2|85d077ab -…|Exception thrown during the operation: The remote server returned an error: (403) Forbidden..\nMicrosoft.WindowsAzure.Storage|Information|3 |85d077ab -…|Checking if the operation should be retried. Retry count = 0, HTTP status code = 403, Exception = The remote server returned an error: (403) Forbidden.. \nMicrosoft.WindowsAzure.Storage|Information|3|85d077ab -…|The next location has been set to Primary, based on the location mode.\nMicrosoft.WindowsAzure.Storage|Error|1|85d077ab -…|Retry policy did not allow for a retry. Failing with The remote server returned an error: (403) Forbidden.\n\nIn this scenario, you should investigate why the SAS token is expiring before the client sends the token to the server:\n\n- Typically, you should not set a start time when you create a SAS for a client to use immediately. If there are small clock differences between the host generating the SAS using the current time and the storage service, then it is possible for the storage service to receive a SAS that is not yet valid.\n- You should not set a very short expiry time on a SAS. Again, small clock differences between the host generating the SAS and the storage service can lead to a SAS apparently expiring earlier than anticipated.\n- Does the version parameter in the SAS key (for example **sv=2012-02-12**) match the version of the Storage Client Library you are using. You should always use the latest version of the Storage Client Library. For more information on SAS token versioning and dependencies on client library version see <a href=\"http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2014/05/14/what-s-new-for-microsoft-azure-storage-at-teched-2014.aspx\" target=\"_blank\"></a>. \n- If you regenerate your storage access keys (click **Manage Access Keys** on any page in your storage account in the Azure portal) this can invalidate any existing SAS tokens. This may be an issue if you generate SAS tokens with a long expiry time for client applications to cache.\n\nIf you are using the Storage Client Library to generate SAS tokens, then it is easy to build a valid token. However, if you are using the Storage REST API and constructing the SAS tokens by hand you should carefully read the topic <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/ee395415.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Delegating Access with a Shared Access Signature</a> on MSDN.\n\n### <a name=\"the-client-is-receiving-404-messages\"></a>The client is receiving HTTP 404 (Not found) messages\nIf the client application receives an HTTP 404 (Not found) message from the server, this implies that the object the client was attempting to use (such as an entity, table, blob, container, or queue) does not exist in the storage service. There are a number of possible reasons for this, such as:\n\n- [The client or another process previously deleted the object]\n- [A Shared Access Signature (SAS) authorization issue]\n- [Client-side JavaScript code does not have permission to access the object]\n- [Network failure]\n\n#### <a name=\"client-previously-deleted-the-object\"></a>The client or another process previously deleted the object\nIn scenarios where the client is attempting to read, update, or delete data in a storage service it is usually easy to identify in the server-side logs a previous operation that deleted the object in question from the storage service. Very often, the log data shows that another user or process deleted the object. In the server-side Storage Logging log, the operation-type and requested-object-key columns show when a client deleted an object.\n\nIn the scenario where a client is attempting to insert an object, it may not be immediately obvious why this results in an HTTP 404 (Not found) response given that the client is creating a new object. However, if the client is creating a blob it must be able to find the blob container, if the client is creating a message it must be able to find a queue, and if the client is adding a row it must be able to find the table. \n\nYou can use the client-side log from the Storage Client Library to gain a more detailed understanding of when the client sends specific requests to the storage service.\n\nThe following client-side log generated by the Storage Client library illustrates the problem when the client cannot find the container for the blob it is creating. This log includes details of the following storage operations:\n\nRequest ID|Operation\n---|---\n07b26a5d-...|**DeleteIfExists** method to delete the blob container. Note that this operation includes a **HEAD** request to check for the existence of the container.\ne2d06d78…|**CreateIfNotExists** method to create the blob container. Note that this operation includes a **HEAD** request that checks for the existence of the container. The **HEAD** returns a 404 message but continues.\nde8b1c3c-...|**UploadFromStream** method to create the blob. The **PUT** request fails with a 404 message\n\nLog entries:\n\nRequest ID |  Operation Text\n---|---\n07b26a5d-...|Starting synchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer.\n07b26a5d-...|StringToSign = HEAD............x-ms-client-request-id:07b26a5d-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:11 GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer.restype:container.\n07b26a5d-...|Waiting for response.\n07b26a5d-... | Response received. Status code = 200, Request ID = eeead849-...Content-MD5 = , ETag =    &quot;0x8D14D2DC63D059B&quot;.\n07b26a5d-... | Response headers were processed successfully, proceeding with the rest of the operation.\n07b26a5d-... | Downloading response body.\n07b26a5d-... | Operation completed successfully.\n07b26a5d-... | Starting synchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer.\n07b26a5d-... | StringToSign = DELETE............x-ms-client-request-id:07b26a5d-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:12    GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer.restype:container.\n07b26a5d-... | Waiting for response.\n07b26a5d-... | Response received. Status code = 202, Request ID = 6ab2a4cf-..., Content-MD5 = , ETag = .\n07b26a5d-... | Response headers were processed successfully, proceeding with the rest of the operation.\n07b26a5d-... | Downloading response body.\n07b26a5d-... | Operation completed successfully.\ne2d06d78-... | Starting asynchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer.</td>\ne2d06d78-... | StringToSign = HEAD............x-ms-client-request-id:e2d06d78-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:12 GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer.restype:container.\ne2d06d78-...| Waiting for response.\nde8b1c3c-... | Starting synchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer/blobCreated.txt.\nde8b1c3c-... |  StringToSign = PUT...64.qCmF+TQLPhq/YYK50mP9ZQ==........x-ms-blob-type:BlockBlob.x-ms-client-request-id:de8b1c3c-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:12 GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer/blobCreated.txt.\nde8b1c3c-... | Preparing to write request data.\ne2d06d78-... | Exception thrown while waiting for response: The remote server returned an error: (404) Not Found..\ne2d06d78-... | Response received. Status code = 404, Request ID = 353ae3bc-..., Content-MD5 = , ETag = .\ne2d06d78-... | Response headers were processed successfully, proceeding with the rest of the operation.\ne2d06d78-... | Downloading response body.\ne2d06d78-... | Operation completed successfully.\ne2d06d78-... | Starting asynchronous request to https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azuremmblobcontainer.\ne2d06d78-...|StringToSign = PUT...0.........x-ms-client-request-id:e2d06d78-....x-ms-date:Tue, 03 Jun 2014 10:33:12 GMT.x-ms-version:2014-02-14./domemaildist/azuremmblobcontainer.restype:container.\ne2d06d78-... | Waiting for response.\nde8b1c3c-... | Writing request data.\nde8b1c3c-... | Waiting for response. \ne2d06d78-... | Exception thrown while waiting for response: The remote server returned an error: (409) Conflict..\ne2d06d78-... | Response received. Status code = 409, Request ID = c27da20e-..., Content-MD5 = , ETag = .\ne2d06d78-... | Downloading error response body.\nde8b1c3c-... | Exception thrown while waiting for response: The remote server returned an error: (404) Not Found..\nde8b1c3c-... | Response received. Status code = 404, Request ID = 0eaeab3e-..., Content-MD5 = , ETag = .\nde8b1c3c-...| Exception thrown during the operation: The remote server returned an error: (404) Not Found..\nde8b1c3c-... | Retry policy did not allow for a retry. Failing with The remote server returned an error: (404) Not Found..\ne2d06d78-... | Retry policy did not allow for a retry. Failing with The remote server returned an error: (409) Conflict..\n\nIn this example, the log shows that the client is interleaving requests from the **CreateIfNotExists** method (request id e2d06d78…) with the requests from the **UploadFromStream** method (de8b1c3c-...); this is happening because the client application is invoking these methods asynchronously. You should modify the asynchronous code in the client to ensure that it creates the container before attempting to upload any data to a blob in that container. Ideally, you should create all your containers in advance.\n\n#### <a name=\"SAS-authorization-issue\"></a>A Shared Access Signature (SAS) authorization issue\n\nIf the client application attempts to use a SAS key that does not include the necessary permissions for the operation, the storage service returns an HTTP 404 (Not found) message to the client. At the same time, you will also see a non-zero value for **SASAuthorizationError** in the metrics.\n\nThe following table shows a sample server-side log message from the Storage Logging log file:\n\n<table>\n  <tr>\n    <td>Request start time</td>\n    <td>2014-05-30T06:17:48.4473697Z</td>\n  </tr>\n  <tr>\n    <td>Operation type</td>\n    <td>GetBlobProperties</td>\n  </tr>\n  <tr>\n    <td>Request status</td>\n    <td>SASAuthorizationError</td>\n  </tr>\n  <tr>\n    <td>HTTP status code</td>\n    <td>404</td>\n  </tr>\n  <tr>\n    <td>Authentication type</td>\n    <td>Sas</td>\n  </tr>\n  <tr>\n    <td>Service type</td>\n    <td>Blob</td>\n  </tr>\n  <tr>\n    <td>Request URL</td>\n    <td>\n    https://domemaildist.blob.core.windows.net/azureimblobcontainer/blobCreatedViaSAS.txt?sv=2014-02-14&amp;amp;sr=c&amp;amp;si=mypolicy&amp;amp;sig=XXXXX&amp;amp;api-version=2014-02-14&amp;amp;</td>\n  </tr>\n  <tr>\n    <td>Request id header</td>\n    <td>a1f348d5-8032-4912-93ef-b393e5252a3b</td>\n  </tr>\n  <tr>\n    <td>Client request ID</td>\n    <td>2d064953-8436-4ee0-aa0c-65cb874f7929</td>\n  </tr>\n</table>\n\nYou should investigate why your client application is attempting to perform an operation it has not been granted permissions for.\n\n#### <a name=\"JavaScript-code-does-not-have-permission\"></a>Client-side JavaScript code does not have permission to access the object\n\nIf you are using a JavaScript client and the storage service is returning HTTP 404 messages, you check for the following JavaScript errors in the browser:\n\n    SEC7120: Origin http://localhost:56309 not found in Access-Control-Allow-Origin header.\n    SCRIPT7002: XMLHttpRequest: Network Error 0x80070005, Access is denied.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] You can use the F12 Developer Tools in Internet Explorer to trace the messages exchanged between the browser and the storage service when you are troubleshooting client-side JavaScript issues. \n\nThese errors occur because the web browser implements the <a href=\"http://www.w3.org/Security/wiki/Same_Origin_Policy\" target=\"_blank\">same-origin policy</a> security restriction that prevents a web page from calling an API in a different domain from the domain the page comes from. \n\nTo work around the JavaScript issue, you can configure Cross Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) for the storage service the client is accessing. For more information, see <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn535601.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Cross-Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) Support for Azure Storage Services</a> on MSDN.\n\nThe following code sample shows how to configure your blob service to allow JavaScript running in the Contoso domain to access a blob in your blob storage service:\n\n    CloudBlobClient client = new CloudBlobClient(blobEndpoint, new StorageCredentials(accountName, accountKey));\n    // Set the service properties.\n    ServiceProperties sp = client.GetServiceProperties();\n    sp.DefaultServiceVersion = \"2013-08-15\";\n    CorsRule cr = new CorsRule();\n    cr.AllowedHeaders.Add(\"*\");\n    cr.AllowedMethods = CorsHttpMethods.Get | CorsHttpMethods.Put;\n    cr.AllowedOrigins.Add(\"http://www.contoso.com\");\n    cr.ExposedHeaders.Add(\"x-ms-*\");\n    cr.MaxAgeInSeconds = 5;\n    sp.Cors.CorsRules.Clear();\n    sp.Cors.CorsRules.Add(cr);\n    client.SetServiceProperties(sp);\n\n#### <a name=\"network-failure\"></a>Network Failure \n\nIn some circumstances, lost network packets can lead to the storage service returning HTTP 404 messages to the client. For example, when your client application is deleting an entity from the table service you see the client throw a storage exception reporting an \"HTTP 404 (Not Found)\" status message from the table service. When you investigate the table in the table storage service, you see that the service did delete the entity as requested.\n\nThe exception details in the client include the request id (7e84f12d…) assigned by the table service for the request: you can use this information to locate the request details in the server-side storage logs by searching in the **request-id-header** column in the log file. You could also use the metrics to identify when failures such as this occur and then search the log files based on the time the metrics recorded this error. This log entry shows that the delete failed with an \"HTTP (404) Client Other Error\" status message. The same log entry also includes the request id generated by the client in the **client-request-id** column (813ea74f…).\n\nThe server-side log also includes another entry with the same **client-request-id** value (813ea74f…) for a successful delete operation for the same entity, and from the same client. This successful delete operation took place very shortly before the failed delete request.\n\nThe most likely cause of this scenario is that the client sent a delete request for the entity to the table service, which succeeded, but did not receive an acknowledgement from the server (perhaps due to a temporary network issue). The client then automatically retried the operation (using the same **client-request-id**), and this retry failed because the entity had already been deleted.\n\nIf this problem occurs frequently, you should investigate why the client is failing to receive acknowledgements from the table service. If the problem is intermittent, you should trap the \"HTTP (404) Not Found\" error and log it in the client, but allow the client to continue.\n\n### <a name=\"the-client-is-receiving-409-messages\"></a>The client is receiving HTTP 409 (Conflict) messages\n\nThe following table shows an extract from the server-side log for two client operations: **DeleteIfExists** followed immediately by **CreateIfNotExists** using the same blob container name. Note that each client operation results in two requests sent to the server, first a **GetContainerProperties** request to check if the container exists, followed by the **DeleteContainer** or **CreateContainer** request.\n\nTimestamp|Operation|Result|Container name|Client request id\n---|---|---|---|---\n05:10:13.7167225|GetContainerProperties|200|mmcont|c9f52c89-…\n05:10:13.8167325|DeleteContainer|202|mmcont|c9f52c89-…\n05:10:13.8987407|GetContainerProperties|404|mmcont|bc881924-…\n05:10:14.2147723|CreateContainer|409|mmcont|bc881924-…\n\nThe code in the client application deletes and then immediately recreates a blob container using the same name: the **CreateIfNotExists** method (Client request ID bc881924-…) eventually fails with the HTTP 409 (Conflict) error. When a client deletes blob containers, tables, or queues there is a brief period before the name becomes available again.\n\nThe client application should use unique container names whenever it creates new containers if the delete/recreate pattern is common.\n\n### <a name=\"metrics-show-low-percent-success\"></a>Metrics show low PercentSuccess or analytics log entries have operations with transaction status of ClientOtherErrors\n\nThe **PercentSuccess** metric captures the percent of operations that were successful based on their HTTP Status Code. Operations with status codes of 2XX count as successful, whereas operations with status codes in 3XX, 4XX and 5XX ranges are counted as unsuccessful and lower the **PercentSucess** metric value. In the server-side storage log files, these operations are recorded with a transaction status of **ClientOtherErrors**. \n\nIt is important to note that these operations have completed successfully and therefore do not affect other metrics such as availability. Some examples of operations that execute successfully but that can result in unsuccessful HTTP status codes include:\n- **ResourceNotFound** (Not Found 404), for example from a GET request to a blob that does not exist.\n- **ResouceAlreadyExists** (Conflict 409), for example from a **CreateIfNotExist** operation where the resource already exists.\n- **ConditionNotMet** (Not Modified 304), for example from a conditional operation such as when a client sends an **ETag** value and an HTTP **If-None-Match** header to request an image only if it has been updated since the last operation.\n\nYou can find a list of common REST API error codes that the storage services return on the page <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dd179357.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Common REST API Error Codes</a>. \n\n### <a name=\"capacity-metrics-show-an-unexpected-increase\"></a>Capacity metrics show an unexpected increase in storage capacity usage\n\n\nIf you see sudden, unexpected changes in capacity usage in your storage account, you can investigate the reasons by first looking at your availability metrics; for example, an increase in the number of failed delete requests might lead to an increase in the amount of blob storage you are using as application specific cleanup operations you might have expected to be freeing up space may not be working as expected (for example, because the SAS tokens used for freeing up space have expired). \n\n### <a name=\"you-are-experiencing-unexpected-reboots\"></a>You are experiencing unexpected reboots of Virtual Machines that have a large number of attached VHDs\n\nIf a Virtual Machine (VM) has a large number of attached VHDs that are in the same storage account, you could exceed the scalability targets for an individual storage account causing the VM to fail. You should check the minute metrics for the storage account (**TotalRequests**/**TotalIngress**/**TotalEgress**) for spikes that exceed the scalability targets for a storage account. See the section \"[Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError]\" for assistance in determining if throttling has occurred on your storage account. \n\nIn general, each individual input or output operation on a VHD from a Virtual Machine translates to **Get Page** or **Put Page** operations on the underlying page blob. Therefore, you can use the estimated IOPS for your environment to tune how many VHDs you can have in a single storage account based on the specific behavior of your application. We do not recommend having more than 40 disks in a single storage account. See <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn249410.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Azure Storage Scalability and Performance Targets</a> for details of the current scalability targets for storage accounts, in particular the total request rate and total bandwidth for the type of storage account you are using. \nIf you are exceeding the scalability targets for your storage account, you should place your VHDs in multiple different storage accounts to reduce the activity in each individual account.\n\n### <a name=\"your-issue-arises-from-using-the-storage-emulator\"></a>Your issue arises from using the storage emulator for development or test\n\nYou typically use the storage emulator during development and test to avoid the requirement for an Azure storage account. The common issues that can occur when you are using the storage emulator are:\n\n- [Feature \"X\" is not working in the storage emulator]\n- [Error \"The value for one of the HTTP headers is not in the correct format\" when using the storage emulator]\n- [Running the storage emulator requires administrative privileges]\n\n#### <a name=\"feature-X-is-not-working\"></a>Feature \"X\" is not working in the storage emulator\n\nThe storage emulator does not support all of the features of the Azure storage services such as the file service. For more information, see <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/gg433135.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Differences Between the Storage Emulator and Azure Storage Services</a> on MSDN.\n\nFor those features that the storage emulator does not support, use the Azure storage service in the cloud.\n\n#### <a name=\"error-HTTP-header-not-correct-format\"></a>Error \"The value for one of the HTTP headers is not in the correct format\" when using the storage emulator\n\nYou are testing your application that use the Storage Client Library against the local storage emulator and method calls such as **CreateIfNotExists** fail with the error message \"The value for one of the HTTP headers is not in the correct format.\" This indicates that the version of the storage emulator you are using does not support the version of the storage client library you are using. The Storage Client Library adds the header **x-ms-version** to all the requests it makes. If the storage emulator does not recognize the value in the **x-ms-version** header, it rejects the request.\n\nYou can use the Storage Library Client logs to see the value of the **x-ms-version header** it is sending. You can also see the value of the **x-ms-version header** if you use Fiddler to trace the requests from your client application.\n\nThis scenario typically occurs if you install and use the latest version of the Storage Client Library without updating the storage emulator. You should either install the latest version of the storage emulator, or use cloud storage instead of the emulator for development and test.\n\n#### <a name=\"storage-emulator-requires-administrative-privileges\"></a>Running the storage emulator requires administrative privileges\n\nYou are prompted for administrator credentials when you run the storage emulator. This only occurs when you are initializing the storage emulator for the first time. After you have initialized the storage emulator, you do not need administrative privileges to run it again. \n\nFor more information, see <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/gg433132.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Initialize the Storage Emulator by Using the Command-Line Tool</a> on MSDN (you can also initialize the storage emulator in Visual Studio, which will also require administrative privileges).\n\n### <a name=\"you-are-encountering-problems-installing-the-Windows-Azure-SDK\"></a>You are encountering problems installing the Azure SDK for .NET\n\nWhen you try to install the SDK, it fails trying to install the storage emulator on your local machine. The installation log contains one of the following messages:\n\n- CAQuietExec:  Error: Unable to access SQL instance\n- CAQuietExec:  Error: Unable to create database\n\nThe cause is an issue with existing LocalDB installation. By default, the storage emulator uses LocalDB to persist data when it simulates the Azure storage services. You can reset your LocalDB instance by running the following commands in a command-prompt window before trying to install the SDK.\n\n    sqllocaldb stop v11.0\n    sqllocaldb delete v11.0\n    delete %USERPROFILE%\\WAStorageEmulatorDb3*.*\n    sqllocaldb create v11.0\n\nThe **delete** command removes any old database files from previous installations of the storage emulator.\n\n### <a name=\"you-have-a-different-issue-with-a-storage-service\"></a>You have a different issue with a storage service\n\nIf the previous troubleshooting sections do not include the issue you are having with a storage service, you should adopt the following approach to diagnosing and troubleshooting your issue.\n\n- Check your metrics to see if there is any change from your expected base-line behavior. From the metrics, you may be able to determine whether the issue is transient or permanent, and which storage operations the issue is affecting.\n- You can use the metrics information to help you search your server-side log data for more detailed information about any errors that are occurring. This information may help you troubleshoot and resolve the issue.\n- If the information in the server-side logs is not sufficient to troubleshoot the issue successfully, you can use the Storage Client Library client-side logs to investigate the behavior of your client application, and tools such as Fiddler, Wireshark, and Microsoft Message Analyzer to investigate your network.\n\nFor more information about using Fiddler, see \"[Appendix 1: Using Fiddler to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic].\"\n\nFor more information about using Wireshark, see \"[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic].\"\n\nFor more information about using Microsoft Message Analyzer, see \"[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic].\"\n\n## <a name=\"appendices\"></a>Appendices\n\nThe appendices describe several tools that you may find useful when you are diagnosing and troubleshooting issues with Azure Storage (and other services). These tools are not part of Azure Storage and some are third-party products. As such, the tools discussed in these appendices are not covered by any support agreement you may have with Microsoft Azure or Azure Storage, and therefore as part of your evaluation process you should examine the licensing and support options available from the providers of these tools.\n\n### <a name=\"appendix-1\"></a>Appendix 1: Using Fiddler to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic\n\nFiddler is a useful tool for analyzing the HTTP and HTTPS traffic between your client application and the Azure storage service you are using. You can download Fiddler from <a href=\"http://www.telerik.com/fiddler\" target=\"_blank\">http://www.telerik.com/fiddler</a>.\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Fiddler can decode HTTPS traffic; you should read the Fiddler documentation carefully to understand how it does this, and to understand the security implications.\n\nThis appendix provides a brief walkthrough of how to configure Fiddler to capture traffic between the local machine where you have installed Fiddler and the Azure storage services.\n\nAfter you have launched Fiddler, it will begin capturing HTTP and HTTPS traffic on your local machine. The following are some useful commands for controlling Fiddler:\n\n- Stop and start capturing traffic. On the main menu, go to **File** and then click **Capture Traffic** to toggle capturing on and off.\n- Save captured traffic data. On the main menu, go to **File**, click **Save**, and then click **All Sessions**: this enables you to save the traffic in a Session Archive file. You can reload a Session Archive later for analysis, or send it if requested to Microsoft support.\n\nTo limit the amount of traffic that Fiddler captures, you can use filters that you configure in the **Filters** tab. The following screenshot shows a filter that captures only traffic sent to the **contosoemaildist.table.core.windows.net** storage endpoint:\n\n![][5]\n\n### <a name=\"appendix-2\"></a>Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic\n\nWireshark is a network protocol analyzer that enables you to view detailed packet information for a wide range of network protocols. You can download Wireshark from <a href=\"http://www.wireshark.org/\" target=\"_blank\">http://www.wireshark.org/</a>.\n\nThe following procedure shows you how to capture detailed packet information for traffic from the local machine where you installed Wireshark to the table service in your Azure storage account.\n\n1.  Launch Wireshark on your local machine.\n2.  In the **Start** section, select the local network interface or interfaces that are connected to the internet.\n3.  Click **Capture Options**.\n4.  Add a filter to the **Capture Filter** textbox. For example, **host contosoemaildist.table.core.windows.net** will configure Wireshark to capture only packets sent to or from the table service endpoint in the **contosoemaildist** storage account. For a complete list of Capture Filters see <a href=\"http://wiki.wireshark.org/CaptureFilters\" target=\"_blank\">http://wiki.wireshark.org/CaptureFilters</a>. \n\n    ![][6]\n\n5.  Click **Start**. Wireshark will now capture all the packets send to or from the table service endpoint as you use your client application on your local machine.\n6.  When you have finished, on the main menu click **Capture** and then **Stop**.\n7.  To save the captured data in a Wireshark Capture File, on the main menu click **File** and then **Save**.\n\nWireShark will highlight any errors that exist in the **packetlist** window. You can also use the **Expert Info** window (click **Analyze**, then **Expert Info**) to view a summary of errors and warnings.\n\n![][7]\n\nYou can also chose to view the TCP data as the application layer sees it by right-clicking on the TCP data and selecting **Follow TCP Stream**. This is particularly useful if you captured your dump without a capture filter. See <a href=\"http://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsug_html_chunked/ChAdvFollowTCPSection.html\" target=\"_blank\">here</a> for more information.\n\n![][8]\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] For more information about using Wireshark, see the <a href=\"http://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsug_html_chunked/\" target=\"_blank\">Wireshark Users Guide</a>.\n\n### <a name=\"appendix-3\"></a>Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic\n\nYou can use Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic in a similar way to Fiddler, and capture network traffic in a similar way to Wireshark.\n\n#### Configure a web tracing session using Microsoft Message Analyzer\n\nTo configure a web tracing session for HTTP and HTTPS traffic using Microsoft Message Analyzer, run the Microsoft Message Analyzer application and then on the **File** menu, click **Capture/Trace**. In the list of available trace scenarios, select **Web Proxy**. Then in the **Trace Scenario Configuration** panel, in the **HostnameFilter** textbox, add the names of your storage endpoints (you can look up these names in the Azure portal). For example, if the name of your Azure storage account is **contosodata**, you should add the following to the **HostnameFilter** textbox:\n\n    contosodata.blob.core.windows.net contosodata.table.core.windows.net contosodata.queue.core.windows.net\n    \n> [AZURE.NOTE] A space character separates the hostnames. \n\nWhen you are ready to start collecting trace data, click the **Start With** button.\n\nFor more information about the Microsoft Message Analyzer **Web Proxy** trace, see <a href=\"http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj674814.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">PEF-WebProxy Provider</a> on TechNet.\n\nThe built-in **Web Proxy** trace in Microsoft Message Analyzer is based on Fiddler; it can capture client-side HTTPS traffic and display unencrypted HTTPS messages. The **Web Proxy** trace works by configuring a local proxy for all HTTP and HTTPS traffic that gives it access to unencrypted messages.\n\n#### Diagnosing network issues using Microsoft Message Analyzer\n\nIn addition to using the Microsoft Message Analyzer **Web Proxy** trace to capture details of the HTTP/HTTPs traffic between the client application and the storage service, you can also use the built-in **Local Link Layer** trace to capture network packet information. This enables you to capture data similar to that which you can capture with Wireshark, and diagnose network issues such as dropped packets.\n\nThe following screenshot shows an example **Local Link Layer** trace with some **informational** messages in the **DiagnosisTypes** column. Clicking on an icon in the **DiagnosisTypes** column shows the details of the message. In this example, the server retransmitted message #305 because it did not receive an acknowledgement from the client:\n\n![][9]\n\nWhen you create the trace session in Microsoft Message Analyzer, you can specify filters to reduce the amount of noise in the trace. On the **Capture / Trace** page where you define the trace, click on the **Configure** link next to **Microsoft-Windows-NDIS-PacketCapture**. The following screenshot shows a configuration that filters TCP traffic for the IP addresses of three storage services:\n\n![][10]\n\nFor more information about the Microsoft Message Analyzer Local Link Layer trace, see <a href=\"http://technet.microsoft.com/library/jj659264.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">PEF-NDIS-PacketCapture Provider</a> on TechNet.\n\n### <a name=\"appendix-4\"></a>Appendix 4: Using Excel to view metrics and log data\n\nMany tools enable you to download the Storage Metrics data from Azure table storage in a delimited format that makes it easy to load the data into Excel for viewing and analysis. Storage Logging data from Azure blob storage is already in a delimited format that you can load into Excel. However, you will need to add appropriate column headings based in the information at <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343259.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Storage Analytics Log Format</a> and <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343264.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Storage Analytics Metrics Table Schema</a>.\n\nTo import your Storage Logging data into Excel after you download it from blob storage:\n\n- On the **Data** menu, click **From Text**.\n- Browse to the log file you want to view and click **Import**.\n- On step 1 of the **Text Import Wizard**, select **Delimited**.\n\nOn step 1 of the **Text Import Wizard**, select **Semicolon** as the only delimiter and choose double-quote as the **Text qualifier**. Then click **Finish** and choose where to place the data in your workbook.\n\n### <a name=\"appendix-5\"></a>Appendix 5: Monitoring with Application Insights for Visual Studio Online\n\nYou can also use the Application Insights feature for Visual Studio Online as part of your performance and availability monitoring. This tool can: \n\n- Make sure your web service is available and responsive. Whether your app is a web site or a device app that uses a web service, it can test your URL every few minutes from locations around the world, and let you know if there’s a problem. \n- Quickly diagnose any performance issues or exceptions in your web service. Find out if CPU or other resources are being stretched, get stack traces from exceptions, and easily search through log traces. If the app’s performance drops below acceptable limits, we can send you an email. You can monitor both .NET and Java web services.\n\nAt the time of writing Application Insights is in preview. You can find more information at <a href=\"http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn481095.aspx\" target=\"_blank\">Application Insights for Visual Studio Online on MSDN</a>.\n\n\n<!--Anchors-->\n[Introduction]: #introduction\n[How this guide is organized]: #how-this-guide-is-organized\n\n[Monitoring your storage service]: #monitoring-your-storage-service\n[Monitoring service health]: #monitoring-service-health\n[Monitoring capacity]: #monitoring-capacity\n[Monitoring availability]: #monitoring-availability\n[Monitoring performance]: #monitoring-performance\n\n[Diagnosing storage issues]: #diagnosing-storage-issues\n[Service health issues]: #service-health-issues\n[Performance issues]: #performance-issues\n[Diagnosing errors]: #diagnosing-errors\n[Storage emulator issues]: #storage-emulator-issues\n[Storage logging tools]: #storage-logging-tools\n[Using network logging tools]: #using-network-logging-tools\n\n[End-to-end tracing]: #end-to-end-tracing\n[Correlating log data]: #correlating-log-data\n[Client request ID]: #client-request-id\n[Server request ID]: #server-request-id\n[Timestamps]: #timestamps\n\n[Troubleshooting guidance]: #troubleshooting-guidance\n[Metrics show high AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency]: #metrics-show-high-AverageE2ELatency-and-low-AverageServerLatency\n[Metrics show low AverageE2ELatency and low AverageServerLatency but the client is experiencing high latency]: #metrics-show-low-AverageE2ELatency-and-low-AverageServerLatency\n[Metrics show high AverageServerLatency]: #metrics-show-high-AverageServerLatency\n[You are experiencing unexpected delays in message delivery on a queue]: #you-are-experiencing-unexpected-delays-in-message-delivery\n\n[Metrics show an increase in PercentThrottlingError]: #metrics-show-an-increase-in-PercentThrottlingError\n[Transient increase in PercentThrottlingError]: #transient-increase-in-PercentThrottlingError\n[Permanent increase in PercentThrottlingError error]: #permanent-increase-in-PercentThrottlingError\n[Metrics show an increase in PercentTimeoutError]: #metrics-show-an-increase-in-PercentTimeoutError\n[Metrics show an increase in PercentNetworkError]: #metrics-show-an-increase-in-PercentNetworkError\n\n[The client is receiving HTTP 403 (Forbidden) messages]: #the-client-is-receiving-403-messages\n[The client is receiving HTTP 404 (Not found) messages]: #the-client-is-receiving-404-messages\n[The client or another process previously deleted the object]: #client-previously-deleted-the-object\n[A Shared Access Signature (SAS) authorization issue]: #SAS-authorization-issue\n[Client-side JavaScript code does not have permission to access the object]: #JavaScript-code-does-not-have-permission\n[Network failure]: #network-failure\n[The client is receiving HTTP 409 (Conflict) messages]: #the-client-is-receiving-409-messages\n\n[Metrics show low PercentSuccess or analytics log entries have operations with transaction status of ClientOtherErrors]: #metrics-show-low-percent-success\n[Capacity metrics show an unexpected increase in storage capacity usage]: #capacity-metrics-show-an-unexpected-increase\n[You are experiencing unexpected reboots of Virtual Machines that have a large number of attached VHDs]: #you-are-experiencing-unexpected-reboots\n[Your issue arises from using the storage emulator for development or test]: #your-issue-arises-from-using-the-storage-emulator\n[Feature \"X\" is not working in the storage emulator]: #feature-X-is-not-working\n[Error \"The value for one of the HTTP headers is not in the correct format\" when using the storage emulator]: #error-HTTP-header-not-correct-format\n[Running the storage emulator requires administrative privileges]: #storage-emulator-requires-administrative-privileges\n[You are encountering problems installing the Azure SDK for .NET]: #you-are-encountering-problems-installing-the-Windows-Azure-SDK\n[You have a different issue with a storage service]: #you-have-a-different-issue-with-a-storage-service\n\n[Appendices]: #appendices\n[Appendix 1: Using Fiddler to capture HTTP and HTTPS traffic]: #appendix-1\n[Appendix 2: Using Wireshark to capture network traffic]: #appendix-2\n[Appendix 3: Using Microsoft Message Analyzer to capture network traffic]: #appendix-3\n[Appendix 4: Using Excel to view metrics and log data]: #appendix-4\n[Appendix 5: Monitoring with Application Insights for Visual Studio Online]: #appendix-5\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/overview.png\n[2]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/portal-screenshot.png\n[3]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/hour-minute-metrics.png\n[4]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/high-e2e-latency.png\n[5]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/fiddler-screenshot.png\n[6]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/wireshark-screenshot-1.png\n[7]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/wireshark-screenshot-2.png\n[8]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/wireshark-screenshot-3.png\n[9]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/mma-screenshot-1.png\n[10]: ./media/storage-monitoring-diagnosing-troubleshooting/mma-screenshot-2.png\n \n"
}