{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Try Azure RemoteApp on your device in 3 minutes or less",
      "pos": [
        29,
        84
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Test drive Azure RemoteApp functionality without installing the service.",
      "pos": [
        103,
        175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Try Azure RemoteApp on your device in 3 minutes or less",
      "pos": [
        470,
        525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Want to see Azure RemoteApp on your device?",
      "pos": [
        527,
        570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can access our demo deployment for 10 minutes, as long as you have a Microsoft account.",
      "pos": [
        571,
        662
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We have Office and a few other applications available.",
      "pos": [
        663,
        717
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is a great way to test drive the user experience for Azure RemoteApp in less than 3 minutes.",
      "pos": [
        718,
        815
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Interested?",
      "pos": [
        817,
        828
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        833,
        899
      ],
      "content": "Go to to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>http://remoteapp.azure.com<ept id=\"p1\">](http://remoteapp.azure.com)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        903,
        954
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Install Client<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the upper right corner."
    },
    {
      "content": "The system automatically detects your device and will take you to the client for your device.",
      "pos": [
        960,
        1053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Install the client.",
      "pos": [
        1054,
        1073
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1077,
        1183
      ],
      "content": "Go back <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>http://remoteapp.azure.com<ept id=\"p1\">](http://remoteapp.azure.com)</ept> and  sign in with your Microsoft account."
    },
    {
      "content": "You can now access applications running in real time on Azure RemoteApp.",
      "pos": [
        1186,
        1258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your opinion matters.",
      "pos": [
        1261,
        1282
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At the end of each session, you will see a dialog box for your feedback.",
      "pos": [
        1283,
        1355
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have a minute, tell us your thoughts and let us know whether you would like Microsoft to contact you for additional information.",
      "pos": [
        1356,
        1491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Because this is a controlled environment for demo use, we have not enabled external internet access from the published demo applications.",
      "pos": [
        1494,
        1644
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because of this, services like OneDrive are not accessible.",
      "pos": [
        1645,
        1704
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Also, clipboard sharing (Copy &amp; Paste) and USB and printer redirection are disabled.",
      "pos": [
        1705,
        1789
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "\n<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Try Azure RemoteApp on your device in 3 minutes or less\"\n    description=\"Test drive Azure RemoteApp functionality without installing the service.\" \n    services=\"remoteapp\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"lizap\" \n    manager=\"mbaldwin\" />\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"remoteapp\" \n    ms.workload=\"compute\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"08/12/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"mbaldwin\" />\n\n\n\n# Try Azure RemoteApp on your device in 3 minutes or less\n\nWant to see Azure RemoteApp on your device? You can access our demo deployment for 10 minutes, as long as you have a Microsoft account. We have Office and a few other applications available. This is a great way to test drive the user experience for Azure RemoteApp in less than 3 minutes.\n\nInterested?\n\n1. Go to to [http://remoteapp.azure.com](http://remoteapp.azure.com).\n2. Click **Install Client** in the upper right corner.  \n3. The system automatically detects your device and will take you to the client for your device. Install the client.\n4. Go back [http://remoteapp.azure.com](http://remoteapp.azure.com) and  sign in with your Microsoft account.\n \nYou can now access applications running in real time on Azure RemoteApp. \n\nYour opinion matters. At the end of each session, you will see a dialog box for your feedback. If you have a minute, tell us your thoughts and let us know whether you would like Microsoft to contact you for additional information.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] Because this is a controlled environment for demo use, we have not enabled external internet access from the published demo applications. Because of this, services like OneDrive are not accessible. Also, clipboard sharing (Copy & Paste) and USB and printer redirection are disabled.  \n\n "
}