{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Storage Analytics",
      "pos": [
        28,
        45
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to manage concurrency for the Blob, Queue, Table, and File services",
      "pos": [
        65,
        136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enabling Storage metrics and viewing metrics data",
      "pos": [
        439,
        488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "By default, Storage Metrics is not enabled for your storage services.",
      "pos": [
        490,
        559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can enable monitoring using either the Azure Management Portal, Windows PowerShell, or programmatically through a storage API.",
      "pos": [
        560,
        690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you enable Storage Metrics, you must choose a retention period for the data: this period determines for how long the storage service keeps the metrics and charges you for the space required to store them.",
      "pos": [
        692,
        901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, you should use a shorter retention period for minute metrics than hourly metrics because of the significant extra space required for minute metrics.",
      "pos": [
        902,
        1061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should choose a retention period such that you have sufficient time to analyze the data and download any metrics you wish to keep for off-line analysis or reporting purposes.",
      "pos": [
        1062,
        1240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Remember that you will also be billed for downloading metrics data from your storage account.",
      "pos": [
        1241,
        1334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to enable Storage metrics using the Azure management portal",
      "pos": [
        1339,
        1402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the Azure Management Portal, you use the Configure page for a storage account to control Storage Metrics.",
      "pos": [
        1404,
        1512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For monitoring, you can set a level and a retention period in days for each of blobs, tables, and queues.",
      "pos": [
        1513,
        1618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In each case, the level is one of the following:",
      "pos": [
        1619,
        1667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Off — this means no metrics are collected.",
      "pos": [
        1672,
        1714
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Minimal — Storage Metrics collects a basic set of metrics such as ingress/egress, availability, latency, and success percentages, which are aggregated for the Blob, Table, and Queue services.",
      "pos": [
        1718,
        1909
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verbose — Storage Metrics collects a full set of metrics that includes the same metrics for each storage API operation, in addition to the service-level metrics.",
      "pos": [
        1913,
        2074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verbose metrics enable closer analysis of issues that occur during application operations.",
      "pos": [
        2075,
        2165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the Management Portal does not currently enable you to configure minute metrics in your storage account; you must enable minute metrics using PowerShell or programmatically.",
      "pos": [
        2167,
        2350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to enable Storage metrics using PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        2356,
        2402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use PowerShell on your local machine to configure Storage Metrics in your storage account by using the Azure PowerShell cmdlet Get-AzureStorageServiceMetricsProperty to retrieve the current settings, and the cmdlet Set-AzureStorageServiceMetricsProperty to change the current settings.",
      "pos": [
        2404,
        2697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The cmdlets that control Storage Metrics use the following parameters:",
      "pos": [
        2699,
        2769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MetricsType possible values are Hour and Minute.",
      "pos": [
        2773,
        2821
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ServiceType possible value are Blob, Queue, and Table.",
      "pos": [
        2825,
        2879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MetricsLevel possible values are None (equivalent to Off in the Management Portal), Service (equivalent to Minimal in the Management Portal), and ServiceAndApi (equivalent to Verbose in the Management Portal).",
      "pos": [
        2883,
        3092
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, the following command switches on minute metrics for the blob service in your default storage account with the retention period set to five days:",
      "pos": [
        3094,
        3252
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following command retrieves the current hourly metrics level and retention days for the blob service in your default storage account:",
      "pos": [
        3380,
        3517
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3597,
        3845
      ],
      "content": "For information about how to configure the Azure PowerShell cmdlets to work with your Azure subscription and how to select the default storage account to use, see: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to install and configure Azure PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](../install-configure-powershell.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "How to enable Storage metrics programmatically",
      "pos": [
        3850,
        3896
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition to using the Azure Management Portal or the Azure PowerShell cmdlets to control Storage Metrics, you can also use one of the Azure Storage APIs.",
      "pos": [
        3898,
        4054
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you are using a .NET language you can use the Storage Client Library.",
      "pos": [
        4055,
        4140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The classes CloudBlobClient, CloudQueueClient, and CloudTableClient all have methods such as SetServiceProperties and SetServicePropertiesAsync that take a ServiceProperties object as a parameter.",
      "pos": [
        4142,
        4338
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the ServiceProperties object to configure Storage Metrics.",
      "pos": [
        4339,
        4409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, the following C# snippet shows how to change the metrics level and retention days for the hourly queue metrics:",
      "pos": [
        4410,
        4534
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Viewing Storage metrics",
      "pos": [
        4926,
        4949
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you have configured Storage Metrics to monitor your storage account, it records the metrics in a set of well-known tables in your storage account.",
      "pos": [
        4951,
        5102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the Monitor page for your storage account in the Management Portal to view the hourly metrics as they become available on a chart.",
      "pos": [
        5103,
        5245
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On this page in the Management Portal, you can:",
      "pos": [
        5246,
        5293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select which metrics to plot on the chart (the choice of available metrics will depend on whether you chose verbose or minimal monitoring for the service on the Configure page).",
      "pos": [
        5297,
        5474
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Select the time range for the metrics displayed on the chart.",
      "pos": [
        5479,
        5540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Choose to use an absolute or relative scale to plot the metrics.",
      "pos": [
        5545,
        5609
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure email alerts to notify you when a specific metric reaches a certain value.",
      "pos": [
        5614,
        5698
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to download the metrics for long-term storage or to analyze them locally, you will need to use a tool or write some code to read the tables.",
      "pos": [
        5701,
        5853
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must download the minute metrics for analysis.",
      "pos": [
        5854,
        5904
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The tables do not appear if you list all the tables in your storage account, but you can access them directly by name.",
      "pos": [
        5905,
        6023
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Many third-party storage-browsing tools are aware of these tables and enable you to view them directly (see the blog post <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Azure Storage Explorers<ept id=\"p1\">](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2014/03/11/windows-azure-storage-explorers-2014.aspx)</ept> for a list of available tools).",
      "pos": [
        6024,
        6319
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hourly metrics",
      "pos": [
        6325,
        6339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "$MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsBlob",
      "pos": [
        6342,
        6377
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "$MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsTable",
      "pos": [
        6380,
        6416
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "$MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsQueue",
      "pos": [
        6419,
        6455
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Minute metrics",
      "pos": [
        6461,
        6475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "$MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsBlob",
      "pos": [
        6478,
        6515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "$MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsTable",
      "pos": [
        6518,
        6556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "$MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsQueue",
      "pos": [
        6559,
        6597
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Capacity",
      "pos": [
        6603,
        6611
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "$MetricsCapacityBlob",
      "pos": [
        6614,
        6634
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can find full details of the schemas for these tables at <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Storage Analytics Metrics Table Schema<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343264.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6636,
        6794
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The sample rows below show only a subset of the columns available, but illustrate some important features of the way Storage Metrics saves these metrics:",
      "pos": [
        6795,
        6948
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PartitionKey",
      "pos": [
        6952,
        6964
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RowKey",
      "pos": [
        6974,
        6980
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Timestamp",
      "pos": [
        7008,
        7017
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "TotalRequests",
      "pos": [
        7020,
        7033
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "TotalBillableRequests",
      "pos": [
        7036,
        7057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "TotalIngress",
      "pos": [
        7060,
        7072
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "TotalEgress",
      "pos": [
        7075,
        7086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Availability",
      "pos": [
        7089,
        7101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AverageE2ELatency",
      "pos": [
        7104,
        7121
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AverageServerLatency",
      "pos": [
        7124,
        7144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PercentSuccess",
      "pos": [
        7147,
        7161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "20140522T1100",
      "pos": [
        7380,
        7393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "user;All",
      "pos": [
        7401,
        7409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2014-05-22T11:01:16.7650250Z",
      "pos": [
        7417,
        7445
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "7",
      "pos": [
        7448,
        7449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "7",
      "pos": [
        7464,
        7465
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "4003",
      "pos": [
        7488,
        7492
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "46801",
      "pos": [
        7503,
        7508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        7517,
        7520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "104.4286",
      "pos": [
        7532,
        7540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "6.857143",
      "pos": [
        7552,
        7560
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        7575,
        7578
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "20140522T1100",
      "pos": [
        7594,
        7607
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "user;QueryEntities",
      "pos": [
        7610,
        7628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2014-05-22T11:01:16.7640250Z",
      "pos": [
        7631,
        7659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "5",
      "pos": [
        7662,
        7663
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "5",
      "pos": [
        7678,
        7679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2694",
      "pos": [
        7702,
        7706
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "45951",
      "pos": [
        7717,
        7722
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        7731,
        7734
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "143.8",
      "pos": [
        7746,
        7751
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "7.8",
      "pos": [
        7766,
        7769
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        7789,
        7792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "20140522T1100",
      "pos": [
        7808,
        7821
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "user;QueryEntity",
      "pos": [
        7825,
        7841
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2014-05-22T11:01:16.7650250Z",
      "pos": [
        7845,
        7873
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        7876,
        7877
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        7892,
        7893
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "538",
      "pos": [
        7916,
        7919
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "633",
      "pos": [
        7931,
        7934
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        7945,
        7948
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3",
      "pos": [
        7960,
        7961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "3",
      "pos": [
        7980,
        7981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        8003,
        8006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "20140522T1100",
      "pos": [
        8022,
        8035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "user;UpdateEntity",
      "pos": [
        8038,
        8055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2014-05-22T11:01:16.7650250Z",
      "pos": [
        8059,
        8087
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        8090,
        8091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "1",
      "pos": [
        8106,
        8107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "771",
      "pos": [
        8130,
        8133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "217",
      "pos": [
        8145,
        8148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        8159,
        8162
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "9",
      "pos": [
        8174,
        8175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "6",
      "pos": [
        8194,
        8195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "100",
      "pos": [
        8217,
        8220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example minute metrics data, the partition key uses the time at minute resolution.",
      "pos": [
        8238,
        8328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The row key identifies the type of information that is stored in the row and this is composed of two pieces of information, the access type, and the request type:",
      "pos": [
        8329,
        8491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The access type is either user or system, where user refers to all user requests to the storage service, and system refers to requests made by Storage Analytics.",
      "pos": [
        8495,
        8656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The request type is either all in which case it is a summary line, or it identifies the specific API such as QueryEntity or UpdateEntity.",
      "pos": [
        8660,
        8797
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The sample data above shows all the records for a single minute (starting at 11:00AM), so the number of QueryEntities requests plus the number of QueryEntity requests plus the number of UpdateEntity requests add up to seven, which is the total shown on the user:All row.",
      "pos": [
        8800,
        9070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Similarly, you can derive the average end-to-end latency 104.4286 on the user:All row by calculating ((143.8 * 5) + 3 + 9)/7.",
      "pos": [
        9071,
        9196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should consider setting up alerts in the Management Portal on the Monitor page so that Storage Metrics can automatically notify you of any important changes in the behavior of your storage services.If you use a storage explorer tool to download this metrics data in a delimited format, you can use Microsoft Excel to analyze the data.",
      "pos": [
        9198,
        9536
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the blog post <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Azure Storage Explorers<ept id=\"p1\">](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2014/03/11/windows-azure-storage-explorers-2014.aspx)</ept> for a list of available storage explorer tools.",
      "pos": [
        9537,
        9744
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Accessing metrics data programmatically",
      "pos": [
        9751,
        9790
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following listing shows sample C# code that accesses the minute metrics for a range of minutes and displays the results in a console Window.",
      "pos": [
        9792,
        9936
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It uses the Azure Storage Library version 4 that includes the CloudAnalyticsClient class that simplifies accessing the metrics tables in storage.",
      "pos": [
        9937,
        10082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What charges do you incur when you enable storage metrics?",
      "pos": [
        12235,
        12293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Write requests to create table entities for metrics are charged at the standard rates applicable to all Azure Storage operations.",
      "pos": [
        12295,
        12424
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Read and delete requests by a client to metrics data are also billable at standard rates.",
      "pos": [
        12426,
        12515
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have configured a data retention policy, you are not charged when Azure Storage deletes old metrics data.",
      "pos": [
        12516,
        12628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, if you delete analytics data, your account is charged for the delete operations.",
      "pos": [
        12629,
        12718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The capacity used by the metrics tables is also billable: you can use the following to estimate the amount of capacity used for storing metrics data:",
      "pos": [
        12720,
        12869
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If each hour a service utilizes every API in every service, then approximately 148KB of data is stored every hour in the metrics transaction tables if you have enabled both service and API level summary.",
      "pos": [
        12873,
        13076
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If each hour a service utilizes every API in every service, then approximately 12KB of data is stored every hour in the metrics transaction tables if you have enabled just service level summary.",
      "pos": [
        13080,
        13274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The capacity table for blobs has two rows added each day (provided user has opted in for logs): this implies that every day the size of this table increases by up to approximately 300 bytes.",
      "pos": [
        13278,
        13468
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next-steps:",
      "pos": [
        13473,
        13484
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enabling Storage logging and accessing log data",
      "pos": [
        13486,
        13533
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Storage Analytics\" \n    description=\"How to manage concurrency for the Blob, Queue, Table, and File services\" \n    services=\"storage\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"tamram\" \n    manager=\"adinah\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"storage\" \n    ms.workload=\"storage\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"dotnet\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"06/18/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"tamram\"/>\n\n# Enabling Storage metrics and viewing metrics data\n\nBy default, Storage Metrics is not enabled for your storage services. You can enable monitoring using either the Azure Management Portal, Windows PowerShell, or programmatically through a storage API.\n\nWhen you enable Storage Metrics, you must choose a retention period for the data: this period determines for how long the storage service keeps the metrics and charges you for the space required to store them. Typically, you should use a shorter retention period for minute metrics than hourly metrics because of the significant extra space required for minute metrics. You should choose a retention period such that you have sufficient time to analyze the data and download any metrics you wish to keep for off-line analysis or reporting purposes. Remember that you will also be billed for downloading metrics data from your storage account.\n\n## How to enable Storage metrics using the Azure management portal\n\nIn the Azure Management Portal, you use the Configure page for a storage account to control Storage Metrics. For monitoring, you can set a level and a retention period in days for each of blobs, tables, and queues. In each case, the level is one of the following:\n\n\n- Off — this means no metrics are collected.\n\n- Minimal — Storage Metrics collects a basic set of metrics such as ingress/egress, availability, latency, and success percentages, which are aggregated for the Blob, Table, and Queue services.\n\n- Verbose — Storage Metrics collects a full set of metrics that includes the same metrics for each storage API operation, in addition to the service-level metrics. Verbose metrics enable closer analysis of issues that occur during application operations.\n\nNote that the Management Portal does not currently enable you to configure minute metrics in your storage account; you must enable minute metrics using PowerShell or programmatically.\n\n\n## How to enable Storage metrics using PowerShell\n\nYou can use PowerShell on your local machine to configure Storage Metrics in your storage account by using the Azure PowerShell cmdlet Get-AzureStorageServiceMetricsProperty to retrieve the current settings, and the cmdlet Set-AzureStorageServiceMetricsProperty to change the current settings.\n\nThe cmdlets that control Storage Metrics use the following parameters:\n\n- MetricsType possible values are Hour and Minute.\n\n- ServiceType possible value are Blob, Queue, and Table.\n\n- MetricsLevel possible values are None (equivalent to Off in the Management Portal), Service (equivalent to Minimal in the Management Portal), and ServiceAndApi (equivalent to Verbose in the Management Portal).\n\nFor example, the following command switches on minute metrics for the blob service in your default storage account with the retention period set to five days:\n\n`Set-AzureStorageServiceMetricsProperty -MetricsType Minute -ServiceType Blob -MetricsLevel ServiceAndApi  -RetentionDays 5`\n\nThe following command retrieves the current hourly metrics level and retention days for the blob service in your default storage account:\n\n`Get-AzureStorageServiceMetricsProperty -MetricsType Hour -ServiceType Blob`\n\nFor information about how to configure the Azure PowerShell cmdlets to work with your Azure subscription and how to select the default storage account to use, see: [How to install and configure Azure PowerShell](../install-configure-powershell.md).\n\n## How to enable Storage metrics programmatically\n\nIn addition to using the Azure Management Portal or the Azure PowerShell cmdlets to control Storage Metrics, you can also use one of the Azure Storage APIs. For example, if you are using a .NET language you can use the Storage Client Library.\n\nThe classes CloudBlobClient, CloudQueueClient, and CloudTableClient all have methods such as SetServiceProperties and SetServicePropertiesAsync that take a ServiceProperties object as a parameter. You can use the ServiceProperties object to configure Storage Metrics. For example, the following C# snippet shows how to change the metrics level and retention days for the hourly queue metrics:\n\n    var storageAccount = CloudStorageAccount.Parse(connStr);\n    var queueClient = storageAccount.CreateCloudQueueClient();\n    var serviceProperties = queueClient.GetServiceProperties();\n     \n    serviceProperties.HourMetrics.MetricsLevel = MetricsLevel.Service;\n    serviceProperties.HourMetrics.RetentionDays = 10;\n     \n    queueClient.SetServiceProperties(serviceProperties);\n    \n## Viewing Storage metrics\n\nWhen you have configured Storage Metrics to monitor your storage account, it records the metrics in a set of well-known tables in your storage account. You can use the Monitor page for your storage account in the Management Portal to view the hourly metrics as they become available on a chart. On this page in the Management Portal, you can:\n\n- Select which metrics to plot on the chart (the choice of available metrics will depend on whether you chose verbose or minimal monitoring for the service on the Configure page).\n\n\n- Select the time range for the metrics displayed on the chart.\n\n\n- Choose to use an absolute or relative scale to plot the metrics.\n\n\n- Configure email alerts to notify you when a specific metric reaches a certain value.\n\n\nIf you want to download the metrics for long-term storage or to analyze them locally, you will need to use a tool or write some code to read the tables. You must download the minute metrics for analysis. The tables do not appear if you list all the tables in your storage account, but you can access them directly by name. Many third-party storage-browsing tools are aware of these tables and enable you to view them directly (see the blog post [Microsoft Azure Storage Explorers](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2014/03/11/windows-azure-storage-explorers-2014.aspx) for a list of available tools).\n\n### Hourly metrics\n- $MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsBlob\n- $MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsTable\n- $MetricsHourPrimaryTransactionsQueue\n\n### Minute metrics\n- $MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsBlob\n- $MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsTable\n- $MetricsMinutePrimaryTransactionsQueue\n\n### Capacity\n- $MetricsCapacityBlob\n\nYou can find full details of the schemas for these tables at [Storage Analytics Metrics Table Schema](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/hh343264.aspx). The sample rows below show only a subset of the columns available, but illustrate some important features of the way Storage Metrics saves these metrics:\n\n| PartitionKey  |       RowKey       |                    Timestamp | TotalRequests | TotalBillableRequests | TotalIngress | TotalEgress | Availability | AverageE2ELatency | AverageServerLatency | PercentSuccess |\n|---------------|:------------------:|-----------------------------:|---------------|-----------------------|--------------|-------------|--------------|-------------------|----------------------|----------------|\n| 20140522T1100 |      user;All      | 2014-05-22T11:01:16.7650250Z | 7             | 7                     | 4003         | 46801       | 100          | 104.4286          | 6.857143             | 100            |\n| 20140522T1100 | user;QueryEntities | 2014-05-22T11:01:16.7640250Z | 5             | 5                     | 2694         | 45951       | 100          | 143.8             | 7.8                  | 100            |\n| 20140522T1100 |  user;QueryEntity  | 2014-05-22T11:01:16.7650250Z | 1             | 1                     | 538          | 633         | 100          | 3                 | 3                    | 100            |\n| 20140522T1100 | user;UpdateEntity  | 2014-05-22T11:01:16.7650250Z | 1             | 1                     | 771          | 217         | 100          | 9                 | 6                    | 100               |\n\nIn this example minute metrics data, the partition key uses the time at minute resolution. The row key identifies the type of information that is stored in the row and this is composed of two pieces of information, the access type, and the request type:\n\n- The access type is either user or system, where user refers to all user requests to the storage service, and system refers to requests made by Storage Analytics.\n\n- The request type is either all in which case it is a summary line, or it identifies the specific API such as QueryEntity or UpdateEntity.\n\n\nThe sample data above shows all the records for a single minute (starting at 11:00AM), so the number of QueryEntities requests plus the number of QueryEntity requests plus the number of UpdateEntity requests add up to seven, which is the total shown on the user:All row. Similarly, you can derive the average end-to-end latency 104.4286 on the user:All row by calculating ((143.8 * 5) + 3 + 9)/7.\n\nYou should consider setting up alerts in the Management Portal on the Monitor page so that Storage Metrics can automatically notify you of any important changes in the behavior of your storage services.If you use a storage explorer tool to download this metrics data in a delimited format, you can use Microsoft Excel to analyze the data. See the blog post [Microsoft Azure Storage Explorers](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazurestorage/archive/2014/03/11/windows-azure-storage-explorers-2014.aspx) for a list of available storage explorer tools.\n\n\n\n## Accessing metrics data programmatically\n\nThe following listing shows sample C# code that accesses the minute metrics for a range of minutes and displays the results in a console Window. It uses the Azure Storage Library version 4 that includes the CloudAnalyticsClient class that simplifies accessing the metrics tables in storage.\n\n    private static void PrintMinuteMetrics(CloudAnalyticsClient analyticsClient, DateTimeOffset startDateTime, DateTimeOffset endDateTime)\n    {\n    // Convert the dates to the format used in the PartitionKey\n    var start = startDateTime.ToUniversalTime().ToString(\"yyyyMMdd'T'HHmm\");\n    var end = endDateTime.ToUniversalTime().ToString(\"yyyyMMdd'T'HHmm\");\n    \n    var services = Enum.GetValues(typeof(StorageService));\n    foreach (StorageService service in services)\n    {\n    Console.WriteLine(\"Minute Metrics for Service {0} from {1} to {2} UTC\", service, start, end);\n    var metricsQuery = analyticsClient.CreateMinuteMetricsQuery(service, StorageLocation.Primary);\n    var t = analyticsClient.GetMinuteMetricsTable(service);\n    var opContext = new OperationContext();\n    var query =\n    from entity in metricsQuery\n    // Note, you can't filter using the entity properties Time, AccessType, or TransactionType\n    // because they are calculated fields in the MetricsEntity class.\n    // The PartitionKey identifies the DataTime of the metrics.\n    where entity.PartitionKey.CompareTo(start) >= 0 && entity.PartitionKey.CompareTo(end) <= 0 \n    select entity;\n    \n    // Filter on \"user\" transactions after fetching the metrics from Table Storage.\n    // (StartsWith is not supported using LINQ with Azure table storage)\n    var results = query.ToList().Where(m => m.RowKey.StartsWith(\"user\"));\n    var resultString = results.Aggregate(new StringBuilder(), (builder, metrics) => builder.AppendLine(MetricsString(metrics, opContext))).ToString();\n    Console.WriteLine(resultString);\n    }\n    }\n    \n    private static string MetricsString(MetricsEntity entity, OperationContext opContext)\n    {\n    var entityProperties = entity.WriteEntity(opContext);\n    var entityString =\n    string.Format(\"Time: {0}, \", entity.Time) +\n    string.Format(\"AccessType: {0}, \", entity.AccessType) +\n    string.Format(\"TransactionType: {0}, \", entity.TransactionType) +\n    string.Join(\",\", entityProperties.Select(e => new KeyValuePair<string, string>(e.Key.ToString(), e.Value.PropertyAsObject.ToString())));\n    return entityString;\n    \n    }\n\n\n\n\n## What charges do you incur when you enable storage metrics?\n\nWrite requests to create table entities for metrics are charged at the standard rates applicable to all Azure Storage operations.\n\nRead and delete requests by a client to metrics data are also billable at standard rates. If you have configured a data retention policy, you are not charged when Azure Storage deletes old metrics data. However, if you delete analytics data, your account is charged for the delete operations.\n\nThe capacity used by the metrics tables is also billable: you can use the following to estimate the amount of capacity used for storing metrics data:\n\n- If each hour a service utilizes every API in every service, then approximately 148KB of data is stored every hour in the metrics transaction tables if you have enabled both service and API level summary.\n\n- If each hour a service utilizes every API in every service, then approximately 12KB of data is stored every hour in the metrics transaction tables if you have enabled just service level summary.\n\n- The capacity table for blobs has two rows added each day (provided user has opted in for logs): this implies that every day the size of this table increases by up to approximately 300 bytes.\n\n## Next-steps:\n[Enabling Storage logging and accessing log data](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn782840.aspx)\n "
}