{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Data Catalog release notes",
      "pos": [
        26,
        58
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Release notes for the 28 August 2015 public preview release of Azure Data Catalog.",
      "pos": [
        76,
        158
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Data Catalog release notes",
      "pos": [
        461,
        493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Notes for the 28 August 2015 release of Azure Data Catalog",
      "pos": [
        498,
        556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data profile missing for some registered data assets",
      "pos": [
        562,
        614
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When registering data sources with the data profiling option selected in the data source registration tool, the data profile information may not be included in the following scenarios:",
      "pos": [
        616,
        800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure SQL Database tables",
      "pos": [
        804,
        829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Server tables and views where there are multiple objects with the same name in different schemas",
      "pos": [
        832,
        932
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Server tables and views with column names greater than 118 characters",
      "pos": [
        935,
        1008
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Oracle tables and views with column names greater than 20 characters",
      "pos": [
        1011,
        1079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Oracle tables and views with spaces or multu-byte characters in column names",
      "pos": [
        1082,
        1158
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These restrictions are due to a known issue in the August 28 release, and will be addressed in a future update to Azure Data Catalog.",
      "pos": [
        1160,
        1293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Notes for the 13 July 2015 release of Azure Data Catalog",
      "pos": [
        1298,
        1354
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Registering and Connecting to Oracle Database",
      "pos": [
        1360,
        1405
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When connecting to Oracle Database data sources users must have installed the correct Oracle drivers that match the bitness (32-bit or 64-bit) of the software being used.",
      "pos": [
        1407,
        1577
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When registering Oracle data sources on a computer running 32-bit Windows, the 32-bit Oracle drivers will be used",
      "pos": [
        1583,
        1696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When registering Oracle data sources on a computer running 64-bit Windows, the 64-bit Oracle drivers will be used",
      "pos": [
        1701,
        1814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When connecting to Oracle data sources using Excel on a computer running the 32-bit version of Microsoft Office, including on 64-bit Windows, the 32-bit Oracle drivers will be used",
      "pos": [
        1819,
        1999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When connecting to Oracle data sources using Excel on a computer running the 64-bit version of Microsoft Office, the 64-bit Oracle drivers will be used",
      "pos": [
        2004,
        2155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Registering and connecting to SQL Server Reporting Services",
      "pos": [
        2161,
        2220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Support for SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) data sources in the initial preview release of Azure Data Catalog is limited to Native Mode servers only.",
      "pos": [
        2222,
        2376
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Support for SSRS in SharePoint mode will be added in a later release.",
      "pos": [
        2377,
        2446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Opening data assets in Excel",
      "pos": [
        2452,
        2480
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When opening data assets in Microsoft Excel from the Azure Data Catalog portal, users may be prompted with a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Excel Security Notice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box.",
      "pos": [
        2482,
        2638
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is standard, expected behavior, and users can select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to continue.",
      "pos": [
        2639,
        2720
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2722,
        2991
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Enable or disable security alerts about links and files from suspicious websites<ept id=\"p1\">](https://support.office.com/en-us/article/Enable-or-disable-security-alerts-about-links-and-files-from-suspicious-websites-A1AC6AE9-5C4A-4EB3-B3F8-143336039BBE)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "BLOB and UDT columns missing in previews",
      "pos": [
        2997,
        3037
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When registering tables and views that contain binary large object (BLOB) and user-defined data type (UDT) columns, and selecting to include preview for the data assets, these columns will not be included in the preview.",
      "pos": [
        3039,
        3259
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Proxy and policy configuration and data source registration",
      "pos": [
        3265,
        3324
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users may encounter a situation where they can log on to the Azure Data Catalog portal, but when they attempt to log on to the data source registration tool they encounter an error message that prevents them from logging on.",
      "pos": [
        3326,
        3550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two potential causes for this problem behavior:",
      "pos": [
        3552,
        3609
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cause 1: Active Directory Federation Services Configuration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        3611,
        3674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The data source registration tool uses Forms Authentication to validate user logons against Active Directory.",
      "pos": [
        3675,
        3784
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For successful logon, Forms Authentication must be enabled in the Global Authentication Policy by an Active Directory administrator.",
      "pos": [
        3785,
        3917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In some situations, this error behavior may occur only when the user is on the company network, or only when the user is connecting from outside the company network.",
      "pos": [
        3919,
        4084
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Global Authentication Policy allows authentication methods to be enabled separately for intranet and extranet connections.",
      "pos": [
        4085,
        4211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Logon errors may occur if Forms Authentication is not enabled for the network from which the user is connecting.",
      "pos": [
        4212,
        4324
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4326,
        4491
      ],
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configuring intranet forms-based authentication for devices that do not support WIA<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn727110.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cause 2: Network Proxy Configuration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        4493,
        4533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the corporate network uses a proxy server, the registration tool may not be able to connect to Azure Active Directory through the proxy.",
      "pos": [
        4534,
        4673
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users can ensure that the registration tool by editing the tool’s configuration file, adding this section to the file:",
      "pos": [
        4674,
        4792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To locate the RegistrationTool.exe.config file, launch the registration tool, and then open the Windows Task Manager utility.",
      "pos": [
        5100,
        5225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the Details tab in Task manager, right-click on RegistrationTool.exe and choose Open file location from the pop-up menu.",
      "pos": [
        5226,
        5349
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        5351,
        5355
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Azure Data Catalog release notes\"\n   description=\"Release notes for the 28 August 2015 public preview release of Azure Data Catalog.\"\n   services=\"data-catalog\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"steelanddata\"\n   manager=\"NA\"\n   editor=\"\"\n   tags=\"\"/>\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"data-catalog\"\n   ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"data-catalog\"\n   ms.date=\"08/28/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"maroche\"/>\n\n# Azure Data Catalog release notes\n\n## Notes for the 28 August 2015 release of Azure Data Catalog\n\n### Data profile missing for some registered data assets\n\nWhen registering data sources with the data profiling option selected in the data source registration tool, the data profile information may not be included in the following scenarios:\n\n* Azure SQL Database tables\n* SQL Server tables and views where there are multiple objects with the same name in different schemas\n* SQL Server tables and views with column names greater than 118 characters\n* Oracle tables and views with column names greater than 20 characters\n* Oracle tables and views with spaces or multu-byte characters in column names\n\nThese restrictions are due to a known issue in the August 28 release, and will be addressed in a future update to Azure Data Catalog.\n\n## Notes for the 13 July 2015 release of Azure Data Catalog\n\n### Registering and Connecting to Oracle Database\n\nWhen connecting to Oracle Database data sources users must have installed the correct Oracle drivers that match the bitness (32-bit or 64-bit) of the software being used.\n\n-   When registering Oracle data sources on a computer running 32-bit Windows, the 32-bit Oracle drivers will be used\n-   When registering Oracle data sources on a computer running 64-bit Windows, the 64-bit Oracle drivers will be used\n-   When connecting to Oracle data sources using Excel on a computer running the 32-bit version of Microsoft Office, including on 64-bit Windows, the 32-bit Oracle drivers will be used\n-   When connecting to Oracle data sources using Excel on a computer running the 64-bit version of Microsoft Office, the 64-bit Oracle drivers will be used\n\n### Registering and connecting to SQL Server Reporting Services\n\nSupport for SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) data sources in the initial preview release of Azure Data Catalog is limited to Native Mode servers only. Support for SSRS in SharePoint mode will be added in a later release.\n\n### Opening data assets in Excel\n\nWhen opening data assets in Microsoft Excel from the Azure Data Catalog portal, users may be prompted with a **Microsoft Excel Security Notice** dialog box. This is standard, expected behavior, and users can select **Enable** to continue.\n\nFor more information, see [Enable or disable security alerts about links and files from suspicious websites](https://support.office.com/en-us/article/Enable-or-disable-security-alerts-about-links-and-files-from-suspicious-websites-A1AC6AE9-5C4A-4EB3-B3F8-143336039BBE).\n\n### BLOB and UDT columns missing in previews\n\nWhen registering tables and views that contain binary large object (BLOB) and user-defined data type (UDT) columns, and selecting to include preview for the data assets, these columns will not be included in the preview.\n\n### Proxy and policy configuration and data source registration\n\nUsers may encounter a situation where they can log on to the Azure Data Catalog portal, but when they attempt to log on to the data source registration tool they encounter an error message that prevents them from logging on.\n\nThere are two potential causes for this problem behavior:\n\n**Cause 1: Active Directory Federation Services Configuration**\nThe data source registration tool uses Forms Authentication to validate user logons against Active Directory. For successful logon, Forms Authentication must be enabled in the Global Authentication Policy by an Active Directory administrator.\n\nIn some situations, this error behavior may occur only when the user is on the company network, or only when the user is connecting from outside the company network. The Global Authentication Policy allows authentication methods to be enabled separately for intranet and extranet connections. Logon errors may occur if Forms Authentication is not enabled for the network from which the user is connecting.\n\nFor more information, see [Configuring intranet forms-based authentication for devices that do not support WIA](https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn727110.aspx).\n\n**Cause 2: Network Proxy Configuration**\nIf the corporate network uses a proxy server, the registration tool may not be able to connect to Azure Active Directory through the proxy. Users can ensure that the registration tool by editing the tool’s configuration file, adding this section to the file:\n\n\n      <system.net>\n        <defaultProxy useDefaultCredentials=\"true\" enabled=\"true\">\n          <proxy usesystemdefault=\"True\"\n                          proxyaddress=\"http://<your corporate network proxy url>\"\n                          bypassonlocal=\"True\"/>\n        </defaultProxy>\n      </system.net>\n\n\nTo locate the RegistrationTool.exe.config file, launch the registration tool, and then open the Windows Task Manager utility. On the Details tab in Task manager, right-click on RegistrationTool.exe and choose Open file location from the pop-up menu.\n\ntest\n"
}