{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "How to Configure an App Service Environment",
      "pos": [
        28,
        71
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuration, management and monitoring of App Service Environments",
      "pos": [
        91,
        159
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configuring an App Service Environment",
      "pos": [
        471,
        509
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        516,
        524
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service Environments is a new Premium Tier capability that is being offered in Preview.",
      "pos": [
        529,
        620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It offers new scaling and network access capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        622,
        676
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This new scale capability allows you to place an instance of the Azure App Service into your VNET.",
      "pos": [
        678,
        776
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are unfamiliar with the App Service Environment (ASE) capability then read the document here [What is an App Service Environment]/app-service-app-service-environment-intro.md).",
      "pos": [
        778,
        961
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information on how to create an ASE read the document here <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Create an App Service Environment<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-web-how-to-create-an-app-service-environment.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        962,
        1129
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "At a high level an App Service Environment consists of several major components:",
      "pos": [
        1132,
        1212
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Compute resources running in the Azure App Environment Hosted Service",
      "pos": [
        1216,
        1285
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Storage",
      "pos": [
        1288,
        1295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Database",
      "pos": [
        1298,
        1306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual Network with at least one subnet",
      "pos": [
        1309,
        1349
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "subnet with the Azure App Environment hosted service running in it",
      "pos": [
        1352,
        1418
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To help manage and monitor your App Service Environments you can access UI for that purpose from Browse -&gt; App Service Environments in the Azure preview portal.",
      "pos": [
        1420,
        1580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The initial release does have what you need to manage the system and will continue to improve with additional capabilities in coming weeks.",
      "pos": [
        1581,
        1720
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][1]",
      "pos": [
        1724,
        1730
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitoring",
      "pos": [
        1735,
        1745
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There aren't many metrics capabilities available in the initial Preview release but they will be rolling out shortly.",
      "pos": [
        1750,
        1867
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Those metrics capabilities will help system administrators to make decisions on system scaling and operations.",
      "pos": [
        1869,
        1979
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Even now in the portal you can list all of the App Service Plans in the ASE as well as all of the web apps in the App Service Environment.",
      "pos": [
        1981,
        2119
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To see either list go to Settings and select the item you are interested in.",
      "pos": [
        2121,
        2197
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][3]",
      "pos": [
        2201,
        2207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In both lists you can see the Worker Pool assignment with how many instances and the size of the compute resource that is being used.",
      "pos": [
        2209,
        2342
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Details around the performance within an individual App Service Plan will be available the same as normal which is by opening up the App Service Plan UI.",
      "pos": [
        2344,
        2497
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][4]",
      "pos": [
        2501,
        2507
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Compute Resources",
      "pos": [
        2512,
        2529
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The compute resources, Storage and Database are all operated by the Azure App Service.",
      "pos": [
        2534,
        2620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The quantity and sizes of compute resources though are up to the user to decide.",
      "pos": [
        2622,
        2702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Regardless of the size of the compute resources, the minimum footprint has 2 Front End servers and 2 Workers.",
      "pos": [
        2706,
        2815
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An App Service Environment can be configured to use up to 55 total compute resources.",
      "pos": [
        2817,
        2902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Of those 55 compute resources, only 50 can be used to host workloads.",
      "pos": [
        2904,
        2973
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The reason for that is two fold.",
      "pos": [
        2974,
        3006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are a minimum of 2 Front End compute resources.",
      "pos": [
        3008,
        3061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "That leaves up to 53 to support worker pool allocation.",
      "pos": [
        3063,
        3118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In order to provide fault tolerance though, you need to have an additional compute resource allocated according to the following rules:",
      "pos": [
        3119,
        3254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "each worker pool needs at least one additional compute resource which cannot be assigned workload",
      "pos": [
        3258,
        3355
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "when the quantity of compute resources in a pool goes above a certain value then another compute resource is required",
      "pos": [
        3358,
        3475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Within any single worker pool the fault tolerance requirements are that for a given value of X resources assigned to a worker pool:",
      "pos": [
        3477,
        3608
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "if X is between 2 to 20, the amount of usable compute resources you can use for workloads is X-1",
      "pos": [
        3612,
        3708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "if X is between 21 to 40, the amount of usable compute resources you can use for workloads is X-2",
      "pos": [
        3711,
        3808
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "if X is between 41 to 53, the amount of usable compute resources you can use for workloads is X-3",
      "pos": [
        3811,
        3908
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition to being able to manage the quantity of compute resources that you can assign to a given pool you also have control over the size.",
      "pos": [
        3910,
        4052
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With App Service Environments you can choose from 4 different sizes labeled P1 through P4.",
      "pos": [
        4054,
        4144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For details around those sizes and their pricing please see here <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>App Service Pricing<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service/app-service-value-prop-what-is.md)</ept> The P1 to P3 compute resource sizes are the same as what is available normally.",
      "pos": [
        4146,
        4362
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The P4 compute resource gives 8 cores with 14 GB of RAM and is only available in an App Service Environment.",
      "pos": [
        4364,
        4472
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As noted earlier, the App Service Environment feature is currently in Preview and as such it still has room to grow.",
      "pos": [
        4474,
        4590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition to additional monitoring capabilities, more management features will be rolled out as App Service Environments moves to GA.",
      "pos": [
        4592,
        4727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For now there are only a few things that can be managed in this interface:",
      "pos": [
        4729,
        4803
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Number of compute resources in each pool",
      "pos": [
        4807,
        4847
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Size of the compute resources in each pool",
      "pos": [
        4850,
        4892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Number of IP addresses available",
      "pos": [
        4895,
        4927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To control these things select the Scale configuration item at the top.",
      "pos": [
        4929,
        5000
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][2]",
      "pos": [
        5004,
        5010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The quantity of compute resources in each pool and their size can be adjusted here.",
      "pos": [
        5012,
        5095
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Before making any changes though it is important to note a few things:",
      "pos": [
        5097,
        5167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "changes made can take hours to complete depending on how large is the change requested",
      "pos": [
        5171,
        5257
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "when there is already a App Service Environment configuration change in work, you cannot start another change",
      "pos": [
        5260,
        5369
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "if you change the size of the compute resources used in a worker pool you can cause outages for the web apps running in that worker pool",
      "pos": [
        5372,
        5508
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adding additional instances to a worker pool is a benign operation and does not incur a system impact.",
      "pos": [
        5510,
        5612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Changing the size of the compute resource used in a worker pool is another story though.",
      "pos": [
        5614,
        5702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To avoid any app down time during a size change to a worker pool it is best to:",
      "pos": [
        5704,
        5783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "use an unused worker pool to bring up the instances required in the size desired",
      "pos": [
        5787,
        5867
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "scale the App Service Plans to the new worker pool.",
      "pos": [
        5870,
        5921
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is much less disruptive to running apps than changing the compute resource size with running workloads.",
      "pos": [
        5926,
        6034
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For details around scaling web apps in an App Service Environment go here <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Scaling Web Apps in an App Service Environment<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-web-scale-a-web-app-in-an-app-service-environment.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        6036,
        6224
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Virtual Network",
      "pos": [
        6231,
        6246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Virtual Network<ept id=\"p1\">][virtualnetwork]</ept> and subnet are all under user control.",
      "pos": [
        6251,
        6327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "App Service Environments does have a few network requirements but the rest is up to the user to control.",
      "pos": [
        6329,
        6433
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Those ASE requirements are:",
      "pos": [
        6435,
        6462
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "a VNET with at least 512 addresses",
      "pos": [
        6466,
        6500
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "a subnet with at least 256 addresses",
      "pos": [
        6503,
        6539
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "the VNET must be a regional VNET",
      "pos": [
        6543,
        6575
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Administering your VNET is done through the normal Virtual Network UI.",
      "pos": [
        6580,
        6650
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because this capability places the Azure App Service into your VNET it means that your apps hosted in your ASE can now access resources made available through ExpressRoute or Site to Site VPNs directly.",
      "pos": [
        6652,
        6854
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The apps within your App Service Environments do not require additional networking features to access resources available to the VNET hosting your App Service Environment.",
      "pos": [
        6856,
        7027
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If desired you can also now control access using Network Security Groups.",
      "pos": [
        7031,
        7104
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This capability allows you to lock down your App Service Environment to just the IP addresses you wish to restrict it to.",
      "pos": [
        7106,
        7227
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information around how to do that see the document here <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Control Inbound Traffic in an App Service Environment<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-app-service-environment-control-inbound-traffic.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        7229,
        7421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deleting an App Service Environment",
      "pos": [
        7426,
        7461
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you want to delete an App Service Environment then simply use the Delete action at the top of the App Service Environment blade.",
      "pos": [
        7466,
        7597
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot delete an ASE though that has content in it.",
      "pos": [
        7599,
        7654
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Be sure to remove all web apps and App Service Plans in order to delete your App Service Environment.",
      "pos": [
        7656,
        7757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Getting started",
      "pos": [
        7764,
        7779
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7781,
        7934
      ],
      "content": "To get started with App Service Environments, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How To Create An App Service Environment<ept id=\"p1\">](app-service-web-how-to-create-an-app-service-environment.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7936,
        8069
      ],
      "content": "For more information about the Azure App Service platform, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure App Service<ept id=\"p1\">](../app-service/app-service-value-prop-what-is.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        9542,
        9546
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"How to Configure an App Service Environment\" \n    description=\"Configuration, management and monitoring of App Service Environments\" \n    services=\"app-service\\web\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"ccompy\" \n    manager=\"stefsch\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"app-service-web\" \n    ms.workload=\"web\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"04/27/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"ccompy\"/>\n\n# Configuring an App Service Environment #\n\n## Overview ##\n\nApp Service Environments is a new Premium Tier capability that is being offered in Preview.  It offers new scaling and network access capabilities.  This new scale capability allows you to place an instance of the Azure App Service into your VNET.  If you are unfamiliar with the App Service Environment (ASE) capability then read the document here [What is an App Service Environment]/app-service-app-service-environment-intro.md). For information on how to create an ASE read the document here [How to Create an App Service Environment](app-service-web-how-to-create-an-app-service-environment.md). \n\nAt a high level an App Service Environment consists of several major components:\n\n- Compute resources running in the Azure App Environment Hosted Service\n- Storage\n- Database\n- Virtual Network with at least one subnet\n- subnet with the Azure App Environment hosted service running in it\n\nTo help manage and monitor your App Service Environments you can access UI for that purpose from Browse -> App Service Environments in the Azure preview portal. The initial release does have what you need to manage the system and will continue to improve with additional capabilities in coming weeks.  \n\n![][1]\n\n## Monitoring ##\n\nThere aren't many metrics capabilities available in the initial Preview release but they will be rolling out shortly.  Those metrics capabilities will help system administrators to make decisions on system scaling and operations.\n\nEven now in the portal you can list all of the App Service Plans in the ASE as well as all of the web apps in the App Service Environment.  To see either list go to Settings and select the item you are interested in.  \n\n![][3]\n\nIn both lists you can see the Worker Pool assignment with how many instances and the size of the compute resource that is being used.  Details around the performance within an individual App Service Plan will be available the same as normal which is by opening up the App Service Plan UI.  \n\n![][4]\n\n## Compute Resources ##\n\nThe compute resources, Storage and Database are all operated by the Azure App Service.  The quantity and sizes of compute resources though are up to the user to decide.  \n\nRegardless of the size of the compute resources, the minimum footprint has 2 Front End servers and 2 Workers.  An App Service Environment can be configured to use up to 55 total compute resources.  Of those 55 compute resources, only 50 can be used to host workloads. The reason for that is two fold.  There are a minimum of 2 Front End compute resources.  That leaves up to 53 to support worker pool allocation. In order to provide fault tolerance though, you need to have an additional compute resource allocated according to the following rules:\n\n- each worker pool needs at least one additional compute resource which cannot be assigned workload\n- when the quantity of compute resources in a pool goes above a certain value then another compute resource is required\n\nWithin any single worker pool the fault tolerance requirements are that for a given value of X resources assigned to a worker pool:\n\n- if X is between 2 to 20, the amount of usable compute resources you can use for workloads is X-1\n- if X is between 21 to 40, the amount of usable compute resources you can use for workloads is X-2\n- if X is between 41 to 53, the amount of usable compute resources you can use for workloads is X-3\n\nIn addition to being able to manage the quantity of compute resources that you can assign to a given pool you also have control over the size.  With App Service Environments you can choose from 4 different sizes labeled P1 through P4.  For details around those sizes and their pricing please see here [App Service Pricing](../app-service/app-service-value-prop-what-is.md) The P1 to P3 compute resource sizes are the same as what is available normally.  The P4 compute resource gives 8 cores with 14 GB of RAM and is only available in an App Service Environment.\n\nAs noted earlier, the App Service Environment feature is currently in Preview and as such it still has room to grow.  In addition to additional monitoring capabilities, more management features will be rolled out as App Service Environments moves to GA.  For now there are only a few things that can be managed in this interface:\n\n- Number of compute resources in each pool\n- Size of the compute resources in each pool\n- Number of IP addresses available\n\nTo control these things select the Scale configuration item at the top.  \n\n![][2]\n\nThe quantity of compute resources in each pool and their size can be adjusted here.  Before making any changes though it is important to note a few things:\n\n- changes made can take hours to complete depending on how large is the change requested\n- when there is already a App Service Environment configuration change in work, you cannot start another change\n- if you change the size of the compute resources used in a worker pool you can cause outages for the web apps running in that worker pool\n\nAdding additional instances to a worker pool is a benign operation and does not incur a system impact.  Changing the size of the compute resource used in a worker pool is another story though.  To avoid any app down time during a size change to a worker pool it is best to:\n\n- use an unused worker pool to bring up the instances required in the size desired\n- scale the App Service Plans to the new worker pool.  \n \nThis is much less disruptive to running apps than changing the compute resource size with running workloads.  For details around scaling web apps in an App Service Environment go here [Scaling Web Apps in an App Service Environment](app-service-web-scale-a-web-app-in-an-app-service-environment.md)  \n\n## Virtual Network ##\n\nThe [Virtual Network][virtualnetwork] and subnet are all under user control.  App Service Environments does have a few network requirements but the rest is up to the user to control.  Those ASE requirements are:\n\n- a VNET with at least 512 addresses\n- a subnet with at least 256 addresses \n- the VNET must be a regional VNET  \n \nAdministering your VNET is done through the normal Virtual Network UI.\n\nBecause this capability places the Azure App Service into your VNET it means that your apps hosted in your ASE can now access resources made available through ExpressRoute or Site to Site VPNs directly.  The apps within your App Service Environments do not require additional networking features to access resources available to the VNET hosting your App Service Environment.  \n\nIf desired you can also now control access using Network Security Groups.  This capability allows you to lock down your App Service Environment to just the IP addresses you wish to restrict it to.  For more information around how to do that see the document here [How to Control Inbound Traffic in an App Service Environment](app-service-app-service-environment-control-inbound-traffic.md).\n\n## Deleting an App Service Environment ##\n\nIf you want to delete an App Service Environment then simply use the Delete action at the top of the App Service Environment blade.  You cannot delete an ASE though that has content in it.  Be sure to remove all web apps and App Service Plans in order to delete your App Service Environment.  \n\n## Getting started\n\nTo get started with App Service Environments, see [How To Create An App Service Environment](app-service-web-how-to-create-an-app-service-environment.md)\n\nFor more information about the Azure App Service platform, see [Azure App Service](../app-service/app-service-value-prop-what-is.md).\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [app-service-web-whats-changed](../../includes/app-service-web-whats-changed.md)]\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [app-service-web-try-app-service](../../includes/app-service-web-try-app-service.md)]\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/app-service-web-configure-an-app-service-environment/configureaseblade.png\n[2]: ./media/app-service-web-configure-an-app-service-environment/configurescale.png\n[3]: ./media/app-service-web-configure-an-app-service-environment/configureasplist.png\n[4]: ./media/app-service-web-configure-an-app-service-environment/configurewebapplist.png\n\n<!--Links-->\n[WhatisASE]: http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/app-service-app-service-environment-intro/\n[Appserviceplans]: http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/azure-web-sites-web-hosting-plans-in-depth-overview/\n[HowtoCreateASE]: http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/app-service-web-how-to-create-an-app-service-environment/\n[HowtoScale]: http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/app-service-web-scale-a-web-app-in-an-app-service-environment/\n[ControlInbound]: http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/app-service-app-service-environment-control-inbound-traffic/\n[virtualnetwork]: https://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/virtual-networks-faq/\n[AppServicePricing]: http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/details/app-service/ \n[AzureAppService]: http://azure.microsoft.com/documentation/articles/app-service-value-prop-what-is/\n \n\ntest\n"
}