{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Plans and Billing in Azure Scheduler",
      "pos": [
        25,
        61
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Plans and Billing in Azure Scheduler",
      "pos": [
        373,
        409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Job Collection Plans",
      "pos": [
        414,
        434
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Job collections are the billable entity in Azure Scheduler.",
      "pos": [
        436,
        495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Job collections contain a number of jobs and come in three plans – Free, Standard, and Premium – that are described below.",
      "pos": [
        496,
        618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Job Collection Plan",
      "pos": [
        623,
        642
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Max # of Jobs per Job Collection",
      "pos": [
        647,
        679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Max Recurrence",
      "pos": [
        684,
        698
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Max Job Collections per Subscription",
      "pos": [
        703,
        739
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Limits",
      "pos": [
        744,
        750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Free",
      "pos": [
        784,
        788
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "5 jobs per job collection",
      "pos": [
        791,
        816
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once per hour.",
      "pos": [
        817,
        831
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cannot execute jobs more often than once an hour",
      "pos": [
        832,
        880
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A subscription is allowed up to 1 free job collection",
      "pos": [
        881,
        934
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        935,
        1020
      ],
      "content": "Cannot use <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>HTTP outbound authorization object<ept id=\"p1\">](scheduler-outbound-authentication.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard",
      "pos": [
        1024,
        1032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "50 jobs per job collection",
      "pos": [
        1035,
        1061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once per minute.",
      "pos": [
        1062,
        1078
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cannot execute jobs more often than once a minute",
      "pos": [
        1079,
        1128
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A subscription is allowed up to 100 standard job collections",
      "pos": [
        1129,
        1189
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access to full feature set of Scheduler",
      "pos": [
        1190,
        1229
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Premium",
      "pos": [
        1234,
        1241
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "50 jobs per job collection",
      "pos": [
        1244,
        1270
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once per minute.",
      "pos": [
        1271,
        1287
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cannot execute jobs more often than once a minute",
      "pos": [
        1288,
        1337
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A subscription is allowed up to 10,000 premium job collections.",
      "pos": [
        1338,
        1401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"mailto:wapteams@microsoft.com\"&gt;</ph>Contact us<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph> for more.",
      "pos": [
        1402,
        1466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Access to full feature set of Scheduler",
      "pos": [
        1467,
        1506
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Upgrades and Downgrades of Job Collection Plans",
      "pos": [
        1512,
        1559
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You may upgrade or downgrade a job collection plan anytime among the Free, Standard, and Premium plans.",
      "pos": [
        1561,
        1664
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, when downgrading to a free job collection, the downgrade may fail for one of the following reasons:",
      "pos": [
        1665,
        1773
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A free job collection already exists in the subscription",
      "pos": [
        1777,
        1833
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A job in the job collection has a higher recurrence than allowed for jobs in free job collections.",
      "pos": [
        1836,
        1934
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The maximum recurrence allowed in a free job collection is once per hour",
      "pos": [
        1935,
        2007
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are more than 5 jobs in the job collection",
      "pos": [
        2010,
        2058
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2061,
        2204
      ],
      "content": "A job in the job collection has an HTTP or HTTPS action that uses an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>HTTP outbound authorization object<ept id=\"p1\">](scheduler-outbound-authentication.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Billing and Azure Plans",
      "pos": [
        2209,
        2232
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Subscriptions are not charged for free job collections.",
      "pos": [
        2234,
        2289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have more than 100 standard job collections (10 standard billing units), then it's a better deal to have all job collections in the premium plan.",
      "pos": [
        2290,
        2442
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have one standard job collection and one premium job collection, you are billed one standard billing unit <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>and<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> one premium billing unit.",
      "pos": [
        2444,
        2588
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Scheduler service bills based on the number of active job collections that are set to either standard or premium; this is explained further in the next two sections.",
      "pos": [
        2589,
        2758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Standard Billable Units",
      "pos": [
        2763,
        2786
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A standard billable unit can include up to 10 standard job collections.",
      "pos": [
        2788,
        2859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since a standard job collection can have up to 50 jobs per job collection, one standard billing unit allows a subscription to have up to 500 jobs – up to almost 22 million job executions per month.",
      "pos": [
        2860,
        3057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have between 1 and 10 standard job collections, you'll be billed for 1 standard billing unit.",
      "pos": [
        3059,
        3159
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have between 11 and 20 standard job collections, you'll be billed for 2 standard billing units.",
      "pos": [
        3160,
        3262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have between 21 and 30 standard job collections, you'll be billed for 3 standard billing units, and so on.",
      "pos": [
        3263,
        3376
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Premium Billable Units",
      "pos": [
        3381,
        3403
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A premium billable unit can include up to 10,000 premium job collections.",
      "pos": [
        3405,
        3478
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since a premium job collection can have up to 50 jobs per job collection, one premium billing unit allows a subscription to have up to 500,000 jobs – up to almost 22 billion job executions per month.",
      "pos": [
        3479,
        3678
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have between 1 and 10,000 premium job collections, you'll be billed for 1 premium billing unit.",
      "pos": [
        3680,
        3782
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have between 10,001 and 20,000 premium job collections, you'll be billed for 2 premium billing units, and so on.",
      "pos": [
        3783,
        3902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Thus, premium job collections have the same functionality as the standard job collections but provide a price break in case your application requires a lot of job collections.",
      "pos": [
        3904,
        4079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Billing and Active Status",
      "pos": [
        4085,
        4110
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Job collections are always active unless your entire subscription has gone into some temporary disabled state due to billing issues.",
      "pos": [
        4112,
        4244
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The only way to ensure that a job collection is not billed is to either set it to the <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>Free<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> plan or to delete the job collection.",
      "pos": [
        4245,
        4375
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Although you may disable all jobs within a job collection in a single operation, it does not change the billing status of the job collection – the job collection will <bpt id=\"p1\">_</bpt>still<ept id=\"p1\">_</ept> be billed.",
      "pos": [
        4377,
        4562
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Similarly, empty job collections are considered active and will be billed.",
      "pos": [
        4563,
        4637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pricing",
      "pos": [
        4643,
        4650
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4652,
        4759
      ],
      "content": "For pricing details, please see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Scheduler Pricing<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/details/scheduler/)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "See Also",
      "pos": [
        4764,
        4772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Scheduler?",
      "pos": [
        4777,
        4795
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduler Concepts, Terminology, and Entity Hierarchy",
      "pos": [
        4821,
        4874
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get Started Using Scheduler in the Management Portal",
      "pos": [
        4908,
        4960
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to Build Complex Schedules and Advanced Recurrence with Azure Scheduler",
      "pos": [
        4998,
        5073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduler REST API Reference",
      "pos": [
        5112,
        5140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduler PowerShell Cmdlets Reference",
      "pos": [
        5193,
        5231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduler High-Availability and Reliability",
      "pos": [
        5272,
        5315
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduler Limits, Defaults, and Error Codes",
      "pos": [
        5364,
        5407
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduler Outbound Authentication",
      "pos": [
        5449,
        5482
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n pageTitle=\"Plans and Billing in Azure Scheduler\" \n description=\"\" \n services=\"scheduler\" \n documentationCenter=\".NET\" \n authors=\"krisragh\" \n manager=\"dwrede\" \n editor=\"\"/>\n<tags \n ms.service=\"scheduler\" \n ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\" \n ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n ms.devlang=\"dotnet\" \n ms.topic=\"article\" \n ms.date=\"08/04/2015\" \n ms.author=\"krisragh\"/>\n \n# Plans and Billing in Azure Scheduler\n\n## Job Collection Plans\n\nJob collections are the billable entity in Azure Scheduler. Job collections contain a number of jobs and come in three plans – Free, Standard, and Premium – that are described below.\n\n|**Job Collection Plan**|**Max # of Jobs per Job Collection**|**Max Recurrence**|**Max Job Collections per Subscription**|**Limits**|\n|:---|:---|:---|:---|:---|\n|**Free**|5 jobs per job collection|Once per hour. Cannot execute jobs more often than once an hour|A subscription is allowed up to 1 free job collection|Cannot use [HTTP outbound authorization object](scheduler-outbound-authentication.md)\n|**Standard**|50 jobs per job collection|Once per minute. Cannot execute jobs more often than once a minute|A subscription is allowed up to 100 standard job collections|Access to full feature set of Scheduler|\n|**Premium**|50 jobs per job collection|Once per minute. Cannot execute jobs more often than once a minute|A subscription is allowed up to 10,000 premium job collections. <a href=\"mailto:wapteams@microsoft.com\">Contact us</a> for more.|Access to full feature set of Scheduler|\n\n## Upgrades and Downgrades of Job Collection Plans\n\nYou may upgrade or downgrade a job collection plan anytime among the Free, Standard, and Premium plans. However, when downgrading to a free job collection, the downgrade may fail for one of the following reasons:\n\n- A free job collection already exists in the subscription\n- A job in the job collection has a higher recurrence than allowed for jobs in free job collections. The maximum recurrence allowed in a free job collection is once per hour\n- There are more than 5 jobs in the job collection\n- A job in the job collection has an HTTP or HTTPS action that uses an [HTTP outbound authorization object](scheduler-outbound-authentication.md)\n\n## Billing and Azure Plans\n\nSubscriptions are not charged for free job collections. If you have more than 100 standard job collections (10 standard billing units), then it's a better deal to have all job collections in the premium plan.\n\nIf you have one standard job collection and one premium job collection, you are billed one standard billing unit _and_ one premium billing unit. The Scheduler service bills based on the number of active job collections that are set to either standard or premium; this is explained further in the next two sections.\n\n## Standard Billable Units\n\nA standard billable unit can include up to 10 standard job collections. Since a standard job collection can have up to 50 jobs per job collection, one standard billing unit allows a subscription to have up to 500 jobs – up to almost 22 million job executions per month.\n\nIf you have between 1 and 10 standard job collections, you'll be billed for 1 standard billing unit. If you have between 11 and 20 standard job collections, you'll be billed for 2 standard billing units. If you have between 21 and 30 standard job collections, you'll be billed for 3 standard billing units, and so on.\n\n## Premium Billable Units\n\nA premium billable unit can include up to 10,000 premium job collections. Since a premium job collection can have up to 50 jobs per job collection, one premium billing unit allows a subscription to have up to 500,000 jobs – up to almost 22 billion job executions per month.\n\nIf you have between 1 and 10,000 premium job collections, you'll be billed for 1 premium billing unit. If you have between 10,001 and 20,000 premium job collections, you'll be billed for 2 premium billing units, and so on.\n\nThus, premium job collections have the same functionality as the standard job collections but provide a price break in case your application requires a lot of job collections. \n\n## Billing and Active Status\n\nJob collections are always active unless your entire subscription has gone into some temporary disabled state due to billing issues. The only way to ensure that a job collection is not billed is to either set it to the _Free_ plan or to delete the job collection.\n\nAlthough you may disable all jobs within a job collection in a single operation, it does not change the billing status of the job collection – the job collection will _still_ be billed. Similarly, empty job collections are considered active and will be billed. \n\n## Pricing\n\nFor pricing details, please see [Scheduler Pricing](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/details/scheduler/).\n\n## See Also\n \n [What is Scheduler?](scheduler-intro.md)\n \n [Scheduler Concepts, Terminology, and Entity Hierarchy](scheduler-concepts-terms.md)\n\n [Get Started Using Scheduler in the Management Portal](scheduler-get-started-portal.md)\n\n [How to Build Complex Schedules and Advanced Recurrence with Azure Scheduler](scheduler-advanced-complexity.md)\n\n [Scheduler REST API Reference](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn528946)   \n\n [Scheduler PowerShell Cmdlets Reference](scheduler-powershell-reference.md)\n \n [Scheduler High-Availability and Reliability](scheduler-high-availability-reliability.md)\n\n [Scheduler Limits, Defaults, and Error Codes](scheduler-limits-defaults-errors.md)\n\n [Scheduler Outbound Authentication](scheduler-outbound-authentication.md)\n  \n"
}