{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "About Azure Virtual Machines",
      "pos": [
        27,
        55
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn about the basics of virtual machines in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        74,
        126
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "About Azure Virtual Machines",
      "pos": [
        514,
        542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Virtual Machines is one of several types of on-demand, scalable computing resources that Azure offers.",
      "pos": [
        544,
        652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, you'll choose a virtual machine instead of another option if you need more control over the computing environment than the other choices offer.",
      "pos": [
        653,
        807
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Another approach is to use a virtual machine on your own hardware.",
      "pos": [
        809,
        875
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Compared to that approach, an Azure virtual machine gives you the flexibility of virtualization without having to buy and maintain the physical hardware that runs the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        876,
        1059
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However, you do still need to maintain the virtual machine -- configuring, patching, and maintaining the operating system and any other software that runs on the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        1060,
        1238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This table helps you compare the choices offered by Azure.",
      "pos": [
        1240,
        1298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        1411,
        1421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Try out a virtual machine by creating a simple virtual machine quickly.",
      "pos": [
        1423,
        1494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For instructions, see one of these tutorials:",
      "pos": [
        1495,
        1540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a virtual machine running Linux",
      "pos": [
        1543,
        1581
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a virtual machine running Windows in the Azure preview portal",
      "pos": [
        1621,
        1689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because those tutorials help you create a virtual machine quickly, they show you only one way to do it instead of describing the various tools you can use to create virtual machines.",
      "pos": [
        1730,
        1912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a summary of these tools and links to instructions, see:",
      "pos": [
        1913,
        1973
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Different ways to create a Linux virtual machine",
      "pos": [
        1976,
        2024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Different ways to create a Windows virtual machine",
      "pos": [
        2073,
        2123
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2173,
        2326
      ],
      "content": "If you're just starting to learn about Azure virtual machines, be sure to also check out the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Frequently asked questions<ept id=\"p1\">](virtual-machines-questions.md)</ept>."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"About Azure Virtual Machines\"\n    description=\"Learn about the basics of virtual machines in Azure.\"\n    services=\"virtual-machines\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"KBDAzure\"\n    manager=\"timlt\"\n    editor=\"tysonn\"\n    tags=\"azure-resource-manager,azure-service-management\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"virtual-machines\"\n    ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"07/14/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"kathydav\"/>\n\n#About Azure Virtual Machines\n\nAzure Virtual Machines is one of several types of on-demand, scalable computing resources that Azure offers. Typically, you'll choose a virtual machine instead of another option if you need more control over the computing environment than the other choices offer.\n\nAnother approach is to use a virtual machine on your own hardware. Compared to that approach, an Azure virtual machine gives you the flexibility of virtualization without having to buy and maintain the physical hardware that runs the virtual machine. However, you do still need to maintain the virtual machine -- configuring, patching, and maintaining the operating system and any other software that runs on the virtual machine.\n\nThis table helps you compare the choices offered by Azure.\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [virtual-machines-choose-me-content](../../includes/virtual-machines-choose-me-content.md)]\n\n## Next steps\n\nTry out a virtual machine by creating a simple virtual machine quickly. For instructions, see one of these tutorials:\n\n[Create a virtual machine running Linux](virtual-machines-linux-tutorial.md)\n\n[Create a virtual machine running Windows in the Azure preview portal](virtual-machines-windows-tutorial.md)\n\nBecause those tutorials help you create a virtual machine quickly, they show you only one way to do it instead of describing the various tools you can use to create virtual machines. For a summary of these tools and links to instructions, see:\n\n[Different ways to create a Linux virtual machine](virtual-machines-linux-choices-create-vm.md)\n\n[Different ways to create a Windows virtual machine](virtual-machines-windows-choices-create-vm.md)\n\nIf you're just starting to learn about Azure virtual machines, be sure to also check out the [Frequently asked questions](virtual-machines-questions.md).\n\n\n<!--links-->\n[App Service]: app-service-choose-me.md\n[Virtual Machines]: #tellmevm\n[Cloud Services]: cloud-services-choose-me.md\n"
}