{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Mobile Engagement Troubleshooting Guide - Analytics",
      "pos": [
        27,
        84
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Troubleshooting Analytics, Monitoring, Segmentation, and Dashboard issues in Azure Mobile Engagement",
      "pos": [
        103,
        203
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Troubleshooting guide for Analytics, Monitoring, Segmentation, and Dashboard issues",
      "pos": [
        520,
        603
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following are possible issues you may encounter with how Azure Mobile Engagement gathers information about your applications, devices, and users.",
      "pos": [
        605,
        754
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Missing/Delayed information",
      "pos": [
        759,
        786
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Issue",
      "pos": [
        792,
        797
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information is delayed in appearing in Analytics, Segmentation, or Dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        800,
        877
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information is missing from Monitoring.",
      "pos": [
        880,
        919
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information is missing from Analytics, Segmentation, or Dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        922,
        988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hitting segmentation limits.",
      "pos": [
        991,
        1019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Causes",
      "pos": [
        1025,
        1031
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the Analytics API, Monitor API, and Segments API to see if any data you are missing from the UI is visible through the APIs.",
      "pos": [
        1035,
        1171
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the Azure Mobile Engagement SDK is not correctly integrated into your app then you won't be able to see information in the Analytics, Segmentation, Monitoring, or Dashboards.",
      "pos": [
        1174,
        1351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Segments can't be changed once they are created, segments can only be \"cloned\" (copied) or \"destroyed\" (deleted).",
      "pos": [
        1354,
        1467
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Segments can only contain 10 criteria.",
      "pos": [
        1468,
        1506
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The best way to test missing information from monitoring is to setup a test device, uninstall and/or reinstall the app on the test device.",
      "pos": [
        1509,
        1647
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information is refreshed every 24 hours for Analytics, Segmentation, or Dashboards.",
      "pos": [
        1650,
        1733
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information in new segments may not be displayed until 24 hours after they are created even if the segment is based on previous information.",
      "pos": [
        1736,
        1876
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Filtering your analytics data in the UI will show all examples of this type regardless of the version of your app (e.g. \"Crashes\" filtered by name will show from version 1 and version 2 of your app).",
      "pos": [
        1879,
        2078
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The time period for Analytics is based on the date from the users' device settings, so a user whose phone has the date incorrectly set could show up in the wrong time period.",
      "pos": [
        2081,
        2255
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "No server side data is logged when you use the button to \"test\" pushes, data is only logged for real push campaigns.",
      "pos": [
        2258,
        2374
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can't locate items in UI",
      "pos": [
        2379,
        2403
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Issue",
      "pos": [
        2409,
        2414
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can't create segments based on certain built in or custom app info tag criteria.",
      "pos": [
        2417,
        2497
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can't find certain built in or custom app info tag criteria in Analytics, Monitoring, or Dashboards.",
      "pos": [
        2500,
        2600
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Can't interpret the data in Analytics, Monitoring, Segmentation, or Dashboards.",
      "pos": [
        2603,
        2682
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Causes",
      "pos": [
        2688,
        2694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some built in items and app info tags are only available as push criteria but may not be added to a segment or visible from Analytics, Monitoring, or Dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        2698,
        2858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For built in items and app info tags that can't be added to a segment, you will need to setup list of targeting criteria in each campaign to perform the same function as targeting based on a segment.",
      "pos": [
        2862,
        3061
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the context menus in the Analytics, Monitoring, Segmentation, and Dashboards sections of the Azure Mobile Engagement UI for more help and how to information.",
      "pos": [
        3064,
        3225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Crash troubleshooting",
      "pos": [
        3230,
        3251
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Issue",
      "pos": [
        3257,
        3262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Application Crashes appearing in Analytics, Monitoring, or Dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        3265,
        3334
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Causes",
      "pos": [
        3340,
        3346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To troubleshoot Application Crashes seen in Analytics, Monitoring, or Dashboard make sure to check the release notes for known issues with previous versions of the SDK.",
      "pos": [
        3350,
        3518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To further troubleshoot application crashes perform an event from a test device with your application installed and look up your device ID in the “Monitor – Events” section of the Azure Mobile Engagement UI.",
      "pos": [
        3521,
        3728
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then perform the event that is causing your application to crash and look up additional information in the “Monitor – Crash” section of the Azure Mobile Engagement UI.",
      "pos": [
        3729,
        3896
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        3901,
        3905
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Azure Mobile Engagement Troubleshooting Guide - Analytics\" \n   description=\"Troubleshooting Analytics, Monitoring, Segmentation, and Dashboard issues in Azure Mobile Engagement\" \n   services=\"mobile-engagement\" \n   documentationCenter=\"\" \n   authors=\"piyushjo\" \n   manager=\"dwrede\" \n   editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"mobile-engagement\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"mobile-multiple\"\n   ms.workload=\"mobile\" \n   ms.date=\"06/18/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"piyushjo\"/>\n\n# Troubleshooting guide for Analytics, Monitoring, Segmentation, and Dashboard issues\n\nThe following are possible issues you may encounter with how Azure Mobile Engagement gathers information about your applications, devices, and users.\n\n## Missing/Delayed information\n\n### Issue\n- Information is delayed in appearing in Analytics, Segmentation, or Dashboard.\n- Information is missing from Monitoring.\n- Information is missing from Analytics, Segmentation, or Dashboard.\n- Hitting segmentation limits.\n\n### Causes\n\n- You can use the Analytics API, Monitor API, and Segments API to see if any data you are missing from the UI is visible through the APIs.\n- If the Azure Mobile Engagement SDK is not correctly integrated into your app then you won't be able to see information in the Analytics, Segmentation, Monitoring, or Dashboards.\n- Segments can't be changed once they are created, segments can only be \"cloned\" (copied) or \"destroyed\" (deleted). Segments can only contain 10 criteria.\n- The best way to test missing information from monitoring is to setup a test device, uninstall and/or reinstall the app on the test device.\n- Information is refreshed every 24 hours for Analytics, Segmentation, or Dashboards.\n- Information in new segments may not be displayed until 24 hours after they are created even if the segment is based on previous information.\n- Filtering your analytics data in the UI will show all examples of this type regardless of the version of your app (e.g. \"Crashes\" filtered by name will show from version 1 and version 2 of your app).\n- The time period for Analytics is based on the date from the users' device settings, so a user whose phone has the date incorrectly set could show up in the wrong time period.\n- No server side data is logged when you use the button to \"test\" pushes, data is only logged for real push campaigns.\n\n## Can't locate items in UI\n\n### Issue\n- Can't create segments based on certain built in or custom app info tag criteria.\n- Can't find certain built in or custom app info tag criteria in Analytics, Monitoring, or Dashboards.\n- Can't interpret the data in Analytics, Monitoring, Segmentation, or Dashboards.\n\n### Causes\n\n- Some built in items and app info tags are only available as push criteria but may not be added to a segment or visible from Analytics, Monitoring, or Dashboard. \n- For built in items and app info tags that can't be added to a segment, you will need to setup list of targeting criteria in each campaign to perform the same function as targeting based on a segment.\n- See the context menus in the Analytics, Monitoring, Segmentation, and Dashboards sections of the Azure Mobile Engagement UI for more help and how to information.\n\n## Crash troubleshooting\n\n### Issue\n- Application Crashes appearing in Analytics, Monitoring, or Dashboard.\n\n### Causes\n\n- To troubleshoot Application Crashes seen in Analytics, Monitoring, or Dashboard make sure to check the release notes for known issues with previous versions of the SDK.\n- To further troubleshoot application crashes perform an event from a test device with your application installed and look up your device ID in the “Monitor – Events” section of the Azure Mobile Engagement UI. Then perform the event that is causing your application to crash and look up additional information in the “Monitor – Crash” section of the Azure Mobile Engagement UI. \n\n \ntest\n"
}