{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Create and preconfigure a Windows Virtual Machine with Resource Manager and Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        27,
        119
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to use Azure PowerShell to create and preconfigure Windows and Resource Manager-based virtual machines in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        138,
        260
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create and preconfigure a Windows Virtual Machine with Resource Manager and Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        618,
        710
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These steps show you how to construct a set of commands in the Resource Manager mode of Azure PowerShell that create and pre-configure a Windows-based Azure virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        712,
        885
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use this building block process to quickly create a command set for a new Windows-based virtual machine and expand an existing deployment.",
      "pos": [
        886,
        1032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also use it to create multiple command sets that quickly build out a custom dev/test or IT pro environment.",
      "pos": [
        1033,
        1148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These steps follow a fill-in-the-blanks approach for creating Azure PowerShell command sets.",
      "pos": [
        1150,
        1242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This approach can be useful if you are new to PowerShell or you just want to know what values to specify for successful configuration.",
      "pos": [
        1243,
        1377
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are an advanced PowerShell user, you can take the commands and substitute your own values for the variables (the lines beginning with \"$\")",
      "pos": [
        1378,
        1523
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use Azure PowerShell to create and preconfigure Windows-based Virtual Machines",
      "pos": [
        1660,
        1738
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 1: Install Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        1800,
        1832
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must also have Azure PowerShell version 0.9.0 or later.",
      "pos": [
        1834,
        1893
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have not installed and configured Azure PowerShell, click <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p1\">](../powershell-install-configure.md)</ept> for instructions.",
      "pos": [
        1894,
        2019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can check the version of Azure PowerShell that you have installed with this command at the Azure PowerShell prompt.",
      "pos": [
        2021,
        2140
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example.",
      "pos": [
        2187,
        2206
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not have Version 0.9.0 or later, you must remove Azure PowerShell using the Programs and Features Control Panel and then install the latest version.",
      "pos": [
        2243,
        2401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>How to Install and Configure Azure PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](../powershell-install-configure.md)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        2402,
        2511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 2: Set your subscription",
      "pos": [
        2516,
        2545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "First, run an Azure PowerShell prompt.",
      "pos": [
        2547,
        2585
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, set your Azure subscription by running these commands at the Azure PowerShell prompt.",
      "pos": [
        2587,
        2678
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replace everything within the quotes, including the &lt; and &gt; characters, with the correct names.",
      "pos": [
        2679,
        2774
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can get the correct subscription name from the display of this command.",
      "pos": [
        2875,
        2950
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, switch Azure PowerShell into Resource Manager mode.",
      "pos": [
        3029,
        3086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 3: Create the required resources",
      "pos": [
        3134,
        3171
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource Manager-based virtual machines require a resource group.",
      "pos": [
        3173,
        3238
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If needed, create a new resource group for your new virtual machine with these commands.",
      "pos": [
        3239,
        3327
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replace everything within the quotes, including the &lt; and &gt; characters, with the correct names.",
      "pos": [
        3328,
        3423
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To determine a unique resource group name, use this command to list your existing resource groups.",
      "pos": [
        3570,
        3668
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To list the Azure locations where you can create Resource Manager-based virtual machines, use these commands.",
      "pos": [
        3750,
        3859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource Manager-based virtual machines require a Resource Manager-based storage account.",
      "pos": [
        3968,
        4057
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If needed, create a new storage account for your new virtual machine with these commands.",
      "pos": [
        4058,
        4147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must pick a globally unique name for your storage account that contains only lowercase letters and numbers.",
      "pos": [
        4483,
        4594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use this command to list the existing storage accounts.",
      "pos": [
        4595,
        4658
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To test whether a chosen storage account name is globally unique, you need to run the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Test-AzureName<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> command in the Azure Service Management mode of PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        4715,
        4879
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use these commands.",
      "pos": [
        4880,
        4899
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the Test-AzureName command displays \"False\", your proposed name is unique.",
      "pos": [
        5006,
        5083
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you have determined a unique name, switch Azure PowerShell back to Resource Manager mode with this command.",
      "pos": [
        5085,
        5197
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource Manager-based virtual machines can use a public domain name label, which can contain only letters, numbers, and hyphens.",
      "pos": [
        5242,
        5371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The first and last character in the field must be a letter or number.",
      "pos": [
        5372,
        5441
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To test whether a chosen domain name label is globally unique, use these commands.",
      "pos": [
        5445,
        5527
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If DNSNameAvailability is \"True\", your proposed name is globally unique.",
      "pos": [
        5745,
        5817
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> The Test-AzureDnsAvailability cmdlet was named Get-AzureCheckDnsAvailability in versions of Azure PowerShell earlier than version 0.9.5.",
      "pos": [
        5820,
        5969
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you're using version 0.9.4 or earlier, replace Test-AzureDnsAvailability with Get-AzureCheckDnsAvailability in the command shown above.",
      "pos": [
        5970,
        6108
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource Manager-based virtual machines can be placed in a Resource Manager-based availability set.",
      "pos": [
        6112,
        6211
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If needed, create a new availability set for the new virtual machine with these commands.",
      "pos": [
        6212,
        6301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use this command to list the existing availability sets.",
      "pos": [
        6515,
        6571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource Manager-based virtual machines can be configured with inbound NAT rules to allow incoming traffic from the Internet and be placed in a load balanced set.",
      "pos": [
        6656,
        6818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In both cases, you must specify a load balancer instance and other settings.",
      "pos": [
        6819,
        6895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a load balancer using Azure Resource Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](../load-balancer/load-balancer-arm-powershell.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6896,
        7026
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource Manager-based virtual machines require a Resource Manager-based virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        7028,
        7117
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If needed, create a new Resource Manager-based virtual network with at least one subnet for the new virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        7118,
        7234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is an example for a new virtual network with two subnets named frontendSubnet and backendSubnet.",
      "pos": [
        7235,
        7336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use these commands to list the existing virtual networks.",
      "pos": [
        7747,
        7804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 4: Build your command set",
      "pos": [
        7927,
        7957
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open a fresh instance of the text editor of your choice or the PowerShell Integrated Scripting Environment (ISE) and copy the following lines to start your command set.",
      "pos": [
        7959,
        8127
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify the name of the resource group, Azure location, and storage account for this new virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        8128,
        8233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Replace everything within the quotes, including the &lt; and &gt; characters, with the correct names.",
      "pos": [
        8234,
        8329
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must specify the name of a Resource Manager-based virtual network and the index number of a subnet in the virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        8496,
        8622
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use these commands to list the subnets for a virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        8624,
        8685
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The subnet index is the number of the subnet in the display of this command, numbering them consecutively from left to right and starting at 0.",
      "pos": [
        8851,
        8994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For this example:",
      "pos": [
        8996,
        9013
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The subnet index for the frontendSubnet is 0 and the subnet index for the backendSubnet is 1.",
      "pos": [
        9174,
        9267
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy these lines to your command set and specify an existing virtual network name and the subnet index for the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        9269,
        9396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, you create a network interface card (NIC).",
      "pos": [
        9620,
        9668
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy one of the following options to your command set and fill in the needed information.",
      "pos": [
        9669,
        9758
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Option 1: Specify a NIC name and assign a public IP address",
      "pos": [
        9764,
        9823
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the following lines to your command set and specify the name for the NIC.",
      "pos": [
        9825,
        9903
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Option 2: Specify a NIC name and a DNS domain name label",
      "pos": [
        10242,
        10298
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the following lines to your command set and specify the name for the NIC and the globally unique domain name label.",
      "pos": [
        10300,
        10420
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create virtual machines in the Service Management mode of Azure PowerShell, Azure completes these steps automatically.",
      "pos": [
        10421,
        10548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Option 3: Specify a NIC name and assign a static, private IP address",
      "pos": [
        10948,
        11016
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the following lines to your command set and specify the name for the NIC.",
      "pos": [
        11018,
        11096
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Option 4: Specify a NIC name and a load balancer instance for an inbound NAT rule.",
      "pos": [
        11523,
        11605
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a NIC and add it to a load balancer instance for an inbound NAT rule, you need:",
      "pos": [
        11607,
        11696
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name of a previously-created load balancer instance that has an inbound NAT rule for traffic being forwarded to the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        11700,
        11836
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The index number of the back end address pool of the load balancer instance to assign to the NIC.",
      "pos": [
        11839,
        11936
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The index number of the inbound NAT rule to assign to the NIC.",
      "pos": [
        11939,
        12001
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12003,
        12193
      ],
      "content": "For information on how to create a load balancer instance with inbound NAT rules, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a load balancer using Azure Resource Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](../load-balancer/load-balancer-arm-powershell.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy these lines to your command set and specify the needed names and index numbers.",
      "pos": [
        12195,
        12279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The $nicName string must be unique for the resource group.",
      "pos": [
        12841,
        12899
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A best practice is to incorporate the virtual machine name in the string, such as \"LOB07-NIC\".",
      "pos": [
        12900,
        12994
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Option 5: Specify a NIC name and a load balancer instance for a load-balanced set.",
      "pos": [
        13000,
        13082
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To create a NIC and add it to a load balancer instance for a load-balanced set, you need:",
      "pos": [
        13084,
        13173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name of a previously-created load balancer instance that has a rule for the load-balanced traffic.",
      "pos": [
        13177,
        13279
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The index number of the back end address pool of the load balancer instance to assign to the NIC.",
      "pos": [
        13282,
        13379
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        13381,
        13585
      ],
      "content": "For information on how to create a load balancer instance with rules for load-balanced traffic, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a load balancer using Azure Resource Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](../load-balancer/load-balancer-arm-powershell.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy these lines to your command set and specify the needed names and index numbers.",
      "pos": [
        13587,
        13671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, create a local VM object and optionally add it to an availability set.",
      "pos": [
        14105,
        14181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy one of the two following options to your command set and fill in the name, size, and availability set name.",
      "pos": [
        14182,
        14294
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Option 1: Specify a virtual machine name and size.",
      "pos": [
        14296,
        14346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To determine the possible values of the VM size string for option 1, use these commands.",
      "pos": [
        14462,
        14550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Option 2: Specify a virtual machine name and size and add it to an availability set.",
      "pos": [
        14661,
        14745
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To determine the possible values of the VM size string for option 2, use these commands.",
      "pos": [
        15005,
        15093
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        15262,
        15386
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Currently with Resource Manager, you can only add a virtual machine to an availability set during its creation."
    },
    {
      "content": "To add an additional data disk to the VM, copy these lines to your command set and specify the disk settings.",
      "pos": [
        15388,
        15497
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, you need to determine the publisher, offer, and SKU of the image for your virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        15959,
        16055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is a table of commonly-used, Windows-based images.",
      "pos": [
        16056,
        16111
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Publisher name",
      "pos": [
        16114,
        16128
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Offer name",
      "pos": [
        16131,
        16141
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SKU name",
      "pos": [
        16144,
        16152
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftWindowsServer",
      "pos": [
        16271,
        16293
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "WindowsServer",
      "pos": [
        16296,
        16309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2008-R2-SP1",
      "pos": [
        16312,
        16323
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftWindowsServer",
      "pos": [
        16327,
        16349
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "WindowsServer",
      "pos": [
        16352,
        16365
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2012-Datacenter",
      "pos": [
        16368,
        16383
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftWindowsServer",
      "pos": [
        16387,
        16409
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "WindowsServer",
      "pos": [
        16412,
        16425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2012-R2-Datacenter",
      "pos": [
        16428,
        16446
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftDynamicsNAV",
      "pos": [
        16450,
        16470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DynamicsNAV",
      "pos": [
        16473,
        16484
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2015",
      "pos": [
        16487,
        16491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftSharePoint",
      "pos": [
        16495,
        16514
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftSharePointServer",
      "pos": [
        16517,
        16542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2013",
      "pos": [
        16545,
        16549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftSQLServer",
      "pos": [
        16553,
        16571
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL2014-WS2012R2",
      "pos": [
        16574,
        16590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enterprise-Optimized-for-DW",
      "pos": [
        16593,
        16620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftSQLServer",
      "pos": [
        16624,
        16642
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL2014-WS2012R2",
      "pos": [
        16645,
        16661
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enterprise-Optimized-for-OLTP",
      "pos": [
        16664,
        16693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftWindowsServerEssentials",
      "pos": [
        16697,
        16729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "WindowsServerEssentials",
      "pos": [
        16732,
        16755
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "WindowsServerEssentials",
      "pos": [
        16758,
        16781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MicrosoftWindowsServerHPCPack",
      "pos": [
        16785,
        16814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "WindowsServerHPCPack",
      "pos": [
        16817,
        16837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "2012R2",
      "pos": [
        16840,
        16846
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        16850,
        17024
      ],
      "content": "If the virtual machine image you need is not listed, use the instructions <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>here<ept id=\"p1\">](resource-groups-vm-searching.md#powershell)</ept> to determine the publisher, offer, and SKU names."
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy these commands to your command set and fill in the publisher, offer, and SKU names.",
      "pos": [
        17026,
        17114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Finally, copy these commands to your command set and fill in the name identifier for the operating system disk for the VM.",
      "pos": [
        17620,
        17742
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step 5: Run your command set",
      "pos": [
        18164,
        18192
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Review the Azure PowerShell command set you built in your text editor or the PowerShell ISE consisting of multiple blocks of commands from Step 4.",
      "pos": [
        18194,
        18340
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ensure that you have specified all the needed variables and that they have the correct values.",
      "pos": [
        18341,
        18435
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Also make sure that you have removed all the &lt; and &gt; characters.",
      "pos": [
        18436,
        18500
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have your commands in a text editor, copy the command set to the clipboard and then right-click your open Azure PowerShell prompt.",
      "pos": [
        18502,
        18639
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will issue the command set as a series of PowerShell commands and create your Azure virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        18640,
        18745
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Alternately, run the command set from the Azure PowerShell ISE.",
      "pos": [
        18746,
        18809
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you will be creating this virtual machine again or a similar one, you can save this command set as a PowerShell script file (*.ps1).",
      "pos": [
        18811,
        18946
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example",
      "pos": [
        18951,
        18958
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "I need a PowerShell command set to create an additional virtual machine for a web-based line-of-business workload that:",
      "pos": [
        18960,
        19079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Is placed in the existing LOBServers resource group",
      "pos": [
        19083,
        19134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Uses the Windows Server 2012 R2 Datacenter image",
      "pos": [
        19137,
        19185
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Has the name LOB07 and is in the existing WEB_AS availability set",
      "pos": [
        19188,
        19253
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Has a NIC with a public IP address in the FrontEnd subnet (subnet index 0) of the existing AZDatacenter virtual network",
      "pos": [
        19256,
        19375
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Has an additional data disk of 200 GB",
      "pos": [
        19378,
        19415
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is the corresponding Azure PowerShell command set to create this virtual machine, based on the process described in Step 4.",
      "pos": [
        19417,
        19545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Additional Resources",
      "pos": [
        22059,
        22079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Compute, Network and Storage Providers under Azure Resource Manager",
      "pos": [
        22082,
        22155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Resource Manager Overview",
      "pos": [
        22203,
        22234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Deploy and Manage Azure Virtual Machines using Resource Manager Templates and PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        22269,
        22357
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a Windows virtual machine with a Resource Manager template and PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        22412,
        22492
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to install and configure Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        22573,
        22618
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Create and preconfigure a Windows Virtual Machine with Resource Manager and Azure PowerShell\"\n    description=\"Learn how to use Azure PowerShell to create and preconfigure Windows and Resource Manager-based virtual machines in Azure.\"\n    services=\"virtual-machines\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"KBDAzure\"\n    manager=\"timlt\"\n    editor=\"\"\n    tags=\"azure-resource-manager\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"virtual-machines\"\n    ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.date=\"07/22/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"kathydav\"/>\n\n# Create and preconfigure a Windows Virtual Machine with Resource Manager and Azure PowerShell\n\nThese steps show you how to construct a set of commands in the Resource Manager mode of Azure PowerShell that create and pre-configure a Windows-based Azure virtual machine. You can use this building block process to quickly create a command set for a new Windows-based virtual machine and expand an existing deployment. You can also use it to create multiple command sets that quickly build out a custom dev/test or IT pro environment.\n\nThese steps follow a fill-in-the-blanks approach for creating Azure PowerShell command sets. This approach can be useful if you are new to PowerShell or you just want to know what values to specify for successful configuration. If you are an advanced PowerShell user, you can take the commands and substitute your own values for the variables (the lines beginning with \"$\")\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [resource-manager-pointer-to-service-management](../../includes/resource-manager-pointer-to-service-management.md)]\n\n- [Use Azure PowerShell to create and preconfigure Windows-based Virtual Machines](virtual-machines-ps-create-preconfigure-windows-vms.md)\n\n## Step 1: Install Azure PowerShell\n\nYou must also have Azure PowerShell version 0.9.0 or later. If you have not installed and configured Azure PowerShell, click [here](../powershell-install-configure.md) for instructions.\n\nYou can check the version of Azure PowerShell that you have installed with this command at the Azure PowerShell prompt.\n\n    Get-Module azure | format-table version\n\nHere is an example.\n\n    Version\n    -------\n    0.9.0\n\nIf you do not have Version 0.9.0 or later, you must remove Azure PowerShell using the Programs and Features Control Panel and then install the latest version. See [How to Install and Configure Azure PowerShell](../powershell-install-configure.md) for more information.\n\n## Step 2: Set your subscription\n\nFirst, run an Azure PowerShell prompt.\n\nNext, set your Azure subscription by running these commands at the Azure PowerShell prompt. Replace everything within the quotes, including the < and > characters, with the correct names.\n\n    $subscr=\"<subscription name>\"\n    Select-AzureSubscription -SubscriptionName $subscr –Current\n\nYou can get the correct subscription name from the display of this command.\n\n    Get-AzureSubscription | Sort SubscriptionName | Select SubscriptionName\n\nNext, switch Azure PowerShell into Resource Manager mode.\n\n    Switch-AzureMode AzureResourceManager\n\n## Step 3: Create the required resources\n\nResource Manager-based virtual machines require a resource group. If needed, create a new resource group for your new virtual machine with these commands. Replace everything within the quotes, including the < and > characters, with the correct names.\n\n    $rgName=\"<resource group name>\"\n    $locName=\"<location name, such as West US>\"\n    New-AzureResourceGroup -Name $rgName -Location $locName\n\nTo determine a unique resource group name, use this command to list your existing resource groups.\n\n    Get-AzureResourceGroup | Sort ResourceGroupName | Select ResourceGroupName\n\nTo list the Azure locations where you can create Resource Manager-based virtual machines, use these commands.\n\n    $loc=Get-AzureLocation | where { $_.Name –eq \"Microsoft.Compute/virtualMachines\" }\n    $loc.Locations\n\nResource Manager-based virtual machines require a Resource Manager-based storage account. If needed, create a new storage account for your new virtual machine with these commands.\n\n    $rgName=\"<resource group name>\"\n    $locName=\"<location name, such as West US>\"\n    $saName=\"<storage account name>\"\n    $saType=\"<storage account type, specify one: Standard_LRS, Standard_GRS, Standard_RAGRS, or Premium_LRS>\"\n    New-AzureStorageAccount -Name $saName -ResourceGroupName $rgName –Type $saType -Location $locName\n\nYou must pick a globally unique name for your storage account that contains only lowercase letters and numbers. You can use this command to list the existing storage accounts.\n\n    Get-AzureStorageAccount | Sort Name | Select Name\n\nTo test whether a chosen storage account name is globally unique, you need to run the **Test-AzureName** command in the Azure Service Management mode of PowerShell. Use these commands.\n\n    Switch-AzureMode AzureServiceManagement\n    Test-AzureName -Storage <Proposed storage account name>\n\nIf the Test-AzureName command displays \"False\", your proposed name is unique.  When you have determined a unique name, switch Azure PowerShell back to Resource Manager mode with this command.\n\n    Switch-AzureMode AzureResourceManager\n\nResource Manager-based virtual machines can use a public domain name label, which can contain only letters, numbers, and hyphens. The first and last character in the field must be a letter or number.  \n\nTo test whether a chosen domain name label is globally unique, use these commands.\n\n    $domName=\"<domain name label to test>\"\n    $loc=\"<short name of an Azure location, for example, for West US, the short name is westus>\"\n    Test-AzureDnsAvailability -DomainQualifiedName $domName -Location $loc\n\nIf DNSNameAvailability is \"True\", your proposed name is globally unique.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] The Test-AzureDnsAvailability cmdlet was named Get-AzureCheckDnsAvailability in versions of Azure PowerShell earlier than version 0.9.5. If you're using version 0.9.4 or earlier, replace Test-AzureDnsAvailability with Get-AzureCheckDnsAvailability in the command shown above.  \n\nResource Manager-based virtual machines can be placed in a Resource Manager-based availability set. If needed, create a new availability set for the new virtual machine with these commands.\n\n    $avName=\"<availability set name>\"\n    $rgName=\"<resource group name>\"\n    $locName=\"<location name, such as West US>\"\n    New-AzureAvailabilitySet –Name $avName –ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName\n\nUse this command to list the existing availability sets.\n\n    Get-AzureAvailabilitySet –ResourceGroupName $rgName | Sort Name | Select Name\n\nResource Manager-based virtual machines can be configured with inbound NAT rules to allow incoming traffic from the Internet and be placed in a load balanced set. In both cases, you must specify a load balancer instance and other settings. For more information, see [Create a load balancer using Azure Resource Manager](../load-balancer/load-balancer-arm-powershell.md).\n\nResource Manager-based virtual machines require a Resource Manager-based virtual network. If needed, create a new Resource Manager-based virtual network with at least one subnet for the new virtual machine. Here is an example for a new virtual network with two subnets named frontendSubnet and backendSubnet.\n\n    $rgName=\"LOBServers\"\n    $locName=\"West US\"\n    $frontendSubnet=New-AzureVirtualNetworkSubnetConfig -Name frontendSubnet -AddressPrefix 10.0.1.0/24\n    $backendSubnet=New-AzureVirtualNetworkSubnetConfig -Name backendSubnet -AddressPrefix 10.0.2.0/24\n    New-AzurevirtualNetwork -Name TestNet -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -AddressPrefix 10.0.0.0/16 -Subnet $frontendSubnet,$backendSubnet\n\nUse these commands to list the existing virtual networks.\n\n    $rgName=\"<resource group name>\"\n    Get-AzureVirtualNetwork -ResourceGroupName $rgName | Sort Name | Select Name\n\n## Step 4: Build your command set\n\nOpen a fresh instance of the text editor of your choice or the PowerShell Integrated Scripting Environment (ISE) and copy the following lines to start your command set. Specify the name of the resource group, Azure location, and storage account for this new virtual machine. Replace everything within the quotes, including the < and > characters, with the correct names.\n\n    Switch-AzureMode AzureResourceManager\n    $rgName=\"<resource group name>\"\n    $locName=\"<Azure location, such as West US>\"\n    $saName=\"<storage account name>\"\n\nYou must specify the name of a Resource Manager-based virtual network and the index number of a subnet in the virtual network.  Use these commands to list the subnets for a virtual network.\n\n    $rgName=\"<resource group name>\"\n    $vnetName=\"<virtual network name>\"\n    Get-AzureVirtualNetwork -Name $vnetName -ResourceGroupName $rgName | Select Subnets\n\nThe subnet index is the number of the subnet in the display of this command, numbering them consecutively from left to right and starting at 0.\n\nFor this example:\n\n    PS C:\\> Get-AzureVirtualNetwork -Name TestNet -ResourceGroupName LOBServers | Select Subnets\n\n    Subnets\n    -------\n    {frontendSubnet, backendSubnet}\n\nThe subnet index for the frontendSubnet is 0 and the subnet index for the backendSubnet is 1.\n\nCopy these lines to your command set and specify an existing virtual network name and the subnet index for the virtual machine.\n\n    $vnetName=\"<name of an existing virtual network>\"\n    $subnetIndex=<index of the subnet on which to create the NIC for the virtual machine>\n    $vnet=Get-AzurevirtualNetwork -Name $vnetName -ResourceGroupName $rgName\n\nNext, you create a network interface card (NIC). Copy one of the following options to your command set and fill in the needed information.\n\n### Option 1: Specify a NIC name and assign a public IP address\n\nCopy the following lines to your command set and specify the name for the NIC.\n\n    $nicName=\"<name of the NIC of the VM>\"\n    $pip = New-AzurePublicIpAddress -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -AllocationMethod Dynamic\n    $nic = New-AzureNetworkInterface -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -SubnetId $vnet.Subnets[$subnetIndex].Id -PublicIpAddressId $pip.Id\n\n### Option 2: Specify a NIC name and a DNS domain name label\n\nCopy the following lines to your command set and specify the name for the NIC and the globally unique domain name label. When you create virtual machines in the Service Management mode of Azure PowerShell, Azure completes these steps automatically.\n\n    $nicName=\"<name of the NIC of the VM>\"\n    $domName=\"<domain name label>\"\n    $pip = New-AzurePublicIpAddress -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -DomainNameLabel $domName -Location $locName -AllocationMethod Dynamic\n    $nic = New-AzureNetworkInterface -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -SubnetId $vnet.Subnets[$subnetIndex].Id -PublicIpAddressId $pip.Id\n\n### Option 3: Specify a NIC name and assign a static, private IP address\n\nCopy the following lines to your command set and specify the name for the NIC.\n\n    $nicName=\"<name of the NIC of the VM>\"\n    $staticIP=\"<available static IP address on the subnet>\"\n    $pip = New-AzurePublicIpAddress -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -AllocationMethod Dynamic\n    $nic = New-AzureNetworkInterface -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -SubnetId $vnet.Subnets[$subnetIndex].Id -PublicIpAddressId $pip.Id -PrivateIpAddress $staticIP\n\n### Option 4: Specify a NIC name and a load balancer instance for an inbound NAT rule.\n\nTo create a NIC and add it to a load balancer instance for an inbound NAT rule, you need:\n\n- The name of a previously-created load balancer instance that has an inbound NAT rule for traffic being forwarded to the virtual machine.\n- The index number of the back end address pool of the load balancer instance to assign to the NIC.\n- The index number of the inbound NAT rule to assign to the NIC.\n\nFor information on how to create a load balancer instance with inbound NAT rules, see [Create a load balancer using Azure Resource Manager](../load-balancer/load-balancer-arm-powershell.md).\n\nCopy these lines to your command set and specify the needed names and index numbers.\n\n    $nicName=\"<name of the NIC of the VM>\"\n    $lbName=\"<name of the load balancer instance>\"\n    $bePoolIndex=<index of the back end pool, starting at 0>\n    $natRuleIndex=<index of the inbound NAT rule, starting at 0>\n    $lb=Get-AzureLoadBalancer -Name $lbName -ResourceGroupName $rgName\n    $nic=New-AzureNetworkInterface -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -Subnet $vnet.Subnets[$subnetIndex].Id -LoadBalancerBackendAddressPool $lb.BackendAddressPools[$bePoolIndex] -LoadBalancerInboundNatRule $lb.InboundNatRules[$natRuleIndex]\n\nThe $nicName string must be unique for the resource group. A best practice is to incorporate the virtual machine name in the string, such as \"LOB07-NIC\".\n\n### Option 5: Specify a NIC name and a load balancer instance for a load-balanced set.\n\nTo create a NIC and add it to a load balancer instance for a load-balanced set, you need:\n\n- The name of a previously-created load balancer instance that has a rule for the load-balanced traffic.\n- The index number of the back end address pool of the load balancer instance to assign to the NIC.\n\nFor information on how to create a load balancer instance with rules for load-balanced traffic, see [Create a load balancer using Azure Resource Manager](../load-balancer/load-balancer-arm-powershell.md).\n\nCopy these lines to your command set and specify the needed names and index numbers.\n\n    $nicName=\"<name of the NIC of the VM>\"\n    $lbName=\"<name of the load balancer instance>\"\n    $bePoolIndex=<index of the back end pool, starting at 0>\n    $lb=Get-AzureLoadBalancer -Name $lbName -ResourceGroupName $rgName\n    $nic=New-AzureNetworkInterface -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -Subnet $vnet.Subnets[$subnetIndex].Id -LoadBalancerBackendAddressPool $lb.BackendAddressPools[$bePoolIndex]\n\nNext, create a local VM object and optionally add it to an availability set. Copy one of the two following options to your command set and fill in the name, size, and availability set name.\n\nOption 1: Specify a virtual machine name and size.\n\n    $vmName=\"<VM name>\"\n    $vmSize=\"<VM size string>\"\n    $vm=New-AzureVMConfig -VMName $vmName -VMSize $vmSize\n\nTo determine the possible values of the VM size string for option 1, use these commands.\n\n    $locName=\"<Azure location of your resource group>\"\n    Get-AzureVMSize -Location $locName | Select Name\n\nOption 2: Specify a virtual machine name and size and add it to an availability set.\n\n    $vmName=\"<VM name>\"\n    $vmSize=\"<VM size string>\"\n    $avName=\"<availability set name>\"\n    $avSet=Get-AzureAvailabilitySet –Name $avName –ResourceGroupName $rgName\n    $vm=New-AzureVMConfig -VMName $vmName -VMSize $vmSize -AvailabilitySetId $avset.Id\n\nTo determine the possible values of the VM size string for option 2, use these commands.\n\n    $rgName=\"<resource group name>\"\n    $avName=\"<availability set name>\"\n    Get-AzureVMSize -ResourceGroupName $rgName -AvailabilitySetName $avName | Select Name\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Currently with Resource Manager, you can only add a virtual machine to an availability set during its creation.\n\nTo add an additional data disk to the VM, copy these lines to your command set and specify the disk settings.\n\n    $diskSize=<size of the disk in GB>\n    $diskLabel=\"<the label on the disk>\"\n    $diskName=\"<name identifier for the disk in Azure storage, such as 21050529-DISK02>\"\n    $storageAcc=Get-AzureStorageAccount -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Name $saName\n    $vhdURI=$storageAcc.PrimaryEndpoints.Blob.ToString() + \"vhds/\" + $vmName + $diskName  + \".vhd\"\n    Add-AzureVMDataDisk -VM $vm -Name $diskLabel -DiskSizeInGB $diskSize -VhdUri $vhdURI  -CreateOption empty\n\nNext, you need to determine the publisher, offer, and SKU of the image for your virtual machine. Here is a table of commonly-used, Windows-based images.\n\n|Publisher name | Offer name | SKU name\n|:---------------------------------|:-------------------------------------------|:---------------------------------|\n|MicrosoftWindowsServer | WindowsServer | 2008-R2-SP1 |\n|MicrosoftWindowsServer | WindowsServer | 2012-Datacenter |\n|MicrosoftWindowsServer | WindowsServer | 2012-R2-Datacenter |\n|MicrosoftDynamicsNAV | DynamicsNAV | 2015 |\n|MicrosoftSharePoint | MicrosoftSharePointServer | 2013 |\n|MicrosoftSQLServer | SQL2014-WS2012R2 | Enterprise-Optimized-for-DW |\n|MicrosoftSQLServer | SQL2014-WS2012R2 | Enterprise-Optimized-for-OLTP |\n|MicrosoftWindowsServerEssentials | WindowsServerEssentials | WindowsServerEssentials |\n|MicrosoftWindowsServerHPCPack | WindowsServerHPCPack | 2012R2 |\n\nIf the virtual machine image you need is not listed, use the instructions [here](resource-groups-vm-searching.md#powershell) to determine the publisher, offer, and SKU names.\n\nCopy these commands to your command set and fill in the publisher, offer, and SKU names.\n\n    $pubName=\"<Image publisher name>\"\n    $offerName=\"<Image offer name>\"\n    $skuName=\"<Image SKU name>\"\n    $cred=Get-Credential -Message \"Type the name and password of the local administrator account.\"\n    $vm=Set-AzureVMOperatingSystem -VM $vm -Windows -ComputerName $vmName -Credential $cred -ProvisionVMAgent -EnableAutoUpdate\n    $vm=Set-AzureVMSourceImage -VM $vm -PublisherName $pubName -Offer $offerName -Skus $skuName -Version \"latest\"\n    $vm=Add-AzureVMNetworkInterface -VM $vm -Id $nic.Id\n\nFinally, copy these commands to your command set and fill in the name identifier for the operating system disk for the VM.\n\n    $diskName=\"<name identifier for the disk in Azure storage, such as OSDisk>\"\n    $storageAcc=Get-AzureStorageAccount -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Name $saName\n    $osDiskUri=$storageAcc.PrimaryEndpoints.Blob.ToString() + \"vhds/\" + $diskName  + \".vhd\"\n    $vm=Set-AzureVMOSDisk -VM $vm -Name $diskName -VhdUri $osDiskUri -CreateOption fromImage\n    New-AzureVM -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -VM $vm\n\n## Step 5: Run your command set\n\nReview the Azure PowerShell command set you built in your text editor or the PowerShell ISE consisting of multiple blocks of commands from Step 4. Ensure that you have specified all the needed variables and that they have the correct values. Also make sure that you have removed all the < and > characters.\n\nIf you have your commands in a text editor, copy the command set to the clipboard and then right-click your open Azure PowerShell prompt. This will issue the command set as a series of PowerShell commands and create your Azure virtual machine. Alternately, run the command set from the Azure PowerShell ISE.\n\nIf you will be creating this virtual machine again or a similar one, you can save this command set as a PowerShell script file (*.ps1).\n\n## Example\n\nI need a PowerShell command set to create an additional virtual machine for a web-based line-of-business workload that:\n\n- Is placed in the existing LOBServers resource group\n- Uses the Windows Server 2012 R2 Datacenter image\n- Has the name LOB07 and is in the existing WEB_AS availability set\n- Has a NIC with a public IP address in the FrontEnd subnet (subnet index 0) of the existing AZDatacenter virtual network\n- Has an additional data disk of 200 GB\n\nHere is the corresponding Azure PowerShell command set to create this virtual machine, based on the process described in Step 4.\n\n    # Switch to the Resource Manager mode\n    Switch-AzureMode AzureResourceManager\n\n    # Set values for existing resource group and storage account names\n    $rgName=\"LOBServers\"\n    $locName=\"West US\"\n    $saName=\"contosolobserverssa\"\n\n    # Set the existing virtual network and subnet index\n    $vnetName=\"AZDatacenter\"\n    $subnetIndex=0\n    $vnet=Get-AzurevirtualNetwork -Name $vnetName -ResourceGroupName $rgName\n\n    # Create the NIC\n    $nicName=\"LOB07-NIC\"\n    $domName=\"contoso-vm-lob07\"\n    $pip=New-AzurePublicIpAddress -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -DomainNameLabel $domName -Location $locName -AllocationMethod Dynamic\n    $nic=New-AzureNetworkInterface -Name $nicName -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -SubnetId $vnet.Subnets[$subnetIndex].Id -PublicIpAddressId $pip.Id\n\n    # Specify the name, size, and existing availability set\n    $vmName=\"LOB07\"\n    $vmSize=\"Standard_A3\"\n    $avName=\"WEB_AS\"\n    $avSet=Get-AzureAvailabilitySet –Name $avName –ResourceGroupName $rgName\n    $vm=New-AzureVMConfig -VMName $vmName -VMSize $vmSize -AvailabilitySetId $avset.Id\n\n    # Add a 200 GB additional data disk\n    $diskSize=200\n    $diskLabel=\"APPStorage\"\n    $diskName=\"21050529-DISK02\"\n    $storageAcc=Get-AzureStorageAccount -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Name $saName\n    $vhdURI=$storageAcc.PrimaryEndpoints.Blob.ToString() + \"vhds/\" + $vmName + $diskName  + \".vhd\"\n    Add-AzureVMDataDisk -VM $vm -Name $diskLabel -DiskSizeInGB $diskSize -VhdUri $vhdURI -CreateOption empty\n\n    # Specify the image and local administrator account, and then add the NIC\n    $pubName=\"MicrosoftWindowsServer\"\n    $offerName=\"WindowsServer\"\n    $skuName=\"2012-R2-Datacenter\"\n    $cred=Get-Credential -Message \"Type the name and password of the local administrator account.\"\n    $vm=Set-AzureVMOperatingSystem -VM $vm -Windows -ComputerName $vmName -Credential $cred -ProvisionVMAgent -EnableAutoUpdate\n    $vm=Set-AzureVMSourceImage -VM $vm -PublisherName $pubName -Offer $offerName -Skus $skuName -Version \"latest\"\n    $vm=Add-AzureVMNetworkInterface -VM $vm -Id $nic.Id\n\n    # Specify the OS disk name and create the VM\n    $diskName=\"OSDisk\"\n    $storageAcc=Get-AzureStorageAccount -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Name $saName\n    $osDiskUri=$storageAcc.PrimaryEndpoints.Blob.ToString() + \"vhds/\" + $vmName + $diskName  + \".vhd\"\n    $vm=Set-AzureVMOSDisk -VM $vm -Name $diskName -VhdUri $osDiskUri -CreateOption fromImage\n    New-AzureVM -ResourceGroupName $rgName -Location $locName -VM $vm\n\n## Additional Resources\n\n[Azure Compute, Network and Storage Providers under Azure Resource Manager](virtual-machines-azurerm-versus-azuresm.md)\n\n[Azure Resource Manager Overview](../resource-group-overview.md)\n\n[Deploy and Manage Azure Virtual Machines using Resource Manager Templates and PowerShell](virtual-machines-deploy-rmtemplates-powershell.md)\n\n[Create a Windows virtual machine with a Resource Manager template and PowerShell](virtual-machines-create-windows-powershell-resource-manager-template-simple)\n\n[How to install and configure Azure PowerShell](../install-configure-powershell.md)\n"
}