{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Machine Learning example app: Frequently Bought Together | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        28,
        102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A Machine Learning web service that performs online shopping cart analysis to produce product recommendations of items frequently bought together from historical transactions provided by the user.",
      "pos": [
        122,
        318
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Machine Learning example app: Frequently Bought Together",
      "pos": [
        652,
        708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "IMPORTANT: THIS SERVICE HAS BEEN DEPRECATED",
      "pos": [
        714,
        757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Frequently Bought Together functionality that this service provides has now been integrated into our more broad [Recommendations API] (http://gallery.azureml.net/MachineLearningAPI/3574432384684cac9cc766e57729ea4c).",
      "pos": [
        759,
        978
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We encourage you to use Recommendations instead of this service.",
      "pos": [
        979,
        1043
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        1047,
        1055
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Frequently Bought Together web service<ept id=\"p1\">]( https://datamarket.azure.com/dataset/amla/mba)</ept> in Machine Learning performs online shopping cart analysis to produce product recommendations of items frequently bought together from historical transactions.",
      "pos": [
        1057,
        1309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Frequently Bought Together recommendations help shoppers identify products in a catalog that are most relevant when purchasing a specific item.",
      "pos": [
        1310,
        1453
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Prominently showing these recommendations has proven effective in improving sales for online retailers.",
      "pos": [
        1454,
        1557
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get started",
      "pos": [
        1659,
        1670
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After you have subscribed to the Frequently Bought Together web service, you can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Market Basket Analysis Service example web application<ept id=\"p1\">](https://marketbasket.cloudapp.net/)</ept> to easily upload your data into a model and discover frequently bought product sets.",
      "pos": [
        1673,
        1939
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use use the application or API, you first need your API key, which you can get from the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Data Market Account Page<ept id=\"p1\">](https://datamarket.azure.com/account)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1940,
        2102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Consumption of web service",
      "pos": [
        2106,
        2132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This service contains APIs to create Frequently Bought Together models, upload historical transactions, and retrieve the best-ranked, frequently bought together product set for a given product.",
      "pos": [
        2135,
        2328
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Examples that demonstrate how to use these APIs can be found on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure-MachineLearning-DataScience<ept id=\"p1\">](https://github.com/Azure/Azure-MachineLearning-DataScience/tree/master/Apps/FrequentlyBoughtTogether)</ept> repository on GitHub.",
      "pos": [
        2329,
        2556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        2560,
        2564
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Machine Learning example app: Frequently Bought Together | Microsoft Azure\" \n    description=\"A Machine Learning web service that performs online shopping cart analysis to produce product recommendations of items frequently bought together from historical transactions provided by the user.\" \n    services=\"machine-learning\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"CoromT\" \n    manager=\"paulettm\" \n    editor=\"cgronlun\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"machine-learning\" \n    ms.workload=\"data-services\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"06/12/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"luisca\"/> \n\n# Machine Learning example app: Frequently Bought Together\n\n\n## IMPORTANT: THIS SERVICE HAS BEEN DEPRECATED\n\nThe Frequently Bought Together functionality that this service provides has now been integrated into our more broad [Recommendations API] (http://gallery.azureml.net/MachineLearningAPI/3574432384684cac9cc766e57729ea4c). We encourage you to use Recommendations instead of this service.\n\n##Overview\n\nThe [Frequently Bought Together web service]( https://datamarket.azure.com/dataset/amla/mba) in Machine Learning performs online shopping cart analysis to produce product recommendations of items frequently bought together from historical transactions. Frequently Bought Together recommendations help shoppers identify products in a catalog that are most relevant when purchasing a specific item. Prominently showing these recommendations has proven effective in improving sales for online retailers. \n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [machine-learning-free-trial](../../includes/machine-learning-free-trial.md)] \n  \n##Get started \n\nAfter you have subscribed to the Frequently Bought Together web service, you can use the [Market Basket Analysis Service example web application](https://marketbasket.cloudapp.net/) to easily upload your data into a model and discover frequently bought product sets. To use use the application or API, you first need your API key, which you can get from the [Azure Data Market Account Page](https://datamarket.azure.com/account).\n\n##Consumption of web service \n\nThis service contains APIs to create Frequently Bought Together models, upload historical transactions, and retrieve the best-ranked, frequently bought together product set for a given product. Examples that demonstrate how to use these APIs can be found on the [Azure-MachineLearning-DataScience](https://github.com/Azure/Azure-MachineLearning-DataScience/tree/master/Apps/FrequentlyBoughtTogether) repository on GitHub.\n\n \ntest\n"
}