{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Every blob in Azure storage must reside in a container.",
      "pos": [
        0,
        55
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The container forms part of the blob name.",
      "pos": [
        56,
        98
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, <ph id=\"ph1\">`mycontainer`</ph> is the name of the container in these sample blob URIs:",
      "pos": [
        99,
        181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A container name must be a valid DNS name, conforming to the following naming rules:",
      "pos": [
        333,
        417
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Container names must start with a letter or number, and can contain only letters, numbers, and the dash (-) character.",
      "pos": [
        422,
        540
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Every dash (-) character must be immediately preceded and followed by a letter or number; consecutive dashes are not permitted in container names.",
      "pos": [
        544,
        690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All letters in a container name must be lowercase.",
      "pos": [
        694,
        744
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Container names must be from 3 through 63 characters long.",
      "pos": [
        748,
        806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> Note that the name of a container must always be lowercase.",
      "pos": [
        810,
        887
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you include an upper-case letter in a container name, or otherwise violate the container naming rules, you may receive a 400 error (Bad Request).",
      "pos": [
        888,
        1036
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "Every blob in Azure storage must reside in a container. The container forms part of the blob name. For example, `mycontainer` is the name of the container in these sample blob URIs:\n\n    https://storagesample.blob.core.windows.net/mycontainer/blob1.txt\n    https://storagesample.blob.core.windows.net/mycontainer/photos/myphoto.jpg\n\nA container name must be a valid DNS name, conforming to the following naming rules:\n\n1. Container names must start with a letter or number, and can contain only letters, numbers, and the dash (-) character.\n1. Every dash (-) character must be immediately preceded and followed by a letter or number; consecutive dashes are not permitted in container names.\n1. All letters in a container name must be lowercase.\n1. Container names must be from 3 through 63 characters long.\n\n> [AZURE.IMPORTANT] Note that the name of a container must always be lowercase. If you include an upper-case letter in a container name, or otherwise violate the container naming rules, you may receive a 400 error (Bad Request). "
}