{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Scheduling and Execution with Data Factory",
      "pos": [
        28,
        70
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn scheduling and execution aspects of Azure Data Factory application model.",
      "pos": [
        90,
        169
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduling &amp; Execution with Data Factory",
      "pos": [
        497,
        537
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article explains the scheduling and execution aspects of Azure Data Factory application model.",
      "pos": [
        541,
        640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article builds on <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating Pipelines<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-pipelines.md)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Creating Datasets<ept id=\"p2\">](data-factory-create-datasets.md)</ept> articles and assumes that you understand basics of data factory application model concepts: activity, pipelines, linked services and datasets.",
      "pos": [
        641,
        918
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduling Activities",
      "pos": [
        923,
        944
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>scheduler<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section in the activity JSON, you can specify a recurring schedule for the activity.",
      "pos": [
        946,
        1053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example you can schedule activity runs every hour as follows:",
      "pos": [
        1054,
        1119
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scheduler example",
      "pos": [
        1207,
        1224
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As shown above, specifying an hourly schedule creates activity runs corresponding to a series of tumbling windows.",
      "pos": [
        1296,
        1410
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tumbling windows are series of fixed-sized, non-overlapping and contiguous time intervals.",
      "pos": [
        1411,
        1501
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For the currently executing activity run, the window time interval can be accessed with <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WindowStart<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>WindowEnd<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> system variables in the activity JSON.",
      "pos": [
        1504,
        1664
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use these variables for different purposes in your activity JSON and scripts associated with the activity including selecting data from input, output datasets representing time series data.",
      "pos": [
        1665,
        1862
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1864,
        2159
      ],
      "content": "For more information on different properties available for scheduler including scheduling at a specific time offset, setting the mode to align processing at the beginning of interval for the window or at the end please refer to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating Pipelines<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-pipelines.md)</ept> article."
    },
    {
      "content": "Time series Datasets and Data Slices",
      "pos": [
        2164,
        2200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Time series data is a continuous sequence of data points typically consisting of successive measurements made over a time interval.",
      "pos": [
        2202,
        2333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Common examples of time series data include sensor data, application telemetry data etc.",
      "pos": [
        2334,
        2422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With Azure Data Factory, you can process time series data in batched fashion with activity runs.",
      "pos": [
        2424,
        2520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Typically, there are recurring cadences at which input data arrives and output data needs to be produced.",
      "pos": [
        2521,
        2626
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This cadence is modeled by specifying <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>availability<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section on the dataset as follows:",
      "pos": [
        2627,
        2716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each unit of data consumed and produced by an activity run is called a data <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>slice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2795,
        2881
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The diagram below shows an example of an activity with an input time series dataset and an output time series dataset each with availability set to hourly frequency.",
      "pos": [
        2882,
        3047
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Availability scheduler",
      "pos": [
        3051,
        3073
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The hourly data slices for the input and output dataset are shown in the diagram above.",
      "pos": [
        3150,
        3237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The diagram shows 3 input slices that are ready for processing and the 10-11AM activity run in progress producing the 10-11AM output slice.",
      "pos": [
        3238,
        3377
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3380,
        3530
      ],
      "content": "The time interval associated with the current slice being produced can be accessed in the dataset JSON with variables <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SliceStart<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SliceEnd<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3532,
        3693
      ],
      "content": "For more information on different properties available for availability section please refer to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating Datasets<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-datasets.md)</ept> article."
    },
    {
      "content": "Sample – Copy Activity moving data from Azure SQL to Azure Blob",
      "pos": [
        3698,
        3761
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3763,
        3992
      ],
      "content": "Let’s put some thing together and in action by revisiting the sample for copy activity shown in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating Pipelines<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-pipelines.md)</ept> article that copies data from an Azure SQL table to Azure blob every hour."
    },
    {
      "content": "Input: Azure SQL dataset",
      "pos": [
        3996,
        4020
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4485,
        4597
      ],
      "content": "Note that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>frequency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Hour<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>interval<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> is set to <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>1<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>availability<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept> section."
    },
    {
      "content": "Output: Azure Blob dataset",
      "pos": [
        4602,
        4628
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6357,
        6469
      ],
      "content": "Note that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>frequency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Hour<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>interval<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> is set to <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>1<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>availability<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept> section."
    },
    {
      "content": "Activity: Copy activity",
      "pos": [
        6475,
        6498
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The sample above shows activity schedule and dataset availability sections set to hourly frequency.",
      "pos": [
        7999,
        8098
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The sample shows how you can leverage the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WindowStart<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>WindowEnd<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> variables to select the relevant data for the given activity run and send it to a blob with appropriate dynamic <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>folderPath<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> parameterized to have the folder for every hour.",
      "pos": [
        8099,
        8350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When 3 of the slices between 8 – 11 AM execute, this is what it will look like for a sample Azure table and Blob.",
      "pos": [
        8352,
        8465
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Suppose the data in Azure SQL is as follows:",
      "pos": [
        8467,
        8511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sample input",
      "pos": [
        8515,
        8527
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On deploying the above pipeline the Azure blob will populated as follows:",
      "pos": [
        8599,
        8672
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "File mypath/2015/1/1/8/Data.",
      "pos": [
        8678,
        8706
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ".txt with data",
      "pos": [
        8712,
        8726
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        8886,
        8895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "will be replaced with an actual guid.",
      "pos": [
        8903,
        8940
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example file name: Data.bcde1348-7620-4f93-bb89-0eed3455890b.txt",
      "pos": [
        8941,
        9005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "File mypath/2015/1/1/9/Data.",
      "pos": [
        9010,
        9038
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ".txt with data:",
      "pos": [
        9044,
        9059
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "File mypath/2015/1/1/10/Data.",
      "pos": [
        9220,
        9249
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": ".txt with no data.",
      "pos": [
        9255,
        9273
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Slices, Active Period for Pipeline and Concurrent Slice Execution",
      "pos": [
        9279,
        9349
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9351,
        9547
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating Pipelines<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-pipelines.md)</ept> article introduced the concept of active period for a pipeline specified by setting the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>start<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>end<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> properties of the pipeline."
    },
    {
      "content": "You can set the start date for the pipeline active period in the past and data factory will automatically calculate (back fill) all data slices in the past and will begin processing them.",
      "pos": [
        9550,
        9737
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With back filled data slices, it is possible to configure them to be run in parallel.",
      "pos": [
        9739,
        9824
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can do that by setting the concurrency property in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> section of the activity JSON as shown in the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Creating Pipelines<ept id=\"p2\">](data-factory-create-pipelines.md)</ept> article.",
      "pos": [
        9825,
        9999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rerunning Failed Data Slices and Automatic Data Dependency Tracking",
      "pos": [
        10004,
        10071
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can monitor execution of slices in a rich visual way.",
      "pos": [
        10073,
        10130
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Monitoring and managing pipelines<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-monitor-manage-pipelines.md)</ept> article for details.",
      "pos": [
        10131,
        10233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Consider the following example which shows two activities.",
      "pos": [
        10236,
        10294
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Activity1 produces a time series dataset with slices as output that is consumed as input by Activity2 to produce the final output time series dataset.",
      "pos": [
        10295,
        10445
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Failed slice",
      "pos": [
        10449,
        10461
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The above diagram shows that out of 3 recent slices there was a failure producing the 9-10 AM slice for <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dataset2<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        10535,
        10652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data factory automatically tracks dependency for time series dataset and as a result holds off kicking off the activity run for 9-10 AM downstream slice.",
      "pos": [
        10653,
        10806
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data factory monitoring &amp; management tools allow you to drill into the diagnostic logs for the failed slice easily find the root cause for the issue and fix it.",
      "pos": [
        10809,
        10969
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you have fixed the issue you can also easily kick off the activity run to produce the failed slice.",
      "pos": [
        10970,
        11074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more details on how to kick off reruns, understand state transitions for data slices please refer to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>monitoring &amp; management<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-monitor-manage-pipelines.md)</ept> article.",
      "pos": [
        11075,
        11260
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you kick off the rerun and the 9-10AM slice for dataset2 is ready, data factory kicks off the run for the 9-10 AM dependent slice on final dataset as shown in the diagram below.",
      "pos": [
        11262,
        11444
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rerun failed slice",
      "pos": [
        11448,
        11466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For deeper dive on specifying dependency and tracking the dependencies for complex chain of activities and datasets, refer to sections below.",
      "pos": [
        11539,
        11680
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Modeling datasets with different frequencies",
      "pos": [
        11685,
        11729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the samples shown above, the frequencies for input and output datasets and activity schedule window were same.",
      "pos": [
        11731,
        11844
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some scenarios require the ability to produce output at a frequency different than frequencies of one or more inputs.",
      "pos": [
        11845,
        11962
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data factory supports modeling these scenarios.",
      "pos": [
        11963,
        12010
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sample 1: Producing daily output report for input data that is available every hour",
      "pos": [
        12016,
        12099
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12101,
        12374
      ],
      "content": "Consider a scenario where we have input measurement data from sensors available every hour in Azure Blob and we want to produce a daily aggregate report with statistics like mean, max, min etc... for the day with data factory <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Hive activity<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-hive-activity.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is how you can model this with data factory:",
      "pos": [
        12376,
        12425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Input Azure blob dataset:",
      "pos": [
        12429,
        12454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The hourly input files are dropped in the folder for the given day.",
      "pos": [
        12458,
        12525
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Availability for input is set Hourly (frequency: Hour, interval: 1).",
      "pos": [
        12526,
        12594
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Output Azure blob dataset",
      "pos": [
        13383,
        13408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One output file will be dropped every day in the folder for the day.",
      "pos": [
        13412,
        13480
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Availability of output is set Daily (frequency: Day and interval: 1).",
      "pos": [
        13481,
        13550
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Activity: Hive activity in a pipeline",
      "pos": [
        14314,
        14351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The hive script receives the appropriate datetime information as parameters leveraging the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WindowStart<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> variable as shown below.",
      "pos": [
        14355,
        14486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The hive script uses this variable to load the data from the right folder for the day and run the aggregation to generate the output.",
      "pos": [
        14487,
        14620
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Here is how this looks like from data dependency point of view.",
      "pos": [
        16300,
        16363
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data dapendency",
      "pos": [
        16367,
        16382
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The output slice for every day depends on 24 hourly slices from input dataset.",
      "pos": [
        16452,
        16530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data factory computes these dependencies automatically by figuring out the input data slices that fall in the same time period as the output slice to be produced.",
      "pos": [
        16531,
        16693
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If any of the 24 input slices is not available (due to processing happening in an activity upstream that produces the that slice for example) data factory will wait for the input slice to be ready before kicking off the daily activity run.",
      "pos": [
        16694,
        16933
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sample 2: Specify dependency with expressions and data factory functions",
      "pos": [
        16940,
        17012
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let’s consider another scenario.",
      "pos": [
        17014,
        17046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Suppose you have a Hive activity that processes two input datasets, one of them has new data daily but one of them gets new data every week.",
      "pos": [
        17047,
        17187
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Suppose you wanted to do a join across the two inputs and produce an output daily.",
      "pos": [
        17188,
        17270
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The simple approach so far where data factory automatically figures out the right input slices to process by including input data slices aligned to the output data slice’s time period no longer works.",
      "pos": [
        17273,
        17473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You need a way to specify for every activity run the data factory should use last week’s data slice for the weekly input dataset.",
      "pos": [
        17475,
        17604
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can do that with the help of Azure Data Factory functions as shows below.",
      "pos": [
        17605,
        17682
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Input1: Azure Blob",
      "pos": [
        17686,
        17704
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        17708,
        17752
      ],
      "content": "First input is Azure blob updated <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>daily<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Input2: Azure Blob",
      "pos": [
        18549,
        18567
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        18571,
        18611
      ],
      "content": "Input2 is Azure blob updated <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>weekly<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Output: Azure Blob",
      "pos": [
        19405,
        19423
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One output file will be dropped every day in the folder for the day.",
      "pos": [
        19427,
        19495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Availability of output is set Daily (frequency: Day, interval: 1).",
      "pos": [
        19496,
        19562
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Activity: Hive activity in a pipeline",
      "pos": [
        20334,
        20371
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The hive activity takes the 2 inputs and produces an output slice every day.",
      "pos": [
        20375,
        20451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can specify every day’s output slice to depend on last week’s input slice for weekly input as follows.",
      "pos": [
        20452,
        20558
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Factory System Variables",
      "pos": [
        22158,
        22187
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Variable Name",
      "pos": [
        22189,
        22202
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        22205,
        22216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Object Scope",
      "pos": [
        22219,
        22231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "JSON Scope and Use Cases",
      "pos": [
        22234,
        22258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "WindowStart",
      "pos": [
        22329,
        22340
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Start of time interval for current activity run window",
      "pos": [
        22343,
        22397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "activity",
      "pos": [
        22400,
        22408
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify data selection queries.",
      "pos": [
        22419,
        22450
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See connector articles referenced in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Data Movement Activities<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-data-movement-activities.md)</ept> article.",
      "pos": [
        22451,
        22569
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Pass parameters to Hive script (sample shown above).",
      "pos": [
        22578,
        22630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "WindowEnd",
      "pos": [
        22636,
        22645
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "End of time interval for current activity run window",
      "pos": [
        22648,
        22700
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "activity",
      "pos": [
        22703,
        22711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "same as above",
      "pos": [
        22714,
        22727
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SliceStart",
      "pos": [
        22728,
        22738
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Start of time interval for data  slice being produced",
      "pos": [
        22741,
        22794
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "activity",
      "pos": [
        22797,
        22805
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "dataset",
      "pos": [
        22810,
        22817
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify dynamic folder paths and file names while working with <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Blob<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-azure-blob-connector.md)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>File System datasets<ept id=\"p2\">](data-factory-onprem-file-system-connector.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        22828,
        23015
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify input dependencies with data factory functions in activity inputs collection.",
      "pos": [
        23024,
        23109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SliceEnd",
      "pos": [
        23120,
        23128
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "End of time interval for current data slice being produced",
      "pos": [
        23131,
        23189
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "activity",
      "pos": [
        23192,
        23200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "dataset",
      "pos": [
        23205,
        23212
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "same as above.",
      "pos": [
        23215,
        23229
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Currently data factory requires that the schedule specified in the activity exactly match the schedule specified in availability of the output dataset.",
      "pos": [
        23234,
        23398
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means WindowStart, WindowEnd and SliceStart and SliceEnd always map to the same time period and a single output slice.",
      "pos": [
        23399,
        23522
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Factory Functions Reference",
      "pos": [
        23528,
        23560
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use functions in data factory along with above mentioned system variables for the following purposes:",
      "pos": [
        23562,
        23671
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        23677,
        23830
      ],
      "content": "Specifying data selection queries (see connector articles referenced by the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Data Movement Activities<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-data-movement-activities.md)</ept> article."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        23836,
        23980
      ],
      "content": "The syntax to invoke a data factory function is: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>$$<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;function&gt;</ph><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for data selection  queries and other properties in the activity and datasets."
    },
    {
      "content": "Specifying input dependencies with data factory functions in activity inputs collection (see sample above).",
      "pos": [
        23986,
        24093
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "$$ is not needed for specifying input dependency expressions.",
      "pos": [
        24099,
        24160
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the following sample, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>sqlReaderQuery<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property in a JSON file is assigned to a value returned by the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Text.Format<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> function.",
      "pos": [
        24165,
        24297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This sample also uses a system variable named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WindowStart<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, which represents the start time of the activity run window.",
      "pos": [
        24298,
        24420
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Functions",
      "pos": [
        24592,
        24601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following tables list all the functions in Azure Data Factory:",
      "pos": [
        24603,
        24669
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Category",
      "pos": [
        24671,
        24679
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Function",
      "pos": [
        24682,
        24690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Parameters",
      "pos": [
        24693,
        24703
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        24706,
        24717
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Time",
      "pos": [
        24766,
        24770
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AddHours(X,Y)",
      "pos": [
        24773,
        24786
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        24789,
        24800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Y: int",
      "pos": [
        24804,
        24810
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adds Y hours to the given time X.",
      "pos": [
        24817,
        24850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: 9/5/2013 12:00:00 PM + 2 hours = 9/5/2013 2:00:00 PM",
      "pos": [
        24854,
        24915
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Time",
      "pos": [
        24920,
        24924
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AddMinutes(X,Y)",
      "pos": [
        24927,
        24942
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        24945,
        24956
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Y: int",
      "pos": [
        24960,
        24966
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adds Y minutes to X.",
      "pos": [
        24973,
        24993
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: 9/15/2013 12: 00:00 PM + 15 minutes = 9/15/2013 12: 15:00 PM",
      "pos": [
        24996,
        25065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Time",
      "pos": [
        25070,
        25074
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StartOfHour(X)",
      "pos": [
        25077,
        25091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: Datetime",
      "pos": [
        25094,
        25105
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the starting time for the hour represented by the hour component of X.",
      "pos": [
        25108,
        25183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: StartOfHour of 9/15/2013 05: 10:23 PM is 9/15/2013 05: 00:00 PM",
      "pos": [
        25187,
        25259
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        25264,
        25268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AddDays(X,Y)",
      "pos": [
        25271,
        25283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        25286,
        25297
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Y: int",
      "pos": [
        25300,
        25306
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adds Y days to X.",
      "pos": [
        25313,
        25330
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 2 days = 9/17/2013 12:00:00 PM",
      "pos": [
        25333,
        25396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        25401,
        25405
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AddMonths(X,Y)",
      "pos": [
        25408,
        25422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        25425,
        25436
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Y: int",
      "pos": [
        25439,
        25445
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adds Y months to X.",
      "pos": [
        25452,
        25471
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 1 month = 10/15/2013 12:00:00 PM",
      "pos": [
        25474,
        25539
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        25545,
        25549
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AddQuarters(X,Y)",
      "pos": [
        25552,
        25568
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        25571,
        25582
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Y: int",
      "pos": [
        25586,
        25592
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adds Y * 3 months to X.",
      "pos": [
        25599,
        25622
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 1 quarter = 12/15/2013 12:00:00 PM",
      "pos": [
        25625,
        25692
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        25697,
        25701
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AddWeeks(X,Y)",
      "pos": [
        25704,
        25717
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        25720,
        25731
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Y: int",
      "pos": [
        25734,
        25740
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adds Y * 7 days to X",
      "pos": [
        25747,
        25767
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 1 week = 9/22/2013 12:00:00 PM",
      "pos": [
        25770,
        25833
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        25838,
        25842
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "AddYears(X,Y)",
      "pos": [
        25845,
        25858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        25861,
        25872
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Y: int",
      "pos": [
        25875,
        25881
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Adds Y years to X.",
      "pos": [
        25888,
        25906
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 1 year = 9/15/2014 12:00:00 PM",
      "pos": [
        25909,
        25972
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        25977,
        25981
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Day(X)",
      "pos": [
        25984,
        25990
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        25993,
        26004
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the day component of X.",
      "pos": [
        26007,
        26035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: Day of 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM is 9.",
      "pos": [
        26038,
        26081
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        26087,
        26091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DayOfWeek(X)",
      "pos": [
        26094,
        26106
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        26109,
        26120
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the day of week component of X.",
      "pos": [
        26123,
        26159
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: DayOfWeek of 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM is Sunday.",
      "pos": [
        26162,
        26216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        26221,
        26225
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DayOfYear(X)",
      "pos": [
        26228,
        26240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        26243,
        26254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the day in the year represented by the year component of X.",
      "pos": [
        26257,
        26321
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Examples:",
      "pos": [
        26324,
        26333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "12/1/2015: day 335 of 2015",
      "pos": [
        26338,
        26364
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "12/31/2015: day 365 of 2015",
      "pos": [
        26369,
        26396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "12/31/2016: day 366 of 2016 (Leap Year)",
      "pos": [
        26401,
        26440
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        26445,
        26449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DaysInMonth(X)",
      "pos": [
        26452,
        26466
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        26469,
        26480
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the days in the month represented by the month component of parameter X.",
      "pos": [
        26483,
        26560
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: DaysInMonth of 9/15/2013 are 30 since there are 30 days in the September month.",
      "pos": [
        26563,
        26651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        26656,
        26660
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EndOfDay(X)",
      "pos": [
        26663,
        26674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        26677,
        26688
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the date-time that represents the end of the day (day component) of X.",
      "pos": [
        26691,
        26766
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: EndOfDay of 9/15/2013 05:10:23 PM is 9/15/2013 11:59:59 PM.",
      "pos": [
        26769,
        26837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        26842,
        26846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "EndOfMonth(X)",
      "pos": [
        26849,
        26862
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        26865,
        26876
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the end of the month represented by month component of parameter X.",
      "pos": [
        26879,
        26951
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: EndOfMonth of 9/15/2013 05:10:23 PM is 9/30/2013 11:59:59 PM (date time that represents the end of September month)",
      "pos": [
        26955,
        27079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Date",
      "pos": [
        27084,
        27088
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "StartOfDay(X)",
      "pos": [
        27091,
        27104
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        27107,
        27118
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the start of the day represented by the day component of parameter X.",
      "pos": [
        27121,
        27195
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example: StartOfDay of 9/15/2013 05:10:23 PM is 9/15/2013 12:00:00 AM.",
      "pos": [
        27198,
        27268
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DateTime",
      "pos": [
        27273,
        27281
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "From(X)",
      "pos": [
        27284,
        27291
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: String",
      "pos": [
        27294,
        27303
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Parse string X to a date time.",
      "pos": [
        27306,
        27336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "DateTime",
      "pos": [
        27337,
        27345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Ticks(X)",
      "pos": [
        27348,
        27356
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: DateTime",
      "pos": [
        27359,
        27370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Gets the ticks property of the parameter X. One tick equals 100 nanoseconds.",
      "pos": [
        27373,
        27449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The value of this property represents the number of ticks that have elapsed since 12:00:00 midnight, January 1, 0001.",
      "pos": [
        27450,
        27567
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Text",
      "pos": [
        27569,
        27573
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Format(X)",
      "pos": [
        27576,
        27585
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "X: String variable",
      "pos": [
        27588,
        27606
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Formats the text.",
      "pos": [
        27609,
        27626
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Text.Format example",
      "pos": [
        27633,
        27652
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> When using a function within another function, you do not need to use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>$$<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> prefix for the inner function.",
      "pos": [
        27906,
        28026
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example: $$Text.Format('PartitionKey eq \\\\'my_pkey_filter_value\\\\' and RowKey ge \\\\'{0:yyyy-MM-dd HH:mm:ss}\\\\'', Time.AddHours(SliceStart, -6)).",
      "pos": [
        28027,
        28175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example, notice that <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>$$<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> prefix is not used for the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Time.AddHours<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> function.",
      "pos": [
        28176,
        28266
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Dependency Deep Dive",
      "pos": [
        28275,
        28300
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        28302,
        28533
      ],
      "content": "In order to generate a dataset slice by an activity run, data factory uses the following <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>dependency model<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to determine the relationships between the dataset(s) consumed by an activity and the dataset(s) produced by an activity."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        28535,
        28653
      ],
      "content": "The time range of the input dataset(s) required to generate the output dataset slice called the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>dependency period<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "An activity run generates a dataset slice only after the data slices in input dataset(s) within the dependency period are available.",
      "pos": [
        28655,
        28787
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It means that all the input slices comprising the dependency period must be in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Ready<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> status  for the output dataset slice to be produced by an activity run.",
      "pos": [
        28788,
        28948
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To generate the dataset slice [start, end], a function is needed to map the dataset slice to its dependency period.",
      "pos": [
        28951,
        29066
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This function is essentially a formula that converts the start and end of the dataset slice to the start and end of the dependency period.",
      "pos": [
        29067,
        29205
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "More formally,",
      "pos": [
        29206,
        29220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "where f and g are mapping functions that calculate the start and end of the dependency period for each activity input.",
      "pos": [
        29313,
        29431
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As seen in samples shown above in most cases the dependency period is same as the period for the data slice to be produced.",
      "pos": [
        29433,
        29556
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In these cases data factory automatically computes the input slices that fall in the dependency period.",
      "pos": [
        29557,
        29660
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example: In the aggregation sample above where output is produced daily and input data is available every hour, the data slice period is 24 hours.",
      "pos": [
        29664,
        29814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data factory finds the relevant hourly input slices for this time period and makes the output slice dependent on the input slice.",
      "pos": [
        29815,
        29944
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also provide your own mapping for the dependency period as shown in the sample above where one of the inputs was weekly and the output slice is produced daily.",
      "pos": [
        29946,
        30113
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Dependency and Validation",
      "pos": [
        30121,
        30151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A dataset can optionally have a validation policy defined that specifies how the data generated by a slice execution can be validated before it is ready for consumption.",
      "pos": [
        30153,
        30322
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating datasets<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-datasets.md)</ept> article for details.",
      "pos": [
        30323,
        30400
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In such cases, once the slice has finished execution, the output slice status is changed to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Waiting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> with a substatus of <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Validation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        30403,
        30542
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once the slices are validated, the slice status changes to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Ready<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        30543,
        30612
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a data slice has been produced but did not pass the validation, activity runs for downstream slices depending on the slice that failed validation will not be processed.",
      "pos": [
        30617,
        30788
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        30790,
        30940
      ],
      "content": "The various states of data slices in data factory are covered in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Monitor and manage pipelines<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-monitor-manage-pipelines.md)</ept> article."
    },
    {
      "content": "External Data",
      "pos": [
        30945,
        30958
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A dataset can be marked as external (as shown in the JSON below), implying it was not generated with Azure Data Factory.",
      "pos": [
        30960,
        31080
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In such a case, the Dataset policy can have an additional set of parameters describing validation and retry policy for the dataset.",
      "pos": [
        31081,
        31212
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creating Pipelines<ept id=\"p1\">](data-factory-create-pipelines.md)</ept> for a description of all the properties.",
      "pos": [
        31214,
        31320
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Similar to datasets that are produced by data factory the data slices for external data need to be ready   before dependent slices can be processed.",
      "pos": [
        31323,
        31471
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        32226,
        32230
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Scheduling and Execution with Data Factory\" \n    description=\"Learn scheduling and execution aspects of Azure Data Factory application model.\" \n    services=\"data-factory\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"spelluru\" \n    manager=\"jhubbard\" \n    editor=\"monicar\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"data-factory\" \n    ms.workload=\"data-services\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"07/28/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"spelluru\"/>\n\n# Scheduling & Execution with Data Factory\n  \nThis article explains the scheduling and execution aspects of Azure Data Factory application model. This article builds on [Creating Pipelines](data-factory-create-pipelines.md) and [Creating Datasets](data-factory-create-datasets.md) articles and assumes that you understand basics of data factory application model concepts: activity, pipelines, linked services and datasets.\n\n## Scheduling Activities\n\nWith the **scheduler** section in the activity JSON, you can specify a recurring schedule for the activity. For example you can schedule activity runs every hour as follows:\n\n    \"scheduler\": {\n        \"frequency\": \"Hour\",\n        \"interval\": 1\n    },  \n    \n![Scheduler example](./media/data-factory-scheduling-and-execution/scheduler-example.png)\n\nAs shown above, specifying an hourly schedule creates activity runs corresponding to a series of tumbling windows. Tumbling windows are series of fixed-sized, non-overlapping and contiguous time intervals.\n \nFor the currently executing activity run, the window time interval can be accessed with **WindowStart** and **WindowEnd** system variables in the activity JSON. You can use these variables for different purposes in your activity JSON and scripts associated with the activity including selecting data from input, output datasets representing time series data.\n\nFor more information on different properties available for scheduler including scheduling at a specific time offset, setting the mode to align processing at the beginning of interval for the window or at the end please refer to the [Creating Pipelines](data-factory-create-pipelines.md) article.\n\n## Time series Datasets and Data Slices\n\nTime series data is a continuous sequence of data points typically consisting of successive measurements made over a time interval. Common examples of time series data include sensor data, application telemetry data etc.\n\nWith Azure Data Factory, you can process time series data in batched fashion with activity runs. Typically, there are recurring cadences at which input data arrives and output data needs to be produced. This cadence is modeled by specifying **availability** section on the dataset as follows:\n\n    \"availability\": {\n      \"frequency\": \"Hour\",\n      \"interval\": 1\n    },\n\nEach unit of data consumed and produced by an activity run is called a data **slice**. The diagram below shows an example of an activity with an input time series dataset and an output time series dataset each with availability set to hourly frequency.\n\n![Availability scheduler](./media/data-factory-scheduling-and-execution/availability-scheduler.png)\n\nThe hourly data slices for the input and output dataset are shown in the diagram above. The diagram shows 3 input slices that are ready for processing and the 10-11AM activity run in progress producing the 10-11AM output slice. \n\nThe time interval associated with the current slice being produced can be accessed in the dataset JSON with variables **SliceStart** and **SliceEnd**.\n\nFor more information on different properties available for availability section please refer to the [Creating Datasets](data-factory-create-datasets.md) article.\n\n## Sample – Copy Activity moving data from Azure SQL to Azure Blob\n\nLet’s put some thing together and in action by revisiting the sample for copy activity shown in the [Creating Pipelines](data-factory-create-pipelines.md) article that copies data from an Azure SQL table to Azure blob every hour.\n\n**Input: Azure SQL dataset**\n\n    {\n        \"name\": \"AzureSqlInput\",\n        \"properties\": {\n            \"published\": false,\n            \"type\": \"AzureSqlTable\",\n            \"linkedServiceName\": \"AzureSqlLinkedService\",\n            \"typeProperties\": {\n                \"tableName\": \"MyTable\"\n            },\n            \"availability\": {\n                \"frequency\": \"Hour\",\n                \"interval\": 1\n            },\n            \"external\": true,\n            \"policy\": {}\n        }\n    }\n\n\nNote that the **frequency** is set to **Hour** and **interval** is set to **1** in the **availability** section. \n\n**Output: Azure Blob dataset**\n    \n    {\n        \"name\": \"AzureBlobOutput\",\n        \"properties\": {\n            \"published\": false,\n            \"type\": \"AzureBlob\",\n            \"linkedServiceName\": \"StorageLinkedService\",\n            \"typeProperties\": {\n                \"folderPath\": \"mypath/{Year}/{Month}/{Day}/{Hour}\",\n                \"format\": {\n                    \"type\": \"TextFormat\"\n                },\n                \"partitionedBy\": [\n                    {\n                        \"name\": \"Year\",\n                        \"value\": {\n                            \"type\": \"DateTime\",\n                            \"date\": \"SliceStart\",\n                            \"format\": \"yyyy\"\n                        }\n                    },\n                    {\n                        \"name\": \"Month\",\n                        \"value\": {\n                            \"type\": \"DateTime\",\n                            \"date\": \"SliceStart\",\n                            \"format\": \"%M\"\n                        }\n                    },\n                    {\n                        \"name\": \"Day\",\n                        \"value\": {\n                            \"type\": \"DateTime\",\n                            \"date\": \"SliceStart\",\n                            \"format\": \"%d\"\n                        }\n                    },\n                    {\n                        \"name\": \"Hour\",\n                        \"value\": {\n                            \"type\": \"DateTime\",\n                            \"date\": \"SliceStart\",\n                            \"format\": \"%H\"\n                        }\n                    }\n                ]\n            },\n            \"availability\": {\n                \"frequency\": \"Hour\",\n                \"interval\": 1\n            }\n        }\n    }\n\n\nNote that the **frequency** is set to **Hour** and **interval** is set to **1** in the **availability** section.\n\n\n\n**Activity: Copy activity**\n\n    {\n        \"name\": \"SamplePipeline\",\n        \"properties\": {\n            \"description\": \"copy activity\",\n            \"activities\": [\n                {\n                    \"type\": \"Copy\",\n                    \"name\": \"AzureSQLtoBlob\",\n                    \"description\": \"copy activity\", \n                    \"typeProperties\": {\n                        \"source\": {\n                            \"type\": \"SqlSource\",\n                            \"sqlReaderQuery\": \"$$Text.Format('select * from MyTable where timestampcolumn >= \\\\'{0:yyyy-MM-dd HH:mm}\\\\' AND timestampcolumn < \\\\'{1:yyyy-MM-dd HH:mm}\\\\'', WindowStart, WindowEnd)\"\n                        },\n                        \"sink\": {\n                            \"type\": \"BlobSink\",\n                            \"writeBatchSize\": 100000,\n                            \"writeBatchTimeout\": \"00:05:00\"\n                        }\n                    },\n                    \"inputs\": [\n                        {\n                            \"name\": \"AzureSQLInput\"\n                        }\n                    ],\n                    \"outputs\": [\n                        {\n                            \"name\": \"AzureBlobOutput\"\n                        }\n                    ],\n                    \"scheduler\": {\n                        \"frequency\": \"Hour\",\n                        \"interval\": 1\n                    }\n                }\n            ],\n            \"start\": \"2015-01-01T08:00:00Z\",\n            \"end\": \"2015-01-01T11:00:00Z\"\n        }\n    }\n\n\nThe sample above shows activity schedule and dataset availability sections set to hourly frequency. The sample shows how you can leverage the **WindowStart** and **WindowEnd** variables to select the relevant data for the given activity run and send it to a blob with appropriate dynamic **folderPath** parameterized to have the folder for every hour.\n\nWhen 3 of the slices between 8 – 11 AM execute, this is what it will look like for a sample Azure table and Blob.\n\nSuppose the data in Azure SQL is as follows:\n\n![Sample input](./media/data-factory-scheduling-and-execution/sample-input-data.png)\n\nOn deploying the above pipeline the Azure blob will populated as follows:\n\n1.  File mypath/2015/1/1/8/Data.<Guid>.txt with data \n\n        10002345,334,2,2015-01-01 08:24:00.3130000\n        10002345,347,15,2015-01-01 08:24:00.6570000\n        10991568,2,7,2015-01-01 08:56:34.5300000\n\n    **Note:** <Guid> will be replaced with an actual guid. Example file name: Data.bcde1348-7620-4f93-bb89-0eed3455890b.txt\n2.  File mypath/2015/1/1/9/Data.<Guid>.txt with data:\n\n        10002345,334,1,2015-01-01 09:13:00.3900000\n        24379245,569,23,2015-01-01 09:25:00.3130000\n        16777799,21,115,2015-01-01 09:47:34.3130000\n3.  File mypath/2015/1/1/10/Data.<Guid>.txt with no data.\n\n\n## Data Slices, Active Period for Pipeline and Concurrent Slice Execution\n\nThe [Creating Pipelines](data-factory-create-pipelines.md) article introduced the concept of active period for a pipeline specified by setting the **start** and **end** properties of the pipeline.\n \nYou can set the start date for the pipeline active period in the past and data factory will automatically calculate (back fill) all data slices in the past and will begin processing them.\n\nWith back filled data slices, it is possible to configure them to be run in parallel. You can do that by setting the concurrency property in **policy** section of the activity JSON as shown in the [Creating Pipelines](data-factory-create-pipelines.md) article.\n\n## Rerunning Failed Data Slices and Automatic Data Dependency Tracking\n\nYou can monitor execution of slices in a rich visual way. See [Monitoring and managing pipelines](data-factory-monitor-manage-pipelines.md) article for details. \n\nConsider the following example which shows two activities. Activity1 produces a time series dataset with slices as output that is consumed as input by Activity2 to produce the final output time series dataset.\n\n![Failed slice](./media/data-factory-scheduling-and-execution/failed-slice.png)\n\n<br/>\n\nThe above diagram shows that out of 3 recent slices there was a failure producing the 9-10 AM slice for **Dataset2**. Data factory automatically tracks dependency for time series dataset and as a result holds off kicking off the activity run for 9-10 AM downstream slice.\n\n\nData factory monitoring & management tools allow you to drill into the diagnostic logs for the failed slice easily find the root cause for the issue and fix it. Once you have fixed the issue you can also easily kick off the activity run to produce the failed slice. For more details on how to kick off reruns, understand state transitions for data slices please refer to the [monitoring & management](data-factory-monitor-manage-pipelines.md) article.\n\nOnce you kick off the rerun and the 9-10AM slice for dataset2 is ready, data factory kicks off the run for the 9-10 AM dependent slice on final dataset as shown in the diagram below.\n\n![Rerun failed slice](./media/data-factory-scheduling-and-execution/rerun-failed-slice.png)\n\nFor deeper dive on specifying dependency and tracking the dependencies for complex chain of activities and datasets, refer to sections below.\n\n## Modeling datasets with different frequencies\n\nIn the samples shown above, the frequencies for input and output datasets and activity schedule window were same. Some scenarios require the ability to produce output at a frequency different than frequencies of one or more inputs. Data factory supports modeling these scenarios.\n\n### Sample 1: Producing daily output report for input data that is available every hour\n\nConsider a scenario where we have input measurement data from sensors available every hour in Azure Blob and we want to produce a daily aggregate report with statistics like mean, max, min etc... for the day with data factory [Hive activity](data-factory-hive-activity.md).\n\nHere is how you can model this with data factory:\n\n**Input Azure blob dataset:**\n\nThe hourly input files are dropped in the folder for the given day. Availability for input is set Hourly (frequency: Hour, interval: 1).\n\n    {\n      \"name\": \"AzureBlobInput\",\n      \"properties\": {\n        \"type\": \"AzureBlob\",\n        \"linkedServiceName\": \"StorageLinkedService\",\n        \"typeProperties\": {\n          \"folderPath\": \"mycontainer/myfolder/{Year}/{Month}/{Day}/\",\n          \"partitionedBy\": [\n            { \"name\": \"Year\", \"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"yyyy\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Month\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%M\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Day\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%d\"}}\n          ],\n          \"format\": {\n            \"type\": \"TextFormat\"\n          }\n        },\n        \"external\": true,\n        \"availability\": {\n          \"frequency\": \"Hour\",\n          \"interval\": 1\n        }\n      }\n    }\n\n**Output Azure blob dataset**\n\nOne output file will be dropped every day in the folder for the day. Availability of output is set Daily (frequency: Day and interval: 1).\n\n\n    {\n      \"name\": \"AzureBlobOutput\",\n      \"properties\": {\n        \"type\": \"AzureBlob\",\n        \"linkedServiceName\": \"StorageLinkedService\",\n        \"typeProperties\": {\n          \"folderPath\": \"mycontainer/myfolder/{Year}/{Month}/{Day}/\",\n          \"partitionedBy\": [\n            { \"name\": \"Year\", \"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"yyyy\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Month\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%M\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Day\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%d\"}}\n          ],\n          \"format\": {\n            \"type\": \"TextFormat\"\n          }\n        },\n        \"availability\": {\n          \"frequency\": \"Day\",\n          \"interval\": 1\n        }\n      }\n    }\n\n**Activity: Hive activity in a pipeline**\n\nThe hive script receives the appropriate datetime information as parameters leveraging the **WindowStart** variable as shown below. The hive script uses this variable to load the data from the right folder for the day and run the aggregation to generate the output.\n\n        {  \n            \"name\":\"SamplePipeline\",\n            \"properties\":{  \n            \"start\":\"2015-01-01T08:00:00\",\n            \"end\":\"2015-01-01T11:00:00\",\n            \"description\":\"hive activity\",\n            \"activities\": [\n                {\n                    \"name\": \"SampleHiveActivity\",\n                    \"inputs\": [\n                        {\n                            \"name\": \"AzureBlobInput\"\n                        }\n                    ],\n                    \"outputs\": [\n                        {\n                            \"name\": \"AzureBlobOutput\"\n                        }\n                    ],\n                    \"linkedServiceName\": \"HDInsightLinkedService\",\n                    \"type\": \"HDInsightHive\",\n                    \"typeProperties\": {\n                        \"scriptPath\": \"adftutorial\\\\hivequery.hql\",\n                        \"scriptLinkedService\": \"StorageLinkedService\",\n                        \"defines\": {\n                            \"Year\": \"$$Text.Format('{0:yyyy}',WindowsStart)\",\n                            \"Month\": \"$$Text.Format('{0:%M}',WindowStart)\",\n                            \"Day\": \"$$Text.Format('{0:%d}',WindowStart)\"\n                        }\n                    },\n                    \"scheduler\": {\n                        \"frequency\": \"Day\",\n                        \"interval\": 1\n                    },          \n                    \"policy\": {\n                        \"concurrency\": 1,\n                        \"executionPriorityOrder\": \"OldestFirst\",\n                        \"retry\": 2,\n                        \"timeout\": \"01:00:00\"\n                    }\n                 }\n             ]\n           }\n        }\n\nHere is how this looks like from data dependency point of view.\n\n![Data dapendency](./media/data-factory-scheduling-and-execution/data-dependency.png)\n\nThe output slice for every day depends on 24 hourly slices from input dataset. Data factory computes these dependencies automatically by figuring out the input data slices that fall in the same time period as the output slice to be produced. If any of the 24 input slices is not available (due to processing happening in an activity upstream that produces the that slice for example) data factory will wait for the input slice to be ready before kicking off the daily activity run.\n\n\n### Sample 2: Specify dependency with expressions and data factory functions\n\nLet’s consider another scenario. Suppose you have a Hive activity that processes two input datasets, one of them has new data daily but one of them gets new data every week. Suppose you wanted to do a join across the two inputs and produce an output daily.\n \nThe simple approach so far where data factory automatically figures out the right input slices to process by including input data slices aligned to the output data slice’s time period no longer works.\n\nYou need a way to specify for every activity run the data factory should use last week’s data slice for the weekly input dataset. You can do that with the help of Azure Data Factory functions as shows below.\n\n**Input1: Azure Blob**\n\nFirst input is Azure blob updated **daily**.\n    \n    {\n      \"name\": \"AzureBlobInputDaily\",\n      \"properties\": {\n        \"type\": \"AzureBlob\",\n        \"linkedServiceName\": \"StorageLinkedService\",\n        \"typeProperties\": {\n          \"folderPath\": \"mycontainer/myfolder/{Year}/{Month}/{Day}/\",\n          \"partitionedBy\": [\n            { \"name\": \"Year\", \"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"yyyy\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Month\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%M\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Day\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%d\"}}\n          ],\n          \"format\": {\n            \"type\": \"TextFormat\"\n          }\n        },\n        \"external\": true,\n        \"availability\": {\n          \"frequency\": \"Day\",\n          \"interval\": 1\n        }\n      }\n    }\n\n**Input2: Azure Blob**\n\nInput2 is Azure blob updated **weekly**.\n\n    {\n      \"name\": \"AzureBlobInputWeekly\",\n      \"properties\": {\n        \"type\": \"AzureBlob\",\n        \"linkedServiceName\": \"StorageLinkedService\",\n        \"typeProperties\": {\n          \"folderPath\": \"mycontainer/myfolder/{Year}/{Month}/{Day}/\",\n          \"partitionedBy\": [\n            { \"name\": \"Year\", \"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"yyyy\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Month\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%M\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Day\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%d\"}}\n          ],\n          \"format\": {\n            \"type\": \"TextFormat\"\n          }\n        },\n        \"external\": true,\n        \"availability\": {\n          \"frequency\": \"Day\",\n          \"interval\": 7\n        }\n      }\n    }\n\n**Output: Azure Blob**\n\nOne output file will be dropped every day in the folder for the day. Availability of output is set Daily (frequency: Day, interval: 1).\n    \n    {\n      \"name\": \"AzureBlobOutputDaily\",\n      \"properties\": {\n        \"type\": \"AzureBlob\",\n        \"linkedServiceName\": \"StorageLinkedService\",\n        \"typeProperties\": {\n          \"folderPath\": \"mycontainer/myfolder/{Year}/{Month}/{Day}/\",\n          \"partitionedBy\": [\n            { \"name\": \"Year\", \"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"yyyy\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Month\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%M\"}},\n            { \"name\": \"Day\",\"value\": {\"type\": \"DateTime\",\"date\": \"SliceStart\",\"format\": \"%d\"}}\n          ],\n          \"format\": {\n            \"type\": \"TextFormat\"\n          }\n        },\n        \"availability\": {\n          \"frequency\": \"Day\",\n          \"interval\": 1\n        }\n      }\n    }\n\n**Activity: Hive activity in a pipeline**\n\nThe hive activity takes the 2 inputs and produces an output slice every day. You can specify every day’s output slice to depend on last week’s input slice for weekly input as follows.\n    \n    {  \n        \"name\":\"SamplePipeline\",\n        \"properties\":{  \n        \"start\":\"2015-01-01T08:00:00\",\n        \"end\":\"2015-01-01T11:00:00\",\n        \"description\":\"hive activity\",\n        \"activities\": [\n          {\n            \"name\": \"SampleHiveActivity\",\n            \"inputs\": [\n              {\n                \"name\": \"AzureBlobInputDaily\"\n              },\n              {\n                \"name\": \"AzureBlobInputWeekly\",\n                \"startTime\": \"Date.AddDays(SliceStart,  -7 - Date.DayOfWeek(SliceStart))\",\n                \"endTime\": \"Date.AddDays(SliceEnd,  -Date.DayOfWeek(SliceEnd))\"  \n              }\n            ],\n            \"outputs\": [\n              {\n                \"name\": \"AzureBlobOutputDaily\"\n              }\n            ],\n            \"linkedServiceName\": \"HDInsightLinkedService\",\n            \"type\": \"HDInsightHive\",\n            \"typeProperties\": {\n              \"scriptPath\": \"adftutorial\\\\hivequery.hql\",\n              \"scriptLinkedService\": \"StorageLinkedService\",\n              \"defines\": {\n                \"Year\": \"$$Text.Format('{0:yyyy}',WindowsStart)\",\n                \"Month\": \"$$Text.Format('{0:%M}',WindowStart)\",\n                \"Day\": \"$$Text.Format('{0:%d}',WindowStart)\"\n              }\n            },\n            \"scheduler\": {\n              \"frequency\": \"Day\",\n              \"interval\": 1\n            },          \n            \"policy\": {\n              \"concurrency\": 1,\n              \"executionPriorityOrder\": \"OldestFirst\",\n              \"retry\": 2,  \n              \"timeout\": \"01:00:00\"\n            }\n           } \n         ]\n       }\n    }\n\n\n\n## Data Factory System Variables\n\nVariable Name | Description | Object Scope | JSON Scope and Use Cases\n------------- | ----------- | ------------ | ------------------------\nWindowStart | Start of time interval for current activity run window | activity | <ol><li>Specify data selection queries. See connector articles referenced in the [Data Movement Activities](data-factory-data-movement-activities.md) article.</li><li>Pass parameters to Hive script (sample shown above).</li>\nWindowEnd | End of time interval for current activity run window | activity | same as above\nSliceStart | Start of time interval for data  slice being produced | activity<br/>dataset | <ol><li>Specify dynamic folder paths and file names while working with [Azure Blob](data-factory-azure-blob-connector.md) and [File System datasets](data-factory-onprem-file-system-connector.md).</li><li>Specify input dependencies with data factory functions in activity inputs collection.</li></ol>\nSliceEnd | End of time interval for current data slice being produced | activity<br/>dataset | same as above. \n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] Currently data factory requires that the schedule specified in the activity exactly match the schedule specified in availability of the output dataset. This means WindowStart, WindowEnd and SliceStart and SliceEnd always map to the same time period and a single output slice.\n \n## Data Factory Functions Reference\n\nYou can use functions in data factory along with above mentioned system variables for the following purposes:\n\n1.  Specifying data selection queries (see connector articles referenced by the [Data Movement Activities](data-factory-data-movement-activities.md) article.\n\n    The syntax to invoke a data factory function is: **$$<function>** for data selection  queries and other properties in the activity and datasets.  \n2. Specifying input dependencies with data factory functions in activity inputs collection (see sample above).\n\n    $$ is not needed for specifying input dependency expressions.   \n\nIn the following sample, **sqlReaderQuery** property in a JSON file is assigned to a value returned by the **Text.Format** function. This sample also uses a system variable named **WindowStart**, which represents the start time of the activity run window.\n    \n    {\n        \"Type\": \"SqlSource\",\n        \"sqlReaderQuery\": \"$$Text.Format('SELECT * FROM MyTable WHERE StartTime = \\\\'{0:yyyyMMdd-HH}\\\\'', WindowStart)\"\n    }\n\n### Functions\n\nThe following tables list all the functions in Azure Data Factory:\n\nCategory | Function | Parameters | Description\n-------- | -------- | ---------- | ----------- \nTime | AddHours(X,Y) | X: DateTime <p>Y: int</p> | Adds Y hours to the given time X. <p>Example: 9/5/2013 12:00:00 PM + 2 hours = 9/5/2013 2:00:00 PM</p>\nTime | AddMinutes(X,Y) | X: DateTime <p>Y: int</p> | Adds Y minutes to X.<p>Example: 9/15/2013 12: 00:00 PM + 15 minutes = 9/15/2013 12: 15:00 PM</p>\nTime | StartOfHour(X) | X: Datetime | Gets the starting time for the hour represented by the hour component of X. <p>Example: StartOfHour of 9/15/2013 05: 10:23 PM is 9/15/2013 05: 00:00 PM</p>\nDate | AddDays(X,Y) | X: DateTime<p>Y: int</p> | Adds Y days to X.<p>Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 2 days = 9/17/2013 12:00:00 PM</p>\nDate | AddMonths(X,Y) | X: DateTime<p>Y: int</p> | Adds Y months to X.<p>Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 1 month = 10/15/2013 12:00:00 PM</p> \nDate | AddQuarters(X,Y) | X: DateTime <p>Y: int</p> | Adds Y * 3 months to X.<p>Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 1 quarter = 12/15/2013 12:00:00 PM</p>\nDate | AddWeeks(X,Y) | X: DateTime<p>Y: int</p> | Adds Y * 7 days to X<p>Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 1 week = 9/22/2013 12:00:00 PM</p>\nDate | AddYears(X,Y) | X: DateTime<p>Y: int</p> | Adds Y years to X.<p>Example: 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM + 1 year = 9/15/2014 12:00:00 PM</p>\nDate | Day(X) | X: DateTime | Gets the day component of X.<p>Example: Day of 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM is 9. </p>\nDate | DayOfWeek(X) | X: DateTime | Gets the day of week component of X.<p>Example: DayOfWeek of 9/15/2013 12:00:00 PM is Sunday.</p>\nDate | DayOfYear(X) | X: DateTime | Gets the day in the year represented by the year component of X.<p>Examples:<br/>12/1/2015: day 335 of 2015<br/>12/31/2015: day 365 of 2015<br/>12/31/2016: day 366 of 2016 (Leap Year)</p>\nDate | DaysInMonth(X) | X: DateTime | Gets the days in the month represented by the month component of parameter X.<p>Example: DaysInMonth of 9/15/2013 are 30 since there are 30 days in the September month.</p>\nDate | EndOfDay(X) | X: DateTime | Gets the date-time that represents the end of the day (day component) of X.<p>Example: EndOfDay of 9/15/2013 05:10:23 PM is 9/15/2013 11:59:59 PM.</p>\nDate | EndOfMonth(X) | X: DateTime | Gets the end of the month represented by month component of parameter X. <p>Example: EndOfMonth of 9/15/2013 05:10:23 PM is 9/30/2013 11:59:59 PM (date time that represents the end of September month)</p>\nDate | StartOfDay(X) | X: DateTime | Gets the start of the day represented by the day component of parameter X.<p>Example: StartOfDay of 9/15/2013 05:10:23 PM is 9/15/2013 12:00:00 AM.</p>\nDateTime | From(X) | X: String | Parse string X to a date time.\nDateTime | Ticks(X) | X: DateTime | Gets the ticks property of the parameter X. One tick equals 100 nanoseconds. The value of this property represents the number of ticks that have elapsed since 12:00:00 midnight, January 1, 0001. \nText | Format(X) | X: String variable | Formats the text.\n\n#### Text.Format example\n\n    \"defines\": { \n        \"Year\" : \"$$Text.Format('{0:yyyy}',WindowStart)\",\n        \"Month\" : \"$$Text.Format('{0:MM}',WindowStart)\",\n        \"Day\" : \"$$Text.Format('{0:dd}',WindowStart)\",\n        \"Hour\" : \"$$Text.Format('{0:hh}',WindowStart)\"\n    }\n\n> [AZURE.NOTE] When using a function within another function, you do not need to use **$$** prefix for the inner function. For example: $$Text.Format('PartitionKey eq \\\\'my_pkey_filter_value\\\\' and RowKey ge \\\\'{0:yyyy-MM-dd HH:mm:ss}\\\\'', Time.AddHours(SliceStart, -6)). In this example, notice that **$$** prefix is not used for the **Time.AddHours** function. \n  \n\n## Data Dependency Deep Dive\n\nIn order to generate a dataset slice by an activity run, data factory uses the following **dependency model** to determine the relationships between the dataset(s) consumed by an activity and the dataset(s) produced by an activity.\n\nThe time range of the input dataset(s) required to generate the output dataset slice called the **dependency period**.\n\nAn activity run generates a dataset slice only after the data slices in input dataset(s) within the dependency period are available. It means that all the input slices comprising the dependency period must be in **Ready** status  for the output dataset slice to be produced by an activity run. \n\nTo generate the dataset slice [start, end], a function is needed to map the dataset slice to its dependency period. This function is essentially a formula that converts the start and end of the dataset slice to the start and end of the dependency period. More formally, \n    \n    DatasetSlice = [start, end]\n    DependecyPeriod = [f(start, end), g(start, end)]\n\nwhere f and g are mapping functions that calculate the start and end of the dependency period for each activity input.\n\nAs seen in samples shown above in most cases the dependency period is same as the period for the data slice to be produced. In these cases data factory automatically computes the input slices that fall in the dependency period.  \n\nFor example: In the aggregation sample above where output is produced daily and input data is available every hour, the data slice period is 24 hours. Data factory finds the relevant hourly input slices for this time period and makes the output slice dependent on the input slice.\n\nYou can also provide your own mapping for the dependency period as shown in the sample above where one of the inputs was weekly and the output slice is produced daily.\n   \n## Data Dependency and Validation\n\nA dataset can optionally have a validation policy defined that specifies how the data generated by a slice execution can be validated before it is ready for consumption. See [Creating datasets](data-factory-create-datasets.md) article for details. \n\nIn such cases, once the slice has finished execution, the output slice status is changed to **Waiting** with a substatus of **Validation**. Once the slices are validated, the slice status changes to **Ready**.\n   \nIf a data slice has been produced but did not pass the validation, activity runs for downstream slices depending on the slice that failed validation will not be processed.\n\nThe various states of data slices in data factory are covered in the [Monitor and manage pipelines](data-factory-monitor-manage-pipelines.md) article.\n\n## External Data\n\nA dataset can be marked as external (as shown in the JSON below), implying it was not generated with Azure Data Factory. In such a case, the Dataset policy can have an additional set of parameters describing validation and retry policy for the dataset.  Please see [Creating Pipelines](data-factory-create-pipelines.md) for a description of all the properties. \n\nSimilar to datasets that are produced by data factory the data slices for external data need to be ready   before dependent slices can be processed.\n\n    {\n        \"name\": \"AzureSqlInput\",\n        \"properties\": \n        {\n            \"type\": \"AzureSqlTable\",\n            \"linkedServiceName\": \"AzureSqlLinkedService\",\n            \"typeProperties\": \n            {\n                \"tableName\": \"MyTable\"  \n            },\n            \"availability\": \n            {\n                \"frequency\": \"Hour\",\n                \"interval\": 1     \n            },\n            \"external\": true,\n            \"policy\": \n            {\n                \"externalData\": \n                {\n                    \"retryInterval\": \"00:01:00\",\n                    \"retryTimeout\": \"00:10:00\",\n                    \"maximumRetry\": 3\n                }\n            }  \n        } \n    } \n\n\n\n\n\n\n  \n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n \n \n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n      \n\n  \n\n\n\n\n\ntest\n"
}