{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Configure Traffic Manager failover traffic routing method | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        27,
        102
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article will help you configure failover traffic routing method in Traffic Manager",
      "pos": [
        120,
        207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure Failover routing method",
      "pos": [
        522,
        555
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Often an organization wants to provide reliability for its services.",
      "pos": [
        557,
        625
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It does this by providing backup services in case their primary service goes down.",
      "pos": [
        626,
        708
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A common pattern for service failover is to provide a set of identical services and send traffic to a primary service, while maintaining a configured list of one or more backup services.",
      "pos": [
        709,
        895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can configure this type of backup with Azure cloud services and websites by following the procedures below.",
      "pos": [
        896,
        1007
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that Azure Websites already provides failover traffic routing method functionality for websites within a datacenter (also known as a region), regardless of the website mode.",
      "pos": [
        1009,
        1187
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traffic Manager allows you to specify failover traffic routing method for websites in different datacenters.",
      "pos": [
        1188,
        1296
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To configure failover traffic routing method:",
      "pos": [
        1301,
        1346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the Management Portal, in the left pane, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Traffic Manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> icon to open the Traffic Manager pane.",
      "pos": [
        1351,
        1463
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have not yet created your Traffic Manager profile, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage Traffic Manager Profiles<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-manage-profiles.md)</ept> for steps to create a basic Traffic Manager profile.",
      "pos": [
        1464,
        1648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the Traffic Manager pane in the Management Portal, locate the Traffic Manager profile that contains the settings that you want to modify, and then click the arrow to the right of the profile name.",
      "pos": [
        1652,
        1851
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will open the settings page for the profile.",
      "pos": [
        1852,
        1901
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On your profile page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Endpoints<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the top of the page and verify that the both cloud services and websites (endpoints) that you want to include in your configuration are present.",
      "pos": [
        1905,
        2094
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For steps to add or remove endpoints, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage Endpoints in Traffic Manager<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-endpoints.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2095,
        2205
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        2209,
        2293
      ],
      "content": "On your profile page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the top to open the configuration page."
    },
    {
      "content": "For <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>traffic routing method settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, verify that the traffic routing method is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Failover<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2297,
        2393
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If it is not, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Failover<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> from the dropdown list.",
      "pos": [
        2394,
        2450
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Failover Priority List<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, adjust the failover order for your endpoints.",
      "pos": [
        2454,
        2531
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Failover<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> traffic routing method, the order of the selected endpoints matters.",
      "pos": [
        2532,
        2633
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The primary endpoint is on top.",
      "pos": [
        2634,
        2665
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the up and down arrows to change the order as needed.",
      "pos": [
        2666,
        2723
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information about how to set the failover priority by using Windows PowerShell, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set-AzureTrafficManagerProfile<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=400880)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2724,
        2894
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Monitoring Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> are configured appropriately.",
      "pos": [
        2898,
        2967
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitoring ensures that endpoints that are offline are not sent traffic.",
      "pos": [
        2968,
        3040
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In order to monitor endpoints, you must specify a path and filename.",
      "pos": [
        3041,
        3109
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that a forward slash “/“ is a valid entry for the relative path and implies that the file is in the root directory (default).",
      "pos": [
        3110,
        3240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about monitoring, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Traffic Manager Monitoring<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-monitoring.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3241,
        3344
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3348,
        3436
      ],
      "content": "After you complete your configuration changes, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the bottom of the page."
    },
    {
      "content": "Test the changes in your configuration.",
      "pos": [
        3440,
        3479
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Testing Traffic Manager Settings<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-testing-settings.md)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        3480,
        3577
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once your Traffic Manager profile is setup and working, edit the DNS record on your authoritative DNS server to point your company domain name to the Traffic Manager domain name.",
      "pos": [
        3582,
        3760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about how to do this, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Point a Company Internet Domain to a Traffic Manager Domain<ept id=\"p1\">](traffic-manager-point-internet-domain.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3761,
        3912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        3917,
        3927
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "About Traffic Manager traffic routing Methods",
      "pos": [
        3930,
        3975
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Traffic Manager?",
      "pos": [
        4022,
        4046
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traffic Manager - Disable, enable or delete a profile",
      "pos": [
        4079,
        4132
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Traffic Manager - Disable or enable an endpoint",
      "pos": [
        4175,
        4222
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cloud Services",
      "pos": [
        4260,
        4274
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Websites",
      "pos": [
        4325,
        4333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Operations on Traffic Manager (REST API Reference)",
      "pos": [
        4386,
        4436
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Traffic Manager Cmdlets",
      "pos": [
        4487,
        4516
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Configure Traffic Manager failover traffic routing method | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"This article will help you configure failover traffic routing method in Traffic Manager\"\n   services=\"traffic-manager\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"joaoma\"\n   manager=\"adinah\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"traffic-manager\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"08/19/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"joaoma\" />\n\n# Configure Failover routing method\n\nOften an organization wants to provide reliability for its services. It does this by providing backup services in case their primary service goes down. A common pattern for service failover is to provide a set of identical services and send traffic to a primary service, while maintaining a configured list of one or more backup services. You can configure this type of backup with Azure cloud services and websites by following the procedures below.\n\nNote that Azure Websites already provides failover traffic routing method functionality for websites within a datacenter (also known as a region), regardless of the website mode. Traffic Manager allows you to specify failover traffic routing method for websites in different datacenters.\n\n## To configure failover traffic routing method:\n\n1. In the Management Portal, in the left pane, click the **Traffic Manager** icon to open the Traffic Manager pane. If you have not yet created your Traffic Manager profile, see [Manage Traffic Manager Profiles](traffic-manager-manage-profiles.md) for steps to create a basic Traffic Manager profile.\n2. On the Traffic Manager pane in the Management Portal, locate the Traffic Manager profile that contains the settings that you want to modify, and then click the arrow to the right of the profile name. This will open the settings page for the profile.\n3. On your profile page, click **Endpoints** at the top of the page and verify that the both cloud services and websites (endpoints) that you want to include in your configuration are present. For steps to add or remove endpoints, see [Manage Endpoints in Traffic Manager](traffic-manager-endpoints.md).\n4. On your profile page, click **Configure** at the top to open the configuration page.\n5. For **traffic routing method settings**, verify that the traffic routing method is **Failover**. If it is not, click **Failover** from the dropdown list.\n6. For **Failover Priority List**, adjust the failover order for your endpoints. When you select the **Failover** traffic routing method, the order of the selected endpoints matters. The primary endpoint is on top. Use the up and down arrows to change the order as needed. For information about how to set the failover priority by using Windows PowerShell, see [Set-AzureTrafficManagerProfile](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=400880).\n7. Verify that the **Monitoring Settings** are configured appropriately. Monitoring ensures that endpoints that are offline are not sent traffic. In order to monitor endpoints, you must specify a path and filename. Note that a forward slash “/“ is a valid entry for the relative path and implies that the file is in the root directory (default). For more information about monitoring, see [Traffic Manager Monitoring](traffic-manager-monitoring.md).\n8. After you complete your configuration changes, click **Save** at the bottom of the page.\n9. Test the changes in your configuration. See [Testing Traffic Manager Settings](traffic-manager-testing-settings.md) for more information.\n10. Once your Traffic Manager profile is setup and working, edit the DNS record on your authoritative DNS server to point your company domain name to the Traffic Manager domain name. For more information about how to do this, see [Point a Company Internet Domain to a Traffic Manager Domain](traffic-manager-point-internet-domain.md).\n\n## Next steps\n\n[About Traffic Manager traffic routing Methods](traffic-manager-load-balancing-methods.md)\n\n[What is Traffic Manager?](traffic-manager-overview.md)\n\n[Traffic Manager - Disable, enable or delete a profile](disable-enable-or-delete-a-profile.md)\n\n[Traffic Manager - Disable or enable an endpoint](disable-or-enable-an-endpoint.md)\n\n[Cloud Services](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=314074)\n\n[Websites](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=393327)\n\n[Operations on Traffic Manager (REST API Reference)](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=313584)\n\n[Azure Traffic Manager Cmdlets](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=400769)\n "
}