{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "How to connect to data sources",
      "pos": [
        26,
        56
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How-to article highlighting how to connect to data sources discovered with Azure Data Catalog.",
      "pos": [
        74,
        168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to connect to data sources",
      "pos": [
        472,
        502
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Introduction",
      "pos": [
        507,
        519
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is a fully managed cloud service that serves as a system of registration and system of discovery for enterprise data sources.",
      "pos": [
        520,
        678
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In other words, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is all about helping people discover, understand, and use data sources, and helping organizations to get more value from their existing data.",
      "pos": [
        679,
        859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A key aspect of this scenario is using the data – once a user discovers a data source and understands its purpose, the next step is to connect to the data source to put its data to use.",
      "pos": [
        860,
        1045
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data source locations",
      "pos": [
        1049,
        1070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "During data source registration, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> receives metadata about the data source.",
      "pos": [
        1071,
        1167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This metadata includes the details of the data source’s location.",
      "pos": [
        1168,
        1233
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The details of the location will vary from data source to data source, but it will always contain the information needed to connect.",
      "pos": [
        1234,
        1366
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, the location for a SQL Server table includes the server name, database name, schema name, and table name, while the location for a SQL Server Reporting Services report includes the server name and the path to the report.",
      "pos": [
        1367,
        1600
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Other data source types will have locations that reflect the structure and capabilities of the source system.",
      "pos": [
        1601,
        1710
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Integrated client tools",
      "pos": [
        1714,
        1737
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The simplest way to connect to a data source is to use the “Open in…”",
      "pos": [
        1738,
        1807
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "menu in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> portal.",
      "pos": [
        1808,
        1850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This menu displays a list of options for connecting to the selected data asset.",
      "pos": [
        1851,
        1930
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using the default tile view, this menu is available on the each tile.",
      "pos": [
        1931,
        2005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Opening a SQL Server table in Excel from the data asset tile",
      "pos": [
        2010,
        2070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When using the list view, the menu is available in the search bar at the top of the portal window.",
      "pos": [
        2143,
        2241
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Opening a SQL Server Reporting Services report in Report Manager from the search bar",
      "pos": [
        2246,
        2330
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your data, your tools",
      "pos": [
        2405,
        2426
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The options available in the menu will depend on the type of data asset currently selected.",
      "pos": [
        2427,
        2518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Of course, not all possible tools will be included in the “Open in…”",
      "pos": [
        2519,
        2587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "menu, but it is still easy to connect to the data source using any client tool.",
      "pos": [
        2588,
        2667
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a data asset is selected in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> portal, the complete location is displayed in the properties pane.",
      "pos": [
        2668,
        2794
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connection information for a SQL Server table",
      "pos": [
        2799,
        2844
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The connection information details will differ from data source type to data source type, but the information included in the portal will give you everything you need to connect to the data source in any client tool.",
      "pos": [
        2917,
        3133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users can copy the connection details for the data sources that they have discovered using <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, enabling them to work with the data in their tool of choice.",
      "pos": [
        3134,
        3309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connecting and data source permissions",
      "pos": [
        3313,
        3351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Although <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> makes data sources discoverable, access to the data itself remains under the control of the data source owner or administrator.",
      "pos": [
        3352,
        3511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Discovering a data source in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> does not give a user any permissions to access the data source itself.",
      "pos": [
        3512,
        3634
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To make it easier for users who discover a data source but do not have permission to access its data, users can provide information in the Request Access property when annotating a data source.",
      "pos": [
        3636,
        3829
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Information provided here – including links to the process or point of contact for gaining data source access – is presented alongside the data source location information in the portal.",
      "pos": [
        3830,
        4016
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connection information with request access instructions provided",
      "pos": [
        4021,
        4085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Summary",
      "pos": [
        4160,
        4167
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Registering a data source with <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> makes that data discoverable by copying structural and descriptive metadata from the data source into the Catalog service.",
      "pos": [
        4168,
        4344
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once a data source has been registered, and discovered, users can connect to the data source from the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Data Catalog<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> portal “Open in…””",
      "pos": [
        4345,
        4488
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "menu or using their data tools of choice.",
      "pos": [
        4489,
        4530
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        4532,
        4536
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"How to connect to data sources\"\n   description=\"How-to article highlighting how to connect to data sources discovered with Azure Data Catalog.\"\n   services=\"data-catalog\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"steelanddata\"\n   manager=\"NA\"\n   editor=\"\"\n   tags=\"\"/>\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"data-catalog\"\n   ms.devlang=\"NA\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"NA\"\n   ms.workload=\"data-catalog\"\n   ms.date=\"08/19/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"maroche\"/>\n\n\n# How to connect to data sources\n\n## Introduction\n**Microsoft Azure Data Catalog** is a fully managed cloud service that serves as a system of registration and system of discovery for enterprise data sources. In other words, **Azure Data Catalog** is all about helping people discover, understand, and use data sources, and helping organizations to get more value from their existing data. A key aspect of this scenario is using the data – once a user discovers a data source and understands its purpose, the next step is to connect to the data source to put its data to use.\n\n##Data source locations\nDuring data source registration, **Azure Data Catalog** receives metadata about the data source. This metadata includes the details of the data source’s location. The details of the location will vary from data source to data source, but it will always contain the information needed to connect. For example, the location for a SQL Server table includes the server name, database name, schema name, and table name, while the location for a SQL Server Reporting Services report includes the server name and the path to the report. Other data source types will have locations that reflect the structure and capabilities of the source system.\n\n##Integrated client tools\nThe simplest way to connect to a data source is to use the “Open in…” menu in the **Azure Data Catalog** portal. This menu displays a list of options for connecting to the selected data asset.\nWhen using the default tile view, this menu is available on the each tile.\n\n ![Opening a SQL Server table in Excel from the data asset tile](./media/data-catalog-how-to-connect/data-catalog-how-to-connect1.png)\n\nWhen using the list view, the menu is available in the search bar at the top of the portal window.\n\n ![Opening a SQL Server Reporting Services report in Report Manager from the search bar](./media/data-catalog-how-to-connect/data-catalog-how-to-connect2.png)\n\n##Your data, your tools\nThe options available in the menu will depend on the type of data asset currently selected. Of course, not all possible tools will be included in the “Open in…” menu, but it is still easy to connect to the data source using any client tool. When a data asset is selected in the **Azure Data Catalog** portal, the complete location is displayed in the properties pane.\n\n ![Connection information for a SQL Server table](./media/data-catalog-how-to-connect/data-catalog-how-to-connect3.png)\n\nThe connection information details will differ from data source type to data source type, but the information included in the portal will give you everything you need to connect to the data source in any client tool. Users can copy the connection details for the data sources that they have discovered using **Azure Data Catalog**, enabling them to work with the data in their tool of choice.\n\n##Connecting and data source permissions\nAlthough **Azure Data Catalog** makes data sources discoverable, access to the data itself remains under the control of the data source owner or administrator. Discovering a data source in **Azure Data Catalog** does not give a user any permissions to access the data source itself.\n\nTo make it easier for users who discover a data source but do not have permission to access its data, users can provide information in the Request Access property when annotating a data source. Information provided here – including links to the process or point of contact for gaining data source access – is presented alongside the data source location information in the portal.\n\n ![Connection information with request access instructions provided](./media/data-catalog-how-to-connect/data-catalog-how-to-connect4.png)\n\n##Summary\nRegistering a data source with **Azure Data Catalog** makes that data discoverable by copying structural and descriptive metadata from the data source into the Catalog service. Once a data source has been registered, and discovered, users can connect to the data source from the **Azure Data Catalog** portal “Open in…”” menu or using their data tools of choice.\n\ntest\n"
}