{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "pos": [
        139,
        214
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a id=\"logon\"&gt;</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>How to log on to the virtual machine after you create it"
    },
    {
      "content": "To manage the settings of the virtual machine and the applications that run on the machine, you can use an SSH client.",
      "pos": [
        219,
        337
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To do this, you must install an SSH client on your computer that you want to use to access the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        338,
        449
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are many SSH client programs that you can choose from.",
      "pos": [
        450,
        510
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following are possible choices:",
      "pos": [
        511,
        546
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using a computer that is running a Windows operating system, you might want to use an SSH client such as PuTTY.",
      "pos": [
        550,
        672
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>PuTTY Download<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        673,
        781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you are using a computer that is running a Linux operating system, you might want to use an SSH client such as OpenSSH.",
      "pos": [
        784,
        906
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>OpenSSH<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.openssh.org/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        907,
        968
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tutorial shows you how to use the PuTTY program to access the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        970,
        1053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Find the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Host Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Port information<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> from the Management Portal.",
      "pos": [
        1058,
        1133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can find the information that you need from the dashboard of the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        1134,
        1219
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the virtual machine name and look for the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SSH Details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Quick Glance<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> section of the dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        1220,
        1333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Find SSH details",
      "pos": [
        1341,
        1357
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Open the PuTTY program.",
      "pos": [
        1421,
        1444
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1449,
        1565
      ],
      "content": "Enter the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Host Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Port information<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> that you collected from the dashboard, and then click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Open<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Enter the host name and port information",
      "pos": [
        1573,
        1613
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log on to the virtual machine using the NewUser1 account that you specified when the machine was created.",
      "pos": [
        1672,
        1777
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Log on to the new virtual machine",
      "pos": [
        1785,
        1818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can now work with the virtual machine just as you would with any other server.",
      "pos": [
        1881,
        1963
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1969,
        2045
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a id=\"attachdisk\"&gt;</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>How to attach a data disk to the new virtual machine"
    },
    {
      "content": "Your application may need to store data.",
      "pos": [
        2050,
        2090
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To set this up, you attach a data disk to the virtual machine that you previously created.",
      "pos": [
        2091,
        2181
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The easiest way to do this is to attach an empty data disk to the machine.",
      "pos": [
        2182,
        2256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note: Data Disk vs. Resource Disk<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>",
      "pos": [
        2258,
        2295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Data Disks reside on Azure Storage and can be used for persistent storage of files and application data.",
      "pos": [
        2298,
        2402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each virtual machine created also has a temporary local <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Resource Disk<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> attached.",
      "pos": [
        2404,
        2485
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Because data on a resource disk may not be durable across reboots, it is often used by applications and processes running in the virtual machine for transient and temporary storage of data.",
      "pos": [
        2486,
        2675
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is also used to store page or swap files for the operating system.",
      "pos": [
        2676,
        2745
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On Linux, the Resource Disk is typically managed by the Azure Linux Agent and automatically mounted to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>/mnt/resource<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>/mnt<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> on Ubuntu images).",
      "pos": [
        2747,
        2899
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the resource disk is a <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>temporary<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> disk, and might be emptied when the VM is deprovisioned.",
      "pos": [
        2900,
        3001
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "On the other hand, on Linux the data disk might be named by the kernel as <ph id=\"ph1\">`/dev/sdc`</ph>, and users will need to partition, format and mount that resource.",
      "pos": [
        3002,
        3153
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Linux Agent User Guide<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.windowsazure.com/manage/linux/how-to-guides/linux-agent-guide/)</ept> for more information.",
      "pos": [
        3154,
        3296
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have not already done so, sign in to the Azure Management Portal.",
      "pos": [
        3303,
        3375
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3380,
        3486
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then select the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>MyTestVM1<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> virtual machine that you previously created."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3491,
        3566
      ],
      "content": "On the command bar, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Attach<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Attach Empty Disk<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3576,
        3621
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Attach Empty Disk<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box appears."
    },
    {
      "content": "Define disk details",
      "pos": [
        3629,
        3648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual Machine Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Storage Location<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>File Name<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> are already defined for you.",
      "pos": [
        3720,
        3818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "All you have to do is enter the size that you want for the disk.",
      "pos": [
        3819,
        3883
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Type <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>5<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Size<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field.",
      "pos": [
        3884,
        3917
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> All disks are created from a VHD file in Azure storage.",
      "pos": [
        3923,
        3988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can provide a name for the VHD file that is added to storage, but the name of the disk is automatically generated.",
      "pos": [
        3989,
        4107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the check mark to attach the data disk to the virtual machine.",
      "pos": [
        4112,
        4180
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can verify that the data disk is successfully attached to the virtual machine by looking at the dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        4185,
        4295
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the name of the virtual machine to display the dashboard.",
      "pos": [
        4296,
        4359
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4365,
        4482
      ],
      "content": "The number of disks is now 2 for the virtual machine and the disk that you attached is listed in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Disks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> table."
    },
    {
      "content": "Attach disk success",
      "pos": [
        4490,
        4509
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The data disk that you just attached to the virtual machine is offline and not initialized after you add it.",
      "pos": [
        4579,
        4687
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must log on to the machine and initialize the disk to use it for storing data.",
      "pos": [
        4688,
        4770
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4775,
        4902
      ],
      "content": "Connect to the virtual machine by using the steps listed above in <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>How to log on to the virtual machine after you create it<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "In the SSH window, type the following command, and then enter the account password:",
      "pos": [
        4908,
        4991
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can find the identifier of the last data disk that was added in the messages that are displayed.",
      "pos": [
        5037,
        5137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Identify disk",
      "pos": [
        5145,
        5158
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the SSH window, type the following command to create a new device, and then enter the account password:",
      "pos": [
        5225,
        5331
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5365,
        5492
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> In this example you may need to use <ph id=\"ph2\">`sudo -i`</ph> on some distributions if /sbin or /usr/sbin are not in your <ph id=\"ph3\">`$PATH`</ph>."
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5498,
        5535
      ],
      "content": "Type <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>n<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to create a new partition."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create new device",
      "pos": [
        5543,
        5560
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5628,
        5792
      ],
      "content": "Type <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>p<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to make the partition the primary partition, type <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>1<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to make it the first partition, and then type enter to accept the default value for the cylinder."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create partition",
      "pos": [
        5800,
        5816
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5883,
        5954
      ],
      "content": "Type <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>p<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to see the details about the disk that is being partitioned."
    },
    {
      "content": "List disk information",
      "pos": [
        5962,
        5983
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6046,
        6092
      ],
      "content": "Type <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>w<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to write the settings for the disk."
    },
    {
      "content": "Write the disk changes",
      "pos": [
        6100,
        6122
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must create the file system on the new partition.",
      "pos": [
        6186,
        6239
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As an example, type the following command to create the file system, and then enter the account password:",
      "pos": [
        6240,
        6345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create file system",
      "pos": [
        6388,
        6406
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> Note that on SUSE Linux Enterprise 11 systems provide only read-only access for ext4 file systems.",
      "pos": [
        6476,
        6587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For these systems it is recommended to format the new file system as ext3 rather than ext4.",
      "pos": [
        6589,
        6680
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next you must have a directory available to mount the new file system.",
      "pos": [
        6686,
        6756
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As an example, type the following command to make a new directory for mounting the drive, and then enter the account password:",
      "pos": [
        6757,
        6883
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Type the following command to mount the drive:",
      "pos": [
        6919,
        6965
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7010,
        7062
      ],
      "content": "The data disk is now ready to use as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>/datadrive<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Add the new drive to /etc/fstab:",
      "pos": [
        7069,
        7101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To ensure the drive is re-mounted automatically after a reboot it must be added to the /etc/fstab file.",
      "pos": [
        7107,
        7210
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In addition, it is highly recommended that the UUID (Universally Unique IDentifier) is used in /etc/fstab to refer to the drive rather than just the device name (i.e. /dev/sdc1).",
      "pos": [
        7211,
        7389
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To find the UUID of the new drive you can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>blkid<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> utility:",
      "pos": [
        7390,
        7458
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The output will look similar to the following:",
      "pos": [
        7493,
        7539
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7778,
        7955
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> blkid may not require sudo access in all cases, however, it may be easier to run with <ph id=\"ph2\">`sudo -i`</ph> on some distributions if /sbin or /usr/sbin are not in your <ph id=\"ph3\">`$PATH`</ph>."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Caution:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Improperly editing the /etc/fstab file could result in an unbootable system.",
      "pos": [
        7961,
        8050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If unsure, please refer to the distribution's documentation for information on how to properly edit this file.",
      "pos": [
        8051,
        8161
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is also recommended that a backup of the /etc/fstab file is created before editing.",
      "pos": [
        8162,
        8248
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Using a text editor, enter the information about the new file system at the end of the /etc/fstab file.",
      "pos": [
        8254,
        8357
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example we will use the UUID value for the new <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>/dev/sdc1<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> device that was created in the previous steps, and the mountpoint <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>/datadrive<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>:",
      "pos": [
        8359,
        8509
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Or, on systems based on SUSE Linux you may need to use a slightly different format:",
      "pos": [
        8607,
        8690
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If additional data drives or partitions are created you will need to enter them into /etc/fstab separately as well.",
      "pos": [
        8792,
        8907
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can now test that the file system is mounted properly by simply unmounting and then re-mounting the file system, i.e.",
      "pos": [
        8913,
        9034
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "using the example mount point <ph id=\"ph1\">`/datadrive`</ph> created in the earlier steps:",
      "pos": [
        9035,
        9107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the second command produces an error, check the /etc/fstab file for correct syntax.",
      "pos": [
        9180,
        9266
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<!---\nDon't use this file. It's deprecated and will be removed. Instead use, virtual-machines-Linux-tutorial-log-on-attach-disk.md\n-->\n\n## <a id=\"logon\"> </a>How to log on to the virtual machine after you create it ##\n\nTo manage the settings of the virtual machine and the applications that run on the machine, you can use an SSH client. To do this, you must install an SSH client on your computer that you want to use to access the virtual machine. There are many SSH client programs that you can choose from. The following are possible choices:\n\n- If you are using a computer that is running a Windows operating system, you might want to use an SSH client such as PuTTY. For more information, see [PuTTY Download](http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/download.html).\n- If you are using a computer that is running a Linux operating system, you might want to use an SSH client such as OpenSSH. For more information, see [OpenSSH](http://www.openssh.org/).\n\nThis tutorial shows you how to use the PuTTY program to access the virtual machine.\n\n1. Find the **Host Name** and **Port information** from the Management Portal. You can find the information that you need from the dashboard of the virtual machine. Click the virtual machine name and look for the **SSH Details** in the **Quick Glance** section of the dashboard.\n\n    ![Find SSH details](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/SSHdetails.png)\n\n2. Open the PuTTY program.\n\n3. Enter the **Host Name** and the **Port information** that you collected from the dashboard, and then click **Open**.\n\n    ![Enter the host name and port information](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/putty.png)\n\n4. Log on to the virtual machine using the NewUser1 account that you specified when the machine was created.\n\n    ![Log on to the new virtual machine](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/sshlogin.png)\n\n    You can now work with the virtual machine just as you would with any other server.\n\n\n## <a id=\"attachdisk\"> </a>How to attach a data disk to the new virtual machine ##\n\nYour application may need to store data. To set this up, you attach a data disk to the virtual machine that you previously created. The easiest way to do this is to attach an empty data disk to the machine.\n\n**Note: Data Disk vs. Resource Disk**  \nData Disks reside on Azure Storage and can be used for persistent storage of files and application data.\n\nEach virtual machine created also has a temporary local *Resource Disk* attached. Because data on a resource disk may not be durable across reboots, it is often used by applications and processes running in the virtual machine for transient and temporary storage of data. It is also used to store page or swap files for the operating system.\n\nOn Linux, the Resource Disk is typically managed by the Azure Linux Agent and automatically mounted to **/mnt/resource** (or **/mnt** on Ubuntu images). Note that the resource disk is a *temporary* disk, and might be emptied when the VM is deprovisioned. On the other hand, on Linux the data disk might be named by the kernel as `/dev/sdc`, and users will need to partition, format and mount that resource. Please see the [Azure Linux Agent User Guide](http://www.windowsazure.com/manage/linux/how-to-guides/linux-agent-guide/) for more information.\n\n\n\n1. If you have not already done so, sign in to the Azure Management Portal.\n\n2. Click **Virtual Machines**, and then select the **MyTestVM1** virtual machine that you previously created.\n\n3. On the command bar, click **Attach**, and then click **Attach Empty Disk**.\n    \n    The **Attach Empty Disk** dialog box appears.\n\n    ![Define disk details](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/attachnewdisklinux.png)\n\n4. The **Virtual Machine Name**, **Storage Location**, and **File Name** are already defined for you. All you have to do is enter the size that you want for the disk. Type **5** in the **Size** field.\n\n    **Note:** All disks are created from a VHD file in Azure storage. You can provide a name for the VHD file that is added to storage, but the name of the disk is automatically generated.\n\n5. Click the check mark to attach the data disk to the virtual machine.\n\n6. You can verify that the data disk is successfully attached to the virtual machine by looking at the dashboard. Click the name of the virtual machine to display the dashboard.\n\n    The number of disks is now 2 for the virtual machine and the disk that you attached is listed in the **Disks** table.\n\n    ![Attach disk success](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/attachemptysuccess.png)\n\n\nThe data disk that you just attached to the virtual machine is offline and not initialized after you add it. You must log on to the machine and initialize the disk to use it for storing data.\n\n1. Connect to the virtual machine by using the steps listed above in **How to log on to the virtual machine after you create it**.\n\n\n2. In the SSH window, type the following command, and then enter the account password:\n\n    `sudo grep SCSI /var/log/messages`\n\n    You can find the identifier of the last data disk that was added in the messages that are displayed.\n\n    ![Identify disk](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/diskmessages.png)\n\n\n3. In the SSH window, type the following command to create a new device, and then enter the account password:\n\n    `sudo fdisk /dev/sdc`\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] In this example you may need to use `sudo -i` on some distributions if /sbin or /usr/sbin are not in your `$PATH`.\n\n\n4. Type **n** to create a new partition.\n\n    ![Create new device](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/diskpartition.png)\n\n\n5. Type **p** to make the partition the primary partition, type **1** to make it the first partition, and then type enter to accept the default value for the cylinder.\n\n    ![Create partition](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/diskcylinder.png)\n\n\n6. Type **p** to see the details about the disk that is being partitioned.\n\n    ![List disk information](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/diskinfo.png)\n\n\n7. Type **w** to write the settings for the disk.\n\n    ![Write the disk changes](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/diskwrite.png)\n\n\n8. You must create the file system on the new partition. As an example, type the following command to create the file system, and then enter the account password:\n\n    `sudo mkfs -t ext4 /dev/sdc1`\n\n    ![Create file system](./media/CreateVirtualMachineLinuxTutorial/diskfilesystem.png)\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] Note that on SUSE Linux Enterprise 11 systems provide only read-only access for ext4 file systems.  For these systems it is recommended to format the new file system as ext3 rather than ext4.\n\n\n9. Next you must have a directory available to mount the new file system. As an example, type the following command to make a new directory for mounting the drive, and then enter the account password:\n\n    `sudo mkdir /datadrive`\n\n\n10. Type the following command to mount the drive:\n\n    `sudo mount /dev/sdc1 /datadrive`\n\n    The data disk is now ready to use as **/datadrive**.\n\n\n11. Add the new drive to /etc/fstab:\n\n    To ensure the drive is re-mounted automatically after a reboot it must be added to the /etc/fstab file. In addition, it is highly recommended that the UUID (Universally Unique IDentifier) is used in /etc/fstab to refer to the drive rather than just the device name (i.e. /dev/sdc1). To find the UUID of the new drive you can use the **blkid** utility:\n    \n        `sudo -i blkid`\n\n    The output will look similar to the following:\n\n        `/dev/sda1: UUID=\"11111111-1b1b-1c1c-1d1d-1e1e1e1e1e1e\" TYPE=\"ext4\"`\n        `/dev/sdb1: UUID=\"22222222-2b2b-2c2c-2d2d-2e2e2e2e2e2e\" TYPE=\"ext4\"`\n        `/dev/sdc1: UUID=\"33333333-3b3b-3c3c-3d3d-3e3e3e3e3e3e\" TYPE=\"ext4\"`\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] blkid may not require sudo access in all cases, however, it may be easier to run with `sudo -i` on some distributions if /sbin or /usr/sbin are not in your `$PATH`.\n\n    **Caution:** Improperly editing the /etc/fstab file could result in an unbootable system. If unsure, please refer to the distribution's documentation for information on how to properly edit this file. It is also recommended that a backup of the /etc/fstab file is created before editing.\n\n    Using a text editor, enter the information about the new file system at the end of the /etc/fstab file.  In this example we will use the UUID value for the new **/dev/sdc1** device that was created in the previous steps, and the mountpoint **/datadrive**:\n\n        `UUID=33333333-3b3b-3c3c-3d3d-3e3e3e3e3e3e   /datadrive   ext4   defaults   1   2`\n\n    Or, on systems based on SUSE Linux you may need to use a slightly different format:\n\n        `/dev/disk/by-uuid/33333333-3b3b-3c3c-3d3d-3e3e3e3e3e3e   /   ext3   defaults   1   2`\n\n    If additional data drives or partitions are created you will need to enter them into /etc/fstab separately as well.\n\n    You can now test that the file system is mounted properly by simply unmounting and then re-mounting the file system, i.e. using the example mount point `/datadrive` created in the earlier steps: \n\n        `sudo umount /datadrive`\n        `sudo mount /datadrive`\n\n    If the second command produces an error, check the /etc/fstab file for correct syntax.\n\n\n    >[AZURE.NOTE] Subsequently removing a data disk without editing fstab could cause the VM to fail to boot. If this is a common occurrence, then most distributions provide either the `nofail` and/or `nobootwait` fstab options that will allow a system to boot even if the disk is not present. Please consult your distribution's documentation for more information on these parameters.\n\n\n"
}