{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation webhooks",
      "pos": [
        27,
        52
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A webhook that allows a client to start a runbook in Azure Automation from an HTTP call.",
      "pos": [
        70,
        158
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This article describes how to create a webhook and how to call one to start a runbook.",
      "pos": [
        160,
        246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation webhooks",
      "pos": [
        551,
        576
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>webhook<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> allows you to start a particular runbook in Azure Automation through a single HTTP request.",
      "pos": [
        578,
        681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This allows external services such as Visual Studio Online, GitHub, or custom applications to start runbooks without implementing a full solution using the Azure Automation API.",
      "pos": [
        682,
        859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Webhooks",
      "pos": [
        863,
        871
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        923,
        1064
      ],
      "content": "You can compare webhooks to other methods of starting a runbook in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Starting a runbook in Azure Automation<ept id=\"p1\">](automation-starting-a-runbook.md)</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "Details of a webhook",
      "pos": [
        1069,
        1089
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following table describes the properties that you must configure for a webhook.",
      "pos": [
        1091,
        1174
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Property",
      "pos": [
        1178,
        1186
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        1189,
        1200
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Name",
      "pos": [
        1216,
        1220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can provide any name you want for a webhook since this is not exposed to the client.",
      "pos": [
        1223,
        1311
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is only used for you to identify the runbook in Azure Automation.",
      "pos": [
        1313,
        1381
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As a best practice, you should give the webhook a name related to the client that will use it.",
      "pos": [
        1388,
        1482
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "URL",
      "pos": [
        1486,
        1489
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The URL of the webhook is the unique address that a client calls with an HTTP POST to start the runbook linked to the webhook.",
      "pos": [
        1491,
        1617
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It is automatically generated when you create the webhook.",
      "pos": [
        1619,
        1677
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot specify a custom URL.",
      "pos": [
        1679,
        1711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The URL contains a security token that allows the runbook to be invoked by a third party system with no further authentication.",
      "pos": [
        1723,
        1850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For this reason, it should be treated like a password.",
      "pos": [
        1851,
        1905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For security reasons, you can only view the URL in the Azure preview portal at the time the webhook is created.",
      "pos": [
        1907,
        2018
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You should note the URL in a secure location for future use.",
      "pos": [
        2019,
        2079
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Expiration date",
      "pos": [
        2085,
        2100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Like a certificate, each webhook has an expiration date at which time it can no longer be used.",
      "pos": [
        2103,
        2198
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This expiration date cannot be changed after the webhook is created, and the webhook also cannot be enabled again after the expiration date is reached.",
      "pos": [
        2200,
        2351
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, you must create another webhook to replace the current one and update the client to use the new webhook.",
      "pos": [
        2353,
        2471
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enabled",
      "pos": [
        2476,
        2483
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A webhook is enabled by default when it is created.",
      "pos": [
        2486,
        2537
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you set it to Disabled, then no client will be able to use it.",
      "pos": [
        2539,
        2604
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enabled<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property when you create the webhook or anytime once it is created.",
      "pos": [
        2606,
        2701
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Parameters",
      "pos": [
        2710,
        2720
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A webhook can define values for runbook parameters that are used when the runbook is started by that webhook.",
      "pos": [
        2721,
        2830
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The webhook must include values for any mandatory parameters of the runbook and may include values for optional parameters.",
      "pos": [
        2831,
        2954
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Multiple webhooks linked to a single runbook can each use different parameter values.",
      "pos": [
        2956,
        3041
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When a client starts a runbook using a webhook, it cannot override the parameter values defined in the webhook.",
      "pos": [
        3043,
        3154
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To receive data from the client, the runbook can accept a single parameter called <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>$WebhookData<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> of type [object] that will contain data that the client includes in the POST request.",
      "pos": [
        3156,
        3340
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Webhookdata",
      "pos": [
        3345,
        3356
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3402,
        3465
      ],
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>$WebhookData<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> object will have the following properties:"
    },
    {
      "content": "Property",
      "pos": [
        3469,
        3477
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        3480,
        3491
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "WebhookName",
      "pos": [
        3509,
        3520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name of the webhook.",
      "pos": [
        3523,
        3547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RequestHeader",
      "pos": [
        3553,
        3566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Hash table containing the headers of the incoming POST request.",
      "pos": [
        3569,
        3632
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RequestBody",
      "pos": [
        3637,
        3648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The body of the incoming POST request.",
      "pos": [
        3651,
        3689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will retain any formatting such as string, JSON, XML, or form encoded data.",
      "pos": [
        3691,
        3771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The runbook must be written to work with the data format that is expected.",
      "pos": [
        3772,
        3846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There is no configuration of the webhook required to support the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>$WebhookData<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> parameter, and the runbook is not required to accept it.",
      "pos": [
        3850,
        3988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the runbook does not define the parameter, then any details of the request sent from the client is ignored.",
      "pos": [
        3990,
        4100
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you specify a value for $WebhookData when you create the webhook, that value will be overriden when the webhook starts the runbook with the data from the client POST request, even if the client does not include any data in the request body.",
      "pos": [
        4102,
        4345
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you start a runbook that has $WebhookData using a method other than a webhook, you can provide a value for $Webhookdata that will be recognized by the runbook.",
      "pos": [
        4347,
        4509
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This value should be an object with the same properties as $Webhookdata so that the runbook can properly work with it.",
      "pos": [
        4511,
        4629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> The values of all input parameters are logged with the runbook job.",
      "pos": [
        4632,
        4712
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means that any input provided by the client in the webhook request will be logged and available to anyone with access to the automation job.",
      "pos": [
        4714,
        4859
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For this reason, you should be cautious about including sensitive information in webhook calls.",
      "pos": [
        4861,
        4956
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Security",
      "pos": [
        4961,
        4969
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The security of a webhook relies on the privacy of its URL which contains a security token that allows it to be invoked.",
      "pos": [
        4971,
        5091
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Automation does not perform any authentication on the request as long as it is made to the correct URL.",
      "pos": [
        5092,
        5201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For this reason, webhooks should not be used for runbooks that perform highly sensitive functions without using an alternate means of validating the request.",
      "pos": [
        5202,
        5359
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can include logic within the runbook to determine that it was called by a webhook by checking the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WebhookName<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property of the $WebhookData parameter.",
      "pos": [
        5361,
        5518
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The runbook could perform further validation by looking for particular information in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>RequestHeader<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>RequestBody<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> properties.",
      "pos": [
        5519,
        5657
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Another strategy is to have the runbook perform some validation of an external condition when it received a webhook request.",
      "pos": [
        5659,
        5783
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, consider a runbook that is called by GitHub whenever there is a new commit to a GitHub repository.",
      "pos": [
        5785,
        5896
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The runbook might connect to GitHub to validate that a new commit had actually just occurred before continuing.",
      "pos": [
        5898,
        6009
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating a webhook",
      "pos": [
        6014,
        6032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following procedure to create a new webhook linked to a runbook in the Azure preview portal.",
      "pos": [
        6034,
        6134
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6139,
        6267
      ],
      "content": "From the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Runbooks blade<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the Azure preview portal, click the runbook that the webhook will start to view its detail blade."
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Webhook<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the top of the blade to open the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add Webhook<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> blade.",
      "pos": [
        6272,
        6348
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Webhooks button<ph id=\"ph2\">](media/automation-webhooks/webhooks-button.png)</ph>",
      "pos": [
        6354,
        6419
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        6423,
        6489
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create new webhook<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to open the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Create webhook blade<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Specify a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Expiration Date<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> for the webhook and whether it should be enabled.",
      "pos": [
        6493,
        6582
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Details of a webhook<ept id=\"p1\">](#details-of-a-webhook)</ept> for more information these properties.",
      "pos": [
        6583,
        6671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click the copy icon and press Ctrl+C to copy the URL of the webhook.",
      "pos": [
        6675,
        6743
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then record it in a safe place.",
      "pos": [
        6745,
        6776
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Once you create the webhook, you cannot retrieve the URL again.",
      "pos": [
        6780,
        6843
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Webhook URL<ph id=\"ph2\">](media/automation-webhooks/copy-webhook-url.png)</ph>",
      "pos": [
        6851,
        6913
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to provide values for the runbook parameters.",
      "pos": [
        6917,
        6983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the runbook has mandatory parameters, then you will not be able to create the webhook unless values are provided.",
      "pos": [
        6985,
        7101
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7105,
        7144
      ],
      "content": "Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to create the webhook."
    },
    {
      "content": "Using a webhook",
      "pos": [
        7150,
        7165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To use a webhook after it has been created, your client application must issue an HTTP POST with the URL for the webhook.",
      "pos": [
        7167,
        7288
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The syntax of the webhook will be in the following format.",
      "pos": [
        7290,
        7348
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The client will receive one of the following return codes from the POST request.",
      "pos": [
        7400,
        7480
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Code",
      "pos": [
        7486,
        7490
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Text",
      "pos": [
        7493,
        7497
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Description",
      "pos": [
        7500,
        7511
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "202",
      "pos": [
        7534,
        7537
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Accepted",
      "pos": [
        7540,
        7548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The request was accepted, and the runbook was successfully queued.",
      "pos": [
        7551,
        7617
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "400",
      "pos": [
        7622,
        7625
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Bad Request",
      "pos": [
        7628,
        7639
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The request was not accepted for one of the following reasons.",
      "pos": [
        7642,
        7704
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The webhook has expired.",
      "pos": [
        7714,
        7738
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The webhook is disabled.",
      "pos": [
        7748,
        7772
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The token in the URL is invalid.",
      "pos": [
        7782,
        7814
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "404",
      "pos": [
        7830,
        7833
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Not Found",
      "pos": [
        7836,
        7845
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The request was not accepted for one of the following reasons.",
      "pos": [
        7849,
        7911
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The webhook was not found.",
      "pos": [
        7921,
        7947
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The runbook was not found.",
      "pos": [
        7957,
        7983
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The account was not found.",
      "pos": [
        7993,
        8019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "500",
      "pos": [
        8036,
        8039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Internal Server Error",
      "pos": [
        8042,
        8063
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The URL was valid, but an error occurred.",
      "pos": [
        8066,
        8107
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Please resubmit the request.",
      "pos": [
        8109,
        8137
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Assuming the request is successful, the webhook response contains the job id in JSON format as follows.",
      "pos": [
        8142,
        8245
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It will contain a single job id, but the JSON format allows for potential future enhancements.",
      "pos": [
        8246,
        8340
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The client cannot determine when the runbook job completes or its completion status from the webhook.",
      "pos": [
        8372,
        8473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It can determine this information using the job id with another method such as <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Windows PowerShell<ept id=\"p1\">](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn690263.aspx)</ept> or the <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Azure Automation API<ept id=\"p2\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/mt163826.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8475,
        8716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Example",
      "pos": [
        8722,
        8729
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following example uses Windows PowerShell to start a runbook with a webhook.",
      "pos": [
        8731,
        8811
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that any language that can make an HTTP request can use a webhook; Windows PowerShell is just used here as an example.",
      "pos": [
        8813,
        8936
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The runbook is expecting a list of virtual machines formatted in JSON in the body of the request.",
      "pos": [
        8938,
        9035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "We also are including information about who is starting the runbook and the date and time it is being started in the header of the request.",
      "pos": [
        9036,
        9175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following image shows the header information (using a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Fiddler<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.telerik.com/fiddler)</ept> trace) from this request.",
      "pos": [
        9687,
        9812
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This includes standard headers of an HTTP request in addition to the custom Date and From headers that we added.",
      "pos": [
        9813,
        9925
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each of these values is available to the runbook in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>RequestHeaders<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property of <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>WebhookData<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        9927,
        10030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Webhooks button",
      "pos": [
        10035,
        10050
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following image shows the body of the request (using a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Fiddler<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.telerik.com/fiddler)</ept> trace)  that is available to the runbook in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>RequestBody<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> property of <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>WebhookData<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        10108,
        10301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is formatted as JSON because that was the format that was included in the body of the request.",
      "pos": [
        10302,
        10401
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Webhooks button",
      "pos": [
        10410,
        10425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following image shows the request being sent from Windows PowerShell and the resulting response.",
      "pos": [
        10480,
        10580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The job id is extracted from the response and converted to a string.",
      "pos": [
        10582,
        10650
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Webhooks button",
      "pos": [
        10654,
        10669
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following sample runbook accepts the previous example request and starts the virtual machines specified in the request body.",
      "pos": [
        10728,
        10856
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Related articles",
      "pos": [
        12159,
        12175
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Starting a Runbook",
      "pos": [
        12180,
        12198
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Viewing the Status of a Runbook Job<ept id=\"p1\">](automation-viewing-the-status-of-a-runbook-job.md)</ept>",
      "pos": [
        12236,
        12324
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        12326,
        12330
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n   pageTitle=\"Azure Automation webhooks\"\n   description=\"A webhook that allows a client to start a runbook in Azure Automation from an HTTP call.  This article describes how to create a webhook and how to call one to start a runbook.\"\n   services=\"automation\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"bwren\"\n   manager=\"stevenka\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags \n   ms.service=\"automation\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"08/04/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"bwren\" />\n\n# Azure Automation webhooks\n\nA *webhook* allows you to start a particular runbook in Azure Automation through a single HTTP request. This allows external services such as Visual Studio Online, GitHub, or custom applications to start runbooks without implementing a full solution using the Azure Automation API.\n\n![Webhooks](media/automation-webhooks/webhooks-overview.png)\n\nYou can compare webhooks to other methods of starting a runbook in [Starting a runbook in Azure Automation](automation-starting-a-runbook.md)\n\n## Details of a webhook\n\nThe following table describes the properties that you must configure for a webhook.\n\n| Property | Description |\n|:---|:---|\n|Name | You can provide any name you want for a webhook since this is not exposed to the client.  It is only used for you to identify the runbook in Azure Automation. <br>  As a best practice, you should give the webhook a name related to the client that will use it. |\n|URL |The URL of the webhook is the unique address that a client calls with an HTTP POST to start the runbook linked to the webhook.  It is automatically generated when you create the webhook.  You cannot specify a custom URL. <br> <br>  The URL contains a security token that allows the runbook to be invoked by a third party system with no further authentication. For this reason, it should be treated like a password.  For security reasons, you can only view the URL in the Azure preview portal at the time the webhook is created. You should note the URL in a secure location for future use.   |\n|Expiration date | Like a certificate, each webhook has an expiration date at which time it can no longer be used.  This expiration date cannot be changed after the webhook is created, and the webhook also cannot be enabled again after the expiration date is reached.  In this case, you must create another webhook to replace the current one and update the client to use the new webhook. |\n| Enabled | A webhook is enabled by default when it is created.  If you set it to Disabled, then no client will be able to use it.  You can set the **Enabled** property when you create the webhook or anytime once it is created. |\n\n\n### Parameters\nA webhook can define values for runbook parameters that are used when the runbook is started by that webhook. The webhook must include values for any mandatory parameters of the runbook and may include values for optional parameters.  Multiple webhooks linked to a single runbook can each use different parameter values.\n\nWhen a client starts a runbook using a webhook, it cannot override the parameter values defined in the webhook.  To receive data from the client, the runbook can accept a single parameter called **$WebhookData** of type [object] that will contain data that the client includes in the POST request. \n\n![Webhookdata](media/automation-webhooks/webhookdata.png)\n\nThe **$WebhookData** object will have the following properties:\n\n| Property | Description |\n|:--- |:---|\n| WebhookName | The name of the webhook.  |\n| RequestHeader | Hash table containing the headers of the incoming POST request. |\n| RequestBody | The body of the incoming POST request.  This will retain any formatting such as string, JSON, XML, or form encoded data. The runbook must be written to work with the data format that is expected.|\n\n\nThere is no configuration of the webhook required to support the **$WebhookData** parameter, and the runbook is not required to accept it.  If the runbook does not define the parameter, then any details of the request sent from the client is ignored.\n\nIf you specify a value for $WebhookData when you create the webhook, that value will be overriden when the webhook starts the runbook with the data from the client POST request, even if the client does not include any data in the request body.  If you start a runbook that has $WebhookData using a method other than a webhook, you can provide a value for $Webhookdata that will be recognized by the runbook.  This value should be an object with the same properties as $Webhookdata so that the runbook can properly work with it.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] The values of all input parameters are logged with the runbook job.  This means that any input provided by the client in the webhook request will be logged and available to anyone with access to the automation job.  For this reason, you should be cautious about including sensitive information in webhook calls.\n\n## Security\n\nThe security of a webhook relies on the privacy of its URL which contains a security token that allows it to be invoked. Azure Automation does not perform any authentication on the request as long as it is made to the correct URL. For this reason, webhooks should not be used for runbooks that perform highly sensitive functions without using an alternate means of validating the request.\n\nYou can include logic within the runbook to determine that it was called by a webhook by checking the **WebhookName** property of the $WebhookData parameter. The runbook could perform further validation by looking for particular information in the **RequestHeader** or **RequestBody** properties.\n\nAnother strategy is to have the runbook perform some validation of an external condition when it received a webhook request.  For example, consider a runbook that is called by GitHub whenever there is a new commit to a GitHub repository.  The runbook might connect to GitHub to validate that a new commit had actually just occurred before continuing.\n\n## Creating a webhook\n\nUse the following procedure to create a new webhook linked to a runbook in the Azure preview portal.\n\n1. From the **Runbooks blade** in the Azure preview portal, click the runbook that the webhook will start to view its detail blade. \n3. Click **Webhook** at the top of the blade to open the **Add Webhook** blade. <br>\n![Webhooks button](media/automation-webhooks/webhooks-button.png)\n4. Click **Create new webhook** to open the **Create webhook blade**.\n5. Specify a **Name**, **Expiration Date** for the webhook and whether it should be enabled. See [Details of a webhook](#details-of-a-webhook) for more information these properties.\n6. Click the copy icon and press Ctrl+C to copy the URL of the webhook.  Then record it in a safe place.  **Once you create the webhook, you cannot retrieve the URL again.** <br>\n![Webhook URL](media/automation-webhooks/copy-webhook-url.png)\n3. Click **Parameters** to provide values for the runbook parameters.  If the runbook has mandatory parameters, then you will not be able to create the webhook unless values are provided.\n1. Click **Create** to create the webhook.\n\n\n## Using a webhook\n\nTo use a webhook after it has been created, your client application must issue an HTTP POST with the URL for the webhook.  The syntax of the webhook will be in the following format.\n\n    http://<Webhook Server>/token?=<Token Value>\n\nThe client will receive one of the following return codes from the POST request.  \n\n| Code | Text | Description |\n|:---|:----|:---|\n| 202 | Accepted | The request was accepted, and the runbook was successfully queued. |\n| 400 | Bad Request | The request was not accepted for one of the following reasons. <ul> <li>The webhook has expired.</li> <li>The webhook is disabled.</li> <li>The token in the URL is invalid.</li>  </ul>|\n| 404 | Not Found |  The request was not accepted for one of the following reasons. <ul> <li>The webhook was not found.</li> <li>The runbook was not found.</li> <li>The account was not found.</li>  </ul> |\n| 500 | Internal Server Error | The URL was valid, but an error occurred.  Please resubmit the request.  |\n\nAssuming the request is successful, the webhook response contains the job id in JSON format as follows. It will contain a single job id, but the JSON format allows for potential future enhancements.\n\n    {\"JobIds\":[\"<JobId>\"]}  \n\nThe client cannot determine when the runbook job completes or its completion status from the webhook.  It can determine this information using the job id with another method such as [Windows PowerShell](http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn690263.aspx) or the [Azure Automation API](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/mt163826.aspx).\n\n### Example\n\nThe following example uses Windows PowerShell to start a runbook with a webhook.  Note that any language that can make an HTTP request can use a webhook; Windows PowerShell is just used here as an example.\n\nThe runbook is expecting a list of virtual machines formatted in JSON in the body of the request. We also are including information about who is starting the runbook and the date and time it is being started in the header of the request.      \n\n    $uri = \"https://s1events.azure-automation.net/webhooks?token=8ud0dSrSo%2fvHWpYbklW%3c8s0GrOKJZ9Nr7zqcS%2bIQr4c%3d\"\n    $headers = @{\"From\"=\"user@contoso.com\";\"Date\"=\"05/28/2015 15:47:00\"}\n    \n    $vms  = @([pscustomobject]@{Name=\"vm01\";ServiceName=\"vm01\"})\n    $vms += @([pscustomobject]@{Name=\"vm02\";ServiceName=\"vm02\"})\n    $body = ConvertTo-Json -InputObject $vms \n\n    $response = Invoke-RestMethod -Method Post -Uri $uri -Headers $headers -Body $body\n    $jobid = ConvertFrom-Json $response \n\n\nThe following image shows the header information (using a [Fiddler](http://www.telerik.com/fiddler) trace) from this request. This includes standard headers of an HTTP request in addition to the custom Date and From headers that we added.  Each of these values is available to the runbook in the **RequestHeaders** property of **WebhookData**. \n\n![Webhooks button](media/automation-webhooks/webhook-request-headers.png)\n\nThe following image shows the body of the request (using a [Fiddler](http://www.telerik.com/fiddler) trace)  that is available to the runbook in the **RequestBody** property of **WebhookData**. This is formatted as JSON because that was the format that was included in the body of the request.     \n\n![Webhooks button](media/automation-webhooks/webhook-request-body.png)\n\nThe following image shows the request being sent from Windows PowerShell and the resulting response.  The job id is extracted from the response and converted to a string.\n\n![Webhooks button](media/automation-webhooks/webhook-request-response.png)\n\nThe following sample runbook accepts the previous example request and starts the virtual machines specified in the request body.\n\n    workflow Test-StartVirtualMachinesFromWebhook\n    {\n        param ( \n            [object]$WebhookData\n        )\n\n        # If runbook was called from Webhook, WebhookData will not be null.\n        if ($WebhookData -ne $null) {   \n            \n            # Collect properties of WebhookData\n            $WebhookName    =   $WebhookData.WebhookName\n            $WebhookHeaders =   $WebhookData.RequestHeader\n            $WebhookBody    =   $WebhookData.RequestBody\n            \n            # Collect individual headers. VMList converted from JSON.\n            $From = $WebhookHeaders.From\n            $VMList = (ConvertFrom-Json -InputObject $WebhookBody).VirtualMachines\n            Write-Output \"Runbook started from webhook $WebhookName by $From.\"\n            \n            # Authenticate to Azure resources\n            $Cred = Get-AutomationPSCredential -Name 'MyAzureCredential'\n            Add-AzureAccount -Credential $Cred\n            \n            # Start each virtual machine\n            foreach ($VM in $VMList)\n            {\n                Write-Output \"Starting $VM.Name.\"\n                Start-AzureVM -Name $VM.Name -ServiceName $VM.ServiceName\n            }\n        }\n        else {\n            Write-Error \"Runbook mean to be started only from webhook.\" \n        } \n    }\n\n    \n\n## Related articles\n\n- [Starting a Runbook](automation-starting-a-runbook.md)\n- [Viewing the Status of a Runbook Job](automation-viewing-the-status-of-a-runbook-job.md) \ntest\n"
}