{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Azure SQL Database Resource Limits",
      "pos": [
        27,
        61
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This page describes some common resource limits for Azure SQL Database.",
      "pos": [
        80,
        151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure SQL Database resource limits",
      "pos": [
        470,
        504
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Overview",
      "pos": [
        509,
        517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure SQL Database manages the resources available to a database using two different mechanisms: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Resources Governance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Enforcement of Limits<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        519,
        671
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic explains these two main areas of resource management.",
      "pos": [
        672,
        736
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource governance",
      "pos": [
        741,
        760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "One of the design goals of the Basic, Standard, and Premium service tiers is for Azure SQL Database to behave as if the database is running on its own machine, completely isolated from other databases.",
      "pos": [
        761,
        962
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resource governance emulates this behavior.",
      "pos": [
        963,
        1006
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the aggregated resource utilization reaches the maximum available CPU, Memory, Log I/O, and Data I/O resources assigned to the database, resource governance will queue queries in execution and assign resources to the queued queries as they free up.",
      "pos": [
        1007,
        1258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As on a dedicated machine, utilizing all available resources will result in a longer execution of currently executing queries, which can result in command timeouts on the client.",
      "pos": [
        1260,
        1438
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Applications with aggressive retry logic and applications that execute queries against the database with a high frequency can encounter errors messages when trying to execute new queries when the limit of concurrent requests has been reached.",
      "pos": [
        1439,
        1681
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Recommendations:",
      "pos": [
        1687,
        1703
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Monitor the resource utilization as well as the average response times of queries when nearing the maximum utilization of a database.",
      "pos": [
        1704,
        1837
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When encountering higher query latencies you generally have three options:",
      "pos": [
        1838,
        1912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Reduce the amount of incoming requests to the database to prevent timeout and the pile up of requests.",
      "pos": [
        1918,
        2020
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Assign a higher performance level to the database.",
      "pos": [
        2026,
        2076
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Optimize queries to reduce the resource utilization of each query.",
      "pos": [
        2082,
        2148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see the Query Tuning/Hinting section in the Azure SQL Database Performance Guidance article.",
      "pos": [
        2149,
        2263
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Enforcement of limits",
      "pos": [
        2268,
        2289
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Resources other than CPU, Memory, Log I/O, and Data I/O are enforced by denying new requests when limits are reached.",
      "pos": [
        2290,
        2407
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Clients will receive an <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>error message<ept id=\"p1\">](sql-database-develop-error-messages.md)</ept> depending on the limit that has been reached.",
      "pos": [
        2408,
        2533
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, the number of connections to a SQL database as well as the number of concurrent requests that can be processed are restricted.",
      "pos": [
        2535,
        2674
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Database allows the number of connections to the database to be greater than the number of concurrent requests to support connection pooling.",
      "pos": [
        2675,
        2820
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "While the amount of connections that are available can easily be controlled by the application, the amount of parallel requests is often times harder to estimate and to control.",
      "pos": [
        2821,
        2998
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Especially during peak loads when the application either sends too many requests or the database reaches its resource limits and starts piling up worker threads due to longer running queries, errors can be encountered.",
      "pos": [
        2999,
        3217
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Service tiers and performance levels",
      "pos": [
        3223,
        3259
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The actual limits of a database are defined by the performance level of the database.",
      "pos": [
        3261,
        3346
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For a detailed explanation, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure SQL Database Service Tiers and Performance Levels<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn741336.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3347,
        3493
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Database provisioning quota",
      "pos": [
        3596,
        3623
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure SQL Database has a DTU quota per logical server of currently 2000 DTUs.",
      "pos": [
        3625,
        3702
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This quota represents the DTUs a logical server can host, based on the sum of the DTUs if the performance level of each database on the server.",
      "pos": [
        3703,
        3846
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, a server with 5 Basic databases (5 X 5 DTUs maximum), 2 Standard S1 databases (2 X 20 DTUs maximum), and 3 Premium P1 databases (3 X 100 DTUs maximum) has consumed 365 DTUs of its 2000 DTU quota.",
      "pos": [
        3847,
        4055
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4058,
        4220
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.NOTE]</ph> You can request an increase of this quota by <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>contacting support<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/blog/2014/06/04/azure-limits-quotas-increase-requests/)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "Resources",
      "pos": [
        4225,
        4234
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Subscription and Service Limits, Quotas, and Constraints",
      "pos": [
        4237,
        4299
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure SQL Database Service Tiers and Performance Levels",
      "pos": [
        4344,
        4399
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Error messages for SQL Database client programs",
      "pos": [
        4459,
        4506
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"Azure SQL Database Resource Limits\"\n    description=\"This page describes some common resource limits for Azure SQL Database.\"\n    services=\"sql-database\"\n    documentationCenter=\"na\"\n    authors=\"rothja\"\n    manager=\"jeffreyg\"\n    editor=\"monicar\" />\n\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"sql-database\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.workload=\"data-management\"\n    ms.date=\"08/28/2015\"\n    ms.author=\"jroth\" />\n\n\n# Azure SQL Database resource limits\n\n## Overview\n\nAzure SQL Database manages the resources available to a database using two different mechanisms: **Resources Governance** and **Enforcement of Limits**. This topic explains these two main areas of resource management.\n\n## Resource governance\nOne of the design goals of the Basic, Standard, and Premium service tiers is for Azure SQL Database to behave as if the database is running on its own machine, completely isolated from other databases. Resource governance emulates this behavior. If the aggregated resource utilization reaches the maximum available CPU, Memory, Log I/O, and Data I/O resources assigned to the database, resource governance will queue queries in execution and assign resources to the queued queries as they free up.\n\nAs on a dedicated machine, utilizing all available resources will result in a longer execution of currently executing queries, which can result in command timeouts on the client. Applications with aggressive retry logic and applications that execute queries against the database with a high frequency can encounter errors messages when trying to execute new queries when the limit of concurrent requests has been reached.\n\n### Recommendations:\nMonitor the resource utilization as well as the average response times of queries when nearing the maximum utilization of a database. When encountering higher query latencies you generally have three options:\n\n1.  Reduce the amount of incoming requests to the database to prevent timeout and the pile up of requests.\n\n2.  Assign a higher performance level to the database.\n\n3.  Optimize queries to reduce the resource utilization of each query. For more information, see the Query Tuning/Hinting section in the Azure SQL Database Performance Guidance article.\n\n## Enforcement of limits\nResources other than CPU, Memory, Log I/O, and Data I/O are enforced by denying new requests when limits are reached. Clients will receive an [error message](sql-database-develop-error-messages.md) depending on the limit that has been reached.\n\nFor example, the number of connections to a SQL database as well as the number of concurrent requests that can be processed are restricted. SQL Database allows the number of connections to the database to be greater than the number of concurrent requests to support connection pooling. While the amount of connections that are available can easily be controlled by the application, the amount of parallel requests is often times harder to estimate and to control. Especially during peak loads when the application either sends too many requests or the database reaches its resource limits and starts piling up worker threads due to longer running queries, errors can be encountered. \n\n## Service tiers and performance levels\n\nThe actual limits of a database are defined by the performance level of the database. For a detailed explanation, see [Azure SQL Database Service Tiers and Performance Levels](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn741336.aspx).\n\n[AZURE.INCLUDE [SQL DB service tiers table](../../includes/sql-database-service-tiers-table.md)]\n\n## Database provisioning quota\n\nAzure SQL Database has a DTU quota per logical server of currently 2000 DTUs. This quota represents the DTUs a logical server can host, based on the sum of the DTUs if the performance level of each database on the server. For example, a server with 5 Basic databases (5 X 5 DTUs maximum), 2 Standard S1 databases (2 X 20 DTUs maximum), and 3 Premium P1 databases (3 X 100 DTUs maximum) has consumed 365 DTUs of its 2000 DTU quota.\n\n>[AZURE.NOTE] You can request an increase of this quota by [contacting support](http://azure.microsoft.com/blog/2014/06/04/azure-limits-quotas-increase-requests/).\n\n## Resources\n\n[Azure Subscription and Service Limits, Quotas, and Constraints](../azure-subscription-service-limits.md)\n\n[Azure SQL Database Service Tiers and Performance Levels](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn741336.aspx)\n\n[Error messages for SQL Database client programs](sql-database-develop-error-messages.md)"
}