{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "What is SQL Database",
      "pos": [
        26,
        46
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Discover the technical details and capabilities of Azure SQL Database, Microsoft's relational database management system (RDBMS) and PaaS solution in the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        64,
        224
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Database Overview",
      "pos": [
        530,
        551
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Database is a relational database service in the cloud based on the Microsoft SQL Server engine, with built-in, mission-critical capabilities.",
      "pos": [
        553,
        699
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Database delivers predictable performance, scalability, business continuity, data protection, and near-zero administration to cloud developers and solution architects.",
      "pos": [
        700,
        871
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Best of all, SQL Database supports existing SQL Server tools, libraries and APIs, making it easy for you to move to the cloud.",
      "pos": [
        872,
        998
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can get a SQL Database <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>up and running within seconds<ept id=\"p1\">](sql-database-get-started.md)</ept>, without having to manage virtual machines or infrastructure.",
      "pos": [
        999,
        1148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The programmatic DBA-like functionality enables efficient DevOps, and self-management ensures near-zero maintenance for the databases.",
      "pos": [
        1149,
        1283
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This allows you to focus on developing and managing your application.",
      "pos": [
        1284,
        1353
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1355,
        1885
      ],
      "content": "SQL Database allows you to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>scale up<ept id=\"p1\">](sql-database-service-tiers.md)</ept> single databases with no downtime and predictable performance that can be dialed up or down as needed, while you can choose <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>elastic databases<ept id=\"p2\">](sql-database-elastic-pool.md)</ept> to scale out to thousands of databases within a budget that you control, leveraging the powerful manageability features of <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>elastic database jobs<ept id=\"p3\">](sql-database-elastic-jobs-overview.md)</ept> and the programmatic features of <bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>elastic database tools<ept id=\"p4\">](sql-database-elastic-scale-get-started.md)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "An industry leading 99.99% availability <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SLA<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/support/legal/sla/)</ept> helps ensure your applications face near-zero downtime.",
      "pos": [
        1887,
        2035
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The built-in data protection via auditing, restore, and geo-replication helps ensure your data is protected.",
      "pos": [
        2036,
        2144
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Database provides you with the ability to restore your data to any point-in-time from any transaction up to 35 days.",
      "pos": [
        2145,
        2265
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can also replicate your data to an Azure region of your choice and easily implement a geographic disaster recovery policy designed for your business needs.",
      "pos": [
        2266,
        2425
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>latest version of SQL Database<ept id=\"p1\">](sql-database-preview-whats-new.md)</ept>, V12, provides nearly complete compatibility with the SQL Server engine.",
      "pos": [
        2426,
        2570
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SQL Database is available in Basic, Standard, and Premium <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>service tiers<ept id=\"p1\">](sql-database-service-tiers.md)</ept> which support light-weight to heavy-weight database workloads, so you can move across or blend the tiers together for innovative application designs.",
      "pos": [
        2572,
        2826
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With the power and reach of Azure, you can mix-and-match Azure services with SQL Database to meet your unique modern app design needs, drive cost and resource efficiencies, and unlock new business opportunities.",
      "pos": [
        2827,
        3038
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3040,
        3213
      ],
      "content": "Get started with a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>free trial<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/)</ept> and then <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>create your first SQL database<ept id=\"p2\">](sql-database-get-started.md)</ept> in just a few minutes."
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"What is SQL Database\"\n   description=\"Discover the technical details and capabilities of Azure SQL Database, Microsoft's relational database management system (RDBMS) and PaaS solution in the cloud.\"\n   services=\"sql-database\"\n   documentationCenter=\"\"\n   authors=\"shontnew\"\n   manager=\"jeffreyg\"\n   editor=\"monicar\"/>\n\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"sql-database\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"data-management\"\n   ms.date=\"07/17/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"shkurhek\"/>\n\n# SQL Database Overview\n\nSQL Database is a relational database service in the cloud based on the Microsoft SQL Server engine, with built-in, mission-critical capabilities. SQL Database delivers predictable performance, scalability, business continuity, data protection, and near-zero administration to cloud developers and solution architects. Best of all, SQL Database supports existing SQL Server tools, libraries and APIs, making it easy for you to move to the cloud. You can get a SQL Database [up and running within seconds](sql-database-get-started.md), without having to manage virtual machines or infrastructure. The programmatic DBA-like functionality enables efficient DevOps, and self-management ensures near-zero maintenance for the databases. This allows you to focus on developing and managing your application.\n\nSQL Database allows you to [scale up](sql-database-service-tiers.md) single databases with no downtime and predictable performance that can be dialed up or down as needed, while you can choose [elastic databases](sql-database-elastic-pool.md) to scale out to thousands of databases within a budget that you control, leveraging the powerful manageability features of [elastic database jobs](sql-database-elastic-jobs-overview.md) and the programmatic features of [elastic database tools](sql-database-elastic-scale-get-started.md).\n\nAn industry leading 99.99% availability [SLA](http://azure.microsoft.com/support/legal/sla/) helps ensure your applications face near-zero downtime. The built-in data protection via auditing, restore, and geo-replication helps ensure your data is protected. SQL Database provides you with the ability to restore your data to any point-in-time from any transaction up to 35 days. You can also replicate your data to an Azure region of your choice and easily implement a geographic disaster recovery policy designed for your business needs. The [latest version of SQL Database](sql-database-preview-whats-new.md), V12, provides nearly complete compatibility with the SQL Server engine.\n\nSQL Database is available in Basic, Standard, and Premium [service tiers](sql-database-service-tiers.md) which support light-weight to heavy-weight database workloads, so you can move across or blend the tiers together for innovative application designs. With the power and reach of Azure, you can mix-and-match Azure services with SQL Database to meet your unique modern app design needs, drive cost and resource efficiencies, and unlock new business opportunities.\n\nGet started with a [free trial](http://azure.microsoft.com/pricing/free-trial/) and then [create your first SQL database](sql-database-get-started.md) in just a few minutes.\n "
}