{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Configure Expressroute and Site-to-Site VPN connections that can coexist | Microsoft Azure",
      "pos": [
        26,
        116
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This tutorial walks you through configuring ExpressRoute and a Site-to-Site VPN connection that can coexist.",
      "pos": [
        134,
        242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure Azure ExpressRoute and Site-to-Site VPN connections that coexist",
      "pos": [
        567,
        641
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can now connect ExpressRoute and Site-to-Site VPN to the same virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        643,
        725
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two different scenarios and two different configuration procedures to choose from.",
      "pos": [
        726,
        818
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scenarios",
      "pos": [
        823,
        832
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scenario 1",
      "pos": [
        838,
        848
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this scenario, you have one local network.",
      "pos": [
        850,
        895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "ExpressRoute is the active link, and your Site-to-Site VPN is the backup.",
      "pos": [
        896,
        969
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If the ExpressRoute connection fails, the Site-to-Site VPN connection would then become active.",
      "pos": [
        970,
        1065
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This scenario is most appropriate for high availability.",
      "pos": [
        1066,
        1122
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Coexist",
      "pos": [
        1126,
        1133
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scenario 2",
      "pos": [
        1184,
        1194
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this scenario, you have two local networks.",
      "pos": [
        1196,
        1242
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can connect one to Azure via ExpressRoute, and the other via Site-to-Site VPN.",
      "pos": [
        1243,
        1325
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, both connections are active at the same time.",
      "pos": [
        1326,
        1385
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Coexist",
      "pos": [
        1389,
        1396
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Creating and configuring",
      "pos": [
        1445,
        1469
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two different sets of procedures to choose from in order to configure your connections to coexist.",
      "pos": [
        1471,
        1579
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The configuration procedure that you select will depend on whether you have an existing virtual network that you want to connect to, or you want to create a new virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        1580,
        1757
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a new virtual network and connections that coexist:",
      "pos": [
        1763,
        1821
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you don’t already have a virtual network, this procedure will walk you through creating a new virtual network and creating new ExpressRoute and Site-to-Site VPN connections.",
      "pos": [
        1829,
        2005
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To configure, follow the steps to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create a new virtual network and connections<ept id=\"p1\">](#create-a-new-virtual-network-and-connections-that-coexist)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        2006,
        2147
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure your existing virtual network for coexisting connections:",
      "pos": [
        2153,
        2220
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You may already have a virtual network in place with an existing Site-to-Site VPN connection or ExpressRoute connection.",
      "pos": [
        2228,
        2348
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configure connections that coexist for your existing virtual network<ept id=\"p1\">](#configure-connections-that-coexist-for-your-existing-virtual-network)</ept> procedure will walk you through deleting the gateway, and then creating new ExpressRoute and Site-to-Site VPN connections.",
      "pos": [
        2349,
        2617
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that when creating the new connections, the steps must be completed in a very specific order.",
      "pos": [
        2618,
        2716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Don't use the instructions in other articles to create your gateways and connections.",
      "pos": [
        2717,
        2802
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this procedure, creating connections that can coexist will require you to delete your gateway, and then configure new gateways.",
      "pos": [
        2808,
        2938
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means you will have downtime for your cross-premises connections while you delete and recreate your gateway and connections, but you will not need to migrate any of your VMs or services to a new virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        2939,
        3155
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Your VMs and services would still be able to communicate out through the load balancer while you configure your gateway if they are configured to do so.",
      "pos": [
        3156,
        3308
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Notes and limitations",
      "pos": [
        3314,
        3335
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You won’t be able to route (via Azure) between your local network connected via Site-to-Site VPN and your local network connected via ExpressRoute.",
      "pos": [
        3339,
        3486
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can't enable Point-to-Site VPN connections to the same VNet that is connected to ExpressRoute.",
      "pos": [
        3489,
        3587
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Point-to-Site VPN and ExpressRoute cannot coexist for the same VNet.",
      "pos": [
        3588,
        3656
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both the ExpressRoute gateway and the Site-to-Site VPN gateway must be either a Standard or HighPerformance gateway SKU.",
      "pos": [
        3659,
        3779
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For information about gateway SKUs, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Gateway SKUs<ept id=\"p1\">](../vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-about-vpngateways.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        3780,
        3884
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If your local network is connected to both ExpressRoute and a Site-to-Site VPN (Scenario 1), you should have a static route configured in your local network to route the Site-to-Site VPN connection to the public Internet.",
      "pos": [
        3887,
        4108
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You must create the ExpressRoute gateway first, before you add the Site-to-Site VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        4111,
        4203
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Both procedures assume that you already have an ExpressRoute circuit configured.",
      "pos": [
        4206,
        4286
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you do not, please see the following articles:",
      "pos": [
        4287,
        4336
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure an ExpressRoute connection through a network service provider (NSP)",
      "pos": [
        4345,
        4422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure an ExpressRoute connection through an exchange provider (EXP)",
      "pos": [
        4465,
        4536
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a new virtual network and connections that coexist",
      "pos": [
        4577,
        4634
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This procedure will walk you through creating a virtual network, as well as creating Site-to-Site and ExpressRoute connections that will coexist.",
      "pos": [
        4636,
        4781
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify that you have the latest version of the PowerShell cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        4786,
        4852
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download and install the latest PowerShell cmdlets from the PowerShell section of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Download page<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/downloads/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        4853,
        5002
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a schema for your virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        5006,
        5047
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about working with the network configuration file, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configure a virtual network using a network configuration file<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-network/virtual-networks-using-network-configuration-file.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5048,
        5262
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about the configuration schema, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Virtual Network Configuration Schema<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj157100.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        5263,
        5421
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you create your schema, make sure you use the following values:",
      "pos": [
        5427,
        5495
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The gateway subnet for the virtual network must be /27 (or a shorter prefix).",
      "pos": [
        5503,
        5580
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The gateway connection type is \"Dedicated\".",
      "pos": [
        5587,
        5630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After creating and configuring your xml schema file, upload the file.",
      "pos": [
        6522,
        6591
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will create your virtual network.",
      "pos": [
        6592,
        6630
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following cmdlet to upload your file, replacing the value with your own.",
      "pos": [
        6636,
        6716
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create an ExpressRoute gateway.",
      "pos": [
        6789,
        6820
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Be sure to specify the GatewaySKU as <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>HighPerformance<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> and the GatewayType as <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>DynamicRouting<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        6821,
        6930
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following sample, substituting the values for your own.",
      "pos": [
        6936,
        6999
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Link the ExpressRoute gateway to the ExpressRoute circuit.",
      "pos": [
        7110,
        7168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After this step has been completed, the connection between your on-premises network and Azure, through ExpressRoute, is established.",
      "pos": [
        7169,
        7301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next, create your Site-to-Site VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        7391,
        7434
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The GatewaySKU must be <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Standard<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>HighPerformance<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> and the GatewayType must be <bpt id=\"p3\">*</bpt>DynamicRouting<ept id=\"p3\">*</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        7435,
        7535
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        7678,
        7820
      ],
      "content": "To retrieve the virtual network gateway settings, including the gateway ID and the public IP, use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway`</ph> cmdlet."
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a local site VPN gateway entity.",
      "pos": [
        8749,
        8788
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This command doesn’t configure your on-premises VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        8789,
        8849
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Rather, it allows you to provide the local gateway settings, such as the public IP and the on-premises address space, so that the Azure VPN gateway can connect to it.",
      "pos": [
        8850,
        9016
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">[AZURE.IMPORTANT]</ph> The local site for the site-to-site VPN is not defined in the netcfg.",
      "pos": [
        9024,
        9111
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Instead, you must use this cmdlet to specify the local site parameters.",
      "pos": [
        9112,
        9183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You cannot define it using the Management Portal or the netcfg file.",
      "pos": [
        9184,
        9252
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following sample, replacing the values with your own.",
      "pos": [
        9258,
        9319
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To retrieve the virtual network gateway settings, including the gateway ID and the public IP, use the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway`</ph> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        9479,
        9621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the following example.",
      "pos": [
        9622,
        9648
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure your local VPN device to connect to the new gateway.",
      "pos": [
        10062,
        10124
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the information that you retrieved in step 6 when configuring your VPN device.",
      "pos": [
        10125,
        10207
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about VPN device configuration, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>VPN Device Configuration<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=615099)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        10208,
        10341
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Link the Site-to-Site VPN gateway on Azure to the local gateway.",
      "pos": [
        10347,
        10411
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this example, connectedEntityId is the local gateway ID, which you can find by running <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureLocalNetworkGateway`</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        10417,
        10538
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can find virtualNetworkGatewayId by using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`Get-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway`</ph> cmdlet.",
      "pos": [
        10539,
        10629
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "After this step, the connection between your local network and Azure via the Site-to-Site VPN connection is established.",
      "pos": [
        10630,
        10750
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure connections that coexist for your existing virtual network",
      "pos": [
        10985,
        11053
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you have an existing virtual network connected via either ExpressRoute or Site-to-Site VPN connection, in order to enable both connections to connect to the existing virtual network, you must first delete the existing gateway.",
      "pos": [
        11055,
        11284
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This means your local premises will lose the connection to your virtual network over the gateway while you are working on this configuration.",
      "pos": [
        11285,
        11426
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        11428,
        11583
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Before you begin configuration:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Verify that you have enough IP addresses left in your virtual network so that you can increase the gateway subnet size."
    },
    {
      "content": "Download the latest version of the PowerShell cmdlets.",
      "pos": [
        11589,
        11643
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can download and install the latest PowerShell cmdlets from the PowerShell section of the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Download page<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/downloads/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        11644,
        11793
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Delete the existing Site-to-Site VPN gateway.",
      "pos": [
        11798,
        11843
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following cmdlet, replacing the values with your own.",
      "pos": [
        11844,
        11905
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Export the virtual network schema.",
      "pos": [
        11963,
        11997
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Use the following PowerShell cmdlet, replacing the values with your own.",
      "pos": [
        11998,
        12070
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Edit the network configuration file schema so that the gateway subnet is /27 (or a shorter prefix).",
      "pos": [
        12138,
        12237
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the following example.",
      "pos": [
        12238,
        12264
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about working with the network configuration file, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configure a Virtual Network using a network configuration file<ept id=\"p1\">](../virtual-network/virtual-networks-using-network-configuration-file.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        12265,
        12479
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information about the configuration schema, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure Virtual Network Configuration Schema<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj157100.aspx)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        12480,
        12638
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12764,
        12871
      ],
      "content": "If your previous gateway was a Site-to-Site VPN, you must also change the connection type to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dedicated<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "At this point, you'll have a VNet with no gateways.",
      "pos": [
        13184,
        13235
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can proceed with <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Step 3<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the article, <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Create a new virtual network and connections<ept id=\"p2\">](#create-a-new-virtual-network-and-connections-that-coexist)</ept>, in order to create new gateways and complete your connections.",
      "pos": [
        13236,
        13454
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        13461,
        13471
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn more about ExpressRoute.",
      "pos": [
        13473,
        13503
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ExpressRoute overview<ept id=\"p1\">](expressroute-introduction.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        13504,
        13566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn more about VPN Gateways.",
      "pos": [
        13568,
        13598
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>About VPN Gateways<ept id=\"p1\">](../vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-about-vpngateways.md)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        13599,
        13673
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        13675,
        13679
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n   pageTitle=\"Configure Expressroute and Site-to-Site VPN connections that can coexist | Microsoft Azure\"\n   description=\"This tutorial walks you through configuring ExpressRoute and a Site-to-Site VPN connection that can coexist.\"\n   documentationCenter=\"na\"\n   services=\"expressroute\"\n   authors=\"cherylmc\"\n   manager=\"carolz\"\n   editor=\"tysonn\" />\n<tags\n   ms.service=\"expressroute\"\n   ms.devlang=\"na\"\n   ms.topic=\"get-started-article\"\n   ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n   ms.workload=\"infrastructure-services\"\n   ms.date=\"08/05/2015\"\n   ms.author=\"cherylmc\"/>\n\n# Configure Azure ExpressRoute and Site-to-Site VPN connections that coexist\n\nYou can now connect ExpressRoute and Site-to-Site VPN to the same virtual network.\nThere are two different scenarios and two different configuration procedures to choose from.\n\n## Scenarios\n\n### Scenario 1\n\nIn this scenario, you have one local network. ExpressRoute is the active link, and your Site-to-Site VPN is the backup. If the ExpressRoute connection fails, the Site-to-Site VPN connection would then become active. This scenario is most appropriate for high availability.\n\n![Coexist](media/expressroute-coexist/scenario1.jpg)\n\n\n\n### Scenario 2\n\nIn this scenario, you have two local networks. You can connect one to Azure via ExpressRoute, and the other via Site-to-Site VPN. In this case, both connections are active at the same time.\n\n![Coexist](media/expressroute-coexist/scenario2.jpg)\n\n\n## Creating and configuring\n\nThere are two different sets of procedures to choose from in order to configure your connections to coexist. The configuration procedure that you select will depend on whether you have an existing virtual network that you want to connect to, or you want to create a new virtual network.\n\n- **Create a new virtual network and connections that coexist:**\n\n    If you don’t already have a virtual network, this procedure will walk you through creating a new virtual network and creating new ExpressRoute and Site-to-Site VPN connections. To configure, follow the steps to [Create a new virtual network and connections](#create-a-new-virtual-network-and-connections-that-coexist).\n\n- **Configure your existing virtual network for coexisting connections:**\n\n    You may already have a virtual network in place with an existing Site-to-Site VPN connection or ExpressRoute connection. The [Configure connections that coexist for your existing virtual network](#configure-connections-that-coexist-for-your-existing-virtual-network) procedure will walk you through deleting the gateway, and then creating new ExpressRoute and Site-to-Site VPN connections. Note that when creating the new connections, the steps must be completed in a very specific order. Don't use the instructions in other articles to create your gateways and connections.\n\n    In this procedure, creating connections that can coexist will require you to delete your gateway, and then configure new gateways. This means you will have downtime for your cross-premises connections while you delete and recreate your gateway and connections, but you will not need to migrate any of your VMs or services to a new virtual network. Your VMs and services would still be able to communicate out through the load balancer while you configure your gateway if they are configured to do so.\n\n\n## Notes and limitations\n\n- You won’t be able to route (via Azure) between your local network connected via Site-to-Site VPN and your local network connected via ExpressRoute.\n- You can't enable Point-to-Site VPN connections to the same VNet that is connected to ExpressRoute. Point-to-Site VPN and ExpressRoute cannot coexist for the same VNet.\n- Both the ExpressRoute gateway and the Site-to-Site VPN gateway must be either a Standard or HighPerformance gateway SKU. For information about gateway SKUs, see [Gateway SKUs](../vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-about-vpngateways.md).\n- If your local network is connected to both ExpressRoute and a Site-to-Site VPN (Scenario 1), you should have a static route configured in your local network to route the Site-to-Site VPN connection to the public Internet.\n- You must create the ExpressRoute gateway first, before you add the Site-to-Site VPN gateway.\n- Both procedures assume that you already have an ExpressRoute circuit configured. If you do not, please see the following articles:\n\n    - [Configure an ExpressRoute connection through a network service provider (NSP)](expressroute-configuring-nsps.md)\n    - [Configure an ExpressRoute connection through an exchange provider (EXP)](expressroute-configuring-exps.md)\n\n\n## Create a new virtual network and connections that coexist\n\nThis procedure will walk you through creating a virtual network, as well as creating Site-to-Site and ExpressRoute connections that will coexist.\n\n1. Verify that you have the latest version of the PowerShell cmdlets. You can download and install the latest PowerShell cmdlets from the PowerShell section of the [Download page](http://azure.microsoft.com/downloads/).\n2. Create a schema for your virtual network. For more information about working with the network configuration file, see [Configure a virtual network using a network configuration file](../virtual-network/virtual-networks-using-network-configuration-file.md). For more information about the configuration schema, see [Azure Virtual Network Configuration Schema](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj157100.aspx).\n\n    When you create your schema, make sure you use the following values:\n\n    - The gateway subnet for the virtual network must be /27 (or a shorter prefix).\n    - The gateway connection type is \"Dedicated\".\n\n              <VirtualNetworkSite name=\"MyAzureVNET\" Location=\"Central US\">\n                <AddressSpace>\n                  <AddressPrefix>10.17.159.192/26</AddressPrefix>\n                </AddressSpace>\n                <Subnets>\n                  <Subnet name=\"Subnet-1\">\n                    <AddressPrefix>10.17.159.192/27</AddressPrefix>\n                  </Subnet>\n                  <Subnet name=\"GatewaySubnet\">\n                    <AddressPrefix>10.17.159.224/27</AddressPrefix>\n                  </Subnet>\n                </Subnets>\n                <Gateway>\n                  <ConnectionsToLocalNetwork>\n                    <LocalNetworkSiteRef name=\"MyLocalNetwork\">\n                      <Connection type=\"Dedicated\" />\n                    </LocalNetworkSiteRef>\n                  </ConnectionsToLocalNetwork>\n                </Gateway>\n              </VirtualNetworkSite>\n\n\n\n3. After creating and configuring your xml schema file, upload the file. This will create your virtual network.\n\n    Use the following cmdlet to upload your file, replacing the value with your own.\n\n    `Set-AzureVNetConfig -ConfigurationPath 'C:\\NetworkConfig.xml'`\n4. Create an ExpressRoute gateway. Be sure to specify the GatewaySKU as *Standard* or *HighPerformance* and the GatewayType as *DynamicRouting*.\n\n    Use the following sample, substituting the values for your own.\n\n    `New-AzureVNetGateway -VNetName MyAzureVNET -GatewayType DynamicRouting -GatewaySKU HighPerformance`\n\n5. Link the ExpressRoute gateway to the ExpressRoute circuit. After this step has been completed, the connection between your on-premises network and Azure, through ExpressRoute, is established.\n\n    `New-AzureDedicatedCircuitLink -ServiceKey <service-key> -VNetName MyAzureVNET`\n\n6. Next, create your Site-to-Site VPN gateway. The GatewaySKU must be *Standard* or *HighPerformance* and the GatewayType must be *DynamicRouting*.\n\n    `New-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway -VNetName MyAzureVNET -GatewayName S2SVPN -GatewayType DynamicRouting -GatewaySKU  HighPerformance`\n\n    To retrieve the virtual network gateway settings, including the gateway ID and the public IP, use the `Get-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway` cmdlet.\n\n        Get-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway\n\n        GatewayId            : 348ae011-ffa9-4add-b530-7cb30010565e\n        GatewayName          : S2SVPN\n        LastEventData        :\n        GatewayType          : DynamicRouting\n        LastEventTimeStamp   : 5/29/2015 4:41:41 PM\n        LastEventMessage     : Successfully created a gateway for the following virtual network: GNSDesMoines\n        LastEventID          : 23002\n        State                : Provisioned\n        VIPAddress           : 104.43.x.y\n        DefaultSite          :\n        GatewaySKU           : HighPerformance\n        Location             :\n        VnetId               : 979aabcf-e47f-4136-ab9b-b4780c1e1bd5\n        SubnetId             :\n        EnableBgp            : False\n        OperationDescription : Get-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway\n        OperationId          : 42773656-85e1-a6b6-8705-35473f1e6f6a\n        OperationStatus      : Succeeded\n\n7. Create a local site VPN gateway entity. This command doesn’t configure your on-premises VPN gateway. Rather, it allows you to provide the local gateway settings, such as the public IP and the on-premises address space, so that the Azure VPN gateway can connect to it.\n\n    > [AZURE.IMPORTANT] The local site for the site-to-site VPN is not defined in the netcfg. Instead, you must use this cmdlet to specify the local site parameters. You cannot define it using the Management Portal or the netcfg file.\n\n    Use the following sample, replacing the values with your own.\n\n    `New-AzureLocalNetworkGateway -GatewayName MyLocalNetwork -IpAddress <local-network- gateway-public-IP> -AddressSpace <local-network-address-space>`\n\n    To retrieve the virtual network gateway settings, including the gateway ID and the public IP, use the `Get-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway` cmdlet. See the following example.\n\n        Get-AzureLocalNetworkGateway\n\n        GatewayId            : 532cb428-8c8c-4596-9a4f-7ae3a9fcd01b\n        GatewayName          : MyLocalNetwork\n        IpAddress            : 23.39.x.y\n        AddressSpace         : {10.1.2.0/24}\n        OperationDescription : Get-AzureLocalNetworkGateway\n        OperationId          : ddc4bfae-502c-adc7-bd7d-1efbc00b3fe5\n        OperationStatus      : Succeeded\n\n\n8. Configure your local VPN device to connect to the new gateway. Use the information that you retrieved in step 6 when configuring your VPN device. For more information about VPN device configuration, see [VPN Device Configuration](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?linkid=615099).\n\n\n9. Link the Site-to-Site VPN gateway on Azure to the local gateway.\n\n    In this example, connectedEntityId is the local gateway ID, which you can find by running `Get-AzureLocalNetworkGateway`. You can find virtualNetworkGatewayId by using the `Get-AzureVirtualNetworkGateway` cmdlet. After this step, the connection between your local network and Azure via the Site-to-Site VPN connection is established.\n\n\n    `New-AzureVirtualNetworkGatewayConnection -connectedEntityId <local-network-gateway-id> -gatewayConnectionName Azure2Local -gatewayConnectionType IPsec -sharedKey abc123 -virtualNetworkGatewayId <azure-s2s-vpn-gateway-id>`\n\n\n## Configure connections that coexist for your existing virtual network\n\nIf you have an existing virtual network connected via either ExpressRoute or Site-to-Site VPN connection, in order to enable both connections to connect to the existing virtual network, you must first delete the existing gateway. This means your local premises will lose the connection to your virtual network over the gateway while you are working on this configuration.\n\n**Before you begin configuration:** Verify that you have enough IP addresses left in your virtual network so that you can increase the gateway subnet size.\n\n\n1. Download the latest version of the PowerShell cmdlets. You can download and install the latest PowerShell cmdlets from the PowerShell section of the [Download page](http://azure.microsoft.com/downloads/).\n\n2. Delete the existing Site-to-Site VPN gateway. Use the following cmdlet, replacing the values with your own.\n\n    `Remove-AzureVNetGateway –VnetName MyAzureVNET`\n\n2. Export the virtual network schema. Use the following PowerShell cmdlet, replacing the values with your own.\n\n    `Get-AzureVNetConfig –ExportToFile “C:\\NetworkConfig.xml”`\n3. Edit the network configuration file schema so that the gateway subnet is /27 (or a shorter prefix). See the following example. For more information about working with the network configuration file, see [Configure a Virtual Network using a network configuration file](../virtual-network/virtual-networks-using-network-configuration-file.md). For more information about the configuration schema, see [Azure Virtual Network Configuration Schema](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj157100.aspx).\n\n\n          <Subnet name=\"GatewaySubnet\">\n            <AddressPrefix>10.17.159.224/27</AddressPrefix>\n          </Subnet>\n4. If your previous gateway was a Site-to-Site VPN, you must also change the connection type to **Dedicated**.\n\n                 <Gateway>\n                  <ConnectionsToLocalNetwork>\n                    <LocalNetworkSiteRef name=\"MyLocalNetwork\">\n                      <Connection type=\"Dedicated\" />\n                    </LocalNetworkSiteRef>\n                  </ConnectionsToLocalNetwork>\n                </Gateway>\n5. At this point, you'll have a VNet with no gateways. You can proceed with **Step 3** in the article, [Create a new virtual network and connections](#create-a-new-virtual-network-and-connections-that-coexist), in order to create new gateways and complete your connections.\n\n\n\n## Next steps\n\nLearn more about ExpressRoute. See the [ExpressRoute overview](expressroute-introduction.md).\n\nLearn more about VPN Gateways. See [About VPN Gateways](../vpn-gateway/vpn-gateway-about-vpngateways.md).\n\ntest\n"
}