{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Policies in Azure API Management",
      "pos": [
        28,
        60
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Learn how to create, edit, and configure policies in API Management.",
      "pos": [
        80,
        148
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policies in Azure API Management",
      "pos": [
        462,
        494
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In Azure API Management, policies are a powerful capability of the system that allow the publisher to change the behavior of the API through configuration.",
      "pos": [
        496,
        651
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policies are a collection of Statements that are executed sequentially on the request or response of an API.",
      "pos": [
        652,
        760
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Popular Statements include format conversion from XML to JSON and call rate limiting to restrict the amount of incoming calls from a developer.",
      "pos": [
        761,
        904
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Many more policies are available out of the box.",
      "pos": [
        905,
        953
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        955,
        1040
      ],
      "content": "See the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Policy Reference<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept> for a full list of policy statements and their settings."
    },
    {
      "content": "Policies are applied inside the proxy which sits between the API consumer and the managed API.",
      "pos": [
        1042,
        1136
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The proxy receives all requests and usually forwards them unaltered to the underlying API.",
      "pos": [
        1137,
        1227
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "However a policy can apply changes to both the inbound request and outbound response.",
      "pos": [
        1228,
        1313
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policy expressions can be used as attribute values or text values in any of the API Management policies, unless the policy specifies otherwise.",
      "pos": [
        1315,
        1458
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Some policies such as the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Control flow<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Set variable<ept id=\"p2\">][]</ept> policies are based on policy expressions.",
      "pos": [
        1459,
        1564
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Advanced policies<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Policy expressions<ept id=\"p2\">][]</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1565,
        1640
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1645,
        1692
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"scopes\"&gt;</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>How to configure policies"
    },
    {
      "content": "Policies can be configured globally or at the scope of a <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Product<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>API<ept id=\"p2\">][]</ept> or <bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>Operation<ept id=\"p3\">][]</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        1693,
        1788
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To configure a policy, navigate to the Policies editor in the Publisher Portal.",
      "pos": [
        1789,
        1868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policies menu",
      "pos": [
        1872,
        1885
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The policies editor consists of three main sections: the policy scope (top), the policy definition where policies are edited (left) and the statements list (right):",
      "pos": [
        1903,
        2067
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Policies editor",
      "pos": [
        2071,
        2086
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To begin configuring a policy you must first select the scope at which the policy should apply.",
      "pos": [
        2106,
        2201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the screenshot below the Starter product is selected.",
      "pos": [
        2202,
        2258
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Note that the square symbol next to the policy name indicates that a policy is already applied at this level.",
      "pos": [
        2259,
        2368
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Scope",
      "pos": [
        2372,
        2377
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since a policy has already been applied, the configuration is shown in the definition view.",
      "pos": [
        2396,
        2487
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Configure",
      "pos": [
        2491,
        2500
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The policy is displayed read-only at first.",
      "pos": [
        2523,
        2566
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In order to edit the definition click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure Policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> action.",
      "pos": [
        2567,
        2637
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Edit",
      "pos": [
        2641,
        2645
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The policy definition is a simple XML document that describes a sequence of inbound and outbound statements.",
      "pos": [
        2663,
        2771
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The XML can be edited directly in the definition window.",
      "pos": [
        2772,
        2828
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A list of statements is provided to the right and statements applicable to the current scope are enabled and highlighted; as demonstrated by the Limit Call Rate statement in the screenshot above.",
      "pos": [
        2829,
        3024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Clicking an enabled statement will add the appropriate XML at the location of the cursor in the definition view.",
      "pos": [
        3026,
        3138
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        3141,
        3235
      ],
      "content": "A full list of policy statements and their settings are available in the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Policy Reference<ept id=\"p1\">][]</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, to add a new statement to restrict incoming requests to specified IP addresses, place the cursor just inside the content of the \"inbound\" XML element and click the Restrict caller IPs statement.",
      "pos": [
        3237,
        3444
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Restriction policies",
      "pos": [
        3448,
        3468
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This will add an XML snippet to the \"inbound\" element that provides guidance on how to configure the statement.",
      "pos": [
        3490,
        3601
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "To limit inbound requests and accept only those from an IP address of 1.2.3.4 modify the XML as follows:",
      "pos": [
        3749,
        3853
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Save",
      "pos": [
        3941,
        3945
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When complete configuring the statements for the policy, click Save and the changes will be propagated to the API Management proxy immediately.",
      "pos": [
        3963,
        4106
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        4110,
        4168
      ],
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a name=\"sections\"&gt;</ph> <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>Understanding policy configuration"
    },
    {
      "content": "A policy is a series of statements that execute in order for a request and a response.",
      "pos": [
        4170,
        4256
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The configuration is divided appropriately into an inbound (request) and outbound (policy) as shown in the configuration.",
      "pos": [
        4257,
        4378
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Since policies can be specified at different levels (global, product, api and operation) then the configuration provides a way for you to specify the order in which this definition's statements execute with respect to the parent policy.",
      "pos": [
        4627,
        4863
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, if you have a policy at the global level and a policy configured for an API, then whenever that particular API is used - both policies will be applied.",
      "pos": [
        4866,
        5030
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "API Management allows for deterministic ordering of combined policy statements via the base element.",
      "pos": [
        5031,
        5131
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In the example policy definition above, the cross-domain statement would execute before any higher policies which would in turn, be followed by the find-and-replace policy.",
      "pos": [
        5306,
        5478
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        5480,
        5574
      ],
      "content": "Note: A global policy has no parent policy and using the <ph id=\"ph1\">`&lt;base&gt;`</ph> element in it has no effect."
    },
    {
      "content": "Next steps",
      "pos": [
        5580,
        5590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Check out following video on policy expressions.",
      "pos": [
        5592,
        5640
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        6869,
        6873
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties \n    pageTitle=\"Policies in Azure API Management\" \n    description=\"Learn how to create, edit, and configure policies in API Management.\" \n    services=\"api-management\" \n    documentationCenter=\"\" \n    authors=\"steved0x\" \n    manager=\"dwrede\" \n    editor=\"\"/>\n\n<tags \n    ms.service=\"api-management\" \n    ms.workload=\"mobile\" \n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\" \n    ms.devlang=\"na\" \n    ms.topic=\"article\" \n    ms.date=\"06/24/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"sdanie\"/>\n\n\n#Policies in Azure API Management\n\nIn Azure API Management, policies are a powerful capability of the system that allow the publisher to change the behavior of the API through configuration. Policies are a collection of Statements that are executed sequentially on the request or response of an API. Popular Statements include format conversion from XML to JSON and call rate limiting to restrict the amount of incoming calls from a developer. Many more policies are available out of the box.\n\nSee the [Policy Reference][] for a full list of policy statements and their settings.\n\nPolicies are applied inside the proxy which sits between the API consumer and the managed API. The proxy receives all requests and usually forwards them unaltered to the underlying API. However a policy can apply changes to both the inbound request and outbound response.\n\nPolicy expressions can be used as attribute values or text values in any of the API Management policies, unless the policy specifies otherwise. Some policies such as the [Control flow][] and [Set variable][] policies are based on policy expressions. For more information, see [Advanced policies][] and [Policy expressions][].\n\n## <a name=\"scopes\"> </a>How to configure policies\nPolicies can be configured globally or at the scope of a [Product][], [API][] or [Operation][]. To configure a policy, navigate to the Policies editor in the Publisher Portal.\n\n![Policies menu][policies-menu]\n\nThe policies editor consists of three main sections: the policy scope (top), the policy definition where policies are edited (left) and the statements list (right):\n\n![Policies editor][policies-editor]\n\nTo begin configuring a policy you must first select the scope at which the policy should apply. In the screenshot below the Starter product is selected. Note that the square symbol next to the policy name indicates that a policy is already applied at this level.\n\n![Scope][policies-scope]\n\nSince a policy has already been applied, the configuration is shown in the definition view.\n\n![Configure][policies-configure]\n\nThe policy is displayed read-only at first. In order to edit the definition click the **Configure Policy** action.\n\n![Edit][policies-edit]\n\nThe policy definition is a simple XML document that describes a sequence of inbound and outbound statements. The XML can be edited directly in the definition window. A list of statements is provided to the right and statements applicable to the current scope are enabled and highlighted; as demonstrated by the Limit Call Rate statement in the screenshot above.\n\nClicking an enabled statement will add the appropriate XML at the location of the cursor in the definition view. \n\nA full list of policy statements and their settings are available in the [Policy Reference][].\n\nFor example, to add a new statement to restrict incoming requests to specified IP addresses, place the cursor just inside the content of the \"inbound\" XML element and click the Restrict caller IPs statement.\n\n![Restriction policies][policies-restrict]\n\nThis will add an XML snippet to the \"inbound\" element that provides guidance on how to configure the statement.\n\n    <ip-filter action=\"allow | forbid\">\n        <address>address</address>\n        <address-range from=\"address\" to=\"address\"/>\n    </ip-filter>\n\nTo limit inbound requests and accept only those from an IP address of 1.2.3.4 modify the XML as follows:\n\n    <ip-filter action=\"allow\">\n        <address>1.2.3.4</address>\n    </ip-filter>\n\n![Save][policies-save]\n\nWhen complete configuring the statements for the policy, click Save and the changes will be propagated to the API Management proxy immediately.\n\n##<a name=\"sections\"> </a>Understanding policy configuration\n\nA policy is a series of statements that execute in order for a request and a response. The configuration is divided appropriately into an inbound (request) and outbound (policy) as shown in the configuration.\n\n    <policies>\n        <inbound>\n            <!-- statements to be applied to the request go here -->\n        </inbound>\n        <outbound>\n            <!-- statements to be applied to the response go here -->\n        </outbound>\n    </policies>\n\nSince policies can be specified at different levels (global, product, api and operation) then the configuration provides a way for you to specify the order in which this definition's statements execute with respect to the parent policy. \n\nFor example, if you have a policy at the global level and a policy configured for an API, then whenever that particular API is used - both policies will be applied. API Management allows for deterministic ordering of combined policy statements via the base element. \n\n    <policies>\n        <inbound>\n            <cross-domain />\n            <base />\n            <find-and-replace from=\"xyz\" to=\"abc\" />\n        </inbound>\n    </policies>\n\nIn the example policy definition above, the cross-domain statement would execute before any higher policies which would in turn, be followed by the find-and-replace policy.\n\nNote: A global policy has no parent policy and using the `<base>` element in it has no effect. \n\n## Next steps\n\nCheck out following video on policy expressions.\n\n> [AZURE.VIDEO policy-expressions-in-azure-api-management]\n\n[Policy Reference]: api-management-policy-reference.md\n[Product]: api-management-howto-add-products.md\n[API]: api-management-howto-add-products.md#add-apis \n[Operation]: api-management-howto-add-operations.md\n\n[Advanced policies]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn894085.aspx\n[Control flow]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn894085.aspx#choose\n[Set variable]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn894085.aspx#set_variable\n[Policy expressions]: https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn910913.aspx\n\n[policies-menu]: ./media/api-management-howto-policies/api-management-policies-menu.png\n[policies-editor]: ./media/api-management-howto-policies/api-management-policies-editor.png\n[policies-scope]: ./media/api-management-howto-policies/api-management-policies-scope.png\n[policies-configure]: ./media/api-management-howto-policies/api-management-policies-configure.png\n[policies-edit]: ./media/api-management-howto-policies/api-management-policies-edit.png\n[policies-restrict]: ./media/api-management-howto-policies/api-management-policies-restrict.png\n[policies-save]: ./media/api-management-howto-policies/api-management-policies-save.png\n\ntest\n"
}