{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "What is Self-Service Signup for Azure?",
      "pos": [
        27,
        65
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An overview self-service signup for Azure, how to manage the sign up process and how to .",
      "pos": [
        84,
        173
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is Self-Service Signup for Azure?",
      "pos": [
        494,
        532
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This topic explains the self-service signup process (sometimes known as viral signup) and how to take over a DNS domain name.",
      "pos": [
        534,
        659
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Why use self-service signup?",
      "pos": [
        666,
        694
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get customers to services they want faster.",
      "pos": [
        698,
        741
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create email-based (viral) offers for a service.",
      "pos": [
        744,
        792
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create email-based signup flows which quickly allow users to create identities using their easy-to-remember work email aliases.",
      "pos": [
        795,
        922
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Unmanaged Azure tenants can grow and become managed tenants later and be reused for other services.",
      "pos": [
        925,
        1024
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Terms and Definitions",
      "pos": [
        1029,
        1050
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        1054,
        1249
      ],
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Self-service sign up<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: This is the method by which a user signs up for a cloud service and has an identity automatically created for them in Azure Active Directory based on their email domain."
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Unmanaged Azure tenant<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: This is the directory where that identity is created.",
      "pos": [
        1252,
        1333
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An unmanaged tenant is a directory that has no global administrator.",
      "pos": [
        1334,
        1402
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Email-verified user<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>: This is a type of user account in Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        1405,
        1473
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A user who has an identity created automatically after signing up for a self-service offer is known as an email-verified user.",
      "pos": [
        1474,
        1600
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An email-verified user is a regular member of a directory tagged with creationmethod=EmailVerified.",
      "pos": [
        1601,
        1700
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Customer experience",
      "pos": [
        1705,
        1724
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "User experience",
      "pos": [
        1730,
        1745
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, let's say a user whose email is Dan@BellowsCollege.com receives sensitive files via email.",
      "pos": [
        1747,
        1850
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The files have been protected by Azure Rights Management (Azure RMS).",
      "pos": [
        1851,
        1920
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "But Dan's organization, Bellows College, has not signed up for Azure RMS, nor has it deployed Active Directory RMS.",
      "pos": [
        1921,
        2036
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In this case, Dan can sign up for a free subscription to RMS for individuals in order to read the protected files.",
      "pos": [
        2037,
        2151
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If Dan is the first user with an email address from BellowsCollege.com to sign up for this self-service offering, then an unmanaged tenant will be created for BellowsCollege.com in Azure AD.",
      "pos": [
        2153,
        2343
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If other users from the BellowsCollege.com domain sign up for this offering or a similar self-service offering, they will also have email-verified user accounts created in the same unmanaged tenant in Azure.",
      "pos": [
        2344,
        2551
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Admin experience",
      "pos": [
        2557,
        2573
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An admin who owns the DNS domain name of an unmanaged Azure tenant can take over or merge the tenant after proving ownership.",
      "pos": [
        2575,
        2700
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The next sections explain the admin experience in more detail, but here's a summary:",
      "pos": [
        2701,
        2785
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you take over an unmanaged Azure tenant, you simply become the global administrator of the unmanaged tenant.",
      "pos": [
        2789,
        2902
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is sometimes called an internal takeover.",
      "pos": [
        2903,
        2949
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you merge an unmanaged Azure tenant, you add the DNS domain name of the unmanaged tenant to your managed Azure tenant and a mapping of users-to-resources is created so users can continue to access services without interruption.",
      "pos": [
        2952,
        3184
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This is sometimes called an external takeover.",
      "pos": [
        3185,
        3231
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What gets created in the Microsoft Azure Directory?",
      "pos": [
        3237,
        3288
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tenant",
      "pos": [
        3295,
        3301
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An Azure tenant for the domain is created, one tenant per domain.",
      "pos": [
        3305,
        3370
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Azure tenant directory has no global admin.",
      "pos": [
        3373,
        3420
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Users",
      "pos": [
        3427,
        3432
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For each user who signs up, a user object is created in the Azure tenant.",
      "pos": [
        3436,
        3509
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each user object is marked as viral.",
      "pos": [
        3512,
        3548
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Each user is given access to the service that they user signed up for.",
      "pos": [
        3551,
        3621
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How do I claim a self-service Azure tenant for a domain I own?",
      "pos": [
        3627,
        3689
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can claim a self-service Azure tenant by performing domain validation.",
      "pos": [
        3691,
        3765
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Domain validation proves you own the domain by creating DNS records.",
      "pos": [
        3766,
        3834
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two ways to do a DNS takeover of an Azure tenant:",
      "pos": [
        3836,
        3895
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "internal takeover (Admin discovers an unmanaged Azure tenant, and wants to turn into a managed tenant)",
      "pos": [
        3899,
        4001
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "external takeover (Admin tries to add a new domain to their managed Azure tenant)",
      "pos": [
        4004,
        4085
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You might be interested in validating that you own a domain because you are taking over an unmanaged tenant after a user performed self-service signup, or you might be adding a new domain to an existing managed tenant.",
      "pos": [
        4087,
        4305
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, you have a domain named contoso.com and you want to add a new domain named contoso.co.uk or contoso.uk.",
      "pos": [
        4306,
        4422
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is domain takeover?",
      "pos": [
        4427,
        4451
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "This section covers how to validate that you own a domain",
      "pos": [
        4455,
        4512
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What is domain validation and why is it used?",
      "pos": [
        4518,
        4563
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In order to perform operations on a tenant, Azure AD requires that you validate ownership of the DNS domain.",
      "pos": [
        4565,
        4673
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Validation of the domain allows you to claim the tenant and either promote the self-service tenant to a managed tenant, or merge the self-service tenant into an existing managed tenant.",
      "pos": [
        4675,
        4860
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Examples of domain validation",
      "pos": [
        4865,
        4894
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "There are two ways to do a DNS takeover of a tenant:",
      "pos": [
        4896,
        4948
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "internal takeover  (For example, an admin discovers a self-service, unmanaged tenant, and wants to turn into managed tenant)",
      "pos": [
        4952,
        5076
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "external takeover (For example, a admin tries to add a new domain to a managed tenant)",
      "pos": [
        5079,
        5165
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Internal Takeover - promote a self-service, unmanaged tenant to be a managed tenant",
      "pos": [
        5171,
        5254
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "When you do internal takeover, the tenant gets converted from an unmanaged tenant to a managed tenant.",
      "pos": [
        5256,
        5358
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You need to complete DNS domain name validation, where you create an MX record or a TXT record in the DNS zone.",
      "pos": [
        5359,
        5470
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "That action:",
      "pos": [
        5471,
        5483
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Validates that you own the domain",
      "pos": [
        5487,
        5520
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Makes the tenant managed",
      "pos": [
        5523,
        5547
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Makes you the global admin of the tenant",
      "pos": [
        5550,
        5590
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Let's say an IT administrator from Bellows College discovers that users from the school have signed up for self-service offerings.",
      "pos": [
        5592,
        5722
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As the registered owner of the DNS name BellowsCollege.com, the IT administrator can validate ownership of the DNS name in Azure and then take over the unmanaged tenant.",
      "pos": [
        5723,
        5892
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The tenant then becomes a managed tenant, and the IT administrator is assigned the global administrator role for the BellowsCollege.com directory.",
      "pos": [
        5893,
        6039
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "External Takeover - merge a self-service tenant into an existing managed tenant",
      "pos": [
        6045,
        6124
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In an external takeover, you already have a managed tenant and you want all users and groups from an unmanaged tenant to join that managed tenant, rather than own two separate tenants.",
      "pos": [
        6126,
        6310
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "As an admin of a managed tenant, you add a domain, and that domain happens to have an unmanaged tenant associated with it.",
      "pos": [
        6312,
        6434
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, let's say you are an IT administrator and you already have a managed tenant for Contoso.com, a domain name that is registered to your organization.",
      "pos": [
        6436,
        6596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You discover that users from your organization have performed self-service sign up for an offering by using email domain name user@contoso.co.uk, which is another domain name that your organization owns.",
      "pos": [
        6597,
        6800
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Those users currently have accounts in an unmanaged tenant for contoso.co.uk.",
      "pos": [
        6801,
        6878
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You don't want to manage two separate tenants, so you merge the unmanaged tenant for contoso.co.uk into your existing IT managed tenant for contoso.com.",
      "pos": [
        6880,
        7032
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "External takeover follows the same DNS validation process as internal takeover.",
      "pos": [
        7034,
        7113
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Difference being: users and services are remapped to the IT managed tenant.",
      "pos": [
        7115,
        7190
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "What's the impact of performing an external takeover?",
      "pos": [
        7197,
        7250
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "With an external takeover, a mapping of users-to-resources is created so users can continue to access services without interruption.",
      "pos": [
        7252,
        7384
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Many applications, including RMS for individuals, handle the mapping of users-to-resources well, and users can continue to access those services without change.",
      "pos": [
        7385,
        7545
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If an application does not handle the mapping of users-to-resources effectively, external takeover may be explicitly blocked to prevent users from a poor experience.",
      "pos": [
        7546,
        7711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Tenant takeover support by service",
      "pos": [
        7718,
        7752
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Currently the following services support takeover:",
      "pos": [
        7754,
        7804
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "RMS",
      "pos": [
        7808,
        7811
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following services will soon be supporting takeover:",
      "pos": [
        7814,
        7870
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "PowerBI",
      "pos": [
        7874,
        7881
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following do not and require additional admin action to migrate user data after an external takeover.",
      "pos": [
        7883,
        7988
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "SharePoint/OneDrive",
      "pos": [
        7992,
        8011
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to perform a DNS domain name takeover",
      "pos": [
        8017,
        8058
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You have a few options for how to perform a domain validation (and do a takeover if you wish):",
      "pos": [
        8060,
        8154
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Management Portal",
      "pos": [
        8160,
        8183
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A takeover is triggered by doing a domain addition.",
      "pos": [
        8189,
        8240
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If a tenant already exists for the domain, you'll have the option to perform an external takeover.",
      "pos": [
        8242,
        8340
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Sign in to the Azure portal using your credentials.",
      "pos": [
        8346,
        8397
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Navigate to your existing tenant and then to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Add domain<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8399,
        8459
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Office 365",
      "pos": [
        8465,
        8475
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "You can use the options on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage domains<ept id=\"p1\">](https://support.office.com/article/Navigate-to-the-Office-365-Manage-domains-page-026af1f2-0e6d-4f2d-9b33-fd147420fac2/)</ept> page in Office 365 to work with your domains and DNS records.",
      "pos": [
        8481,
        8711
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "See <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Verify your domain in Office 365<ept id=\"p1\">](https://support.office.com/article/Verify-your-domain-in-Office-365-6383f56d-3d09-4dcb-9b41-b5f5a5efd611/)</ept>.",
      "pos": [
        8712,
        8858
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        8864,
        8882
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following steps are required to perform a validation using Windows PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        8888,
        8970
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Step",
      "pos": [
        8976,
        8980
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Cmdlet to use",
      "pos": [
        8988,
        9001
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a credential object",
      "pos": [
        9034,
        9060
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-Credential",
      "pos": [
        9063,
        9077
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connect to Azure AD",
      "pos": [
        9082,
        9101
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Connect-MsolService",
      "pos": [
        9104,
        9123
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "get a list of domains",
      "pos": [
        9128,
        9149
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-MsolDomain",
      "pos": [
        9154,
        9168
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create a challenge",
      "pos": [
        9173,
        9191
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-MsolDomainVerificationDns",
      "pos": [
        9195,
        9224
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Create DNS record",
      "pos": [
        9229,
        9246
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Do this on your DNS server",
      "pos": [
        9251,
        9277
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Verify the challenge",
      "pos": [
        9282,
        9302
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Confirm-MsolEmailVerifiedDomain",
      "pos": [
        9308,
        9339
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example:",
      "pos": [
        9341,
        9353
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9358,
        9571
      ],
      "content": "Connect to Azure AD using the credentials that were used to respond to the self-service offering:\n     import-module MSOnline\n     $msolcred = get-credential\n     connect-msolservice -credential $msolcred",
      "leadings": [
        "",
        "   ",
        "   ",
        "   "
      ],
      "nodes": [
        {
          "content": "Connect to Azure AD using the credentials that were used to respond to the self-service offering:",
          "pos": [
            0,
            97
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "import-module MSOnline",
          "pos": [
            103,
            125
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "$msolcred = get-credential",
          "pos": [
            131,
            157
          ]
        },
        {
          "content": "connect-msolservice -credential $msolcred",
          "pos": [
            163,
            204
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get a list of domains:",
      "pos": [
        9576,
        9598
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-MsolDomain",
      "pos": [
        9604,
        9618
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Then run the Get-MsolDomainVerificationDns cmdlet to create a challenge:",
      "pos": [
        9623,
        9695
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        9701,
        9780
      ],
      "content": "Get-MsolDomainVerificationDns –DomainName <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>your_domain_name<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> –Mode DnsTxtRecord"
    },
    {
      "content": "For example:",
      "pos": [
        9786,
        9798
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Get-MsolDomainVerificationDns –DomainName contoso.com –Mode DnsTxtRecord",
      "pos": [
        9804,
        9876
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Copy the value (the challenge) that is returned from this command.",
      "pos": [
        9881,
        9947
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example:",
      "pos": [
        9953,
        9965
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "MS=32DD01B82C05D27151EA9AE93C5890787F0E65D9",
      "pos": [
        9971,
        10014
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "In your public DNS namespace, create a DNS txt record that contains the value that you copied in the previous step.",
      "pos": [
        10019,
        10134
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The name for this record is the name of the parent domain, so if you create this resource record by using the DNS role from Windows Server, leave the Record name blank and just paste the value into the Text box",
      "pos": [
        10140,
        10350
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Run the Confirm-MsolDomain cmdlet to verify the challenge:",
      "pos": [
        10355,
        10413
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        10419,
        10481
      ],
      "content": "Confirm-MsolEmailVerifiedDomain -DomainName <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>your_domain_name<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>"
    },
    {
      "content": "for example:",
      "pos": [
        10487,
        10499
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Confirm-MsolEmailVerifiedDomain -DomainName contoso.com",
      "pos": [
        10505,
        10560
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "A successful challenge returns you to the prompt without an error.",
      "pos": [
        10562,
        10628
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How do I control self-service settings?",
      "pos": [
        10633,
        10672
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Admins have two self-service controls today.",
      "pos": [
        10674,
        10718
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "They can control:",
      "pos": [
        10719,
        10736
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Whether or not users can join the tenant via email.",
      "pos": [
        10740,
        10791
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Whether or not users can license themselves for applications and services.",
      "pos": [
        10794,
        10868
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How can I control these capabilities?",
      "pos": [
        10875,
        10912
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "An admin can configure these capabilities using these Azure AD cmdlet Set-MsolCompanySettings parameters:",
      "pos": [
        10914,
        11019
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AllowEmailVerifiedUsers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> controls whether a user can create or join an unmanaged tenant.",
      "pos": [
        11023,
        11114
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you set that parameter to $false, no email-verified users can join the tenant.",
      "pos": [
        11115,
        11196
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AllowAdHocSubscriptions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> controls the ability for users to perform self-service sign up.",
      "pos": [
        11199,
        11290
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "If you set that parameter to $false, no users can perform self-service signup.",
      "pos": [
        11291,
        11369
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How do the controls work together?",
      "pos": [
        11376,
        11410
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "These two parameters can be used in conjunction to define more precise control over self-service sign up.",
      "pos": [
        11412,
        11517
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "For example, the following command will allow users to perform self-service sign up, but only if those users already have an account in Azure AD (in other words, users who would need an email-verified account to be created cannot perform self-service sign up):",
      "pos": [
        11518,
        11778
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The following flowchart explains all the different combinations for these parameters and the resulting conditions for the tenant and self-service sign up.",
      "pos": [
        11872,
        12026
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "![][1]",
      "pos": [
        12028,
        12034
      ]
    },
    {
      "pos": [
        12036,
        12188
      ],
      "content": "For more information and examples of how to use these parameters, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set-MsolCompanySettings<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn194127.aspx)</ept>."
    },
    {
      "content": "See Also",
      "pos": [
        12193,
        12201
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "How to install and configure Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        12207,
        12252
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure PowerShell",
      "pos": [
        12293,
        12309
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Azure Cmdlet Reference",
      "pos": [
        12372,
        12394
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Set-MsolCompanySettings",
      "pos": [
        12457,
        12480
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "test",
      "pos": [
        12644,
        12648
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "<properties\n    pageTitle=\"What is Self-Service Signup for Azure?\"\n    description=\"An overview self-service signup for Azure, how to manage the sign up process and how to .\"\n    services=\"active-directory\"\n    documentationCenter=\"\"\n    authors=\"curtand\"\n    manager=\"stevenpo\"\n    editor=\"LisaToft\"/>\n\n<tags\n    ms.service=\"active-directory\"\n    ms.devlang=\"na\"\n    ms.topic=\"article\"\n    ms.tgt_pltfrm=\"na\"\n    ms.workload=\"identity\"\n    ms.date=\"08/14/2015\" \n    ms.author=\"stevenpo\"/>\n\n\n# What is Self-Service Signup for Azure?\n\nThis topic explains the self-service signup process (sometimes known as viral signup) and how to take over a DNS domain name.  \n\n## Why use self-service signup?\n\n- Get customers to services they want faster.\n- Create email-based (viral) offers for a service.\n- Create email-based signup flows which quickly allow users to create identities using their easy-to-remember work email aliases.\n- Unmanaged Azure tenants can grow and become managed tenants later and be reused for other services.\n\n## Terms and Definitions\n\n+ **Self-service sign up**: This is the method by which a user signs up for a cloud service and has an identity automatically created for them in Azure Active Directory based on their email domain.\n+ **Unmanaged Azure tenant**: This is the directory where that identity is created. An unmanaged tenant is a directory that has no global administrator.\n+ **Email-verified user**: This is a type of user account in Azure AD. A user who has an identity created automatically after signing up for a self-service offer is known as an email-verified user. An email-verified user is a regular member of a directory tagged with creationmethod=EmailVerified.\n\n## Customer experience\n\n### User experience\n\nFor example, let's say a user whose email is Dan@BellowsCollege.com receives sensitive files via email. The files have been protected by Azure Rights Management (Azure RMS). But Dan's organization, Bellows College, has not signed up for Azure RMS, nor has it deployed Active Directory RMS. In this case, Dan can sign up for a free subscription to RMS for individuals in order to read the protected files.\n\nIf Dan is the first user with an email address from BellowsCollege.com to sign up for this self-service offering, then an unmanaged tenant will be created for BellowsCollege.com in Azure AD. If other users from the BellowsCollege.com domain sign up for this offering or a similar self-service offering, they will also have email-verified user accounts created in the same unmanaged tenant in Azure.\n\n### Admin experience\n\nAn admin who owns the DNS domain name of an unmanaged Azure tenant can take over or merge the tenant after proving ownership. The next sections explain the admin experience in more detail, but here's a summary:\n\n- When you take over an unmanaged Azure tenant, you simply become the global administrator of the unmanaged tenant. This is sometimes called an internal takeover.\n- When you merge an unmanaged Azure tenant, you add the DNS domain name of the unmanaged tenant to your managed Azure tenant and a mapping of users-to-resources is created so users can continue to access services without interruption. This is sometimes called an external takeover.\n\n### What gets created in the Microsoft Azure Directory?\n\n#### Tenant\n\n- An Azure tenant for the domain is created, one tenant per domain.\n- The Azure tenant directory has no global admin.\n\n#### Users\n\n- For each user who signs up, a user object is created in the Azure tenant.\n- Each user object is marked as viral.\n- Each user is given access to the service that they user signed up for.\n\n### How do I claim a self-service Azure tenant for a domain I own?\n\nYou can claim a self-service Azure tenant by performing domain validation. Domain validation proves you own the domain by creating DNS records.\n\nThere are two ways to do a DNS takeover of an Azure tenant:\n\n- internal takeover (Admin discovers an unmanaged Azure tenant, and wants to turn into a managed tenant)\n- external takeover (Admin tries to add a new domain to their managed Azure tenant)\n\nYou might be interested in validating that you own a domain because you are taking over an unmanaged tenant after a user performed self-service signup, or you might be adding a new domain to an existing managed tenant. For example, you have a domain named contoso.com and you want to add a new domain named contoso.co.uk or contoso.uk.\n\n## What is domain takeover?  \n\nThis section covers how to validate that you own a domain\n\n### What is domain validation and why is it used?\n\nIn order to perform operations on a tenant, Azure AD requires that you validate ownership of the DNS domain.  Validation of the domain allows you to claim the tenant and either promote the self-service tenant to a managed tenant, or merge the self-service tenant into an existing managed tenant.\n\n## Examples of domain validation\n\nThere are two ways to do a DNS takeover of a tenant:\n\n+ internal takeover  (For example, an admin discovers a self-service, unmanaged tenant, and wants to turn into managed tenant)\n+ external takeover (For example, a admin tries to add a new domain to a managed tenant)\n\n### Internal Takeover - promote a self-service, unmanaged tenant to be a managed tenant\n\nWhen you do internal takeover, the tenant gets converted from an unmanaged tenant to a managed tenant. You need to complete DNS domain name validation, where you create an MX record or a TXT record in the DNS zone. That action:\n\n+ Validates that you own the domain\n+ Makes the tenant managed\n+ Makes you the global admin of the tenant\n\nLet's say an IT administrator from Bellows College discovers that users from the school have signed up for self-service offerings. As the registered owner of the DNS name BellowsCollege.com, the IT administrator can validate ownership of the DNS name in Azure and then take over the unmanaged tenant. The tenant then becomes a managed tenant, and the IT administrator is assigned the global administrator role for the BellowsCollege.com directory.\n\n### External Takeover - merge a self-service tenant into an existing managed tenant\n\nIn an external takeover, you already have a managed tenant and you want all users and groups from an unmanaged tenant to join that managed tenant, rather than own two separate tenants.\n\nAs an admin of a managed tenant, you add a domain, and that domain happens to have an unmanaged tenant associated with it.\n\nFor example, let's say you are an IT administrator and you already have a managed tenant for Contoso.com, a domain name that is registered to your organization. You discover that users from your organization have performed self-service sign up for an offering by using email domain name user@contoso.co.uk, which is another domain name that your organization owns. Those users currently have accounts in an unmanaged tenant for contoso.co.uk.\n\nYou don't want to manage two separate tenants, so you merge the unmanaged tenant for contoso.co.uk into your existing IT managed tenant for contoso.com.\n\nExternal takeover follows the same DNS validation process as internal takeover.  Difference being: users and services are remapped to the IT managed tenant.\n\n#### What's the impact of performing an external takeover?\n\nWith an external takeover, a mapping of users-to-resources is created so users can continue to access services without interruption. Many applications, including RMS for individuals, handle the mapping of users-to-resources well, and users can continue to access those services without change. If an application does not handle the mapping of users-to-resources effectively, external takeover may be explicitly blocked to prevent users from a poor experience.\n\n#### Tenant takeover support by service\n\nCurrently the following services support takeover:\n\n- RMS\n\n\nThe following services will soon be supporting takeover:\n\n- PowerBI\n\nThe following do not and require additional admin action to migrate user data after an external takeover.\n\n- SharePoint/OneDrive\n\n\n## How to perform a DNS domain name takeover\n\nYou have a few options for how to perform a domain validation (and do a takeover if you wish):\n\n1.  Azure Management Portal\n\n    A takeover is triggered by doing a domain addition.  If a tenant already exists for the domain, you'll have the option to perform an external takeover.\n\n    Sign in to the Azure portal using your credentials.  Navigate to your existing tenant and then to **Add domain**.\n\n2.  Office 365\n\n    You can use the options on the [Manage domains](https://support.office.com/article/Navigate-to-the-Office-365-Manage-domains-page-026af1f2-0e6d-4f2d-9b33-fd147420fac2/) page in Office 365 to work with your domains and DNS records. See [Verify your domain in Office 365](https://support.office.com/article/Verify-your-domain-in-Office-365-6383f56d-3d09-4dcb-9b41-b5f5a5efd611/).\n\n3.  Windows PowerShell\n\n    The following steps are required to perform a validation using Windows PowerShell.\n\n    Step    |   Cmdlet to use\n    ------- | -------------\n    Create a credential object | Get-Credential\n    Connect to Azure AD | Connect-MsolService\n    get a list of domains   | Get-MsolDomain\n    Create a challenge  | Get-MsolDomainVerificationDns\n    Create DNS record   | Do this on your DNS server\n    Verify the challenge    | Confirm-MsolEmailVerifiedDomain\n\nFor example:\n\n1. Connect to Azure AD using the credentials that were used to respond to the self-service offering:\n        import-module MSOnline\n        $msolcred = get-credential\n        connect-msolservice -credential $msolcred\n\n2. Get a list of domains:\n\n    Get-MsolDomain\n\n3. Then run the Get-MsolDomainVerificationDns cmdlet to create a challenge:\n\n    Get-MsolDomainVerificationDns –DomainName *your_domain_name* –Mode DnsTxtRecord\n\n    For example:\n\n    Get-MsolDomainVerificationDns –DomainName contoso.com –Mode DnsTxtRecord\n\n4. Copy the value (the challenge) that is returned from this command.\n\n    For example:\n\n    MS=32DD01B82C05D27151EA9AE93C5890787F0E65D9\n\n5. In your public DNS namespace, create a DNS txt record that contains the value that you copied in the previous step.\n\n    The name for this record is the name of the parent domain, so if you create this resource record by using the DNS role from Windows Server, leave the Record name blank and just paste the value into the Text box\n\n6. Run the Confirm-MsolDomain cmdlet to verify the challenge:\n\n    Confirm-MsolEmailVerifiedDomain -DomainName *your_domain_name*\n\n    for example:\n\n    Confirm-MsolEmailVerifiedDomain -DomainName contoso.com\n\nA successful challenge returns you to the prompt without an error.\n\n## How do I control self-service settings?\n\nAdmins have two self-service controls today. They can control:\n\n- Whether or not users can join the tenant via email.\n- Whether or not users can license themselves for applications and services.\n\n\n### How can I control these capabilities?\n\nAn admin can configure these capabilities using these Azure AD cmdlet Set-MsolCompanySettings parameters:\n\n+ **AllowEmailVerifiedUsers** controls whether a user can create or join an unmanaged tenant. If you set that parameter to $false, no email-verified users can join the tenant.\n+ **AllowAdHocSubscriptions** controls the ability for users to perform self-service sign up. If you set that parameter to $false, no users can perform self-service signup.\n\n\n### How do the controls work together?\n\nThese two parameters can be used in conjunction to define more precise control over self-service sign up. For example, the following command will allow users to perform self-service sign up, but only if those users already have an account in Azure AD (in other words, users who would need an email-verified account to be created cannot perform self-service sign up):\n\n    Set-MsolCompanySettings -AllowEmailVerifiedUsers $false -AllowAdHocSubscriptions $true\n\nThe following flowchart explains all the different combinations for these parameters and the resulting conditions for the tenant and self-service sign up.\n\n![][1]\n\nFor more information and examples of how to use these parameters, see [Set-MsolCompanySettings](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn194127.aspx).\n\n## See Also\n\n-  [How to install and configure Azure PowerShell](../powershell-install-configure/)\n\n-  [Azure PowerShell](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj156055.aspx)\n\n-  [Azure Cmdlet Reference](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/jj554330.aspx)\n\n-  [Set-MsolCompanySettings](https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/azure/dn194127.aspx)\n\n<!--Image references-->\n[1]: ./media/active-directory-self-service-signup/SelfServiceSignUpControls.png\n\ntest\n"
}