{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "A subset of data from the blood donor database of the Blood Transfusion Service Center of Hsin-Chu City, Taiwan.",
      "pos": [
        0,
        112
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Donor data includes the months since last donation), and frequency, or the total number of donations, time since last donation, and amount of blood donated.",
      "pos": [
        120,
        276
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Usage:<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph> The goal is to predict via classification whether the donor donated blood in March 2007, where 1 indicates a donor during the target period, and 0 a non-donor.",
      "pos": [
        284,
        457
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;b&gt;</ph>Related Research:<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/b&gt;</ph> Yeh, I.C., (2008).",
      "pos": [
        466,
        509
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "UCI Machine Learning Repository <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml\"&gt;</ph>http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>.",
      "pos": [
        510,
        616
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Irvine, CA: University of California, School of Information and Computer Science",
      "pos": [
        617,
        697
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Yeh, I-Cheng, Yang, King-Jang, and Ting, Tao-Ming, \"Knowledge discovery on RFM model using Bernoulli sequence, \"Expert Systems with Applications, 2008, <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;a href=\"http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2008.07.018\"&gt;</ph>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2008.07.018<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;/a&gt;</ph>",
      "pos": [
        706,
        961
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "A subset of data from the blood donor database of the Blood Transfusion Service Center of Hsin-Chu City, Taiwan.<p> </p>Donor data includes the months since last donation), and frequency, or the total number of donations, time since last donation, and amount of blood donated.<p> </p><b>Usage:</b> The goal is to predict via classification whether the donor donated blood in March 2007, where 1 indicates a donor during the target period, and 0 a non-donor. <p> </p><b>Related Research:</b> Yeh, I.C., (2008). UCI Machine Learning Repository <a href=\"http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml\">http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml</a>. Irvine, CA: University of California, School of Information and Computer Science <p> </p>Yeh, I-Cheng, Yang, King-Jang, and Ting, Tao-Ming, \"Knowledge discovery on RFM model using Bernoulli sequence, \"Expert Systems with Applications, 2008, <a href=\"http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2008.07.018\">http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2008.07.018</a>"
}